import{_ as k,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as p,p as c,e as f,f as j,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},T={class:"review-content"};function x(e,a,s,g,t,u){return i(),o("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",T,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const S=k(q,[["render",x],["__scopeId","data-v-9c65044f"]]),I=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Тамак жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Тамак үчүн асмандагы куш торго түшүптүр."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පොල් පර්යේෂණාගාරය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ කොහෙද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පොල් පර්යේෂණාගාරය පිහිටා ඇත්තේ ලුණුවිල නගරයෙහිය."},{"question":"කිතු දහමේ එන  මූල පාපය නම් කුමක්ද?","answer":"“මූල පාපය” යන පදය හොඳ සහ නරක දැනගැනීමේ වෘක්ෂයෙන් කෑම කරණකොටගෙන ආදම්ගේ අකීකරුකම නමැති පාපය හේතු කොටගෙන මුලු මහත් මනුෂ්‍යය වර්ගයාටම ඇතිවූ බලපෑම කෙරෙහි කටයුතු කරයි. මූල පාපය අපට අර්ථ දැක්විය හැක්කේ “ඒදන් උයනෙහි ආදම් විසින් සිදු කළ පාපයේ සෘජු ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස දෙවියන් වහන්සේගේ ඇස් හමූහයෙහි අපට අයිතිව ඇති පාපය සහ එහි වරදකාරිත්වය” ලෙසයි. අප දැනුවත්ව පව් කිරීමට දැනුම් තේරුම් ඇති වයසකට පත් වන්නටත් ප්‍රථමයෙන්, මූල පාපය නම් මතවාදය අපගේ ස්වභාවයට ඇති බලපෑම සහ දෙවියන් වහන්සේ ඉදිරියේ අපගේ ස්ථාවරභාවය කෙරෙහි විශේෂයෙන්ම යොමුවේ. එම බලපෑම කෙරෙහි කටයුතු කරන ප්‍රධාන මතයන් 3 ක් (තුනක්) තිබේ."},{"question":"Hallo, ik ben Anna, de virtuele chatbot van uw energiebedrijf. Vertel me uw vraag, en ik help u zo snel mogelijk verder","answer":"O nee he, niet zo'n stomme prutchatbot. Ik wil een mens spreken. Nu meteen. "},{"question":"Айман сымалдуулар деген ...","answer":"Айман сымалдуулар — Кузнечиковые чегирткелердин бир чоң тукуму, буларга накта аймандар тукуму (лат. Tettigoniidea), булардын кыйла уруусу жана түрү бар: узун бут айман (Pinegia longipes), чоң баш айман, жашыл айман (Tettigonia viridissima), жалбыраксымак айман (Tanusia corrupta), Малайя айманы (Leptoderes ornatipennis), керикайман, оранжерея айманы (Tachycines asynamorus), чекилдек айман (Tettigonia cantans), ээрчек айман (Ephippiger ephippiger), боз айман (Decticus verrucivorus), Судан айманы (Eurycorypha fallax), Уссури жашыл айманы (Tettigonia ussuriana), куйруктуу айман (Т. caudata), жашыл аймандар (уруу) (Tettigonia), боз аймандар (уруу) (Decticus), секирчээк аймандар (уруу) (Platycleis)."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa gobalka uu ku dhashay Maxamed Gacal Xaayow? ","answer":"Gobalka uu kudhashay Maxamed Gacal Xaayow waa gobalka Banaadir. "},{"question":"காரல் மார்க்சின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"மனிதர்களின் வாழ்நிலையை நிர்ணயிப்பது அவர்களின் உணர்வு அல்ல. மாறாக,, அவர்களது சமூக வாழ்நிலையே அவர்களது உணர்வை நிர்ணயிக்கிறது."},{"question":"لدي نص غير مشكل، قم بتشكيله:  الواقف ببعض منافعها كدرها أو صوفها فظاهر أنه لا حق له في جلدها ا هـ قوله وإذا دبغه إلخ قال في شرح الروض أو اندفع بنفسه فيما يظهر ا هـ قوله لكن جزم الماوردي إلخ ويجمع بينهما بحمل كل منهما على ما اقتضته المصلحة فإن تعذر جميع ذلك صرف للموقوف عليه فيما يظهر م ر قوله ولو عجزت عنه جاز استعمال.","answer":"النص المشكل:  الْوَاقِفُ بِبَعْضِ مَنَافِعِهَا كَدَرِهَا أَوْ صُوفِهَا فَظَاهِرٌ أَنَهُ لَا حَقَ لَهُ فِي جِلْدِهَا ا هـ قَوْلُهُ وَإِذَا دَبَغَهُ إلَخْ قَالَ فِي شَرْحِ الرَوْضِ أَوْ انْدَفَعَ بِنَفْسِهِ فِيمَا يَظْهَرُ ا هـ قَوْلُهُ لَكِنْ جَزَمَ الْمَاوَرْدِيُ إلَخْ وَيَجْمَعُ بَيْنَهُمَا بِحَمْلِ كُلٍ مِنْهُمَا عَلَى مَا اقْتَضَتْهُ الْمَصْلَحَةُ فَإِنْ تَعَذَرَ جَمِيعُ ذَلِكَ صُرِفَ لِلْمَوْقُوفِ عَلَيْهِ فِيمَا يَظْهَرُ م ر قَوْلُهُ وَلَوْ عَجَزَتْ عَنْهُ جَازَ اسْتِعْمَالُ."},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள்: கார்கில் போர் நடந்தபோது, நிவாரண நிதி சேகரிப்பின் ஒரு பகுதியாக இவர் தெருவோர நிகழ்ச்சிகளை செய்தார். 2019இல் புல்வாமா தாக்குதல் நடந்தபோது, இவர், தனது மாணவர்களுடன் தேசப் பக்தி பாடல்களை பாடினார். பெங்களூரில் உள்ள சித்ரகலா பரிஷத்தில் தனது சொந்த சுர்பஹார் அமைப்பு மூலம் மாநிலத்தின் பிரமுகர்கள் முன்னிலையில் \\" ஏ வதன் கே நௌஜாவன்\\" என்ற பாடலை அர்ப்பணித்தார்.","answer":"புல்வாமா தாக்குதல்"},{"question":"Euskal Herriko mendizalean, zer da turismo aktiboaren eragina?","answer":"Turismo aktiboaren eragina da ekonomia bultzatzea eta ingurumenaren kontserbazioa sustatzea."},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :অপেক্ষক বা ফাংশন","answer":"একটি গাণিতিক ধারণা যা দুইটি রাশির মধ্যে পারস্পরিক নির্ভরশীলতা প্রকাশ করে। একটি রাশিকে বলা হয় প্রদত্ত রাশি, বা স্বাধীন চলক বা অপেক্ষকটির আর্গুমেন্ট বা ইনপুট। অপরটিকে উৎপাদিত রাশি বা অপেক্ষকের মান বা আউটপুট বলা হয়।"},{"question":"Pelu bi eto ọrọ-aje ṣe denukọlẹ, ijọba mi ko ni i gbaṣẹ lọwọ oṣiṣẹ kankan- Akeredolu","answer":"Lasiko to n sinu aawẹ pẹlu awọn Musulumi lalẹ ọjọ Aiku, Sannde ọsẹ yii, ni gbọngan asa igbalode Doomu, to wa loju ọna Igbatoro, niluu Akurẹ, ni Gomina ipinlẹ Ondo, Rotimi Akeredolu, ti sọ pe oun ko ṣetan lati gba iṣẹ lọwọ eyikeyii ninu awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba latari eto ọrọ aje orilẹ-ede to n saisan lọwọ.Arakunrin ni loootọ la ti ri awọn ipinlẹ bii Kaduna to gba iṣẹ lọwọ ọgọọrọ awọn oṣiṣẹ, nigba tawọn mi-in kọ jalẹ lati maa san ẹgbẹrun mejidinlogun to jẹ owo awọn oṣiṣẹ to kere ju lọ, ṣugbọn ti oun ko ṣetan ati ṣe bẹẹ ni toun.O ni ẹbẹ loun n bẹ awọn oṣiṣẹ ki wọn tubọ mu suuru fun ijọba laarin asiko yii ti nnkan ko fi bẹẹ rọgbọ feto ọrọ aje ipinlẹ Ondo nitori pe gbogbo ẹtọ wọn ko ni i sai tẹ wọn lọwọ nigbakuugba ti nnkan ba ti n ṣenuure.Lati bii oṣu mẹfa sẹyin lọkan-o-jọkan ede aiyede ti n suyọ laarin ijọba ati ẹgbẹ oṣiṣẹ ipinlẹ naa latari bi wọn ko ṣe rowo osu wọn san deedee mọ bii ti atẹyinwa.Ẹkọọkan tijọba ba si tun fẹẹ sanwo, aabọ owo-osu ni wọn n ri san, eyi lo si ṣokunfa bawọn oṣiṣẹ eto ilera, awọn dokita atawọn nọọsi ṣe bẹrẹ iyansẹlodi ọlọjọ gbọọrọ loṣu bii meji sẹyin.Ko ti i ju bii ọsẹ meji lọ sasiko yii nigba ti wọn ṣẹṣẹ pada ṣẹnu iṣẹ wọn.Wahala mi-in tun fẹẹ su yọ laarin ijọba atawọn ẹgbẹ oṣiṣẹ lọsẹ to kọja yii pẹlu bi wọn ṣe fẹẹ san ida ọgọta fawọn oṣiṣẹ gẹgẹ bii owo-oṣu keji, eyi ti ẹgbẹ awọn nọọsi yari kanlẹ pe awọn ko ni i gba lọwọ ijọba."},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa shahiidkii ugu horeeyey Islaamka","answer":" Waxay ahayd Sumaya bintu Khayaad, (Aala Yaasir) Camaar ibnu Yaasir hooyadii"},{"question":"Isikan tempat-tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang sesuai. \\"Salmah memang cantik orangnya. Namun, dia ibarat __________ kerana suka _________ apabila bergaul dengan masyarakat setempat.\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah \\"bunga dedap\\" dan \\"bermuka-muka\\"."},{"question":"Аббревиатура деген эмне ?","answer":"Аббревиатура (италиялык тилден алганда — кыскартылган сөздөр) жазуу жана оозеки речтеги кыскартылган сөздөр. Анын практикалык мааниси — үнөмдүүлүк. Ал аз болсо да көркөм чыгармаларда кездешет.1.Сөздөрдүн башкы бөлүктөрүнөн кыскартылган сөздөр. Тийдиби эле, комсомол, Жалпы окууга жардамың? (Ж. Бөкөнбаев)2.Башкы сөзү кыскартылып, калганы кыскартылбай алынган сөздөр. Отко күйбөс, ок өтпөгөн партбилет, Күнден бийик, баа жетпеген партбилет! (А. Токтомушев)3.Башкы тыбыштарынан кыскартылган сөздөр. Ааламда күндөн артык даңкка конгон, Ал Чынар — СССР, кең Мекеним! (К. Акаев)"},{"question":"પાઇ એટલે શુ ?","answer":"પાઇ એ ગાણિતિક અચલ સંખ્યા અને વર્તુળના પરિઘ અને તેના વ્યાસનો ગુણોત્તર છે. જેનું મૂલ્ય સામાન્ય રીતે અંદાજે ૩.૧૪૧૫૯ ઉપયોગમાં લેવાય છે. ૧૮મી સદીના મધ્ય ભાગથી પાઇને 'π' તરીકે રજૂ કરવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Pandangan beliau mengenai kematian Greg Dyke dalam sinetron radio, The Archers, yang dipetik oleh Grace Archer dalam McTaggart Lecture pada tahun 2000. Ayat 2: Pandangan beliau mengenai kematian Grace Archer dalam sinetron radio, The Archers, yang dipetik oleh Greg Dyke dalam kuliah McTaggart pada tahun 2000. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"ஆத்திகன் என்றால் முட்டாள் ஆராய்ச்சித் தன்மை அற்றவன் என்று பொருள்."},{"question":"வினா: இசையை ஆதரிக்காத மொகலாய மன்னன் யார்? ","answer":"விடை: ஒரௌங்கசீப்"},{"question":"Ngikubonile mntanomuntu uyiphaka,Ngikubonile nkosazana uyididiyelaNgikuzwile mntanomfazi uyiyalelaNgikuzwile ngane yabantu uyikhakhabeza.Uyiphake angakholwa nkosazana,Uyisuse kwelakini koMelikaWayisingisa kwelenkolo koSadamu,Uyiphake yadl'amadoda mame,Uyiphake kwasuka izidumo Nozidumo.1. Yisho amagama AMABILI imbongi ebiza ngawo uNozidumo","answer":"OKUBILI kwalokhu:• Mntanomuntu• Nkosazana• Mntanomfazi• Ngane yabantu"},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.පියා සලයි ඉහල නොයයිහිත රිදුනොත් මෙයා අඬයි         ","answer":"ඇස"},{"question":"Hãy hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Theo Reuters, ông Mikhail Razvozhayev, lãnh đạo của Sevastopol, viết trên mạng xã hội Telegram rằng \\"một vật thể không xác định đã bay vào sân của trụ sở hạm đội. Theo thông tin sơ bộ, đó là một máy bay không người lái\\". Sevastopol là thành phố lớn nhất ở Crimea và là nơi đóng trú của Hạm đội Biển Đen thuộc Hải quân Nga. Ông Razvozhayev nói rằng Ukraine đã quyết định \\"làm hỏng Ngày Hải quân\\", một ngày lễ hằng năm của Nga, trong đó các hạm đội tổ chức cuộc thao diễn hải quân và tôn vinh các thủy thủ. Ông cho hay 5 nhân viên tại trụ sở Hạm đội Biển Đen đã bị thương trong vụ tấn công và Cơ quan An ninh Liên bang Nga (FSB) đang điều tra tình hình. Ông Razvozhayev cho biết tất cả các hoạt động kỷ niệm ở Sevastopol đã bị hủy bỏ vì lý do an ninh, và kêu gọi mọi người giữ bình tĩnh. Hiện chưa có thông tin về phản ứng của Bộ Quốc phòng Nga cũng như Bộ Quốc phòng Ukraine về cáo buộc trên. Thứ trưởng Quốc phòng Ukraine Volodymyr Havrylov hôm 19.7 nói rằng Kyiv đang chuẩn bị cuộc tấn công nhằm vào Hạm đội Biển Đen của Nga. Ông Havrylov cũng cho biết Ukraine lên kế hoạch giành lại Crimea thông qua biện pháp ngoại giao hoặc quân sự. Cũng trong hôm 31.7, trang The Kyiv Independent dẫn thông báo từ Bộ Chỉ huy chiến dịch miền nam Ukraine nói rằng đã phá hủy 2 lựu pháo Msta-B của Nga, 1 bệ phóng rốc két đa nòng Grad, 2 kho đạn cùng 3 xe bọc thép và quân sự trong ngày 30.7, khiến 33 binh sĩ Nga thiệt mạng. Hiện chưa có thông tin về phản ứng của Nga đối với tổn thất mới do quân đội Ukraine đưa ra, trong bối cảnh lực lượng Ukraine đang phản công ở miền nam. Hôm 30.7, phía Ukraine cũng nói rằng đã loại 100 binh sĩ Nga và 7 xe tăng khỏi vòng chiến đấu ở miền nam. Vùng Kherson ở miền nam hiện là tâm điểm của chiến dịch phản công của Ukraine, và là một mắt xích then chốt trong tuyết tiếp tế của Nga. Quân đội Ukraine hôm 30.7 nói đường sắt băng qua sông Dnipro đến Kherson đã bị cắt đứt, có thể làm cho lực lượng Nga ở bờ tây sông bị cô lập hơn nữa. Còn ở miền đông, quân đội Ukraine xác nhận Nga \\"thành công một phần\\" trong việc kiểm soát khu dân cư Semyhirya ở phía nam thị trấn Bakhmut, nơi Nga xem là một mục tiêu chính ở Donetsk. Trước tình hình giao tranh ác liệt ở miền đông, Tổng thống Ukraine Volodymyr Zelensky ngày 30.7 ra lệnh bắt buộc sơ tán người dân ở tỉnh Donetsk. Theo Reuters, trong bài phát biểu trước toàn dân khuya 30.7, Tổng thống Ukraine Volodymyr Zelensky nói hàng trăm ngàn người cần phải rời khỏi các khu vực chiến sự thuộc vùng Donbass, bao gồm tỉnh Donetsk và tỉnh Luhansk.","answer":"\\"Càng có nhiều người rời khỏi khu vực Donetsk thì sẽ càng ít người thiệt mạng dưới tay lực lượng Nga\\", tổng thống Ukraine nói như vậy, đồng thời cho biết thêm rằng những cư dân rời đi sẽ được bồi thường. Tổng thống Zelensky cũng cho biết hàng trăm ngàn người vẫn đang sống trong khu vực giao tranh diễn ra ác liệt và kêu gọi nỗ lực thuyết phục họ đi sơ tán. Cùng ngày, tờ The Kyiv Independent dẫn lời Phó thủ tướng Ukraine Iryna Vereshchuk cho biết việc sơ tán cần phải diễn ra trước khi mùa đông bắt đầu vì nguồn cung cấp khí đốt tự nhiên trong khu vực đã bị phá hủy. Bà Vereshchuk nói rằng việc sơ tán 200.000 dân thường phải bắt đầu trước thời điểm mọi người cần dùng máy sưởi. Theo bà Vereshchuk, nếu từ chối sơ tán, người dân sẽ buộc phải ký vào một văn bản cam kết chịu trách nhiệm về mọi rủi ro có thể xảy ra. Hiện vùng Donbass không có nguồn cung cấp điện thích hợp và không có nguồn cung cấp khí đốt trong khi Nga tiếp tục phá hủy các thiết bị sưởi ấm, Phó thủ tướng Vereshchuk cho biết như vậy. Trong diễn biến khác, Ukraine đang tiếp tục nhận thêm vũ khí từ phương Tây. Theo The Kyiv Independent, Bộ Quốc phòng Lithuania thông báo họ sẽ cung cấp cho Ukraine thêm 10 xe bọc thép M113 APC cùng các gói thuốc nổ và lựu đạn khói. Lithuania cũng sẽ đào tạo cho thợ máy và đặc công Ukraine. Lầu Năm Góc cũng cho biết Mỹ sắp cung cấp hệ thống phòng không tầm ngắn và tầm trung NASAMS cho Ukraine. Tên lửa đất đối không NASAMS có thể bắn trúng mục tiêu ở cự ly tới 180 km và ở độ cao lên tới 21 km. \\"Tôi không có thông tin chi tiết về quá trình ký kết hợp đồng nhưng chúng tôi đang trong quá trình mua sắm hệ thống trên\\", một quan chức quốc phòng cấp cao của Mỹ cho biết như vậy."},{"question":"Comment s’appelle une unité de force électromotrice ?","answer":"Une unité de force électromotrice (FEM) est appelée « volt ». Le volt (symbole : V) est l'unité standard de mesure de la force électromotrice, qui est une mesure de la différence de potentiel entre deux points d'un circuit électrique. La FEM représente l'énergie électrique par unité de charge fournie par une source, telle qu'une batterie ou un générateur, pour pousser les électrons à travers un circuit."},{"question":"Мээ жана эс-тутум тууралуу факты жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Мээ денеден кийин ойгонот. Эртең менен жаңы ойгонгон адамдын мээси эки түн катары менен эмгектенген адамдын же мас абалындагы адамдын мээсинен да жаман иштейт. Таң эрте денени ойготуу үчүн кандай көнүгүүлөр жасалса, мээ үчүн да бир аз интеллектуалдык көнүгүү пайда. Мисалы, ойгоноор замат сыналгы көрүүнүн ордуна кроссворд чечкен жакшы."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cari salah'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berusaha untuk mengetahui kesalahan orang. Contoh ayat: Omar cuba mencari salah Zainal dengan membuka semula laporan peribadi kawannya itu."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Saya beraksi di atas pentas dengan memakai seluar pendek dan berkasut, saya juga bersarung tangan untuk berlawan dengan pencabar saya di atas pentas. Siapakah saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Ahli Tinju"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa Kumuu ahaa saxaabigii uu Rasuulka (NNKH) Ku magacaabay amiinka Umadaan?","answer":"Saxaabigii uu Rasuulka (NNKH) Ku magacaabay amiinka umadaan wuxuu ahaa  Abii Cubeyda Caamir Bin Jaraax (RC)."},{"question":"Inona no niseho ny 13 mey 2002 teto Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny 13 mey 2002 dia nanao sesitany ny tenany tany Frantsa ny amiraly Didier Ratsiraka."},{"question":"Escribe una continuación para el siguiente párrafo: Con 47 votos, el proyecto italiano conformado por las ciudades de Milán y Cortina d'Ampezzo fue seleccionado como sede de los Juegos Olímpicos de Invierno de 2026.","answer":" La otra candidatura, Estocolmo y Åre, recibió 34 votos. La votación ocurrió en el marco de la 134.ª Sesión del Comité Olímpico Internacional, en Lausana, Suiza."},{"question":"ශ්‍රීලංකාව වෙනුවෙන් දෙවන වරට ඔලිම්පික් පදක්කමක් ජයග්‍රහණය කළේ කවුද?","answer":"සුසන්තිකා ජයසිංහ මහත්මිය"},{"question":"নিম্নলিখিত অনুচ্ছেদের বিষয় কি ?ইন্ডিয়া গেট ভারতের জাতীয় স্মৃতিসৌধ। এটি ভারতের রাজধানী নতুন দিল্লির কেন্দ্রস্থলে অবস্থিত। এটি দিল্লির অন্যতম দ্রষ্টব্য স্থান। প্যারিসের আর্ক দে ত্রিম্ফের আদলে ১৯৩১ সালে নির্মিত এই সৌধটির নকশা করেন স্যার এডউইন লুটিয়েনস। আগে এর নাম ছিল \\"অল ইন্ডিয়া ওয়ার মনুমেন্ট\\"। প্রথম বিশ্বযুদ্ধ ও তৃতীয় ইঙ্গ-আফগান যুদ্ধে নিহত ৯০,০০০ ভারতীয় সেনা জওয়ানদের স্মৃতিরক্ষার্থে এই স্মৃতিসৌধটি নির্মিত হয়। এটি লাল ও সাদা বেলেপাথর ও গ্র্যানাইট পাথরে তৈরি।","answer":"তৃতীয় ইঙ্গ-আফগান যুদ্ধ |"},{"question":"Амстердам  жөнүндө кыскача эмне айта аласың ?","answer":"Амстердам :Кыйшык имараттар, бул Амстердамдын өзгөчөлүгү.Качан бир кезде шаар бир калыпта жана тыкан көрүнчү, бирок кийин убакыт өз ролун ойноду. Үйлөрдүн баары үйүлгөн, көбүнчө жыгач. Үймөктөр чирип, тыкан алачыктар тирөөчтөн ажырап, чөгүп, капталга кулай баштады.Нидерланды 🇳🇱"},{"question":"Inona no zavatra voaresaka anatin'ity fanehoan-kevitra manaraka ity?« Tahaka ny nanaovana vakisiny ireo zanako jiaby fony fahakeliny, dia ataoko azo antoka ny fanaraha-maso ny zafikeliko rehetra mba ho vita vakisiny ara-potoana, toy ny nataoko fony fahakelin’ny zanako, amin’izay koa mitombo tsara ao anatin’ny fahasalamana izy ireo »","answer":"Miresaka momba ny fanaovana vakisiny ny zaza io fanehoan-kevitra io."},{"question":"inona ny laokanay omaly?","answer":"ny laokanay omaly dia hena ritra"},{"question":"Эвфемизм деген эмне?","answer":"Эвфемизм (гр. – жакшы сүйлөймүн) - көрүнүштөрдүн, кубулуштардын же буюмдардын одоно, орой аталыштарын жумшартып, сылык формага алмаштырып, синонимдик байланыштар менен кошуп айтуу. Мисалы, “төрөдү” дегендин ордуна – «көз жарды», «боюнан бошоду» деген сөздөр колдонулат "},{"question":"ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਦਾ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ : ਅਰਬੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ","answer":"ਇਰਾਕ ਦੀ ਰਾਜਧਾਨੀ ਬਗ਼ਦਾਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸਾਕ ਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਹਰਫ਼ਨਮੌਲਾ ਆਦਮੀ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਚੋਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਸੀ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕਈ ਚੇਲੇ ਸਨ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਇੱਕ ਲੜਕੀ ਨੇ ਜਨਮ ਲਿਆ। ਉਹ ਬਹੁਤ ਸੁੰਦਰ ਸੀ। ਜਦ ਉਹ ਵੱਡੀ ਹੋਈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਖ਼ੂਬਸੂਰਤੀ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਸਿੱਧੀ ਦੂਰ-ਦੂਰ ਤਕ ਫੈਲ ਗਈ। ਇਸਾਕ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ ਰੱਖਿਆ। ਇੱਕ ਦਿਨ ਇੱਕ ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਖ਼ੈਰ ਮੰਗਣ ਇਸਾਕ ਦੇ ਬੂਹੇ ਆਇਆ। ਉਹ ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਜੋਤਿਸ਼-ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰ ਦਾ ਗਿਆਤਾ ਸੀ। ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ ‘ਤੇ ਪਈ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ ਦੇ ਪਿਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਬੁਲਾਇਆ ਤੇ ਆਖਿਆ, ”ਤੁਹਾਡੀ ਲੜਕੀ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮਤ ਬੜੀ ਚੰਗੀ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦਾ ਪਤੀ ਰਾਜ ਦਾ ਬੜਾ ਵੱਡਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।”ਇਸਾਕ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ”ਤੁਸੀਂ ਜੋ ਕਿਹਾ, ਉਹ ਸੁਣਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੜਾ ਚੰਗਾ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਲੜਕੀ ਲਈ ਤਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਸ਼ਰੀਫ਼ ਖਾਨਦਾਨ ਦਾ ਮਾਮੂਲੀ ਲੜਕਾ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਮਿਲ ਸਕੇਗਾ।” ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਨੇ ਜਵਾਬ ਦਿੱਤਾ, ”ਖ਼ੁਦਾ ਦੀ ਕੁਦਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਆਸਾਨ ਹੈ। ਉਹ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ, ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਪਿਆਰੀ ਬੇਟੀ ਦੇ ਹੱਥ ਦੀਆਂ ਲਕੀਰਾਂ ਜੋ ਕਹਿ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।” ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਐਨੀ ਗੱਲ ਕਹਿ ਕੇ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ। ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ ਜਿਉਂ-ਜਿਉਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਗਈ, ਉਸ ਦੇ ਵਿਆਹ ਲਈ ਇਸਾਕ ਦੀ ਚਿੰਤਾ ਵੀ ਵਧਦੀ ਗਈ। ਫ਼ਕੀਰ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਝੂਠੀ ਲੱਗੀ ਸੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰਵਾਉਣ ਨੂੰ ਉਂਜ ਤਾਂ ਕਈ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਤਿਆਰ ਸਨ ਪਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅਪਰਾਧੀ ਚੇਲੇ ਸਨ। ਅੰਤ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੌਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਜਿਹੜਾ ਵੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਕੰਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਚਲਾਕ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ, ਉਸੇ ਨਾਲ ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਕਰ ਦੇਵੇਗਾ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਚੇਲਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਸੁਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੌਜਵਾਨਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਲੀ ਤੇ ਵਲੀ ਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਨੌਜਵਾਨ ਸਨ। ਅਲੀ ਚੋਰ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਵਲੀ ਜੇਬਕਤਰਾ। ਜਦੋਂ ਇਸਾਕ ਨੇ ਚੇਲਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਗੱਲ ਦੱਸੀ, ਅਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਵਲੀ ਆਪਣੀ-ਆਪਣੀ ਯੋਗਤਾ ਦਿਖਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਤੁਰ ਪਏ।ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰ ਵੱਲ ਗਏ। ਉੱਥੇ ਇੱਕ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਦੂਜੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਤੋਂ ਆਇਆ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਜਣੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਲੱਗ ਗਏ। ਇੱਕ ਥਾਂ ਮੌਕਾ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਵਲੀ ਨੇ ਬੜੀ ਫੁਰਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜੇਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੱਥ ਪਾਇਆ ਤੇ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਬਟੂਆ ਕੱਢ ਲਿਆ। ਵਪਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਵੀ ਨਾ ਲੱਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ‘ਚੋਂ ਸੋਨੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਇੱਕ ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਅਸ਼ਰਫ਼ੀਆਂ ਨਿਕਲੀਆਂ। ਇਸਾਕ, ਅਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਵਲੀ ਦੇ ਹੱਥ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਾਈ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਕਰਨ ਲੱਗਿਆ। ਵਲੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ”ਉਸਤਾਦ ਜੀ, ਅਜੇ ਤਾਂ ਮੇਰਾ ਕੰਮ ਅਧੂਰਾ ਹੀ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਾ ਕਰਨ ਵਾਲੀ ਕਿਹੜੀ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ? ਜਿਸ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਬਟੂਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਚੁੱਪ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਤਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਬੈਠੇਗਾ। ਉਹ ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਕੋਲ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਰੋਵੇਗਾ, ਪਿੱਟੇਗਾ। ਫੇਰ ਮੈਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਫੜਿਆ ਜਾਵਾਂਗਾ।”ਇਸਾਕ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ”ਤਾਂ ਫੇਰ ਤੂੰ ਕੀ ਕਰੇਂਗਾ?”ਵਲੀ ਬੋਲਿਆ, ”ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਫੜ ਕੇ ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਕੋਲ ਲੈ ਜਾਵਾਂਗਾ। ਉੱਥੇ ਮੈਂ ਸਾਬਤ ਇਹ ਕਰਾਂਗਾ ਕਿ ਬਟੂਏ ਦਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਮੈਂ ਹਾਂ। ਇਸ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਹੀ ਬਟੂਆ ਚੋਰੀ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਫੇਰ ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਬਟੂਆ ਦੇ ਦੇਵੇਗਾ।” ਐਨਾ ਕਹਿ ਕੇ ਵਲੀ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਬਟੂਏ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣੇ ਪੱਲਿਓਂ ਵੀਹ ਅਸ਼ਰਫ਼ੀਆਂ ਹੋਰ ਪਾ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ। ਇੱਕ ਡੱਬੀ ਵੀ ਉਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਰੱਖ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਿਸ ‘ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਖੁਣਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ।ਦੋਵੇਂ ਜਣੇ ਫੇਰ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰ ਗਏ। ਉਹ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਅਜੇ ਤਕ ਉੱਥੇ ਹੀ ਘੁੰਮ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਅਜੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਜੇਬ ਕੱਟੇ ਜਾਣ ਦਾ ਭੋਰਾ ਇਲਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ। ਦੋਵੇਂ ਫਿਰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮਗਰ ਲੱਗ ਗਏ। ਵਲੀ ਨੇ ਮੌਕਾ ਦੇਖ ਕੇ ਬਟੂਆ ਫੇਰ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਜੇਬ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਲਕੜੇ ਜਿਹੇ ਪਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਫੇਰ ਝਟਪਟ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਧੌਣ ਤੋਂ ਫੜ ਕੇ ਉੱਚੀ-ਉੱਚੀ ਰੌਲਾ ਪਾਉਣ ਲੱਗਾ, ”ਦੇਖੋ, ਇਸ ਨੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਬਟੂਆ ਚੋਰੀ ਕਰ ਲਿਆ ਹੈ।”ਕੁਝ ਆਦਮੀ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਫੜ ਕੇ ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਕੋਲ ਲੈ ਗਏ। ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਨੇ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਬੜੇ ਗਹੁ ਨਾਲ ਸੁਣੀ। ਫੇਰ ਉਹ ਕਹਿਣ ਲੱਗਾ, ”ਇਸ ਦਾ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਤਾਂ ਬੜਾ ਸੌਖਾ ਹੈ। ਮੈਨੂੰ ਦੱਸੋ, ਤੁਹਾਡੇ ਬਟੂਏ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀ ਹੈ। ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਸੱਚੀ ਨਿਕਲੇਗੀ, ਉਸੇ ਦਾ ਬਟੂਆ ਹੈ।”ਵਪਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ”ਹਜ਼ੂਰ ਮੇਰੇ ਬਟੂਏ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਸੋਨੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਅਸ਼ਰਫ਼ੀਆਂ ਸਨ।”ਵਲੀ ਬੋਲਿਆ, ”ਨਹੀਂ ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਸਾਹਿਬ, ਬਟੂਆ ਮੇਰਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਹਜ਼ਾਰ ਵੀਹ ਅਸ਼ਰਫੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਇਲਾਵਾ ਮੇਰੀ ਡੱਬੀ ਵੀ ਬਟੂਏ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ‘ਤੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਨਾਂ ਖੁਣਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੈ।”ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਨੇ ਬਟੂਆ ਖੋਲ੍ਹ ਕੇ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਵਲੀ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਸਹੀ ਨਿਕਲੀ। ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਨੇ ਬਟੂਆ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਹੁਣ ਅਲੀ ਦੀ ਵਾਰੀ ਆਈ ਆਪਣਾ ਹੁਨਰ ਦਿਖਾਉਣ ਦੀ। ਉਹ ਬੋਲਿਆ, ”ਮੇਰੇ ਦੋਸਤ ਵਲੀ ਨੇ ਵਪਾਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਕਾਜ਼ੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਘੱਟਾ ਪਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਉੱਲੂ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਤਾਕਤ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹਾਂ।”ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਮਹੱਲ ਦੇ ਪਿਛਵਾੜੇ ਪੁੱਜੇ। ਵਾਹਵਾ ਸੰਘਣਾ ਹਨੇਰਾ ਪਸਰਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਸੀ। ਅਲੀ ਦਰੱਖਤ ਦੇ ਆਸਰੇ ਕੰਧ ਟੱਪ ਕੇ ਮਹੱਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ-ਪਿੱਛੇ ਵਲੀ ਵੀ ਆ ਗਿਆ। ਅੰਦਰ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਤਖ਼ਤਪੋਸ਼ ‘ਤੇ ਸੌਂ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਇੱਕ ਸੇਵਕ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪੈਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਲਸ਼ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ। ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਪੈਰ ਮਲਵਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਆਦਤ ਸੀ। ਇਸੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਨੀਂਦ ਆਉਂਦੀ ਸੀ।ਅਲੀ ਨੇ ਝਟਪਟ ਆਪਣਾ ਹੱਥ ਸੇਵਕ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ‘ਤੇ ਧਰਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਹੱਥ ਨਾਲ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹੱਥ-ਪੈਰ ਕੱਸ ਕੇ ਬੰਨ੍ਹ ਦਿੱਤੇ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੱਪੜਾ ਤੁੰਨ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਤਾਂ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਆਵਾਜ਼ ਬਾਹਰ ਨਾ ਨਿਕਲ ਸਕੇ। ਉਹ ਆਪ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਥਾਂ ਬੈਠ ਕੇ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਪੈਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਲਸ਼ ਕਰਨ ਲੱਗਾ। ਤਦੇ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਦੀ ਅੱਖ ਖੁੱਲ੍ਹ ਗਈ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਦੇਖ ਲਿਆ। ਅਲੀ ਸੇਵਕ ਜਿਹੀ ਆਵਾਜ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੋਲਿਆ, ”ਜਹਾਂ ਪਨਾਹ ਨੂੰ ਨੀਂਦ ਨਾ ਆ ਰਹੀ ਹੋਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਇੱਕ ਮਜ਼ੇਦਾਰ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਸੁਣਾਵਾਂ?”ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ”ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰੋ ਕਹਾਣੀ।”ਅਲੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਸੁਣਾਉਣ ਲੱਗਾ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ, ਇਸਾਕ, ਵਲੀ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਹੂ-ਬ-ਹੂ ਜਿਵੇਂ ਵਾਪਰੀ ਸੀ, ਉਵੇਂ ਹੀ ਸੁਣਾਉਣੀ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਸਲਤਨਤ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਬਦਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਕਹਾਣੀ ਪੂਰੀ ਹੋਣ ‘ਤੇ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਨੂੰ ਨੀਂਦ ਆ ਗਈ। ਅਲੀ ਨੇ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਦੀ ਜ਼ਰੀਦਾਰ ਜੁੱਤੀ ਚੁੱਕ ਲਈ ਅਤੇ ਚੁੱਪਚਾਪ ਉਹ ਦੋਵੇਂ ਮਹੱਲ ‘ਚੋਂ ਬਾਹਰ ਆ ਗਏ। ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੱਡੇ ‘ਤੇ ਪੁੱਜੇ। ਅਲੀ ਨੇ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਜੁੱਤੀਆਂ ਇਸਾਕ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਖਾਈਆਂ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਹੈਰਾਨ ਰਹਿ ਗਿਆ। ਵਲੀ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਕਰਾਮਾਤ ਦੀ ਗਵਾਹੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਉਸ ਨੇ ਹਾਰ ਮੰਨ ਲਈ। ਇਸਾਕ ਨੇ ਗੁਲਅਨਾਰ, ਅਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਸੌਂਪ ਦਿੱਤੀ।ਉਧਰ ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਸੌਂ ਕੇ ਉਠਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਬੜਾ ਗੁੱਸਾ ਆਇਆ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸੇਵਕ ਕਿੱਥੇ ਚਲਾ ਗਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੀ ਭਾਲ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਈ। ਆਖਰ ਉਹ ਪਲੰਘ ਹੇਠੋਂ ਮਿਲਿਆ। ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹੱਥ-ਪੈਰ ਅਤੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਖੋਲ੍ਹਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਸਾਰੀ ਆਪਬੀਤੀ ਸੁਣਾ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਨੇ ਮੁਨਾਦੀ ਕਰਵਾਈ, ”ਜੋ ਆਦਮੀ ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਰਾਤ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਹੱਲ ਵਿੱਚ ਆ ਕੇ ਮੇਰੀਆਂ ਜੁੱਤੀਆਂ ਚੁੱਕ ਕੇ ਲੈ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਜੁਰਮ ਮੁਆਫ਼ ਕਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਉਹ ਬੇਖੌਫ਼ ਮੇਰੇ ਦਰਬਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਾਜ਼ਰ ਹੋਵੇ।”ਅਲੀ ਨੇ ਸੁਣਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਜੁੱਤੀਆਂ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਦਰਬਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਹਾਜ਼ਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ। ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਨੇ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਇਨਾਮ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਦਾ ਕੋਤਵਾਲ ਬਣਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਸੁਲਤਾਨ ਨੇ ਸੋਚਿਆ ਕਿ ਐਨਾ ਚਲਾਕ ਕੋਤਵਾਲ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ ਤਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਚੋਰ ਬਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕੇਗਾ।"},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut. Siapakah yang memainkan watak Noah Newman dalam The Young and the Restless?","answer":"Robert Gillespie Adamson IV yang memainkan watak tersebut dalam The Young and the Restless."},{"question":"රුධිර වර්ගිකරණය සොයාගත්තේ කවුද?","answer":"රුධිර වර්ගිකරණය සොයාගත්තේ කාල්‌ ලැන්ස්ටයිනර්‌ මහතාය."},{"question":"கேள்வி:சங்ககால வரலாற்றை அறிந்து கொள்ள, புகளூர்க் கல்வெட்டு எவ்வகையில் துணைபுரிகிறது – விளக்குக.","answer":"பதில்:புகளூர், கரூர் மாவட்டத்தில் அமைந்துள்ளது. இந்த ஊரில் ஆறுநாட்டான் என்று ஒரு மலை உள்ளது. மலையடிவாரத்து ஊரை வேலாயுதம்பாளையம் என்பர். இம்மலைப்பகுதியில் இக்கல்வெட்டுகள் காணப்படுகின்றன. மொத்தம் 12 கல்வெட்டுகள் காணப்படுகின்றன. இவை அனைத்தும் சங்ககாலத் தமிழ் எழுத்தில் எழுதப் பெற்றுள்ள மொழி தமிழாகும். இவற்றுள் இரு கல்வெட்டுகள் சேர மன்னர்கள் வழங்கிய கொடை பற்றிக் கூறுகின்றன. எனவே, இக்கல்வெட்டுகள் சங்க வரலாற்றைத் தெரிந்து கொள்ளப் பெரிதும் துணைபுரிகின்றன.கல்வெட்டு -1மூதா அமண்ணன் யாற்றூர்செங்காயபன் உறைய்ஆதன் செல்லிரும் பொறை மகன்பெருங்கடுங்கோன் மகன் (இளங்கடுங்கோ (இளங்கோ ஆக அறுத்த கல்யாற்றூரைச் சேர்ந்த செங்காயபன் என்னும் துறவிக்குச் சேர மன்னர் செல்லிரும் பொறை மகனான பெருங்கடுங்கோவின் மகன் இளங்கடுங்கோ இளவரசர் ஆவதை முன்னிட்டு வழங்கப்பட்ட கொடை. சேர அரசின் மூன்று தலைமுறை இதன் மூலம் தெரிய வந்துள்ளது. இதிலுள்ள அரசர்கள் பதிற்றுப்பத்தில் 7, 8, 9 ஆம் பத்திற்குரிய தலைவர்களாக அடையாளப்படுத்தப் பெற்றுள்ளனர்.கல்வெட்டு -2, 3யாற்றூர் செங்காயப்பன்(தா)வன் பின்னம் கொற்றன்அறுபித்த அதிட்டானம்யாற்றூரில் செங்காயபனுக்குத் தாவன் பின்னன் கொற்றன் என்பவர் அதிட்டானம் கொடுத்தது பற்றிக் கூறுகிறது. அதிட்டானம் என்றால் தரைப்பகுதி என்று பொருள்.கல்வெட்டு – 4நலிய்) ஊர் பிடன் குறும்மகள்கீரள்கொற்றி செய்பிதபளிநலி ஊரை சேர்ந்த பிடனுடைய இள மகளான கீரன் கொற்றி செய்பித்த பாளியைப் பற்றி கூறுகிறது.கல்வெட்டு – 5நலி(ய்) ஊர் பிடந்தை மகள் கீரன்கொறி அதிட்டான்நலி ஊரை சேர்ந்த பிடந்தையின் மகளான கீரன் கொற்றி கொடுத்த படுக்கை. மேற்கண்டவாறு மொத்தம் 10 கல்வெட்டுகள் கிடைத்துள்ளன. அவை அனைத்தும் தமிழின் தமிழரின் பெருமையையும் அரசனின் பெருமையையும் எடுத்தியம்புகின்றன.சிறப்புகள் :• சங்ககால சேர அரசர்களின் கல்வெட்டு.• கோ ஆதன் செல்லிரும் பொறை பெருங்கடுங்கோ, இளங்கடுங்கோ ஆகிய அரசர்களின் பெயர்கள் குறிப்பிடப் பெற்றுள்ளன.• சேர அரசின் மூன்று தலைமுறை இதன் மூலம் தெரியவந்துள்ளது.• பதிற்றுப்பத்தில் 7, 8, 9 ஆம் பத்திற்குரிய தலைவர்களாக அடையாளப்படுத்த பெற்றுள்ளனர்."},{"question":"88 inç tv kac cm?","answer":"Signature OLED TV 88 İnç 222 cm 8K Çözünürlük Akıllı Ses Tanıma."},{"question":"السؤال: ما اسم السورة التي اُفتتحت باسمٍ من أسماء الله الحسنى؟","answer":" الجواب: سورة الرّحمن."},{"question":"పురాణాలలో ప్రస్తావించిన కొన్ని ముఖ్యమైన వైద్యులు ఎవరు?","answer":"పురాణాలలో ధన్వంతరి, చరక, సుశ్రుత వంటి ప్రఖ్యాత వైద్యుల ప్రస్తావన ఉంది. వారు ఆయుర్వేద వైద్యశాస్త్రానికి పునాది వేసి, దాని ప్రాథమిక సూత్రాలను రూపొందించారు. వారి రచనలు ఇప్పటికీ వైద్య విద్యలో ఉపయోగించబడుతున్నాయి మరియు సాంప్రదాయ వైద్యులు దీనిని అనుసరిస్తారు."},{"question":"Nibo lẹyin n gbe, nibo lẹyin wa: Nigba t’Abiọla atawọn eeyan rẹ kọju ija si Awolọwọ ni 1979 (5)","answer":"Idi Theophilous Akindele ko le ṣe ko ma domi, idi rẹ yoo domi, nitori gẹgẹ bii olori ileeṣẹ to n ṣeto ibanisọrọ ijọba apapọ, ọga agba ni nileeṣẹ tẹlifoonu patapata, o mọ Ọgagun Muritala Muhammed daadaa. Ẹẹmeji ni wọn ti pade, ṣugbọn ẹẹmejeeji, alaafia kọ ni wọn fi tuka. Muritala ni olori ẹka awọn ologun to n ri si eto ibanisọrọ, bii tẹlifoonu ni o, ati awọn irinṣẹ ti wọn n lo lati maa fi ba awọn ọmọ ogun wọn sọrọ tabi ileeṣẹ ologun gbogbo sọrọ kaakiri, bo ṣe nilẹ yii tabi loke-okun. Nidii eyi, gbogbo igba ni wọn maa n lo irinṣẹ oriṣiiriṣii, gbogbo igba ni wọn si maa n lo awọn oṣiṣẹ lati ileeṣẹ eleto ibanisọrọ yii. Eeyan ko si le ṣe ooṣa lodo ki labẹlabẹ ma mọ, ko sohun ti wọn yoo ṣe ti Akindele ko ni i mọ, paapaa nigba to ti di ọga patapata fun ileeṣẹ naa, to si jẹ abẹ rẹ ni awọn ọmọọṣẹ gbogbo ti n jade lọ.Ni ọjọ kan, Akindele jokoo si ọọfiisi rẹ, bẹẹ ni akọwe agba nileeṣẹ to n ri si eto inawo ijọba apapọ, Abdul Atta, fi faili kan ranṣẹ si i, o ni ko ba oun wo o kiakia, ko si gba oun nimọran lori ohun to yẹ ki oun ṣe. Faili naa jẹ ti ileeṣẹ ologun, wọn ṣẹṣẹ ko irinṣẹ kan wọlu ni, irinṣẹ naa pọ diẹ, wọn si ti ra a, ohun to ku ni ki ijọba san owo rẹ. Owo ti wọn kọ pọ gan-an, ṣugbọn eyi kọ ni iṣoro ibẹ, nitori owo kuku wa lapo ijọba Gowon aye ọjọ naa. Ohun ti Atta fẹẹ mọ ni boya irinṣẹ naa to iye owo ti wọn kọ pe o jẹ ko too di pe wọn sanwo fun wọn. Attah ti mọ pe bi ẹni kan ba wa nibi kan to le sọ bi ọrọ naa ti jẹ foun gan-an, Akindele ti i ṣe ọga agba pata ni ẹka eto ibanisọrọ yii ni. Nitori ẹ lo ṣe gbe faili naa fun un. Nigba ti Akindele yẹ faili wo sọtun-un, to yẹ ẹ wo sosi, to yẹ awọn irinṣẹ ti wọn darukọ wọnyi wo, ohun to kọ sinu faili naa ree:“Irinṣẹ ti wọn ra yii ti pẹ nigba, koda, ọjọ ti lọ lori rẹ. Bii ọdun meje sẹyin, iyẹn ni 1963, ni wọn ti ṣe irinṣẹ mi-in, iru eleyii gan-an, ṣugbọn to jẹ ti igbalode. Awọn ti wọn ra iru irinṣẹ bayii wa kan n da owo Naijiria sinu omi okun lasan ni, nitori ohun ti wọn ra yii ko ni i wulo fẹni kan, tabi fun ileeṣẹ wọn paapaa, ifowoṣofo lasan ni. Ohun ti wọn tori rẹ sọ pe awọn ra irinṣẹ yii, irinṣẹ naa ko ni i ṣee lo fun un, ko si sidii kan ti ẹnikẹni fi gbọdọ ko owo le iru irinṣẹ bẹẹ, tabi ti yoo ni ki wọn ko o wa fawọn. Nitori bẹẹ, ẹni yoowu to jẹ to ra iru irinṣẹ yii, tabi to ni ki wọn ko o wa fun ijọba Naijiria, tọhun gbọdọ jiya, bẹẹ ni wọn gbọdọ gba ninu owo to na danu yii lọwọ oun funra ẹ, ki wọn ni ko san ninu owo irinṣẹ buruku to ra, ko le mọ pe ohun ti oun ṣe ko dara.”Ọdun 1970 leleyii ṣẹlẹ, Akindele ko ti i pade Muritala ri, ohun to kan mọ ni pe ileeṣẹ ITT lo ta irinṣẹ buruku bẹẹ fun wọn.N loun ba kọwe, o si fi faili ranṣẹ pada si ẹni to gbe e fun un. Oun ko ranti ọrọ naa mọ, o n ba iṣẹ rẹ lọ. O to ọjọ kẹrin ti ọrọ yii ṣẹlẹ ni awọn ọga ṣọja meji ba wọ ọọfiisi rẹ lai kan ilẹkun, bẹẹ ni wọn ko si duro lọdọ sẹkitiri ẹ ko le lọọ sọ fun ọga rẹ pe ẹni kan fẹẹ waa ri i, wọn ja wọle bẹẹ ni. Asiko naa jẹ asiko ti ogun abẹle ṣẹṣẹ pari, to jẹ ko si ibi ti awọn eeyan ti ri ṣọja ti wọn ki i ṣe ẹrujẹjẹ, agaga bi wọn ba waa jẹ ọga ṣọja bẹẹ, kaluku yoo fi ara ṣoko ni. Awọn ṣọja eleyii tilẹ waa yatọ, ọkan ninu wọn ga firigbọn, ibinu ni wọn si tun n ba bọ, ko sẹni kan ti wọn bi daadaa ti yoo duro loju ọna, kaluku sa danu ni. Laye igba naa, ko sẹni ti yoo ni Lebe ko pọn ọmọọre, ko ṣeni ti yoo duro beere ọrọ lọwọ ṣọja, ohun ti ṣọja ba ṣe, aṣegbe ni. Nitori bẹẹ lo ṣe jẹ ko sẹni kan to le da awọn ṣọja meji yii duro, ọkan jẹ ọga gidi, ikeji si jẹ ọọfisa to tẹle e.Eyi to jẹ ọga yii, Kọnẹeli ni ninu iṣẹ ṣọja, awọn ọga igba naa niyẹn. Bo ṣe wọle lo leju koko mọ Akindele, iyẹn ti ko si ti i mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ, ti ẹni to si wa siwaju ẹ ko sọ pe oun n bọ tẹlẹ, ti ko si mọ ẹni to jẹ, niṣẹ lo dorikodo sibi iwe to n ka, nitori awọn ti wọn wọle naa ko kuku ki i. Nigba ti ko wo oju wọn yii, eyi to jẹ ọga fibinu ju faili kan si ori tabili ẹ. Lẹyin naa lo fi ohun ramuramu sọ pe ‘Nigba mi-in, ma maa kọ ikọkukọ bayii nipa ẹka ibanisọrọ ileeṣẹ ologun o, nijọ mi-ni ti o ba tun ṣe bẹẹ, mo maa ni ki wọn yinbọn pa ẹ ni!’ Akindele naa ki i ṣe eeyan daadaa kan tọrọ ba da bẹẹ, oun naa ki i pẹẹ binu rara. Nigba ti ọga yii ti sọ ohun to sọ yii, inu ti bi oun naa kọja aala. O jọ pe ohun to dun un ju ni pe bawo ni ẹni kan ti oun ko mọ ri yoo ṣe  deede ja wọ ọọfiisi oun, oun naa toun jẹ ọga pata laaye oun, ti yoo si maa halẹ bayii mọ oun.N lo ba dide naro si ṣọja, ohun to si sọ fun un ni pe. “Wo o, Ọgbẹni Kọnẹeli, bi ki i baa ṣe aṣọ ijọba to o wọ sọrun, ṣe o mọ pe oo kan le deede ja wọ ọọfiisi mi ko o maa ṣe bo o ti n ṣe yii! Nitori bẹẹ, jade nibi yii, ko o sare jade bo o ṣe sare wọle, ki ibinu emi naa too di nnkan mi-in mọ ẹ lọwọ. Nigba mi-in, ki o si kọ ẹkọ iwa ọmọluabi, pe bi eeyan ba de ọdọ ẹni ti ko mọ ri, eeyan n huwa daadaa ni. Ọga ṣọja ko mọ pe ẹni kan yoo sọ bẹẹ soun laelae, o si wo Akindele lati oke de isalẹ, bo si ti n wo o yii, akọda to tẹle e ti mu ọwọ lọ sibi bẹliiti ẹ, o fẹẹ yọ ibọn to fi ha sibẹ. Ṣugbọn ọga rẹ sọ pe ko ma yọ ara ẹ lẹnu, o ni ko jẹ kawọn maa lọ, n lawọn mejeeji ba fibinu jade bi wọn ti fibinu wọle. Wọn n lọ kemọkemọ. Igba ti wọn lọ tan ni awọn oṣiṣẹ to ti sa lọ tẹlẹ too bẹrẹ si i pada wa, wọn waa wo Akindele, paapaa nigba ti wọn ko gbọ iro ibọn.Bi awọn ṣọja naa ti jade ni Akindele pe Attah to gbe iṣẹ fun un nijọsi pada, lo ba ṣalaye pe ki lo n ṣe, ọga ṣọja kan ma ṣẹṣẹ wa sibi yii to ni oun yoo yinbọn foun ma ni. Attah ni ko juwe ṣọja naa, nigba to si juwe ẹ, Attah ni, Ọgagun M.R. Muhammed niyẹn, oun ni olori ẹka eto ibanisọrọ awọn ṣọja. O ni ki Akindele ma dahun, ko maa ṣiṣẹ tirẹ lọ, ko ṣaa mọ bi yoo ti maa ṣe pẹlu wọn, pe oniwahala kan ni wọn. Lẹyin eyi ni akọwe agba fun ileeṣẹ tiwọn naa, Ọgbẹni Lawson, pada waa ba Akindele, o ni ko ma maa ṣe aya gbangba bẹẹ yẹn mọ si awọn ṣọja o, pe to ba jẹ wọn yinbọn pa a bẹẹ, ko si ohun ti yoo ṣẹlẹ o, nitori awọn ni wọn n ṣejọba, awọn nijọba wa lọwọ rẹ, ohun ti wọn ba si ṣe, aṣegbe ni o. Akindele dupẹ dupẹ, o loun gbọ, oun yoo maa ṣọ ara oun, igba akọkọ si niyẹn ti oun ati Muritala kọkọ pade ara wọn. Ni 1970.Ko si ẹni ti yoo gbọ iroyin iku bẹẹ ti yoo tun maa ṣe agidi, afi to ba ṣe pe nnkan mi-in wa nibẹ fun tọhun nikan ni. Firifiri ti Akindele ri yii ti mu ko sọ pe lọjọ mi-in ti oun ba tun ni anfaani lati pade Muritala, oun yoo ri i pe awọn ko fija tuka, yoo si le ri i pe eeyan daadaa loun naa i ṣe. Ṣugbọn lẹyin ti wọn ti rira ni 1970 yii, wọn ko tun rira mọ, afi ni 1973, ọdun kẹta lẹyin ti wọn ti kọkọ pade lakọọkọ. Ipo kan naa ti wọn wa nijọsi naa ni awọn mejeeji tun wa. Akindele ni olori ẹka ibanisọrọ to n ri si ọrọ tẹlifoonu jake-jado Naijiria, Muritala si ni olori eto ibanisọrọ nileeṣẹ awọn ologun ilẹ wa. Ijọba apapọ lo ni iṣẹ to gbe awọn mejeeji pade, ohun to si ta koko nibẹ ni pe Akindele ko mọ pe Muritala ni yoo ba pade, Muritala naa ko mọ pe Akindele naa loun yoo tun ba pade, afi bawọn mejeeji ṣe tun pade ara wọn ganboro. O ṣe ni laaanu pe ipade naa ko tun mu eeso rere kan dani, ajatuka ni ti agbaarin ni wọn fi i ṣe!Ẹ maa ka a lọ lọsẹ to n bọ."},{"question":"Londra'da kaç bölge var?","answer":"Londra birbirini kaplayan çemberler şeklinde 6 bölgeye ayrılmıştır; ulaşım ücretleri bu bölgelere göre değişmektedir."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది పదాలకు వ్యతిరేక పదాలు రాయండి. రెండు పదాలనూ ఉపయోగించి సొంతవాక్యాలు రాయండి.ఉదా :అజాగ్రత్త × జాగ్రత్తనేను ఏ విషయమైనా జాగ్రత్తగా పరిశీలిస్తాను. ఎప్పుడూ అజాగ్రత్తగా ఉండను.అ) నీతి ఆ) నిస్స్వార్గంఇ) సుఖంఈ) శాంతిఉ) నిగర్విఊ) అంగీకారం ఎ) నిర్భయం","answer":"అ) నీతి × అవినీతివాక్య ప్రయోగం : నీతి కలవారు, అవినీతిని చూచి ‘సహించలేరు.ఆ) నిస్స్వార్గం × స్వార్థంవాక్య ప్రయోగం : నేను నిస్స్వార్థంగా జీవిస్తాను, స్వార్థంగా జీవించను.ఇ) సుఖం × కష్టంవాక్య ప్రయోగం : సుఖం వెంబడి కష్టం ఉంటుందని గుర్తించాలి.ఈ) శాంతి × అశాంతివాక్య ప్రయోగం : ప్రపంచంలోని అశాంతి పోవాలంటే శాంతి దేవతను ఆహ్వానించాలి.ఉ) నిగర్వి × గర్వివాక్య ప్రయోగం : నిగర్వి ఆనందాన్నీ, గర్వి దుఃఖాన్ని తప్పక పొందుతాడు.ఊ) అంగీకారం × అనంగీకారంవాక్య ప్రయోగం : నా చదువు విషయంలో అమ్మానాన్నాల మధ్య ఇంకా అంగీకారం, అనంగీకారం ఉంది.ఎ) నిర్భయం × భయంవాక్య ప్రయోగం : నిర్భయంగా మాట్లాడేవారంటే అందరికీ భయం."},{"question":"ما عاصمة إسبانيا ؟","answer":"مدريد"},{"question":"次の文章を読んで、その内容に適したタイトルを付けてください： 「推し」は好きなアイドルや俳優、趣味などのことです。北海道の札幌市にある保育園は、働いている人たちが「推し」のコンサートや映画などに行くために仕事を休むことができる「推し休暇」を来月から始めます。休んでも給料をもらうことができます。法律で決まっている休みのほかに「推し休暇」で1年に10日休むことができます。この保育園は、日曜日なども仕事があって忙しいため、働く人に自分の好きなことを楽しんでほしいと考えて、この休みを作りました。働いている人は「ディズニーランドが好きなので、映画のトイ・ストーリーの乗り物などを楽しみたいです。仕事をもっと頑張ることができると思います」と話しています。","answer":"好きなアイドルのコンサートなどで仕事を休める「推し休暇」"},{"question":"السؤال: في أي دولة حديثة وُلدت الفيزيائية والكيميائية ماري كوري؟","answer":"الإجابة: بولندا"},{"question":"Gịnị bụ ajụjụ a: \\"Interlibrary mgbazinye (abbreviated ILL, na mgbe ụfọdụ a na-akpọ interloan, akwụkwọ nnyefe, ma ọ bụ akwụkwọ ọkọnọ) bụ ọrụ site n'nke a onye ọrụ nke otu n'ọbá akwụkwọ nwere ike gbaziri akwụkwọ ma ọ bụ na-enweta photocopies nke akwụkwọ na-ekesịpde ọzọ n'ọbá akwụkwọ\\"? Isiokwu a bụ Interlibrary loan.","answer":"\\"Olee mgbe ịgbaziri ihe n'ọ́bá akwụkwọ si arụ ọrụ?\\""},{"question":"શો ગ્રેની એનાટોમીએ તેના સમગ્ર કાર્યકાળ દરમિયાન વિવિધતા અને પ્રતિનિધિત્વના મુદ્દાઓને કેવી રીતે સંબોધિત કર્યા છે?","answer":"Grey's Anatomy has made an effort to feature a diverse cast of characters, including people of color, LGBTQ+ individuals, and characters with disabilities. While the show has faced criticism for its portrayal of certain groups, it has also been praised for its efforts to represent a wider range of experiences."},{"question":"Hãy viết một bài báo có thể sử dụng tiêu đề sau đây: Tiêu đề: Cảnh sát Úc 'phá âm mưu cho nổ máy bay'","answer":"Ông đưa ra phát ngôn sau khi bốn người bị bắt trong các cuộc đột kích khắp Sydney.Các nhà điều tra cho biết họ có thông tin rằng âm mưu cho nổ máy bay liên quan đến việc sử dụng một \\"thiết bị nổ tự tạo\\".Ông Turnbull nói rằng các cuộc đột kích tiến hành theo \\"chiến dịch chống khủng bố chung\\".Úc phá được 'âm mưu khủng bố' Ngày Giáng sinhÚc: Cứu rạn san hô Great Barrier thế nào?Ông nói thêm rằng an ninh đang được tăng cường tại các sân bay nội địa và quốc tế.Các cuộc đột kích diễn ra ở các vùng ngoại ô của Sydney: Surry Hills, Lakemba, Wiley Park và Punchbowl, ABC tường thuật.Mức độ đe dọa khủng bố tại Úc đang ở mức \\"có thể xảy ra\\".Cảnh sát trưởng Liên bang Úc Andrew Colvin nói rằng bốn người đàn ông bị bắt liên quan đến một âm mưu \\"lấy cảm hứng từ Hồi giáo\\".\\"Trong những ngày gần đây, chúng tôi nhận được tin cho thấy một số người ở Sydney đang có âm mưu tiến hành một cuộc tấn công khủng bố sử dụng thiết bị nổ tự tạo\\", ông nói trong một cuộc họp báo."},{"question":"சே குவேராவின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"ஒவ்வொரு அநீதியையும் கண்டு ஆத்திரத்தில் அதிர்ந்துபோவாயானால், நீ எனது தோழன்."},{"question":"Закінчи речення:  Брав участь у чемпіонаті світу 2002 року, який приймали Японія і Південна Корея, ","answer":"утім на мундіалі був здебільшого резервним гравцем і виходив на поле лише в одній грі групового етапу, який його команда не подолала."},{"question":"Түш тууралуу кызыктуу фактыларды жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Кээде адамдар ойгонуп кетип,түштөрүндөгү таттуу кыялдарында бейтааныш бирөөнү көргөнүн айтышат. Чындыгында биз качандыр бир көргөн кишилерди гана көрөбүз. Болгону сиз ал жөнүндө унутуп калгансыз, ал эми мээ болсо ошол образды сактап калып, көргөзө берет."},{"question":" شنو هي ثاني اكبر دوله عربيه من حيث المساحه ؟","answer":"الجزائر"},{"question":"Birleşik Krallık hangi ülkelerinden oluşmaktadır?","answer":"Birleşik Krallık, resmi adıyla Büyük Britanya ve Kuzey İrlanda Birleşik Krallığı, İngiltere, İskoçya, Galler ve Kuzey İrlanda olmak üzere dört kurucu ülkeden oluşan bir devlettir. Büyük Britanya terimi ise sadece; İngiltere, İskoçya ve Galler’i kapsamaktadır."},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Top 5 xe tay ga giá ổn định, sánh cạnh với Honda Vision ở Việt Nam","answer":" Yamaha Janus thiết kế thời trang, trẻ trung năng động, có trang bị hiện đại với hệ thống động cơ Blue Core, mang lại hiệu suất linh hoạt và tiết kiệm xăng. Xe có chìa khóa thông minh, cốp đựng đồ rộng, rất phù hợp với mẫu hình một xe tay ga đô thị. Giá xe lại hợp lý và ổn định, ít chênh giá.  Yamaha Latte là dòng xe tay ga mới được phân phối tại thị trường Việt Nam, thiết kế theo phong cách xe tay ga châu Âu, sang chảnh nhưng giá bán ra lại rất dễ chịu. Chìa khóa thông minh, nắp bình xăng đặt phía trước, cốp đựng đồ rộng 37 lít không kém với LEAD bao nhiêu, mặt đồng hồ điện tử đẹp, và động cơ Blue Core tiết kiệm xăng là những tính năng được ưa chuộng trên dòng xe tay ga Latte.  SYM New Attila 125 thiết kế đậm chất nữ tính, đốn tin phái đẹp với các đường nét mềm mại, đuôi xe tròn trịa cao cấp, đồng hồ LCD hiện đại, cốp đựng đồ rộng, cùng bộ động cơ vận hành nhẹ nhàng và có giá bán ra hợp lý.  Thiết kế lấy cảm hứng từ dòng xe ga Burgman huyền thoại, Impulse của Suzuki nhìn cao cấp với đầu xe cá tính. Phía trước xe có hộc đựng đồ, trong khi dưới yên ngồi là khoang đựng đồ rộng, đồng hồ điều khiển loại mới hiện đại, trong khi động cơ xe loại 125 FI vận hành mạnh mẽ và hiệu quả.  Piaggio Zip 100 thiết kế thời trang, kiểu dáng độc đáo, gọn nhẹ. Xe sở hữu động cơ Hi-PER4 Piaggio Zip 100 4T xy lanh đơn, có hiệu suất cao, đạt tiêu chuẩn khí thải Euro 3. Nguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/top-5-xe-tay-ga-gia-on-dinh-sanh-canh-voi-honda-vision-o-viet-nam-1382478.ngnNguồn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/top-5-xe-tay-ga-gia-on-dinh-sanh-canh-voi-honda-vision-o-viet-nam-1382478.ngn "},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ gómínà àkọ́kọ́ ní ìpínlẹ̀ Abia?","answer":"Ogbonnaya Onu ni."},{"question":"Ngiyabonga sayitsheni. Ukube anifikanga ngabe indaba yamiisingumlando. Ngibonga kakhulu sayitsheni.Ubonga ngakhona Duma kodwa nguwe oyimbangela yalokhu.Usho ukuthini sayitsheni? Yimi yini ovimba intuthuko lapha kulendawo?Uyakhumbula ngikubuza ukuthi uyathathisa na enkosini umauzokwenza utho endaweni yayo? Wathini wena? Angithi wadazainkani? Nenhlangano yakho yaphinde yakuyala ngokuhlonipha inkosi,wena wenza okuthandwa nguwe. Bafile-ke manje abantu. UMbandlwasiyezwa ukuthi ubengungqa phambili ekutheni wenze lokhuobukwenza. Naye uDlamini kuyavela ukuthi ubethukuthela aze enzeizinto ezingalungile njengakho ukushaya uMbandlwa.Angimsoli-ke yena kakhulu ngoba ubehlukunyezwa ngukubona wenauthela inkosi yakhe ngothuli.(ukuzithoba kuyadlondlobala. Useze watshekisa ngisho nekhanda.Izandla zakhe ulokhu ezihlanganisa njengomuntu okhuluma nomuntuamhlonipha ngendlela exakile) Ngiyezwa sayitsheni. (athule kancane)Sekwenzekile-ke okubuhlungu sayitsheni. Ngiyaphinda ngithi velesekonakele. Manje, ngizocela nigcine ukuthula endaweni, minasengizowuyeka-ke lo msebenzi wobukhansela.(enyuse izwi ngenxa yentukuthelo) Uthini? Uyeke? Niqala izinto besenigabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele? Lutho! Wena yelekelelaekucisheni lo mlilo wothathe osuwokhele.Kahle sayitsheni. Ngizowucisha kanjani lo mlilo? Bazongibulala phelaabantu.1. Ukungaqondi kukaDuma nenkosi uShandu ukubaluleka kokusebenzisanaphakathi kwabo njengabaholi endaweni kwaba namuphi umphumela? ","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo:• Kwaba nodlame.• Kwafa uNobhala wekhansela uMbandlwa nenduna uDlamini. "},{"question":"“Miteraka sery ve ny matory amin'ny varavarankely misokatra?”","answer":"Tsia, tsy voatery hiteraka sery ny matory amin'ny varavarankely misokatra."},{"question":"Est-ce que c'est Vrai ou Faux? Le plagiat inclut le fait de reprendre sans en mentionner la source des propos oraux de prestations publiques (exemples : films, entrevues, conférences…).","answer":"Vrai. Le plagiat ne se limite pas au matériel écrit : il touche tout emprunt, y compris l’information orale."},{"question":"«ملیچ» در گویش همدانی به چه معناست؟","answer":"همدانی ها به گنجشک می‌گویند ملیچ.گنجشک پرنده‌ای است کوچک با منقار کلفت و مخروطی و پاهای نسبتاً کوتاه که اغلب پر و بال رنگارنگ ندارد و به رنگ قهوه ای روشن و تیره هستند. گنجشکان بیشتر به صورت اجتماعی به سر می‌برند و به طور گروهی زاد و ولد می‌کنند. پروازی نیرومند دارند. در سوراخ‌های درختان، شکاف دیوار و صخره‌ها لانه می‌سازند. بیشتر از دانه‌ها و مواد گیاهی و گاه جانوری تغذیه می‌کنند."},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、このトピックに関する記事を書きなさい： 千葉県で震度5強の地震　1週間ぐらいは気をつけて","answer":"11日午前4時16分、千葉県でマグニチュード5.2の地震がありました。千葉県木更津市は震度5強で、強く揺れました。千葉市や東京都の23区、神奈川県横浜市などは震度4でした。津波はありませんでした。この地震で、千葉県と神奈川県では11日昼までに、家で転んだ人など4人がけがをしました。木更津市では家の屋根の瓦が落ちたり、ビルの窓のガラスが割れて落ちたりしました。気象庁は「強く揺れた所では、山から石が落ちてきたり崖が崩れたりする危険があります。これから1週間ぐらいは、また大きな地震があるかもしれないので、気をつけてください」と言っています。特に、雨が降ると山が崩れやすくなるため、大雨の警報が出たときは早く避難してほしいと言っています。"},{"question":"පාරු කවියක් සඳහා  උදාහරණයක් දෙන්න. ","answer":"කරුවල තොටේ මම නාමින් ඉන්න        කොටලස්සන ලියක් අාවයි මගෙ ඉස්ස         රටකරේ තිබුණු මුතු දෙපොටේ ලස්ස         නටඅරන් යන්න හිතුනයි අගුලෙන්              ගමට"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ලංකා ලංකා පෙම්බර ලංකා පිනවමු ඔබ ලංකාහොබවමු ඔබ ලංකා දිවි දී සුරකිමු ඔබ ලංකා","answer":"ලංකා ලංකා පෙම්බර ලංකා පිනවමු ඔබ ලංකාහොබවමු ඔබ ලංකා දිවි දී සුරකිමු ඔබ ලංකාබලිතරු රාවණ ගැමුණු විජයබා නිරිඳුන් ලද ලංකාපුලතිසි දැමි සිරි රහල් කුමරතුඟු පඬුවන් ලද ලංකාවිදු සක්විති මහ පැරැකුම් කිවිසුරු කිවියන් ලද ලංකාඔබ රැකුනොත් ලෝ කුඹුවද අප හට සීත ගඟුල ලංකාමහවැලි කළු කැළණි වලවේ අත් හතරක් ඇති ලංකාසමනොළ කිරිගල් පිදුරුතලා නෙක කෙහෙ ගැට බැඳි ලංකාතේ වතු පොල් වතු කෙත් වතු පෙළ උකුලේ නලවන ලංකාමුහුදින් අඟලක් ඔබ වැව හොත් එහි පනිමු පනිමු ලංකාහෙළ මුතු මිණි වැල් එකට දමාලා ඔබ සරසමු ලංකාගස් වැල් වලැ මල් එකට ගොතාලා ඔබ පළඳමු ලංකාරුහුණේ කිරි පැණි එකට අනාලා ඔබ පිනවමු ලංකාඔබ වෙනුවෙන් එන වෙඩි සැර මල් පෙති සේ සලකමු ලංකාඔබ හට අත පොවනට උන් මුන් හට ඉඩ නොතබමු ලංකාඅවහොත් මෙහි උන් ලුහුබඳවා ගොළු මුහුද ගෙවමු ලංකාගොඩ දිය අහසේ හැමතැනැ ඔබගේ නම කියවමු ලංකාඅවසනැ ඔබට මැ පොහොරට මේ කය මෙහි මැ හොවමු ලංකා"},{"question":"“పెద్దలు పనికి – పిల్లలు బడికి” – అనే నినాదాన్ని సమర్థిస్తూ రాయండి.","answer":"పెద్దవారు పనిచేసి డబ్బు సంపాదించి, సంసారాన్ని పోషించాలి. పిల్లలు చక్కగా బడికి వెళ్ళి, చదువుకొని మంచి విజ్ఞానాన్ని సంపాదించాలి. చిన్నపిల్లలను పనులకు పంపి, వారు సంపాదించే చిన్నపాటి కూలీ డబ్బులను పెద్దలు ఆశించరాదు. పిల్లలను చదువులు మాన్పించి వారిని పనులకు పంపిస్తే, పిల్లల బంగారు భవిష్యత్తు నాశనం అవుతుంది."},{"question":"16世紀のフランス人予言者で、1999年に地球が破滅すると予言したとされる人物は？","answer":"ノストラダムスです。"},{"question":"世界衛生組織的英文縮寫是？","answer":"WHO"},{"question":"📚Кыргызстандын дартка даба атактуу 👨‍⚕️ дарыгери жөнүндө эмне айта аласыз?","answer":"Мамбет Мамакеев 2020- жылы Гиннестин рекорддор китебине кирген.Китептин расмий сайтында айтылат.Сайтта Мамакеев медицинадагы жетишкендиги үчүн Кыргызстандын ардактуу атуулу экени да белгиленет.Мамбет Мамакеев 95 жашта, ушул күнгө чейин операция жасайт. 1927-жылы Ысык-Көл облусунун Кереге-Таш айылында төрөлгөн. 15 миңден ашуун операция жасаган. Бир нече илимий иштердин, дарылоо ыкмаларынын автору."},{"question":"लिनिअर रिग्रेशन\\" (Linear Regression) ","answer":"\\"लिनिअर रिग्रेशन\\" (Linear Regression) हे एक सांख्यिकीशास्त्रीय प्रौद्योगिकी आहे ज्याचा उपयोग दोन वा तीन अद्यतित चरणांमध्ये संवेग अथवा एक किंवा एकाधिक स्वाधिकृत मापदंडांमध्ये संबंध साधण्यासाठी केला जातो. या अल्गोरिथ्ममचा उपयोग डेटा अध्ययन केल्यानंतर दोन किंवा दोनपेक्षा अधिक मापदंडांसाठी मूल्य अथवा दर अथवा इतर परिमाणांच्या मूल्यांच्या साथी वर्गीकरणसाठी केला जातो.लिनिअर रिग्रेशनच्या मुख्य गोष्टी:सरळ सरांश: लिनिअर रिग्रेशनला सरळ रूपात प्रस्तुत केले जाते, त्यामुळे संवेगाच्या दरम्यान संबंधाची सारखी संरेखा तयार केली जाते.मॉडेल तयार करणे: मॉडेल तयार करण्यासाठी डेटा अध्ययन केला जातो, ज्यामध्ये स्वाधिकृत मापदंडांमध्ये दोनपेक्षा अधिक मापदंड आणि त्याच्या संवेगाच्या मूल्यांच्या संबंधाची डेटा वापरला जातो.मॉडेल शिक्षण: मॉडेलला प्रशिक्षण दिल्यानंतर, मॉडेलला डेटा संवेग अथवा मूल्य अथवा इतर परिमाणांच्या मूल्यांची मूल्यांतर करण्यात आणण्याचा प्रक्रियासाठी वापरला जातो.पूर्वानुमान: शिक्षित मॉडेलचा उपयोग अज्ञात मूल्यांच्या पूर्वानुमान किंवा अनुमानसाठी केला जातो.लिनिअर रिग्रेशन हा एक सरल, प्रसिद्ध आणि वापरकर्त्यांना परिपूर्ण सांख्यिकीशास्त्रीय टूल आहे आणि डेटा अध्ययनात, डेटा प्रशिक्षणात, आणि डेटा पूर्वानुमानात विशिष्ट अर्थांकनासाठी वापरला जातो."},{"question":"පීකි බ්ලයින්ඩර්ස් කතා මාලාවේ ටොමී ශෙල්බි සමග මුලින් ගැටුම් ඇතිකරගෙන පසුව ඔහු සමඟ මිත්‍ර වන ඉතාලි ජාතිකයා  කවුද?","answer":"පීකි බ්ලයින්ඩර්ස් කතා මාලාවේ ටොමී ශෙල්බි සමග මුලින් ගැටුම් ඇතිකරගෙන පසුව ඔහු සමඟ මිත්‍ර වන ඉතාලි ජාතිකයා   ඇල්ෆි සොලමන්ස් වේ."},{"question":"*ما اللقب الذي أطلق على زوجات الرسول ؟","answer":"أمهات المؤمنين"},{"question":"Lamento que no se hayan aprobado en el Pleno las propuestas aprobadas por la Comision de Agricultura y Desarrollo Rural que figuran en mi opinion , concretamente las relativas a la necesidad de modificar la PAC y cambiar los objetivos de sus anteriores reformas , pues han provocado una reduccion de los ingresos de las pequenas y medianas explotaciones agricolas , absentismo y el abandono de la actividad agricola y solo favorecen a los grandes terratenientes.Dame una versión más simple del texto anterior. ","answer":"Lamento las propuestas contenidas en mi opinion que presentamos en el Pleno y que la Comision de Agricultura y Desarrollo Rural adopto , en particular sobre la necesidad de revisar la PAC para invertir los objetivos de sus reformas anteriores . Han sido responsables de la perdida de ingresos de los pequenos y medianos agricultores , el absentismo y el abandono de la actividad agricola  , favoreciendo unicamente a los grandes propietarios ."},{"question":"Kinsa ang gipaila sa Dios nga si Jesus human sa iyang baba ug angay siyang pagpaminawon?","answer":"Kini mao ang akong Anak nga hinigugmaon, sa iya ako nalipay.”Nganong gipanamkon si Jesus sa Jordan River ni San Juan Bautista?"},{"question":"Fan mooy péeyum réewum Luxembourg?","answer":"Péeyum réewum Luxembourg mu ngi tudu Luxembourg."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kicang-kecoh bertembung ciak'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tiap-tiap perkara yang hendak disiasat hendaklah ada buktinya"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී පාදස්ථානය වන්දනා කිරීමට ගිය , එකම ඉංග්‍රීසි ආණ්ඩුකාරවරයා කවුද ?","answer":"නිවැරදි පිලිතුර ................සර්  විල්මට් හෝර්ටන් ( 1831-1837 )"},{"question":"Isilah titik-titik berikut dengan kata, frasa, atau penggalan kalimat jawaban yang tepat, sehingga membentuk kalimat yang sempurna dan relevan dengan konteks yang diberikan.Konteks: Ciri-ciri zat makananKetika makan tempe atau kacang-kacangan, selanjutnya makanan akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul … dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan maka selanjutnya …Jawaban:","answer":"Ketika makan tempe atau kacang-kacangan, selanjutnya makanan akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul yang lebih kecil atau halus, yaitu asam amino dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan, maka selanjutnya diubah menjadi urea dan dikeluarkan bersama urin."},{"question":"ماهو بحر القصيدة التالية : \\"حتى عَلا بَيتُك المُهَذَّبُ من # خِندِفَ عَليَاءَ تَحتَها العَرَبُ\\"\\tبحر : ","answer":"المنسرح"},{"question":"我國發現最早的紙幣是在哪個時期？","answer":"宋朝"},{"question":"శీర్షిక: ఈజిప్ట్ టిక్‌టాక్‌, ఇన్‌స్టాగ్రామ్ స్టార్లను 'అసభ్యత' పేరుతో జైల్లో పెడుతున్న ప్రభుత్వంఊహాత్మక కథనం యొక్క పైన పేర్కొన్న శీర్షికను బట్టి, కథనాన్ని ఉహించి రాయండి.","answer":"జైలు శిక్షకు గురైన అయిదుగురు సోషల్ మీడియా స్టార్లలో ఒకరైన మవడా అల్-అదామ్22 ఏళ్ల మవడా అల్ అదామ్‌ అనే సోషల్ మీడియా స్టార్‌కు ఇటీవల ఈజిప్ట్‌లో కోర్టు రెండేళ్ల జైలు శిక్ష విధించింది.ఆమె చేసిన నేరం టిక్‌టాక్ వీడియోలు చేయడమే. అవి కుటుంబ విలువలకు విరుద్ధంగా ఉన్నాయంటూ కోర్టు ఆమెకు శిక్ష విధించింది.ఆధునిక దుస్తులు ధరించి, కొన్ని పాపులర్ పాటలకు డ్యాన్స్ చేస్తూ మవడా టిక్‌టాక్, ఇన్‌స్టాగ్రామ్‌ల్లో వీడియోలు పోస్టు చేస్తుంటారు. ఫొటోలు పెడుతుంటారు.గత మేలో మవడాను పోలీసులు అరెస్టు చేశారు. ఆమె వీడియోలు అసభ్యకరంగా ఉన్నాయని కోర్టు నిర్ధారించింది. ‘‘మేం షాక్ తిన్నాం. ఆమె ఏ తప్పూ చేయలేదు, నేరస్థురాలూ కాదు. ఫేమస్ అవ్వాలనుకుందంతే’’ అని మవడా చెల్లెలు రహ్మ అంటున్నారు. ‘‘మా అమ్మ ఇప్పుడు పూర్తిగా మంచం పట్టారు. ఏడుస్తూ ఉన్నారు. కొన్ని కొన్ని సార్లు రాత్రి నిద్ర లేచి, మవడా ఇంటికి వచ్చేసిందా అని అడుగుతున్నారు’’ అని రహ్మ చెప్పారు.ఒక్క మవడానే కాదు.మవడాకు మాత్రమే కాదు, మరో నలుగురు యువతులకు కూడా టిక్‌టాక్ వీడియోలు చేసినందుకు ఈజిప్ట్ కోర్టులు ఇదే శిక్ష విధించాయి. రెండేళ్ల జైలు శిక్షతోపాటు దాదాపు రూ.15 లక్షల జరిమానా కూడా విధించాయి.ఈ ఐదుగురిని ఇప్పుడు ‘టిక్‌టాక్ గర్ల్స్’ అని పిలుస్తున్నారు.హనీన్ హోసమ్ అనే సోషల్ మీడియా స్టార్ కూడా ఈ ఐదుగురిలో ఉన్నారు. మిగతా ముగ్గురి పేర్లు బయటకు వెల్లడి కాలేదు.‘‘కొన్ని పేరు పొందిన ఫ్యాషన్ బ్రాండ్లకు మా అక్క సోషల్ మీడియాలో మోడలింగ్ చేస్తున్నారు. ఆమె పెద్ద పెద్ద లక్ష్యాలు పెట్టుకున్నారు. నటి అవ్వాలన్నది ఆమె కల’’ అని రహ్మ తన అక్క గురించి వివరించారు.మవడా ‘అసభ్యకరంగా’ కనిపించిందనడానికి ఆధారంగా 17 ఫొటోలను ప్రొసిక్యూషన్ కోర్టుకు చూపించినట్లు మానవ హక్కుల సంస్థ ఆమ్నెస్టీ ఇంటర్నేషనల్ తెలిపింది. అయితే, తన ఫోన్ గత ఏడాది చోరీకి గరైందని, దాని నుంచి ఈ ఫొటోలు బయటకు లీక్ అయ్యాయని మవడా చెప్పారు.ఆగస్టు 17న మవడా శిక్షపై అప్పీలు విచారణకు రావాల్సి ఉంది.తన అక్కకు కనీసం శిక్షనైనా తగ్గిస్తారని రహ్మ ఆశాభావంతో ఉన్నారు.‘‘మా అక్కనే ఎందుకు లక్ష్యంగా చేసుకున్నారు? చాలా మంది సినీ తారలు శరీరం కనిపించేలా డ్రెస్సులు వేసుకుంటుంటారు. కానీ, వారిని ఎవరూ ఏమీ అనరు’’ అని రహ్మ ఆగ్రహం వ్యక్తం చేశారు.కోర్టు తీర్పు వినగానే మవడా స్పృహ తప్పి పడిపోయారని ఆమె న్యాయవాది అహ్మద్ బాహ్క్రీ అన్నారు."},{"question":"次の段落は何について話しているのか？ NHKは、中学校でサッカーや野球など29の運動部に生徒がどのくらい入っているか、都道府県の体育の団体などに聞いて調べました。北海道と36の県で、運動部に入っている生徒の割合が今まででいちばん低いことがわかりました。いちばん低かったのは奈良県で、50.7%でした。長野県が51%、福岡県が54.6%でした。県などによると、生まれる子どもが減って生徒も少ないため、運動部などがなくなっています。全部の生徒が部活動をしなければならないという決まりをやめた学校が増えていることも理由だと言っています。専門家は「練習のしすぎが問題になっていた運動部について学校などがよく考えることはいいと思います。授業や学校の行事も大切にしてほしいです」と話しています。","answer":"運動部に入っている中学生の割合が今まででいちばん低い"},{"question":"Oyetọla yan ọmọ Bisi Akande ni kọmiṣanna, o tun fiyawo rẹ ṣe oluranlọwọ lọfiisi ọkọ ẹ","answer":"Awuyewuye ti bẹrẹ bayii laarin awọn lameetọ ilu ninu iṣejọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun nigba ti aṣiri tu pe ijọba yan iyawo kọmisanna fun eto-idajọ, Ọnarebu Fẹmi Akande, gẹgẹ bii oluranlọwọ pataki nileeṣẹ naa.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wa ninu lẹta igbanisiṣẹ ti wọn fun iyawo kọmiṣanna naa, Arabinrin Akande Yeṣide Oyinkansọla, ijọba yan an lọjọ kẹrin, oṣu keji, ọdun 2020, gẹgẹ bii oluranlọwọ (Personal Assistant) si ọkọ rẹ.Akọwe ijọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Ọmọọba Oluwọle Oyebamiji, lo fọwọ si iwe igbanisiṣẹ naa, wọn si sọ pe igbanisiṣẹ rẹ bẹrẹ lọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun 2019.O pẹ ki aṣiri ọrọ naa too tu sita, o si jẹ iyalẹnu fun awọn araalu nigba ti wọn gbọ pe ijọba le ṣe iru nnkan bẹẹ fun kọmiṣanna naa, ẹni to jẹ ọmọ bibi gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun tẹlẹ, Oloye Adebisi Akande.Gbogbo igbesẹ ti awọn oniroyin gbe lati gbọ tẹnu kọmiṣanna ti ọrọ kan ni ko so eso rere, ko gbe ipe rẹ, bẹẹ ni ko fesi si atẹjiṣẹ ti wọn fi ranṣẹ si i.Bakan naa ni a ko rẹni fesi lori rẹ ninu Kọmiṣanna feto iroyin, Funkẹ Ẹgbẹmọde ati Akọwe iroyin fun gomina, Ismail Omipidan."},{"question":"Ñaata fan la jigéen di am ak dereeti mbaax ?","answer":"digante  ñett fan beu jurrom benn fan"},{"question":"A que categoría corresponde la siguiente pregunta : ¿Cuál fue el primer equipo de Tom Brady?.","answer":"La categoría corresponde a deportes. "},{"question":"Lori ẹsun agbere, wọn da olukọ Fasiti FUOYE duro","answer":"Latari ẹsun pe o fọgbọn alumọkọrọyi ba akẹkọọ kan ni yunifasiti ijọba apapọ FUOYE to wa ni ilu Oye-Ekiti, igbimọ alaṣẹ ileewe naa lawọn ti da olukọ agba kan, Dokita Jonathan Mbachaga, duro lọgan.Olukọ naa to jẹ ọkan ninu awọn ọga ni ẹka eto ẹkọ ere ori itage ati iroyin (Theatre and Media Art) ni wọn sọ pe o ba ọmọ ileewe ọhun to wa ni ipele kẹrin nileewe naa ni ajọṣepọ pẹlu ero pe ko le fun un ni maaki lẹyin igba ti akẹkọọ naa ti fidi-rẹmi nigba meji leralera.Gẹgẹ bii lẹta kan ti Oludamọran lori eto iroyin si ọga agba FUOYE naa, Ọgbẹni Folusho Ogunmọdẹde, ṣe wi, o sọ pe ọga agba pata ọhun lo paṣẹ pe ki olukọ Mbachaga ṣi lọọ rọọkun nile fun igba kan, lẹyin igba ti wọn gba a mu pẹlu ẹri to daju pe o ṣẹ ẹṣẹ naa.Wọn sọ pe olukọ naa ba akẹkọọ ọhun laṣepọ nigba meji leralera, to si tun kọ lati fun un ni maaki to ṣeleri, eyi ni wọn sọ po bi akẹkọ-binrin naa ninu to pariwo olukọ Mbachaga yii sita.Ninu lẹta naa, wọn ṣalaye pe igbesẹ dida olukọ yii duro lọgan jẹ lati faaye silẹ fun igbimọ ẹlẹni marun-un kan ti igbimọ alaṣẹ ileewe naa gbe kalẹ lati ṣewadii ẹsun yii.Ọga agba Fasiti ọhun sọ ninu lẹta naa pe oun ko ni i faaye silẹ fun idọti laarin olukọ ati ọmọ ileewe, ati pe gbogbo olukọ to ba jẹbi ọrọ ninu iṣẹlẹ yii lawọn yoo fọwọ osi juwe ile fun."},{"question":"Tới năm 2023, Việt Nam có bao nhiêu ngọn hải đăng?","answer":"Đáp án 92Theo số liệu thống kê của Tổng cục Hàng hải, Việt Nam hiện có 92 ngọn hải đăng, trải dài từ Móng Cái đến Hà Tiên và trên hầu hết các đảo thuộc lãnh hải Việt Nam.Hải đăng được dùng để đánh dấu các đường bờ biển hay bãi cạn nguy hiểm, các lối an toàn vào cảng. Bên cạnh đó, hải đăng còn có thể hỗ trợ việc định hướng của các máy bay. Trước đây, các ngọn hải đăng được sử dụng rộng rãi đối với ngành hàng hải, nhưng hiện nay số lượng các ngọn hải đăng đã giảm đi do đã được thay thế bởi các công cụ dẫn đường điện tử hiện đại, chẳng hạn GPS."},{"question":"Kuşkonmaz kimler yememeli?","answer":"Gut hastalığı olan kişiler tarafından kullanılmamalıdır. Emziren anneler tarafından süt arttırıcı özelliği olsa da hamile kadınlar tarafından tüketimi zararlı olabilir. Kuşkonmaz aynı zamanda doğum kontrolünde kullanılan bir besin olduğu için hamilelik döneminde kullanımında kaçınılmalıdır."},{"question":"Amabutho akaZulu alwa impi yaseSandlwana ngaphansi kwayiphi iNkosi?","answer":"Amabutho akaZulu alwa impi yaseSandlwana ngaphansi kwaKing Cetshewayo"},{"question":"Sentença 1: Līvi é uma aldeia na freguesia de Biksti e no município de Dobele na região histórica de Zemgale e na região de planejamento de Zemgale na Letónia. Frase 2: Līvi é uma aldeia na Letônia e município de Dobele na região histórica de Zemgale, e na região de planejamento de Zemgale na freguesia de Biksti. Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou não?","answer":"Não."},{"question":"Кыргыз эл артисти Роза Аманова  Ала-Тоо көрккө келбейт, эл болбосо-деген ырынын сөзү кандай?","answer":"Аккан суу түз кеталбайт, сай болбосо,Караңгы жарык болбойт, ай болбосо,Чыракта пилик күйбөйт, май болбосо.Талаанын көркү кайда, гүл болбосо?Гүл ачып, кубат албайт, күн болбосо,Акындар ырдай албайт, тил болбосо,Душманың жазганабы, сүр болбосо?Ала-Тоо көрккө келбейт эл болбосо?Комуздан абаз чыкпайт, кыл болбосо,Сүйүшүп эл каалабайт, ыр болбосо.Аялдын көркү кайда, чач болбосоТоолордун салмагы аз, таш болбосо.Узакка кабар жетпейт, кат болбосо,Жигиттин наамы чыкпайт, март болбосо,Ак жүздө кызыл болбойт, нур болбосо,Сооданын иши жүрбөйт, пул болбосо,Кишинин сыны кайда, бой болбосо.Учкан куш колго түшпөйт, тор болбосо.Ар киши адашасың, жол болбосо,Төөлөргө жүк жүктөлбөйт, ком болбосо.Буудан ат ташыркабайт, тоң болбосо.Курут, май кайдан болот, сүт болбосо?Эмгекчил токтоно албайт, иш болбосо,Тамакка даам кирбейт, туз болбосо,Нан чайнап жута албайсың, тиш болбосо,Балбандын аты чыкпайт, күч болбосо.Көздөгөн максатыңа жете албайсың,Колуңда бардык жарак бүт болбосо.Чарбанын көркү болбойт мал болбосо,Сулуунун көркү болбойт, кал болбосо.Өрдөк, каз кайда конот көл болбосо,Арчанын саясы жок, шак болбосо,Булбул куш кайда конот, бак болбосоДайралар толкуп, ташпайт, сел болбосоАргымак ат арыбайт, бел болбосо,Дыйканга түшүм кайда, жер болбосо,Ала-Тоо көрккө келбейт, эл болбосо!"},{"question":"Австроменийлер деген эмне ?","answer":"Австроменийлер (Austromenidia) — балыктардын бир уруусу."},{"question":"வினா: சுக்ரீவன் ஆட்சி செய்த நாடு?","answer":"விடை: கிட்கிந்தை"},{"question":"විද්‍යා ප්‍රබන්ධ යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"විද්‍යා ප්‍රබන්ධ වශයෙන් හැඳින්වෙන්නේ නවීන විද්‍යාත්මක පරිකල්පනයන් රසවත් කථාන්දර ලෙසින් ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම තුළින් බිහි ව ඇති සාහිත්‍යය යි. මෙහි දී බොහෝ විට විද්‍යාවේ සහ තාක්ෂණයේ විස්මයජනක අනාගත වර්ධනයන්, අභ්‍යවකාශ තරණය (space exploration), වෙනත් ග්‍රහලෝක පද්ධති ජනාවාස කිරීම (space colonization), දුරස්ථ ග්‍රහලෝකවල පැවතිය හැකි බුද්ධිමය ජීවීන් (extraterrestrial/alien life), කාලතරණය (time travel), සමාන්තර විශ්ව (parallel universes) වැනි පවතින අනාගතවාදී (futurism) සහ විද්‍යාත්මක තේමා ඇසුරු කරගනිමින් කථා ලියැවෙනු දැකිය හැකි ය.මෙම සාහිත්‍ය විසින් විද්‍යාත්මක සහ තාක්ෂණික නව සොයාගැනීම් පිළිබඳ පරිකල්පනයන් නැතිනම් අනාවැකි ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම මෙන් ම ඒ ආශ්‍රිත ව සමාජය මුහුණ දිය හැකි අභියෝග පිළිබඳ ව සාකච්ඡා කිරීම ද සිදු වේ. ඓතිහාසික ව ගත්විට විද්‍යා ප්‍රබන්ධ සාහිත්‍යය අද දවසේ යතාර්ථයක් ව ඇති ඇතැම් විද්‍යාත්මක නිපැයුම් පිළිබඳ සාර්ථක අනාවැකි ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ද සමත් වී ඇති අතර වත්මන් සමාජයේ පවතින විෂමතා ආදිය පිළිබඳ විවේචන සහ ඒවාට විකල්ප ඉදිරිපත් කිරීමට ඇතැම් ලේඛකයන් විසින් යොදාගෙන තිබේ."},{"question":"inona no iantsoana ny renin'ny vady?","answer":"rafozana no iantsoana ny renin'ny vady"},{"question":"ගෞතම බුද්ධ ශාසනයේ \\" ගිහි ධර්ම කථිකයන් අතරින් අග්‍ර \\" වූයේ කවුද ?","answer":"චිත්ත ගෘහපති "},{"question":"ጽሑፉን ጠቅለል አድርገህ ተናገር፦  (ሲ ኤን ኤን) -- የቼክ ቴኒስ ደጋፊዎች ከ30 ዓመታት በፊት ከነበረው የቬልቬት አብዮት በፊት ታይቶ የማይታወቅ የሀብት መጨመር እያገኙ ነው። የቼክ ሪፐብሊክ የሴቶች ቡድን እሁድ እለት በተከታታይ ለሁለተኛ ዓመት የፌዴራል ዋንጫን አሸንፏል - በ 1980 ዎቹ በማርቲና ናቭራቲሎቫ የሚመራው የቼኮስሎቫኪያ ቡድን ሁሉን ያሸነፈውን ስኬት በማስታወስ ። ሉሲ ሳፋሮቫ በሴርቢያ ላይ ያሸነፈችውን ነጥብ በማስመዝገብ በፕራግ የቀድሞውን የዓለም ቁጥር 1 ጄሌና ጃንኮቪክን 6-1 6-1 በማሸነፍ በመጨረሻው ጨዋታ ላይ የማይነካ 3-1 መሪነትን አቋቁማለች ። \\"በዚህ አይነት ህዝብ ውስጥ እዚህ ቤት ውስጥ መቆየት በቃላት ሊገለፅ የማይችል ነው ፣ አስገራሚ ስሜት ነው\\" ብለዋል ሳፋሮቫ በዓለም ደረጃ 17 ኛ ደረጃ ላይ የሚገኙት። \\"በጣም ብዙ ስሜቶችና ደስታዎች አሉ - ይህ ደግሞ በየቀኑ የምንለማመደው ስሜት ነው፣ ምንም እንኳን ለመስራት ስሜት ባይኖርህም እንኳ።\\" የፌዴራል ዋንጫ ትኩሳት ፕራጋን ይመታል ። ቼኮቹ ከቅዳሜው የመክፈቻ ግጥሚያ በኋላ 2-0 ሲመሩ ሳለ ሰርቢያውያን ግን ሌላዋ የቀድሞ ቁጥር 1 የሆነችው አና ኢቫኖቪች ባለፈው ዓመት የዊምብሌዶን ሻምፒዮን የነበረችውን ፔትራ ክቪቶቫን 6-3 7-5 በማሸነፍ በጨዋታው ውስጥ ቆይታለች። ባለፈው ወር በኢስታንቡል በተካሄደው የ WTA ሻምፒዮና ላይ የዋንጫዋን መከላከያ ያጠናቀቀ ህመም ቢኖርም ከጃንኮቪች ጋር የመጀመሪያዋን ጨዋታ ያሸነፈችው ክቪቶቫ \\"ብዙ ኃይል አልነበረኝም እናም በፍርድ ቤቱ ላይ ግልፅ ነበር\\" ብላለች። \\"ለጥቂት ጥይቶች ብቻ ለመጫወት ሞክሬ ነበር፤ ረዘም ላለ ጊዜ መጫወት አልቻልኩም፤ ለዚያም ነው ስህተት መሥራቴ የጀመረው።\\" ቼኮች ከጣሊያን (2009-10) እና ከሩሲያ (2007-08) በኋላ ማዕረጉን ለመከላከል ሦስተኛው ተከታታይ ብሔር ሆነዋል ። እስከ 1988 ድረስ በአሮጌዋ ቼኮዝሎቫኪያ የተሸነፉትን አምስት ሲቆጥሩ በአውስትራሊያ የተሸነፉትን ሰባት ጋር ይዛመዳሉ - በአጠቃላይ ሁለተኛ ፣ ግን ከአሜሪካ 10 ዓይናፋር (* ዓይናፋር ሲጥቀም ምን ለማለት ፈልጎ እንደሆነ አላውቅም)። ባለፈው ዓመት የተገኘው ድል ከስሎቫኪያ ጋር በ1993 ከተለያየ ወዲህ የመጀመሪያው ነው። ይህ በእንዲህ እንዳለ ዴቪድ ፌሬር እሁድ እለት በፓሪስ በተደረገው የፍፃሜ ውድድር የጀርዚ ጃኖቪች ግዙፍ ገዳይ ሩጫን ካቆመ በኋላ የመጀመሪያውን የኤቲፒ ማስተርስን ማዕረግ አነሳ ። አምስተኛው ደረጃ ላይ የሚገኘው ስፔናዊው 6-4 6-3 አሸንፎ ከዓለም አራቱ ምርጥ ተጫዋቾች ውጪ ከሮቢን ሶደርሊንግ ወዲህ ከሁለት ዓመት በፊት በተመሳሳይ ውድድር ማስተር 1000 ውድድርን ያሸነፈ የመጀመሪያው ተጫዋች ሆኗል ። የፖላንድ 69ኛ ደረጃ...","answer":"የቼክ ሪፐብሊክ የሴቶች ቡድን ለሁለተኛ ተከታታይ ዓመት የፌዴራል ዋንጫ ፍፃሜ አሸነፈ። ሉሲ ሳፋሮቫ በአና ኢቫኖቪች አሸናፊነት 3 ለ 1 መሪነትን አገኘች ። የቀድሞዋ ቼኮዝሎቫኪያ እስከ 1988 ድረስ አምስት ጊዜ አሸናፊ ሆናለች ። ዴቪድ ፌሬር እሁድ እለት በፓሪስ የፍፃሜ ውድድር አሸንፎ የመጀመሪያውን የኤቲፒ ማስተርስ ዋንጫ አሸነፈ።"},{"question":"सूर्यग्रहण र चन्द्रगहण कुनकुन किनाराबाट लाग्न सुरु गर्दछ?","answer":"सूर्यग्रहण पश्चिमबाट र चन्द्रग्रहण पूर्वबाट"},{"question":"கீழ்க்கண்ட கேள்விக்கு பதில் சொல்லுங்கள். ஐரோப்பாவில் அதிக மக்கள் தொகை கொண்ட 5 நகரங்கள் யாவை?","answer":"ஐரோப்பாவில் அதிக மக்கள் தொகை கொண்ட 5 நகரங்கள்: இஸ்தான்புல், மாஸ்கோ, லண்டன், செயின்ட் பீட்டர்ஸ்பேர்க், மற்றும் பெர்லின் ஆகும்.இஸ்தான்புல், துருக்கியில் உள்ள நகரங்களில் அதிகூடிய மக்கள் தொகை கொண்ட நகரமாகும். அந்நாட்டின் பண்பாட்டு மற்றும் பொருளாதாரத் தலைநகரமும் இதுவேயாகும். துருக்கியின் இஸ்தான்புல் மாகாணத்தின் தலைநகரமாகவும் இது விளங்குகின்றது. உரோமைப் பேரரசன் கான்ஸ்டன்டைன் பெயரால் பழங்காலத்தில் இது, கான்ஸ்டண்டினோப்பிள் என அழைக்கப்பட்டது. 41° வ 28° கி இல் பொஸ்போரஸ் நீரிணையில் அமைந்துள்ள இந்நகரம், தங்கக் கொம்பு (Golden Horn) என அழைக்கப்படும் இயற்கைத் துறைமுகத்தையும் உள்ளடக்கியுள்ளது. பொஸ்போரஸ் நீரிணை, ஐரோப்பாவையும், ஆசியாவையும், பிரிக்கும் எல்லையாக இருப்பதால், இதன் இரு கரைகளிலும் அமைந்துள்ள இந்நகரம் இரு கண்டங்களில் அமைந்துள்ள ஒரே பெரு நகரமாக விளங்குகின்றது. உலக வரலாற்றில், மூன்று பேரரசுகளுக்குத் தலைநகரமாக விளங்கிய ஒரே நகரம் என்ற பெருமையும் இதற்கு உண்டு. கி.பி 330 - 395 வரை ரோமப் பேரரசின் தலைநகரமாகவும், 395 - 1453 வரை பைசண்டைன் பேரரசின் தலைநகராகவும், 1453 - 1923 வரை ஓட்டோமான் பேரரசின் தலைநகரமாகவும் இது விளங்கியது. 1923 இல் துருக்கிக் குடியரசு உருவாக்கப்பட்டபோது, தலைநகரம், இஸ்தான்புல்லிலிருந்து அங்காராவுக்கு மாற்றப்பட்டது. ஐரோப்பாவில், மாஸ்கோவிற்கு அடுத்தபடியாக அதிக மக்கள்தொகை கொண்ட நகரம் இதுவே ஆகும்."},{"question":"Ngiyabonga sayitsheni. Ukube anifikanga ngabe indaba yamiisingumlando. Ngibonga kakhulu sayitsheni.Ubonga ngakhona Duma kodwa nguwe oyimbangela yalokhu.Usho ukuthini sayitsheni? Yimi yini ovimba intuthuko lapha kulendawo?Uyakhumbula ngikubuza ukuthi uyathathisa na enkosini umauzokwenza utho endaweni yayo? Wathini wena? Angithi wadazainkani? Nenhlangano yakho yaphinde yakuyala ngokuhlonipha inkosi,wena wenza okuthandwa nguwe. Bafile-ke manje abantu. UMbandlwasiyezwa ukuthi ubengungqa phambili ekutheni wenze lokhuobukwenza. Naye uDlamini kuyavela ukuthi ubethukuthela aze enzeizinto ezingalungile njengakho ukushaya uMbandlwa.Angimsoli-ke yena kakhulu ngoba ubehlukunyezwa ngukubona wenauthela inkosi yakhe ngothuli.(ukuzithoba kuyadlondlobala. Useze watshekisa ngisho nekhanda.Izandla zakhe ulokhu ezihlanganisa njengomuntu okhuluma nomuntuamhlonipha ngendlela exakile) Ngiyezwa sayitsheni. (athule kancane)Sekwenzekile-ke okubuhlungu sayitsheni. Ngiyaphinda ngithi velesekonakele. Manje, ngizocela nigcine ukuthula endaweni, minasengizowuyeka-ke lo msebenzi wobukhansela.(enyuse izwi ngenxa yentukuthelo) Uthini? Uyeke? Niqala izinto besenigabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele? Lutho! Wena yelekelelaekucisheni lo mlilo wothathe osuwokhele.Kahle sayitsheni. Ngizowucisha kanjani lo mlilo? Bazongibulala phelaabantu. 1. Fingqa ngamaphuzu AMABILI imizamo eyenziwa nguhulumeni kanyenezinhlangano zepolitiki ekudambiseni udlame endaweni yenkosi? ","answer":"• Amaphoyisa kahulumeni enza yonke imizamo yokuthi kube nokuthulakule ndawo.√/• Uhulumeni wathumela iziphathimandla ngosuku lomhlangano ukuthizizofaka isandla ekudaleni uxolo.√/• Izinhlangano zezepolitiki zathumela abaholi bazo ukuzosiza endaweni.√/• Inhlangano kaDuma yezepolitiki yameluleka ukuthi akahloniphe inkosiukuze kube nokuthula endaweni yenkosi.√"},{"question":"ਮਾਤਰਵੰਸ਼ੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਕਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਮਾਤਰਵੰਸ਼ੀ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਸੰਪੱਤੀ ਪੁੱਤਰੀ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"Qual é o nome do filme brasileiro que ganhou o Oscar de Melhor Filme Internacional em 2020?","answer":"O filme brasileiro que ganhou o Oscar de Melhor Filme Internacional em 2020 é 'A vida invisível'."},{"question":"Adeshina di Aarẹ banki idagbasoke Afrika lẹẹkeji","answer":"Ọmọ ilẹ wa, Akinwumi Adeshina, ti wọle lẹẹkeji gẹgẹ bii Aarẹ banki idagbasoke ilẹ Afrika fun ọdun marun-un mi-in.Eyi waye lonii lẹyin ipade ti awọn alaṣẹ banki naa ṣe lori ayelujara, bẹẹ ni ko sẹni to ba a du ipo naa.Laipẹ yii ni wọn fi ẹsun ipaṣipayọ owo kan Adeshina, ṣugbọn wọn pada da ẹjọ naa nu nitori ko lẹsẹ nilẹ, eyi to fun un lanfaani lati du ipo yii nigba keji.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọdun 2015 ni Adeshina di aarẹ banki yii, eyi to sọ ọ di ọmọ Naijiria akọkọ to di ipo naa mu.Ẹni ọgọta ọdun ni ọkunrin naa, o si ti ṣe minisita fun nnkan ọgbin ati idagbasoke igberiko nilẹ Naijiria laye iṣejọba Ọmọwe Goodluck Jonathan."},{"question":"fehezanteny voalohany: Nahafantatra fanjakana sy firenena maro namolavola ny tantarany i Madagasikara.fehezanteny faharoa: Ny Mpanjaka Radama I dia nampifandray ny fanjakana malagasy tamin’ireo fanjakana eoropeanina, indrindra fa i Frantsa.Misy ifandraisany ve ireo fehezanteny ireo?","answer":"Eny, misy ifandraisany ireo fehezanteny ireo."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"awak menangis diberi pisang\\"?","answer":"Pujukan yang tepat pada masa"},{"question":"ప్రధాన సంఖ్య లేక సంయుక్త సంఖ్యను పొందు ఘటనలు(A) పరస్పర వర్జిత ఘటనలు(B) సమసంభవ ఘటనలు(C) అసంభవ ఘటనలు(D) ఏదీకాదు","answer":"(A) పరస్పర వర్జిత ఘటనలు"},{"question":"Hãy viết một đoạn văn ít nhất 200 chữ dựa trên nội dung được nói tới trong câu sau: Tài xế gấp rút dán thẻ thu phí không dừng trước giờ 'G' ngay cao tốc","answer":"Tối 31/7, trên chuyến xe từ Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu về TP.HCM, anh Trần Thanh Hoàng tranh thủ dừng lại ở tuyến cao tốc TP.HCM - Long Thành - Dầu Giây để dán thẻ thu phí không dừng. Sử dụng 2 chiếc ôtô và thường xuyên di chuyển trên cao tốc, anh Hoàng nhờ nhân viên hỗ trợ đồng bộ vào một tài khoản. Tài xế này cho biết mỗi tuần anh đều đi qua cao tốc này và bất ngờ khi hôm nay là ngày cuối tuần, cao tốc không ùn tắc do nhiều xe đã sử dụng thu phí không dừng. \\"Hôm nay là ngày cuối cùng còn thu vé thủ công nên tôi tranh thủ dán thẻ không dừng. Tôi khá bất ngờ vì về muộn thế này vẫn còn nhân viên hỗ trợ dán thẻ cho mình\\", anh Hoàng bày tỏ. Biết tới việc thu phí không dừng đã lâu nhưng tới hôm nay, anh Thanh Thiện (ngụ tỉnh Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu) mới quyết định dán thẻ. Chần chừ vì tài xế này thấy thông tin thu phí của các trạm chưa thống nhất, \\"trạm thì yêu cầu đơn vị này, nơi thì đơn vị nọ\\". Sau khi được hướng dẫn dán thẻ, anh Thiện vui mừng cho biết từ mai đỡ phải chuẩn bị tiền mặt mỗi khi đi xe, tất cả thông tin được thông báo qua ứng dụng. Việc này giúp anh tiết kiệm thời gian, đỡ phải chờ đợi khi qua trạm thu phí. \\"Những ngày gần đây, tôi đọc thông tin trên báo, thấy hệ thống ETC còn nhiều lỗi kỹ thuật. Mong thời gian tới, các lỗi được khắc phục để tài xế thuận tiện\\", anh Thiện nói thêm. Dán thẻ ETC từ lâu, nhưng anh Công Nghiệp (quận Bình Tân, TP.HCM) bị mất thẻ sau một lần va chạm giao thông. Biết ngày mai các trạm áp dụng thu phí không dừng bắt buộc, tài xế này tranh thủ dừng xe dán lại thẻ ETC. Lúc đầu, anh Nghiệp không đồng ý trả mức phí 120.000 đồng cho lần đổi thẻ tiếp theo vì nghe thông tin \\"miễn phí\\". Sau khi được nhân viên Công ty VETC giải thích, anh Nghiệp dán thẻ lần thứ 2 và phí sẽ được trừ sau khi anh nạp tiền vào tài khoản, tài xế này đồng ý. Trao đổi với Zing, anh Hoàng Trung Hiếu, chuyên viên kinh doanh Công ty VETC, cho hay lượng khách hàng có nhu cầu dán thẻ những ngày gần đây tăng đột biến. Để đáp ứng nhu cầu của khách hàng, VETC triển khai mạng lưới cộng tác viên hỗ trợ và tăng cường tại nhiều điểm dán thẻ, đặc biệt là trên các tuyến cao tốc lớn. Hôm nay, VETC sẽ bố trí nhân viên hoạt động xuyên đêm để hỗ trợ khách hàng chưa kịp dán thẻ. Đơn vị đang dán thẻ miễn phí cho khách hàng và bắt đầu thu phí dán thẻ từ ngày 6/8 với mức 120.000 đồng/lần. Sau hơn 6 năm triển khai hệ thống thu phí không dừng và dán thẻ định danh ETC, Chính phủ ấn định 0h ngày 1/8 là \\"giờ G\\" để áp dụng thu phí không dừng bắt buộc tại các tuyến cao tốc trên toàn quốc. Ở khu vực phía nam hiện có 3 tuyến cao tốc gồm: TP.HCM - Long Thành - Dầu Giây, TP.HCM - Trung Lương và Trung Lương - Mỹ Thuận. Đến nay, chỉ có tuyến TP.HCM - Long Thành - Dầu Giây do VEC quản lý sẵn sàng vận hành thu phí không dừng hoàn toàn. Tuyến TP.HCM - Trung Lương đang cho khai thác miễn phí. Còn tuyến Trung Lương - Mỹ Thuận đã vận hành, nhưng chưa được cấp có thẩm quyền phê duyệt thu phí."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'macam ular kekenyangan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang buncit perutnya sehingga berjalannya pun sudah tidak betul lagi."},{"question":"মৌলিক গণতন্ত্র নামে একটি ব্যবস্থা চালু করা হয় কেন?","answer":"সামরিক শাসনকে দীর্ঘায়িত করার লক্ষ্যে ১৯৫৮ সালে আইয়ুব খান মৌলিক গণতন্ত্র চালু করেন।মৌলিক গণতন্ত্র ব্যবস্থায় পূর্ব পাকিস্তান ও পশ্চিম পাকিস্তান থেকে মোট ৮০ হাজার নির্বাচিত ইউনিয়ন কাউন্সিল সদস্য নিয়ে নির্বাচকমণ্ডলী গঠন করা হয়। রাষ্ট্রপতি নির্বাচন, জাতীয় ও প্রাদেশিক পরিষদ নির্বাচনে এরাই শুধু অংশগ্রহণের মাধ্যমে মতামত প্রকাশের সুযোগ পেত। মূলত এ নির্বাচন পদ্ধতি পূর্ব পাকিস্তানের সব ক্ষেত্রে বৈষম্যের সৃষ্টি করে। এর মধ্য দিয়ে আইয়ুব খান তার শাসনামলকে সুসংহত করার চেষ্টা করেন।"},{"question":"විෂමජාතීය මිශ්‍රණ යනු මොනවාද?","answer":"විෂමජාතීය මිශ්‍රණ යනු මිශ්‍රණය පුරාම සංයුතිය ඒකාකාර නොවන මිශ්‍රණ වර්ගයකි."},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira de Omã.","answer":"A bandeira de Omã é uma faixa vermelha vertical no canto superior esquerdo, seguida por uma faixa branca horizontal no meio da bandeira e uma faixa vermelha vertical no canto inferior direito. No cantão superior esquerdo, há um emblema nacional que inclui uma adaga cruzada com duas espadas, conhecida como o \\"Khanjar.\\""},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：什么是中国古代宫廷音乐，它有哪些特色？","answer":"答案：中国古代宫廷音乐是中国皇室和贵族所创造和欣赏的音乐形式。其特色包括庄重典雅的曲调、古朴华美的乐器演奏和严谨的音乐制度，代表了中国古代宫廷文化的精髓和独特风格。"},{"question":"رشحلى خمس أفلام عربى أتفرج عليهم.","answer":"بالتأكيد، السينما العربية حافلة بالأفلام الممتعة. لو عاوز خمس أفلام ممكن أرشحلك دول:1. الحريف2. البيضة و الحجر3. الحموات الفاتنات4. الحفيد5. صعيدى فى الجامعة الأمريكية"},{"question":"Уй жөнүндө малымат жазып бере аласыңбы?","answer":"Кой - майда малдын катарына кирип, минерге же жалгыз өзү чоң тойдун союшуна жарабаса да, кыргыз баласы үчүн орду чоң. Ошон үчүн бул жандыкка тиешелүү сөздөр кыргыз тилинде көп.Ошентип, кой баласы козу болот. Бир жашка толуп калганын күрпөң дешет. Минтип ажыратып аталып калганы, бир жаштан кийин койду соё берсе болот экен. Койдун эки жашка чыккан ургаачысы – токту. Ал төлдөй турган жашына жеткенде тубар кой аталат. Бирок жибек кездеменин түрүн атоочу тубар деген сөзгө үндөш болгону менен, бул сөз чынында туур, тууй турган деген сөз менен уңгулаш. Төрт жаштан ашкан ургаачы койду соолук дешет.Тукум улоого эмес, семиртип этке союла турган эркек козу бычылып, бир жаштан ашкандан кийин ирик аталат.Ал эми бычылбаган, тукумдукка багыла турган эркек кой кочкор болот.Кой жүнүнө жараша да бөлүнөт. Айылдын энелери жүнү кыркыла элек койлордун бирин карап \\"жарагандай жүнү бар экен\\" десе, дагы бирин \\"муну кырксаң, сатып эле ийбесең болбойт\\" деп көз менен эле баалап коюшат. Алардын айырмасы эмне?Мытыс (метис) койдун жүнү жумшак жана ичке болот (меринос). Андан айырмаланып кылчык жүндүү кой. Жанагы сатып ийгенге жарачусу дал ушул кылчыктуусу болот.Уяң жүндүү койлор кездешет. Ошону жана кара жүндүү койлорду кыргыз кой деп да аташат. Тегерек май куйруктуу койлор эл арасында кисер аталат. Аны көбүнчө кыргыз кой деп жаңылыш айтышат. Чынында, бул Тажикстандан чыккан гисар (жердин аталышы боюнча) деп аталчу, кылчык жүндүү койдун өзү. Аны совет доорунда кыргыздын уяң жүндүү кою менен аргындаштырып, айкөл деп аталган түрүн өстүрүшкөн. Ал эт-май жагынан да, жүн жагынан да берекелүү мал болуп эсептелет."},{"question":"Эмнеге иттер тилдерин чыгарып эс алат?","answer":"Иттердин оозун ачып, тилин чыгарып эс алуусу органзмине автомобилдин радиатору сыяктуу функциясын аткарат. Жөнөкөй тил менен айтканда, денесин ысыктыктан сактайт. Иттердин денесинде аябай аз болгон \\"тер бездери\\" болот, анын көп бөлүгү бутунун тамандарында.Биз адамдар ысыганыбызда денебиз нымдалып тердейбиз, а бирок, бул нерсе иттерде жок. Ошондуктан, алар тилин чыгарып алып өпкөсүнүн жардамы менен бүтүн денесиндеги ысыктыкты төмөндөтөт."},{"question":" sheeg sanadkii uu geeriyooday boqorkii Quree Victoria","answer":" jawab. wuxu geeriyooday sanadkii 1901-dii."},{"question":"மெய்ப்பாடு என்றால் என்ன?","answer":"இலக்கியத்தைப் படிக்கின்றபோது அதன் பொருளை ஆழப்படுத்தும் வகையில் காட்டப்படும் உணர்ச்சி வெளிப்பாட்டு சுவையே மெய்ப்பாடு என்பர். ‘சொற்கேட்டார்க்குப் பொருள் கண் கூடாதல்கவி கண் காட்டும்’ என்று உரையாசிரியர், பேராசிரியர் குறிப்பிடுகிறார்."},{"question":"नेपाली लिपि के हो र यसमा कतिवटा अक्षरहरू छन्?","answer":"नेपाली लिपिलाई \\"देवनागरी\\" भनिन्छ र यसमा ३६ अक्षरहरू छन्।"},{"question":"س139 - كم يبلغ عدد الصلوات التي فرضها الله في اليوموالليلة ؟","answer":"ج139 - 5 صلوات"},{"question":"Гетеризм деген эмне ?","answer":"Гетеризм — байыркы грекче гетера деген сөздөн чыккан термин; жыныстык катнашуулардын тартипке салынбагандыгынан улам жыныстардын ортосундагы мамилелердин башталыш тарыхый формасын жана ал форманы алмаштырган аралаш никени белгилөө үчүн швейцариялык тарыхчы И. Я. Бахофен тарабынан орунсуз киргизилген.Азыркы илимде бул «промискуитет» деген термин менен белгиленип, бир катар элдерде сакта­лып калган аралаш нике саркындыларын атоо үчүн гана колдонулат."},{"question":"Cad é an Cogadh na Saoirse a tharla in Éirinn? ","answer":"Tugtar Cogadh na Saoirse, Uaireanta ar a dtugtar Cogadh Angla-Éireannach, 21 Eanáir 1919 go dtí 11 Iúil 1921, ar an treallchogadh idir Rialtas na Breataine in Éirinn agus Óglaigh na hÉireann, a bhí faoi smacht na Chéad Dála. Parlaimint neamhspleách a bhí ann, agus í curtha i dtoll le chéile as feisirí Éireannacha a vótáladh isteach in olltoghchán Westminster sa bhliain 1918, an tromlach acu a thoiligh le dul ar an Dáil mar theachtaí."},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:એક જ સમયમાં થઈ ગયેલું","answer":"સમકાલીન"},{"question":"Completa il testo seguente:\\"Il nome Bangladesh ...\\"","answer":"\\"... significa in bengalese Paese del Bengala. Il Bengala (in bengalese Bôngo (বঙ্গ), Bangla (বাংলা), Bôngodesh (বঙ্গদেশ), o Bangladesh (বাংলাদেশ)), è una regione nord-orientale del Subcontinente indiano. La maggior parte è divisa tra il Bangladesh (Bengala Orientale) e lo Stato federato indiano del Bengala Occidentale, mentre alcuni territori appartenenti allo scomparso Regno del Bengala (durante il periodo della monarchia locale e del dominio britannico) sono divenuti territorio di alcuni Stati confinanti dell'India nord-orientale, come Bihar, Tripura e Orissa. La gran parte del territorio del Bengala è abitata da bengalesi.La regione del Bengala è una tra le più densamente popolate della terra, con un tasso superiore a 900 ab./km². La maggior parte della regione soggiace nel delta del Gange-Brahmaputra, il più grande delta fluviale del mondo. Nella parte meridionale del delta si trovano le Sundarbans, la più grande foresta di mangrovie del mondo nonché habitat della tigre del Bengala. Anche se la maggior parte della popolazione è di estrazione rurale e agraria, nella regione si trovano le metropoli di Calcutta, Dacca e Chittagong.\\""},{"question":"මොල්ටීස් භාෂාව යනු කුමක් ද?  ","answer":"මෝල්ටීස් භාෂාව යනු, රෝමානුක ආභාෂය සහිතව පශ්චාත්-මධ්‍යතන සිසිලියානු ඇරබීය භාෂාවෙන් විකාශනය වුණ, මෝල්ටීස් ජනයා විසින් වහරනු ලබන භාෂාව යි. එය ඇෆ්‍රෝ- ආසියාතික භාෂා පවුලේ, සෙමිටික් උපභාෂා පවුලට අයත් භාෂාවකි. එය මෝල්ටාවේ ජාතික භාෂාව වන අතර, එය යුරෝපා සංගමයේ නිළ භාෂාවක් ලෙස සැලකෙන එක ම සෙමිටික් භාෂාවයි. මෙම භාෂාව ක්‍රි.ව. 831 - 1091 අතර කාලයේ දී සිසිලියේ එමිරේට් හී දී මග්‍රේබී ඇරබීය උපභාෂාවක් ලෙස විකාශනය වුණ සික්‍යුලෝ- ඇරබික් භාෂාවෙන් පැවත එන, රෝමානුකරණයට නතු වුණ භාෂිත ‍පුරාණ ඇරබීය භාෂාවකින් පැවත එන්නකි. මෝල්ටාව මුහුණ දුන් නෝර්මානු ආක්‍රමණයන්ගේ හා මෝල්ටාව යළි ක්‍රිස්තියානීකරණය කිරීමේ ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස, සම්භාව්‍ය අරාබි භාෂාවෙන් ස්වාධීන ව ක්‍රමානුකූල ව රෝමානුකරණය වෙමින් විකාශනය විය. සම්භාව්‍ය අරාබි හෝ නූතන සම්මත අරාබි භාෂාවන්ට ඩිග්ලොසීය ඥාතීත්වයක් නොමැති මෙම භාෂාව ඒ හේතුවෙන් සුවිශේෂී භාෂාවක් ලෙස හැඳින්වීම උචිත ය. ඉතාලි හා සිසිලියානු භාෂාවල බලපෑමට ලක් වූ වාග්කෝෂය හේතුවෙන් එය අනෙක් අරාබි භාෂාවන්ගෙන් වෙනස් භාෂාවක් ලෙස හඳුනා ගත හැකි ය.["},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ny marina toy ny rano ka _\\"","answer":"\\"tsy mety kapaina\\""},{"question":"Bu metin hangi önemli olayla ilgilidir: Büyük Kafkas Sıradağları, Gürcistan'ın kuzey sınırını oluşturur. Sıradağlardan Rusya topraklarına giden ana yollar, Şida Kartli ile Kuzey Osetya arasındaki Roki Tüneli'nden ve (Gürcü Hevi bölgesinde) Daryal Boğazı'ndan geçmektedir. Roki Tüneli, 2008 Rus-Gürcü Savaşı'nda Rus ordusu için hayati öneme sahipti, çünkü Kafkas Dağları'ndan geçen tek doğrudan yoldu. Ülkenin güney kısmı Küçük Kafkas Dağları ile sınırlanmıştır. Büyük Kafkas Sıradağları, deniz seviyesinden 5.000 metre yüksekliğe ve daha fazlasına ulaşan en yüksek zirveler ile Küçük Kafkas Dağları'ndan çok daha yüksektir.","answer":"2008 Rus-Gürcü Savaşı"},{"question":"Ṣe oju lasan lọrọ baba agba yii ṣa, ọmọ ọdun meji lo ba lo pọ l’Agbado","answer":"Ọwọ awọn ọlọpaa Agbado, nipinlẹ Ogun, ti tẹ baba agbalagba ẹni ọdun mẹrinlelọgọta yii (64), Alagba Ayọtunde Taiwo, ẹni ti wọn lo fipa ba ọmọ ọdun meji pere lo pọ lọjọ Iṣẹgun,Tusidee, ọjọ keje, oṣu kẹsan-an yii, l’Agbado.Gẹgẹ bi iya ọmọdebinrin naa ṣe ṣalaye fawọn ọlọpaa ni nnkan bii aago mọkanla aarọ ọjọ naa, o ni oun kan deede ri i pe ọmọ oun ko le rin daadaa ni, niṣe lo n gadi rin. O loun sun mọ ọn, oun yẹ ara rẹ wo, nigba naa loun si ri ẹjẹ loju ara rẹ.Iya ọmọ naa ni oun beere lọwọ ọmọde yii pe ki lo ṣẹlẹ si i, o si nawọ si ile to wa lọọọkan ile awọn, loun ba mu un gba ibẹ lọ.O ni nigba tawọn debẹ, niṣe lawọn ba baba agba yii, Ayọtunde Taiwo, to n fọ ṣokoto penpe tawọn ọkunrin maa n wọ tẹlẹ (boxer), eyi ti ẹjẹ wa lara rẹ, eyi si fi han pe oun lo fipa ṣe ere buruku fun ọmọ kekere ọhun.Ohun to mu iya ọmọ gba teṣan lọ ree, ti CSP Kẹhinde Kuranga, DPO teṣan Agbado, fi ko awọn ikọ rẹ lẹyin, ti wọn si lọọ mu baba agba yii.Ọmọ kekere to ṣe yankanyankan naa ti wa labẹ itọju lọsibitu, wọn si ti taari baba naa si ẹka to n gbọ ẹsun bii eyi l’Ọta, nibi ti wọn yoo ti pe Ayọtunde Taiwo lẹjọ."},{"question":"Kumuu ahaa saxaabigii dilay musaylamah Al-kadaab ?","answer":"Waxshi RC ."},{"question":"What are the components of the Attention Mechanism in a Transformer?","answer":"The Attention Mechanism includes three components: Query, Key, and Value. It computes attention scores by measuring the similarity between the query and key, then uses these scores to weight the values for the final output."},{"question":"കേരളത്തിലെ ഹൈക്കോടതി എവിടെയാണ് സ്ഥിതി ചെയ്യുന്നത് ഓപ്ഷൻ: 1. എറണാകുളം 2. തിരുവനന്തപുരം 3. തൃശൂർ 4. കോഴിക്കോട്","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഓപ്ഷൻ 1. എറണാകുളം"},{"question":"Inona no vanim-potoana ahafahan'ny lehilahy manan-janaka sy manangana fianakaviana?a) Fahatanoranab) Fahamatoranad) Fahazazanae) Ray aman-dreny","answer":"b) Fahamatorana no vanim-potoana ahafahan'ny lehilahy manan-janaka sy manangana fianakaviana."},{"question":"Mo mọ Tinubu daadaa, oun lo le ṣe aarẹ lọdun 2023- Alagba Faṣọranti","answer":"Olori ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre to ṣẹṣẹ gbe kinni ọhun silẹ fun Oloye Ayọ Adebanjọ, Alagba Reuben Faṣọranti, ti sọ pe oun fara mọ ọn daadaa pe ki Aṣiwaju Bọla Tinubu, di aarẹ Naijiria lọdun 2023, nitori ẹni toun mọ daadaa ti yoo si ṣe ohun ti araalu n fẹ ni bo ba de ipo naa.Ikọ to n polongo ibo fun Tinubu, eyi ti wọn n pe ni ‘South West Agenda For Asiwaju Bola Ahmed Tinubu’(SWAGA 23) lo ṣabẹwo sile Alagba Faṣọranti niluu Akurẹ, ti wọn waa beere fun atilẹyin baba naa.Ninu ọrọ ti baba ẹni ọdun marundinlọgọrun-un(95) naa sọ fun wọn lo ti fi atilẹyin rẹ han fun Tinubu, baba naa sọ pe,’’Tinubu kunju oṣuwọn lati ṣakoso Naijiria, nitori oriṣiiriṣii nnkan lo ti gbe ṣe lorilẹ-ede yii. Mo fọwọ si i, mo si tun gba a ladura pe ki Ọlọrun jẹ ko ṣee ṣe fun un. Nitori to ba depo naa tan, gbogbo ohun ti a fẹ ni yoo ṣe. Tinubu ko ni i ja awọn ọmọ Naijiria kulẹ, mo mọ ọn daadaa’’Baba fi kun un pe ọna kan ṣoṣo ti ipo aarẹ ko fi ni i bọ mọ Yoruba lọwọ lọdun 2023 ni ki gbogbo eeyan gbaruku ti Tinubu, o ni didun lọsan yoo so bi gbogbo ilu ba ṣatilẹyin fun un.Ṣugbọn latigba ti baba ti sọrọ yii lawọn eeyan ti n bu ẹnu atẹ lu olori ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre tẹlẹ naa, oriṣiiriṣii ọrọ lo si n ja ran-in lori ayelujara bayii si baba naa, ti wọn n sọ pe ojo ogbo ti n da ọkunrin yii laamu, wọn ni ko daju pe o mọ ohun to n sọ.Ọpọ eeyan lo n sọ pe ṣe baba ti gbagbe iku ọmọ rẹ tawọn Fulani pa lọdun 2019, Funkẹ Ọlakunrin, ni. Wọn ni ṣe ko ranti ọrọ ti Tinubu sọ nigba to lọọ ki baba naa nile lori iku Funkẹ, to ni ki i ṣe Fulani lo pa obinrin naa, abi maaluu wo lawọn to n sọ bẹẹ ri lọwọ awọn to pa Funkẹ.Awọn mi-in tilẹ sọ pe afẹnifẹbi ni baba, o ti kuro ninu ẹgbẹ Afẹnifẹre. Bẹẹ lawọn mi-in sọ pe owo ti wọn gbe wa fun baba arugbo naa lo n ṣiṣẹ rẹ. Wọn ni nigba tawọn SWAGA 23 ko ti i wa sile rẹ, njẹ o polongo atilẹyin fun Tinubu bi, wọn ni owo ti wọn waa fi di Baba Faṣọranti lẹnu lo jẹ ko maa sọ ohun ti ko tọ sẹnu ẹni ti ọjọ ti dalẹ fun bii eyi.Yatọ si Baba Faṣọranti, awọn ọba meji to tun fi atilẹyin wọn han fun Bọla Tinubu l’Ondo ni, Ọsẹmawe, Ọba Victor Kiladejọ, ati Abodi Ikalẹ, Ọba George Faduyile. Wọn ni ki gbogbo ọmọ Yoruba ti Jagaban lẹyin, nitori oun ni ipo aṣiwaju Naijiria tọ si."},{"question":"முகமது கஜினி இந்தியாவை எத்தனை முறை தாக்கினார்?","answer":"மஹ்மூத் கஜினி 1000 முதல் 1027 வரை இந்தியாவை 17 முறை தாக்கினார்."},{"question":"Following the Wall Street Crash of 1929 , greatest gains for the Nazis came in the Protestant , rural towns of the North , while Catholic areas remained with the Centre Party .","answer":" the Wall Street Crash of 1929 , the Nazis and Communists made great gains at the 1930 Election ."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය ගයනා  කරන්නේ කව්ද ?ළමා වියේ කිරි සුවඳ ගියේ නැති ළමා වියේදීකසාවතක් හැඳ පොඩි හාමුදුරුවො පුංචිම කාලේතනියම හිතිලද මහණ වුණේසසර පුරුද්දක් හිතේ තියෙන්නැතිපෙර සංසාරේ පින් කරලා ඇතිපොඩි හාමුදුරුවො පුංචිම කාලේතනියම හිතිලද මහණ වුණේපොඩි හාමුදුරුවො වාගේ සුරතල්පුංචි ළමුන්ගේ කෙළි සෙල්ලම් දැකසන්සුන් ගමනින් කොහෙද වඩින්නේසෙල්ලම් පිට්ටනි පසු කරලා","answer":"මාලනී බුලත්සිංහල"},{"question":"صلاة يقوم فيها المصلي بالركوع والسجود أربع مرات، فما هي تلك الصلاة ؟\\t","answer":"صلاة الكسوف"},{"question":"Iza no renivohitr'i Espaina?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Espaina dia \\"Madrid\\"."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao :   \\"raha tonga ny tokoa tokoa  _\\" ","answer":" \\"raha tonga ny tokoa tokoa dia alavitra ny lainga\\" "},{"question":"வினா:தமிழ்நாட்டில் உள்ள அரியலூர் மாவட்டத்தைப்பற்றிச் சில தகவல்களைத் தருக.","answer":"விடை :அரியலூர் மாவட்டம் இந்திய மாநிலமான தமிழ்நாட்டின் 38 மாவட்டங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். இம்மாவட்டத்தின் நிர்வாகத் தலைமையிடம் அரியலூர் ஆகும். இந்த மாவட்டம் 1,940.00 ச.கி.மீ பரப்பளவைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. சோழ மன்னர்களில் ஒருவரான, இராஜேந்திர சோழனால் கட்டப்பட்ட கங்கைகொண்ட சோழபுரம், இந்த மாவட்டத்தில் அமைந்துள்ள யுனெஸ்கோ உலகப் பாரம்பரியக் களமாகும். பிரம்மாண்டமான முதுகெலும்பில்லாத உயிரினங்கள் மற்றும் தாடை மீன்களின் பல புதைபடிவங்கள், டைனோசர் முட்டைகள் போன்றவை இங்கு கண்டுபிடிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. புதைபடிவங்களை பாதுகாப்பதற்கு கீழப்பழூரில் ஒரு ஆன்-சைட் அருங்காட்சியகம் அமைக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அரியலூர் மாவட்டத்தில், சிமெண்ட் தொழிற்சாலைகள் அதிகளவில் உள்ளது.வரலாறுசனவரி 1, 2001-இல் பெரம்பலூர் மாவட்டத்தின் சில பகுதிகளைக் கொண்டு உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. ஆனால் மார்ச் 31, 2002இல் அண்ணா திராவிட முன்னேற்றக் கழக ஆட்சியில் பொருளாதாரத்தை காரணம் கூறி அரியலூர் மாவட்டம் மீண்டும் பெரம்பலூர் மாவட்டத்துடன் இணைக்கப்பட்டது. பின்னர் மீண்டும் பெரம்பலூர் மாவட்டத்தை இரண்டாக பிரித்து, தமிழகத்தின் 31-வது மாவட்டமாக அரியலூர் மாவட்டம் நவம்பர் 23, 2007இல் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது.மாவட்ட நிர்வாகம்மாவட்ட வருவாய் நிர்வாகம்இம்மாவட்டத்தில் அரியலூர், உடையார்பாளையம் ஆகிய 2 வருவாய் கோட்டங்களும், அரியலூர், செந்துறை, உடையார்பாளையம், ஆண்டிமடம் ஆகிய 4 வருவாய் வட்டங்களும், 15 உள்வட்டங்களும், 195 வருவாய் கிராமங்களும் கொண்டது.உள்ளாட்சி மற்றும் ஊரக வளர்ச்சி நிர்வாகம்இம்மாவட்டம் 12 உறுப்பினர்கள் கொண்ட ஒரு மாவட்ட ஊரக வளர்ச்சி முகமையும், 6 ஊராட்சி ஒன்றியங்களும், 201 கிராம ஊராட்சிகளும், அரியலூர், ஜெயங்கொண்டம் என இரண்டு நகராட்சிகளும், வரதராஜன்பேட்டை மற்றும் உடையார்பாளையம் என 2 பேரூராட்சிகளும் கொண்டது.மக்கள் வகைப்பாடு2011 ஆம் ஆண்டு இந்திய மக்கள் தொகை கணக்கெடுப்பின் படி, 1,940 சதுர கிலோ மீட்டர் பரப்புள்ள  அரியலூர் மாவட்டத்தின் மொத்த மக்கள் தொகை 754,894 ஆக உள்ளது. அதில் ஆண்கள் 374,703 ஆகவும் பெண்கள் 380,191 ஆகவும் உள்ளனர். பாலின விகிதம் ஆயிரம் ஆண்களுக்கு 1015 பெண்கள் வீதம் உள்ளனர். மக்கள் தொகை அடர்த்தி ஒரு சதுர கிலோ மீட்டரில் 389 பேர் என்ற வீதம் வாழ்கின்றனர். இம்மாநிலத்தின் சராசரி படிப்பறிவு 71.34% ஆகவும், ஆண்களின் படிப்பறிவு 81.23% ஆகவும், பெண்களின் படிப்பறிவு 61.74% ஆகவும் உள்ளது. ஆறு வயதிற்குட்பட்ட குழந்தைகளின் எண்ணிக்கை 81,187 ஆக உள்ளது. மக்கள்தொகை வளர்ச்சி விகிதம் 8.54% ஆக உள்ளது.சமயம்இம்மாவட்டத்தில் இந்து சமயத்தவரின் மக்கள்தொகை 708,397 (93.84 %) ஆகவும், இசுலாமிய மக்கள்தொகை 7,942 (1.05 %)  ஆகவும், கிறித்தவ சமயத்தினரின் மக்கள்தொகை 37,403 (4.95 %) ஆகவும், சீக்கிய மக்கள்தொகை 104 (0.01 %) ஆகவும், பௌத்த சமய மக்கள்தொகை 88 (0.01 %) ஆகவும், சைன சமய மக்கள்தொகை 65 (0.01 %) ஆகவும், பிற சமயத்து மக்கள்தொகை 42 (0.01 %) ஆகவும் மற்றும் சமயம் குறிப்பிடாதவர்கள் மக்கள்தொகை 853 (0.11 %) ஆகவும் உள்ளது.அரசியல்சட்டமன்றம்இம்மாவட்டத்தில் அரியலூர், குன்னம், ஜெயங்கொண்டம் என மூன்று சட்டமன்றத் தொகுதிகளை கொண்டது.மக்களவைஇம்மாவட்டப் பகுதிகள் சிதம்பரம் மக்களவைத் தொகுதியில் உள்ளது.பொருளாதாரம்இங்கு சுண்ணாம்புக் கல் மிகுதியாக கிடைப்பதால் இங்கு தமிழகத்திலேயே அதிகமான எண்ணிக்கையில் சிமெண்ட் ஆலைகள் உள்ளன. இதனால் அரியலூர் சிமெண்ட் சிட்டி (Cement city) என்றும் பரவலாக அழைக்கப்படுகிறது.சிமெண்ட் தவிர நிலக்கரி அதிக அளவில் கிடைக்கிறது. தமிழகத்தில்  நெய்வேலிக்கு அடுத்தபடியாக ஜெயங்கொண்டம் பகுதியில் அதிக அளவில் படிமங்களாகக்  கிடைக்கிறது, இதனையடுத்து தமிழக அரசும் ஜெயங்கொண்டம் அனல் மின்நிலைய திட்டம் என்ற ஒரு திட்டத்தை ஆரம்பித்து அதற்கான பூர்வாங்கப் பணிகளை மேற்கொண்டு வருகின்றது. இது தவிர இம்மாவட்டத்தில் செம்மண் மிகுந்து காணப்படுவதால் முந்திரி அதிக அளவில் பயிரிடப்படுகிறது.புவியியல்இம்மாவட்டத்தின் மூன்று முக்கிய நதிகளாவன‌ : கொள்ளிடம், மருதையாறு, வெள்ளாறு.இம்மாவட்டத்தின் மூன்று முக்கிய நகரங்கள் :  அரியலூர், உடையார்பாளையம், ஜெயங்கொண்டம்.எல்லைகள்வடக்கு வடகிழக்கு மற்றும் கிழக்கில் : கடலூர் மாவட்டம்தெற்கு மற்றும் தென்கிழக்கில் : தஞ்சாவூர் மாவட்டம்தென்மேற்கே : திருச்சிராப்பள்ளி மாவட்டம்மேற்கு மற்றும் வடமேற்கில் : பெரம்பலூர் மாவட்டம்வேளாண்மைஇம்மாவட்டத்தினுடைய பொருளாதாரத்தில் வேளாண்மைத் தொழில், முக்கிய பங்காக தொடர்ந்து இருந்து வருகிறது. இம்மாவட்டத்தின் எழுபது சதவிகித மக்கள் வேளாண்மை அல்லது அது சார்ந்தத் தொழில்களைச் செய்து வருகின்றனர். தமிழ்நாட்டில் ஏழு பெரிய வேளாண் காலநிலை மண்டலங்களாக வகைப்படுத்தப்பட்டுள்ளது. இம்மாவட்டம் மண்டல எண் -V எனக் குறியீடு தரப்பட்டுள்ளது. அதாவது காவிரி டெல்டா மண்டலம். வெப்பநிலை அதிகபட்சமாக 38℃-லிருந்து குறைந்தபட்சமாக 24℃ வரை நிலவி வருகிறது.பரப்பளவுஇம்மாவட்டத்தின் மொத்த பரப்பு, 1,949.31 சதுர கிலோ மீட்டராகும். அதில் மொத்த பயிர் பரப்பானது 1.118 இலட்சம் எக்டேராகும். சராசரி வருடாந்திர மழை அளவானது 954 மி.மீ ஆகும். இந்நிலப்பரப்பில் 45136 எக்டேர் நீர் பாசன வசதிப் பெறுகிறது. காவிரியின் கிளைகள் வழியாக 10389 எக்டேர் திருமானூர், தா. பழூர் மற்றும் ஜெயங்கொண்டம் வட்டாரம் பாசனம் பெறுகின்றது. மீதமுள்ள 66738 எக்டேர், மழை நீரை சார்ந்த மானாவாரி (மழை நீரை மட்டுமே சார்ந்த வேளாண்மை) பகுதிகளாகும்.மண் வகைமைமண்ணின் இயல்பு பெரும்பாலும் களிமண் பாங்காகவும், சிவப்பு நிறமானை மேற்பகுதியும், மஞ்சள் நிறமான அடிப்பகுதியும் காணப்படுகின்றன. இதன் வேதியியல் தன்மைகளான இரும்புச் சத்து அதிகமும், சுண்ணாம்புக் கல்லும் கலந்துள்ள, செந்நிற களிமண் (Ferruginous red loam) உள்ள நிலத்தின் தன்மை காணப்படுகின்றன. மண்ணின் நடு ஆழத்தில், சிறந்த வடிகால் வசதியும், உப்பும், காரத் தன்மையும் இல்லாமல்,  காரகாடித்தன்மைச் சுட்டெண் 6.5-லிருந்து 8 வரை காணப்படுகின்றன. அங்ககத் தன்மைகளான, தழைச்சத்துக்களும், மணிச்சத்துக்களும் அளவு குறைந்து இருக்கின்றன. ஆனால், சாம்பல் சத்தும், சுண்ணாம்பும் அளவு அதிகமாகவே காணப்படுகின்றன. செந்துறை, தா. பழூர், ஆண்டிமடம், ஜெயங்கொண்டம் வட்டாரங்களில் செம்மையான சரளைமண் காணப்படுகிறது. திருமானூரிலும், அரியலூர் வட்டாரங்களிலும், கரிசல் மண் அதிகமாகக் காணப்படுகின்றன.மண் வளத்தை உயிர் உரங்கள் கொண்டு மேம்படுத்துதல், தேசிய வேளாண்மை வளர்ச்சித் திட்டம், ஒருங்கிணைந்த ஊட்டச்சத்து மேலாண்மை, விதை கிராமத் திட்டம், மண்வள அட்டை இயக்கம், தேசிய எண்ணெய் வித்துக்கள் மற்றும் எண்ணெய் பனை இயக்கம், பசுந்தாள் உரம், தேசிய உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பு இயக்கம், தமிழ்நாடு பருத்திச் சாகுபடி இயக்கம், தேசிய நீடித்த வேளாண்மை இயக்கம், ஒருங்கிணைந்த பூச்சி மேலாண்மைத் தொழில் நுட்பங்கள் போன்றத் திட்டங்களுக்கு முக்கியத்துவம் அளிக்கப்படுகிறது.மாநில அரசின் பங்குஅரியலூர் மாவட்டத்தில் பலவகையான பயிர்கள் சாகுபடி செய்யப்படுவதால் வேளாண் சார்ந்த தொழிற்சாலைகளுக்கு மூலப்பொருட்கள் தேவையைப் பூர்த்தி செய்தல், ஊரக மக்கள் தொகைக்கு வேலை வாய்ப்பினை அளித்தல் ஆகியவையே வேளாண்மைத் துறையின் முக்கிய கொள்கையாகவும், கோட்பாடுகளாகவும் இருப்பதாக தெரிவிக்கப்படுகின்றன. வேளாண் வளர்ச்சித் திட்டங்களை செயல்படுத்துதல், அதற்குரியத் தொழில் நுட்பங்களை கண்டறிதல், அதனை பரப்புதல் ஆகிய செயல் திட்டங்களினால் வேளாண்மை துறை செயற்திட்டத்துடன் செயற்படுகிறது.நடுவண் அரசின் பங்குஇருப்பினும், நடுவண் அரசின் திட்டங்களான, பிரதம மந்திரி கிஸான் சம்மான் நிதி திட்டம் வழியே சொந்த கிராமத்தில் வசிக்காத விவசாயிகளின் பட்டியல்களை காணும் போது, அரியலூர் உள்வட்டம், ஏலாக்குறிச்சி உள்வட்டம், கீழப்பழூர் உள்வட்டம், நாகமங்கலம் உள்வட்டம், திருமானூர் உள்வட்டம், செந்துறை உள்வட்டம், பொன்பரப்பி உள்வட்டம்,  ஆர்.எஸ். மாத்தூர் உள்வட்டம், உடையார்பாளையம் உள்வட்டம், ஜெயங்கொண்டம் உள்வட்டம், குண்டவெளி உள்வட்டம், சுத்தமல்லி உள்வட்டம், தா.பழூர் உள்வட்டம், ஆண்டிமடம் உள்வட்டம், குவாகம் உள்வட்டம், பல்வேறு வட்டங்களில் குடிபெயர்வு நடைபெற்றுள்ளதை அறிய இயலும். மேலும், பிரதம மந்திரி கிசான் சம்மான் நிதி திட்டத்தின் கீழ் திருத்தப்பட்ட தகுதியற்றோர் பட்டியல் உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. அரியலூர் உள்வட்டம், ஏலாக்குறிச்சி உள்வட்டம், கீழப்பழூர் உள்வட்டம், நாகமங்கலம் உள்வட்டம்,திருமானூர் உள்வட்டம், செந்துறை உள்வட்டம், பொன்பரப்பி உள்வட்டம்,  ஆர்.எஸ். மாத்தூர் உள்வட்டம், உடையார்பாளையம் உள்வட்டம், ஜெயங்கொண்டம் உள்வட்டம், குண்டவெளி உள்வட்டம், சுத்தமல்லி உள்வட்டம், தா.பழூர் உள்வட்டம், ஆண்டிமடம் உள்வட்டம், குவாகம் உள்வட்டம் ஆகிய அரியலூர் உள்வட்டங்களுக்கான தனித்தனி பட்டியல்கள் உருவாக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன.போக்குவரத்து வசதிகள்தமிழகத்தின் பல பகுதிகளுக்கும் சாலை மூலம் சென்று வர அரியலூர் மற்றும் ஜெயங்கொண்டம் ஆகிய நகரங்களில் பேருந்துகள் இயக்கப்படுகின்றன. மேலும் தொடருந்து மூலம் சென்று வர அரியலூர் தொடருந்து நிலையம் முக்கிய சந்திப்பாக இருக்கிறது. மேலும் அரியலூர் மாவட்டத்தின் தொடருந்து நிலையங்களான சில்லக்குடி, வெள்ளூர், ஒட்டக்கோவில், செந்துறை, ஆர்.எஸ்.மாத்தூர், ஈச்சங்காடு மற்றும் ஈச்சங்காடு (ஹால்ட்) வரை உள்ளது.சுற்றுலா தளங்கள்கங்கைகொண்ட சோழபுரம்சோழர்களின் பெருமரசை நிறுவிய முதலாம் இராஜராஜ சோழன் மகனான இராசேந்திர சோழனால் உருவாக்கப்பட்டு பிற்காலச் சோழர்களின் தலைநகரமாக விளங்கியது. இங்கு இராஜேந்திர சோழனால் கட்டப்பட்ட சிவாலயம் இன்றும் உள்ளது. அதனை ஐக்கிய நாடுகள் அமைப்பு உலக பாரம்பரிய சின்னமாக அறிவித்தது. கங்கைகொண்ட சோழபுரம் கோயில் தஞ்சாவூர் கோயிலை விட சிறியது, ஆனால் சுத்திகரிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது. இவை இரண்டும் தென்னிந்தியாவின், மிகப்பெரிய சிவன் கோயில்களில் ஒன்றாகும். இக்கோயில் தஞ்சாவூரிலிருந்து சுமார் 70 கிலோமீட்டர் (43 மைல்) தொலைவில் உள்ளது.வேட்டக்குடி ‍ கரைவெட்டி பறவைகள் சரணாலயம்தமிழ்நாட்டிலுள்ள மிக முக்கியமான நன்னீர் ஏரிகளுள் ஒன்றாக விளங்குகிறது. மாநிலத்தின் பெரிய ஏரிகளுள் இதுவும் ஒன்று. இந்த ஏரி, மாநிலத்தின் மிக அதிக அளவிலான நீர்ப்பறவைகள் வந்து கூடும் இடமாக பதிவு செய்யப்பட்டிருக்கிறது. இச்சரணாலயத்தில் உள்ள 188 பறவை இனங்களில் 82 இனங்கள் நீர்ப்பறவைகளாகும். அருகிவரும் பட்டைதலை வாத்து, இந்த ஏரியின் முக்கிய வருகையாளர்களுள் ஒன்றாகும்."},{"question":"'Kulungile-ke. Asihlale phansi njengoba usho. Sizoqhubeka. Vele useleleumntanami, isilele indodana yami.''Hlala lapha-ke. Ngizohlala la, ungangithinti bandla Sipho, ngiyakucela.Ungangithinti.' Ahlale abheke le. Kusobala ukuthi usengilahlile ngempelauNokwazi. Kodwa pho eminyakeni emibili nje vo!'Uphumaphi Sipho?' ebuza.'Nokwazi, ngicela uxolo, Sithandwa. Ngizozama ukulubeka udaba lonke, yizengizolubeka ngezinqamulelayo nje ukuze sisheshe singene endlini. Ngasengikhathele ukusebenza ngingayiboni imali. Ngase ngifuna ukusheshangiqedele ilobolo ebese sishada. Ngangifuna sithi singashada ebese siyohlalasobathathu edolobheni, mina nawe nendodana yethu, sibe ngumndenionentokozo.' Ngigwinye amathe.'Kwase kubanjani Sipho?' kubuza yena.'Ngahamba Nokwazi sengiyibonile imali laphaya emsebenzini ukuthiigcinwaphi. Akekho owayesebenza ngalelo langa engahamba ngalo. Ngafikasekumnyama kuthule kuthe cwaka. Ngavula kahle ngokhiye engasengiwebile, ngayithatha yonke leyo mali.''Uqonde ukuthi wawufuna ukungishada ngemali yokwebiwa? Ngemaliyokwebiwa Sipho?''Ayikho into engangizoyenza Nokwazi. Uyihlo nawe uyazi ukuthi wayejahekanjani ukuthi sishade nawe. Nami futhi ngangifuna ukuba usheshe usondeleneno.''Qhubeka Sipho.''Ngayithatha-ke imali ngaphuma. Kwaba yinhlanhla nje ukuthi onogadabangangizwa ngisangena. Inkinga yaba lapho sengiphuma, bangibona.Saqhuma kanye isibhamu ...!''Isibhamu futhi!' egxuma ema laphaya. 'Namanje usakhuluma ngesibhamu!'Uyazwelana yini nomlingiswa onguSipho ngesimo ayesebhekenenaso ngasekugcineni kwale ndaba emfushane?","answer":"Yebo ngiyazwelana ngoba ...Ukuzithola usuhlezi phezu kwethuna akuyona into emnandi,isimo esethusayo nesihlasimulisa umzimba.  Ukungabibikho kwezinto zokuhamba eziningi endaweniyakubo kaNokwazi kwamenza wafika ebusuku, watholaizinkinga endleleni.Cha angizwelani ngoba ...Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Wakhombisa ukungethembeki ngesikhathi entshontsha imalilapho ayesebenza khona. Kwakungafanele avumele ukuthi izinkinga zakhe zimfakeesilingweni sokuntshontsha."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai udang bertahi di kepala\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang sentiasa berhutang. Contohnya, Ghanesh terjebat dalam ketagihan judi dan bagai udang bertahi di kepala akibatnya. "},{"question":"現在のボウリングの原型である「ナインピンズ」を考案したといわれる、ドイツの宗教改革者といえば誰でしょう？","answer":"マルチン・ルター"},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Descascar o abacaxi?\\"","answer":"Significa resolver algo complicado."},{"question":"Unsa ang nasudnon nga hayop sa Pilipinas?","answer":"Ang nasudnon nga prutas sa Pilipinas mao ang Kabaw/Kalabaw."},{"question":"Zadzikisa nyaudzosingwi nezvainoreva:ndee ","answer":"kutarisa"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：美國的「大提頓國家公園」位於哪個州？","answer":"答案：美國的大提頓國家公園（Great Smoky Mountains National Park）位於田納西州和北卡羅來納州的交界處。這是美國最受歡迎的國家公園之一，以其壯麗的山脈景觀和豐富的生態系統而聞名。"},{"question":"現在モハメッド・エルバラダイ (Mohammed Elbaradei) が事務局長を務めている 、1957年に原子力平和利用促進と核拡散防止を目的に設立された国連機関は何でしょう？","answer":"国際原子力機関 (IAEA: International Atomic Energy Agency)です。"},{"question":"Apakah latar belakang Bank Muamalat? ","answer":"Bank Muamalat Malaysia Berhad adalah bank kedua yang menawarkan Perbankan Islam di bawah \\"Akta Perbankan Islam 1983\\" di Malaysia, selepas Bank Islam.Bank Muamalat memulakan operasinya pada 1 Oktober 1999 dan merupakan gabungan aset dan liabiliti bahagian perbankan Islam daripada Bank Bumiputra Malaysia Berhad, Bank of Commerce (M) Berhad dan BBMB Kewangan. Khazanah Nasional Berhad memegang 70% daripada saham syarikat, manakala 30% lagi dipegang oleh Commerce Asset-Holdings Berhad.Pada pertengahan Ogos 2012, diketahui bahawa DRB Hicom memegang 70% saham di dalam bank manakala Khazanah Nasional Berhad memegang selebihnya dan Bank Affin dibenarkan oleh Bank Negara Malaysia untuk berbincang dengan pemilik bank ini mengenai penggabungan bank ini dengan Bank Affin."},{"question":"Wasu launika ne a jikin tutar Najeriya?","answer":"Launikan jikin tutar Najeriya sune kore da fari. Wanda aka jerasu kamar haka: \\"kore, fari, kore\\"."},{"question":"Ahlaki davranış ne demek?","answer":"AHLÂKÎ DAVRANIŞ VE BİLGİ1Ahlâkın konusu insan davranışlarıdır. Ancak insanın her davranışı değil, iradeli, bilinçli, iyi veya kötü olarak nitelendirilebilecek, toplum içinde uyması gereken kurallara uygun davranışlarıdır."},{"question":"inona no teny mifanohitra amin'ny hoe fitiavana?","answer":"ny teny mifanohitra amin'ny hoe fitiavana dia fankahalana"},{"question":"Londres mooy péeyu man réew ?","answer":"Londres mooy péeyu réewum Royaume-Uni"},{"question":"கேள்வி: முகப்பருவை அகற்றுவது எப்படி?","answer":"பதில் :முகப்பருவை அகற்ற வழிமுறைகள் :முகப்பரு வல்காரிஸ் அல்லது முகப்பரு என்பது முகம், மார்பு மற்றும் முதுகில் உள்ள மயிர்க்கால்களில் ஏற்படும் ஒரு நோயாகும், இது பருவமடையும் போது கிட்டத்தட்ட அனைத்து இளம் வயதினரையும் பாதிக்கும். பாக்டீரியாக்கள் இதை ஏற்படுத்தாது, ஆனால் பாக்டீரியாக்கள் அவற்றின் வளர்ச்சியில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கின்றன. முகப்பரு வல்காரிஸ் என்பது வழக்கமான டீனேஜ் முகப்பரு ஆகும், இது மூன்று வகையான புண்களால் வகைப்படுத்தப்படுகிறது:காமெடோ அல்லது கரும்புள்ளி அழற்சி பருப்புஅழற்சி பருப்புகொப்புளம் மற்றும் பருமுகப்பரு தோலில் தோன்றும்:கரும்புள்ளிகள் அல்லது வெண்புள்ளிகள்பருக்கள்கொப்புளங்கள்நீர்க்கட்டிகள்அறிகுறிகள்உடலில் கிட்டத்தட்ட எல்லா இடங்களிலும் முகப்பருவை அடையாளம் காணலாம். இது பெரும்பாலும் முகம், முதுகு, கழுத்து, மார்பு மற்றும் தோள்களில் நிகழ்கிறது. உங்களுக்கு ஏற்கனவே முகப்பரு இருந்தால், வெள்ளை அல்லது கருப்பு மாத்திரைகளை நீங்கள் கவனிக்கத் தொடங்குவீர்கள். பிளாக்ஹெட்ஸ் மற்றும் ஒயிட்ஹெட்ஸ் ஆகியவை எரித்மாவாக அங்கீகரிக்கப்படுகின்றன. வளிமண்டலத்தில் உள்ள ஆக்ஸிஜன் காரணமாக, கரும்புள்ளிகள் தோலின் மேற்பரப்பில் திறக்கப்படுகின்றன. ஒயிட்ஹெட்ஸ் தோலின் மேற்பரப்பின் கீழ் மூடப்பட்டிருக்கும், இது ஒரு வெள்ளை தோற்றத்தை அளிக்கிறது.அழற்சி முகப்பரு மற்றும் கரும்புள்ளிகள் முகப்பருவில் காணப்படும் மிகவும் பொதுவான புண்கள் என்றாலும், அந்த சில வகைகளும் ஏற்படலாம். அழற்சி புண்கள் தோலில் வடுக்கள் ஏற்படுவதற்கான வாய்ப்புகள் அதிகம். இதில் அடங்கும்:பருக்கள்கொப்புளங்கள்முடிச்சுகள்நீர்க்கட்டிகள்மருத்துவர் ஆலோசனைமுகப்பரு வகைகள்பிளாக்ஹெட்ஸ்அதிகப்படியான எண்ணெய் மற்றும் இறந்த செல்களை ஏற்றும் தோலில் திறந்த புடைப்புகள். அவை புடைப்பில் அழுக்கு குவிந்திருப்பதைப் போல தோற்றமளிக்கின்றன, ஆனால் அத்தியாவசிய பொருட்களின் குறைபாடு, அடைபட்ட நுண்ணறையிலிருந்து பிரதிபலிக்கும் அசாதாரண ஒளியால் ஏற்படுகிறது.வைட்ஹெட்ஸ்எண்ணெய் மற்றும் இறந்த சருமத்தால் மூடப்பட்டிருக்கும் புடைப்புகள்.பருக்கள்சிறிய சிவப்பு அல்லது இளஞ்சிவப்பு புடைப்புகள் வீக்கமடைகின்றன.கொப்புளங்கள்சீழ் கொண்டிருக்கும் பருக்கள். அவை சிவப்பு வளையங்களால் சூழப்பட்ட வெண்புள்ளிகள் போல இருக்கும். அவை கீறப்பட்டால் சில தீவிர எதிர்வினைகளை ஏற்படுத்தும்.பூஞ்சை முகப்பருமயிர்க்கால்களில் அதிகப்படியான ஈஸ்ட் உருவாகும்போது இந்த வகை ஏற்படுகிறது. இது அரிப்பு மற்றும் வீக்கமாக மாறும்.முடிச்சுகள்இது தோலின் ஆழத்தில் இருக்கும் ஒரு திடமான பரு. அவை பெரியவை மற்றும் மிகவும் வேதனையானவை.நீர்க்கட்டிகள்சீழ் நிறைந்த பருக்கள் உங்கள் தோலில் தழும்புகளை ஏற்படுத்தும்.காரணங்கள்உங்கள் சருமத்தின் துளைகள் எண்ணெய், இறந்த செல்கள் அல்லது பாக்டீரியாவால் தடுக்கப்படும் போதெல்லாம் முகப்பரு ஏற்படுகிறது. உங்கள் தோலின் ஒவ்வொரு துளையும் உண்மையில் ஒரு நுண்ணறை திறப்பு ஆகும். நீர்க்கட்டி முடி மற்றும் ஒரு செபாசியஸ் (எண்ணெய்) சுரப்பியைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. எண்ணெய் சுரப்பி உங்கள் முடி வழியாகவும், உங்கள் துளை வழியாகவும், உங்கள் தோல் வழியாகவும் செல்லும் செபம் (எண்ணெய்) வெளியிடுகிறது. சருமம் உங்கள் சருமத்தை மென்மையாகவும் நீரேற்றமாகவும் வைத்திருக்க உதவுகிறது.இந்த உயவு செயல்பாட்டில் ஒன்று அல்லது அதற்கு மேற்பட்ட பிரச்சினைகள் முகப்பருவை பாதிக்கலாம். இது எப்போது நிகழலாம்:உங்கள் நுண்குமிழிகளால் அதிகப்படியான எண்ணெய்கள் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படுகின்றனஉங்கள் துளைகளில் இறந்த சரும செல்கள் உருவாகின்றனஉங்கள் துளைகளில் பாக்டீரியாவை உருவாக்குங்கள்இந்த முக்கிய பிரச்சினைகள் குழாய்களின் வளர்ச்சிக்கு பங்களிக்கின்றன. அடைபட்ட துளையில் பாக்டீரியா பெருகும் போது அன்னாசி தோன்றும், அதே போல் எண்ணெய் வெளியேற முடியாது.முகப்பருவை ஏற்படுத்தும் பிற தூண்டுதல்கள்:க்ரீஸ் அழகுசாதனப் பொருட்கள்ஹார்மோன் மாற்றங்கள்உணர்ச்சி மன அழுத்தம்மாதவிடாய்ஆபத்து காரணிகள்சில கட்டுக்கதைகள் முகப்பரு உருவாவதற்கு பங்களிக்கின்றன. சாக்லேட் அல்லது சாக்லேட் போன்ற உணவுகளை பலர் தவறாகப் பயன்படுத்துகின்றனர் French பொரியல் முகப்பருவுக்கு பங்களிக்கும். இந்த கூற்றுகளுக்கு மிகவும் சிறிய குறிப்பிட்ட ஆதரவு உள்ளது. உருவாக்கப்பட்ட சில ஆபத்து காரணிகள் உள்ளன:பருவமடைதல் அல்லது கர்ப்பம் காரணமாக ஏற்படும் ஹார்மோன் மாற்றங்கள்கருத்தடை மாத்திரைகள் அல்லது கார்டிகோஸ்டீராய்டுகள் அடங்கிய மருந்துஅதிக அளவு கார்போஹைட்ரேட் மற்றும் சர்க்கரை கொண்ட ரொட்டி மற்றும் சிப்ஸ் போன்ற உயர் உணவுசிகிச்சைவீட்டு பராமரிப்பு சிகிச்சை:முகப்பரு சிகிச்சையில் உதவும் சில சுகாதார நடவடிக்கைகள்:அதிகப்படியான அழுக்கு மற்றும் எண்ணெய்களை அகற்ற, தினமும் லேசான சோப்புடன் உங்கள் சருமத்தை சுத்தம் செய்யவும்.உங்கள் தலைமுடியை உங்கள் முகத்திற்கு வெளியே வைக்க தவறாமல் துவைக்கவும்திரவ அல்லது \\"நான்-காமெடோஜெனிக்\\" என்று பெயரிடப்பட்ட ஒப்பனையைப் பயன்படுத்தவும் (துளை-அடைப்பு அல்ல)பாக்டீரியா மற்றும் அடைபட்ட துளைகளை பரப்பும் பருக்களை கசக்கவோ எடுக்கவோ வேண்டாம்.தொப்பிகள் அல்லது இறுக்கமான தலையணிகளை அணிய வேண்டாம்உங்கள் முகத்தைத் தொடாதே"},{"question":"Aiza no misy an'i Jordana mifandray amin'ny fanjakan'i Palestina?","answer":"ny misy an'i Jordana mifandray amin'ny fanjakan'i Palestina dia ny ao Atsinanana"},{"question":"问题：铅笔刀的使用是否需要额外的技巧？","answer":"答案：基本的铅笔刀使用不需要额外的技巧，但熟练的使用者可以通过掌握适当的旋转和施加力度来获得更好的削铅笔效果。"},{"question":"السؤال: من من أمهات المؤمنين كانت من سلالة الأنبياء هارون وموسى عليهما السلام؟","answer":"الإجابة: صفية بنت حيي بن أخطب"},{"question":"Ki laa ti waa ṣeyi si, awọn Fulani tun pa agbẹ meji n’Igangan","answer":"O kere tan, eeyan meji lo ku, tọpọ eeyan si fara pa nigba ti awọn Fulani agbegbe Oke-Ogun, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, tun  kọ lu awọn agbẹ niluu Igangan, nirọlẹ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee.ALAROYE gbọ pe niṣe lawọn Fulani to filu Igangan ṣebugbe ọhun lọọ da awọn agbẹ to n ti inu oko wọn bọ lọna, ti wọn si pa meji ninu wọn loju-ẹsẹ.Iroyin awọn iṣẹlẹ to ni i ṣe pẹlu iroyin ìṣekúpani, ijinigbe ati ìkọlù lo n ti agbegbe Oke-Ogun jade lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii, paapaa lawọn ilu bii Igboọra, Igangan, Iganna, Idere, Ayetẹ ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ. Awọn Fulani lawọn ara agbegbe naa si maa n tọka si gẹgẹ bii afurasi ọdaran lọpọlọpọ igba ti awọn iṣẹlẹ ibanujẹ bẹẹ ba waye.Eyi la gbọ pe o mu ki akinkanju ọmọ Yoruba nni, Oloye Sunday Adeyẹmọ ti gbogbo eeeyan mọ si Sunday Igboho, lọọ ṣabẹwo si Seriki Fulani ti Igangan, Ọgbẹni Saliu Kadiri, lati ba awọn eeyan ẹ sọrọ pe ki wọn dẹ́kun ijinigbe ati pipa ti wọn n pa awọn Yoruba nilẹ baba wọn.Gẹgẹ bi oludari ẹgbẹ to n ja fun idagbasoke ilẹ Igangan, Ọladiran Ọladokun, ṣe fidi ẹ mulẹ, o ni “Sunday Igboho wa si Igangan lati dẹkun awọn iwa ọdaran ti awọn Fulani maa n hu. O kọkọ lọ si ọja Kaara, nitori inu ọja yẹn lawọn Fulani wọnyẹn ti saaba maa n ṣe awọn laabi wọn. Nitori ẹ lawọn kan ṣe n sọ pe ki ijọba ti ọja yẹn pa.“Lẹyin naa lo lọ si aafin Seriki Fulani, to si sọ fun un pe oun ko gbọdọ gbọ pe awọn Fulani tun pa Yoruba nibi kankan mọ, nitori naa, ko yaa kilọ fun awọn eeyan ẹ daadaa.”Igbesẹ ti Sunday Igboho gbe yii la gbọ pe awọn Fulani kan ninu ilu naa ka si iwa arifin si ọba wọn, ti wọn fi lọọ kọ lu awọn agbẹ to n lọ sile jẹẹjẹ wọn nirọlẹ ọjọ Ẹti ọhun, ti wọn si pa meji ninu wọn da sọna oko.Nigba ti akọroyin wa pe Ọgbẹni Dapọ Salami ti i ṣe oludamọran fun Sunday Igboho lori ẹrọ ibanisọrọ, ọkunrin naa ṣalaye pe ‘‘Loootọ l’Alayé (Igboho) lọ si Igangan lati lọọ ba Seriki Fulani ibẹ sọrọ. Ko si si ọrọ pupọ naa nibẹ ju ikilọ lọ.“Wọn kilọ fun Seriki Fulani lati ba awọn eeyan ẹ sọrọ, pe dùǹdú awọn Fulani ti n láta ju nilẹ Yoruba. Bawo lawọn ajeji ṣe le maa ji wa gbe, ti wọn yoo maa pa wa nilẹ baba wa. Wọn ni ki Seriki kilọ fawọn eeyan ẹ ki wọn so ewé agbéjẹ́ẹ́ mọ́wọ́.“Lẹyin ti wọn (Igboho) kuro n’Igangan tan la gbọ pe awọn Fulani ko ibọn ati ada jade, ti wọn si pa ọmọ Yoruba meji. Njẹ o yẹ ki awọn Fulani le maa gbe ibọn ati ada rin bo ṣe wu wọn nigba ti ko si anfaani iru ẹ fun awa ta a nìlú nitori pe ofin orileede yii ko faaye ẹ silẹ?’’"},{"question":"世界の薬品化学メーカーで、「チバガイギー」はスイスの会社ですが、「バイエル」はどこの国の会社でしょう？","answer":"ドイツです。"},{"question":"సెంట్రియోల్ యొక్క బండిచక్రం నిర్మాణంపై వ్యాఖ్యానించండి.","answer":"సెంట్రోసోమ్ అనే కణాంగము సాధారణంగా సెంట్రియోల్లు అనే రెండు స్థూపాకార నిర్మాణాలను చూపిస్తుంది. ఇవి రూపరహిత పెరిసెంట్రియోలార్ పదార్థాలతో ఆవరించి ఉంటాయి. సెంట్రోసోమ్లోని సెంట్రియోల్లు ఒకదానికి మరొకటి లంబంగా అమర్చబడి ప్రతిదానిలో బండి చక్రంలాంటి నిర్మాణాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటుంది. సెంట్రియోల్లో తొమ్మిది సమదూరంకల ట్యూబ్యులిన్చే నిర్మించబడిన పరిధీయ పోచలు ఉంటాయి. ప్రతి పరిధీయ పోచలో 3 సూక్ష్మ నాళికలు ఉంటాయి. ప్రక్క ప్రక్కనున్న పరిధీయ పోచలు త్రికాలు కలుపబడి ఉంటాయి. సెంట్రియోల్ కేంద్రభాగము ప్రోటీను పదార్థం నిర్మితమై హబ్ గా పిలవబడుతుంది. హబ్ భాగము ప్రోటీనాయుతమైన వ్యాసార్ధ పోచలతో పరిధీయంగా ఉన్న ట్రిప్లెట్ పోచలకు కలపబడి ఉంటుంది. సెంట్రియోల్లు శైలికలు లేదా కశాభాలను, కండెపోగులను ఉత్పత్తి చేసే ఆధారకణికలుగా పనిచేస్తాయి. కణవిభజన సమయంలో జంతుకణాలు కండెపోగుల నుంచి కండె పరికరమును ఉత్పత్తి చేస్తాయి."},{"question":"බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ ගල් අඟුරු ආකර බහුල ප්‍රදේශ මොනවාද?","answer":"බ්‍රිතාන්‍යයේ පහත ප්‍රදේශ වල ගල් අඟුරු බහුලව ඇත.- දකුණු වේල්ස්- යෝක්ෂයර්- ලැන්කැෂයර්"},{"question":"கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள கேள்விக்குச் சரியான பதிலளி:முகலாயர் கால ஓவிய கலைக்கு வித்திட்டவர் யார்?அ) அக்பர்ஆ) ஜகாங்கீர்இ) ஹூமாயூன் ஈ) ஷாஜகான்","answer":"விடை: இ) ஹூமாயூன். முகலாய ஓவியம் என்பது, பதினாராம் நூற்றாண்டு தொடக்கம், பத்தொன்பதாம் நூற்றாண்டு வரையில் இந்தியாவில் இருந்த முகலாயப் பேரரசுக் காலத்தில் உருவாகி வளர்ந்த ஒரு ஓவியப் பாணியாகும். இரண்டாவது முகலாயப் பேரரசனான ஹுமாயூன், தப்ரீசில் இருந்தபோது, அவருக்குப் பாரசீக ஓவியங்கள் அறிமுகமானது. ஹுமாயூன் இந்தியா திரும்பியபோது, பாரசீக ஓவியப் பாணியில் திறமை பெற்ற இரண்டு ஓவியர்களையும் அழைத்து வந்தார். இவர்கள் மூலம் இந்தியாவுக்கு அறிமுகமான இப் பாணி, பின்னர் உள்ளூர்ப் பாணிகளுடனும் கலந்து முகலாயப் பாணி எனப்பட்ட புதிய பாணியொன்றை உருவாக்கியது."},{"question":"Rujuk petikan di bawah dan kemudian jawab soalan selepas itu dalam bahasa yang sama seperti petikan:  Petikan: Dilahirkan di Tardebigge, Worcestershire, John Vane adalah salah satu daripada tiga anak dan dibesarkan di pinggir bandar Birmingham. Bapanya, Maurice Vane, ialah anak imigran Yahudi Rusia dan ibunya, Frances Vane, berasal dari keluarga petani Worcestershire. Beliau belajar di sekolah negeri tempatan dari usia 5 tahun, sebelum berpindah ke Sekolah King Edward di Edgbaston, Birmingham. Minat beliau dalam kimia menjadi inspirasi untuk mengkaji subjek tersebut di Universiti Birmingham pada tahun 1944.  Soalan: Siapakah bapa beliau?","answer":"Maurice Vane"},{"question":"महाभारताचे युद्ध कोणत्या कालखंडात झाले?उत्तर - ","answer":"द्वापर युग."},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:Duñu ko mébét mukk ngir la seen yoxo ya jëf [ci lu bon]. Yàlla ku xam la way-tooñ ña.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Du ñu ko mébat mukk ngìr la séen yoxo ya jëf [ci lu bon]. Yàlla ku xàm la waytooñ ña."},{"question":"தமிழ்மொழி எவற்றை அறிந்து வளரும் என்று பாரதியார் கூறுகிறார்?","answer":"தமிழ்மொழி வானம் வரை உள்ளடங்கியுள்ள எல்லாப் பொருண்மைகளையும் அறிந்து மேன்மேலும் வளரும் என்று பாரதியார் கூறுகிறார்."},{"question":"2023 වන විට නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගලාභීන් වැඩිම පිරිසක් බිහිවී ඇති රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"2023 වන විට නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගලාභීන් වැඩිම පිරිසක් බිහිවී ඇති රට වන්නේ ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපදයයි. 2023 වන විට ඇමරිකා එක්සත් ජනපද​යේ නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගලාභීන් 403ක් ඇ​ත. දෙවන ස්ථානය ත්‍යාගලාභීන් 137ක් සිටින එක්සත් රාජධානිය හිමි කර ගනී."},{"question":"නොවැම්බර් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"නොවැම්බර් යනු ග්‍රෙගරි දින දසුන අනුව අවුරුද්දේ එකොළොස්වන මාසයයි."},{"question":"1 – 10, 11 – 20 పౌనఃపున్య విభాజన తరగతులలో 1-10 తరగతి ఎగువ హద్దు ఎంత ?","answer":"1-10 తరగతి ఎగువ హద్దు = 10.5"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පිහිටි එකම තෙත්බිම් ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පිහිටි එකම තෙත්බිම් ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානය පොලොන්නරුවේ පිහි​ටි ජලගැලුම් නිම්න ජාතික වනෝද්‍යානයයි."},{"question":"Inty misy fehezanteny:\\"Mody ny mpianatra.\\"Omeo ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay mandrafitra io fehezanteny io.","answer":"Indro ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay mandrafitra io fehezanteny io:Mody: Enti-milazany mpianatra: Lazaina"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini?  Apa yang hanya anjing ada tetapi binatang lain tiada?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah anak anjing. "},{"question":"Мотивация (түрткү) бере турган сөздөр менен бөлүш !","answer":"Жашоо - театрда ойнолгон пьеса сыяктуу. Маанилүүсү анын канчалык узакка созулгандыгы эмес, канчалык мыкты деңгээлде ойнолгондугу."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'nyawa-nyawa ikan'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud hampir mati. Contoh ayat: Burung itu nyawa-nyawa ikan semasa ditemui Ali."},{"question":"Unsay bisaya sa light","answer":"Ang bisaya sa light kay suga"},{"question":"Bella Awa Gassama","answer":"Bella Awa Gassama jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Gámbíà.Gassama ní ìbátan pẹ̀lú oníìdájọ́ bọ́ọ̀lù àfẹsẹ̀gbá tí n ṣe Bakary \\"Papa\\" Gassama. Ó parí ẹ̀kọ́ girama rẹ̀ ní ilé-ìwé Marina International School ní ọdún 2004. Ó kó àkọ́kọ́ ipa rẹ̀ nínu fíìmù tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Arrou ní ọdún 2004 yìí kan náà. Wọ́n wo fíìmù náà níbi ayẹyẹ Pan-African Film Festival kan tí ó wáyé ní ìlú Los Angeles, Gassama náà sì tún rí yíyàn fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ 2nd Africa Movie Academy Awards. Wọ́n tún yàán fún òṣèré ilẹ̀ Gámbíà tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ Vinasha Film Festival. Ní ọdún 2008 bákan náà, Gassama tún kó àkọ́kọ́ ipa rẹ̀ nínu fíìmù ilẹ̀ Nàìjíríà tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ My Gambian Holiday pẹ̀lú àjọṣepọ̀ Desmond Elliot àti Oge Okoye. Ó tún kó ipa amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ nínu fíìmù Mirror Boy ti ọdún 2011, ní àjọṣepọ̀ pẹ̀lú Fatima Jabbe àti Genevieve Nnaji. Ní ọdún 2012, Gassama parí ìkẹ́kọ̀ọ́ láti ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gígaTask Crown College.Gassama kópa nínu eré Sidy Diallo kan ti ọdún 2014 tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ The Soul. Wọ́n yàán fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ Zulu African Film Academy Awards. Ó kópa nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù ti ọdún 2019 kan tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ jẹ́ Nakala. Ní Oṣù kọkànlá Ọdún 2019, Gassama ṣe ìgbéyàwó pẹ̀lú Pa Lie Low"},{"question":"కిరణజన్య సంయోగక్రియకు అవసరమైన ముఖ్య కారకాలుA) కాంతి, కార్బన్ డై ఆక్సైడ్, పత్రహరితం, ఉష్ణోగ్రతB) కాంతి, నీరు, పత్రహరితం, ఉష్ణోగ్రతC) కాంతి, ఉష్ణోగ్రత, పత్రహరితం, కార్బన్ డై ఆక్సైడ్D) కాంతి, నీరు, పత్రహరితం, కార్బన్ డై ఆక్సైడ్","answer":"D) కాంతి, నీరు, పత్రహరితం, కార్బన్ డై ఆక్సైడ్"},{"question":"溫哥華人口有多少？","answer":"根據2021年加拿大統計局人口普查，溫哥華市人口有66.2萬人，而大溫哥華地區的人口為264萬。"},{"question":"Thực hiện bài tập: Em hãy viết đoạn văn phát biểu cảm nghĩ về một trong các bài thơ có yếu tố tự sự, miêu tả đã học (“Đêm nay Bác không ngủ”, “Lượm”, “Gấu con chân vòng kiềng”).","answer":"Bài thơ Lượm của Tố Hữu đã để lại ấn tượng sâu đậm trong lòng người đọc hình ảnh một em bé thiếu nhi hi sinh vì nhiệm vụ trong cuộc kháng chiến chống thực dân Pháp. Nội dung chính của bài thơ tự sự – trữ tình kể về cuộc đời ngắn ngủi nhưng rất anh dũng của chú bé liên lạc, hồn nhiên, nhí nhảnh, yêu đời, dũng cảm đã ngã xuống để bảo vệ sự bình yên cho chính mảnh đất quê hương mình. Về nghệ thuật, Tố Hữu chủ yếu sử dụng sử dụng từ láy, lối thơ tự sự, điệp từ, so sánh,… góp phần thể hiện hình ảnh Lượm – một em bé liên lạc hồn nhiên, vui tươi say mê tham gia công tác kháng chiến thật đáng mến, đáng yêu. Lượm xuất hiện với dáng người nhỏ nhắn, mang theo chiếc xắc xinh xinh vui sướng đi làm nhiệm vụ. Ngoại hình với đôi má ửng đỏ bồ quẩn, dáng đi thoăn thoắt, cái đầu nghênh nghênh, miệng huýt sáo vang,… đều tô đạm nét hồn nhiên ở chú bé. Thế nhưng giữa cánh đồng lúa chín, em nằm đó, máu chảy đỏ như hoàng hôn. Lượm đã hi sinh trên đường làm nhiệm vụ nhưng hình ảnh của em còn mãi với quê hương, đất nước và trong lòng mọi người. Bằng lời thơ bốn chữ giản dị, tác giả đã thể hiện thành công lớp người thiếu niên nhỏ tuổi yêu nước trong thời kì kháng chiến."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السورة التي يجب قراءتها في كل ركعة في الصلاة؟","answer":"الإجابة: الفاتحة"},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny 07 febroary 2009?","answer":"Ny 07 febroary 2009 dia nanao diabe nankany amin’ny Lapa-mpanjakana Ambohitsorohitra ny mpomba ny TGV. Nitifitra niaro ny Lapa ny mpiambina ka nahafaty olon-tsotra maro. Nierendoza kosa ny mpitarika ny fihetsiketsehana… Nitsangana ny Fahefana Avon’ny Tetezamita (FAT) na “Haute Autorité de la Transition” notarihan’i Andry Rajoelina. "},{"question":"Qual é o país mais populoso do mundo?","answer":"China. Em 2020, tinha 1.439.323.776 de habitantes, de acordo com a Organização das Nações Unidas (ONU)."},{"question":"Gbogbo Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, lawọn oṣiṣẹ yoo fi maa wọṣo adirẹ nipinlẹ Ọṣun bayii","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Alhaji Adegboyega Oyetọla, ti kede pe ṣiṣẹ aṣọ adirẹ lọpọ yanturu ati tita rẹ yoo bẹrẹ nipinlẹ naa bayii.Bakan naa ni gomina pọn ọn ni dandan fun gbogbo awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba lati maa wọ aṣọ adirẹ lẹẹkan laarin ọsẹ, iyẹn Ojọbọ, eyi to pe orukọ rẹ ni “Ọjọ Adirẹ Ọṣun”Lasiko to n ṣe ifilọlẹ ṣiṣe adirẹ naa nibi  ayẹyẹ ‘Ọsẹ Oge’ to wa lati ṣagbelarugẹ lilo aṣọ adirẹ eleyii ti ileeṣẹ aṣa atibudo isẹmbaye l’Ọṣun pẹlu ajọṣepọ Musty Great Development and Alexandria Jones Cultures, ni USA, ṣe ni Oyetọla ti ni ilu aro ti wọn mọ Oṣogbo ti i ṣe olu ilu ipinlẹ Ọṣun mọ gbọdọ di gbajugbaja.O ni igbesẹ naa wa lati ran awọn eeyan leti ọkan lara awọn nnkan to jẹ ami idanimọ ipinlẹ Ọṣun, paapaa, lati ṣi oju Adirẹ Ẹlẹkọ si gbogbo agbaye.Oyetọla, ẹni ti akọwe ijọba rẹ, Ọmọọba Wọle Oyebamiji, ṣoju fun ṣalaye pe igbelarugẹ awọn aṣa ti Eledua fi jinnku ipinlẹ Ọṣun jẹ oun logun, nitori yoo tun mu ki eto ọrọ-aje burẹkẹ si i.O ni yoo tun jẹ orisun ipese iṣẹ fun ogunlọgọ awọn olugbe ipinlẹ Ọṣun, bẹẹ ni awọn oniṣowo atawọn to fẹran aṣa kaakiri orileede yii ati loke-okun yoo lo anfaani naa lati ṣabẹwo sibi.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, “A ti bẹrẹ atunṣe oniruuru awọn ibudo aṣa atawọn nnkan isẹmbaye ti a ni kaakiri Ọṣun, bẹẹ nijọba apapọ atawọn abaniṣiṣẹ ti n dowo pọ pẹlu wa lati sọ awọn ibudo yẹn di apewaawo lagbaaye.“Lati sọ ipinlẹ Ọṣun di aṣaaju ninu aṣa Yoruba, gbogbo Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, lọsọọsẹ ti di ọjọ ti awọn oṣiṣẹ ijọba yoo maa wọ aṣọ adirẹ bayii, nitori a gbọdọ fi apẹẹrẹ rere lelẹ.“Ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹjọ, ọdun yii, ni aṣẹ yii yoo bẹrẹ si i fẹsẹ mulẹ. Mo rọ gbogbo awọn eeyan ipinlẹ yii lati lo anfaani yii fun idagbasoke iṣẹ ti wọn n ṣe”Gbogbo awọn lookọ-lookọ nidii igbelarugẹ ọrọ aṣa nilẹ yii bii oludasilẹ iwe iroyin Alaroye, Alagba Alao Adedayọ, Iyaafin Nikẹ Okundaye, Oloye Jimoh Buraimon ati Oloye Muraina Oyelami ni wọn rọ awọn eeyan ipinlẹ Ọṣun lati ṣagbelarugẹ igbesẹ ijọba naa."},{"question":"把以下的古文成现代汉字：匡衡勤学而烛，邻居有烛而不逮，衡乃穿壁引其光，发书映光而读之。邑人大姓文不识，家富多书，衡乃与其佣作而不求偿。主人怪问衡，衡曰：“愿得主人书遍读之。”主人感叹，资给以书，遂成大学。","answer":"匡衡很勤学，但没有蜡烛，邻居有蜡烛却照不到（他的房间）。匡衡于是就在墙上打了一个洞用来引进烛光，用书映着光来读书。当地有一大户人家叫文不识，家里十分富有，书又很多，匡衡就给他家作雇工，辛苦劳动而不要求报酬，主人感到奇怪，就问匡衡，匡衡回答说：“希望可以读遍主人的书。”主人感叹，就把书借给他，（匡衡）终于成了大学问家。"},{"question":"අක්කරයට පර්චස් කීයද?","answer":"අක්කරයට පර්චස් 160 ක් ඇත "},{"question":"كيف يمكنني حماية نفسي إذا كنت في منطقة متأثرة؟","answer":"تتمثل مبادئ الحماية الثلاثة في \\"الاحتماء والبقاء في الداخل والاستماع\\" لتلقي التعليمات.وعليك بالحرص دوماً على اتباع إرشادات السلامة الصادرة عن السلطات المحلية والوطنية والبقاء على اتصال لتلقي آخر المعلومات. إذا طُلب منك البقاء في الداخل فافعل ذلك، لأن الجدران والسقف يمكن أن توفر الحماية من التسرب الإشعاعي في الخارج. وعند الإمكان، امكث في غرفة بلا نوافذ أو أبواب خارجية وأغلق النوافذ وأنظمة التهوية داخل المنزل (أجهزة التكييف أو التدفئة)."},{"question":"Lập dan ý để kể lại truyền thuyết “Thánh Gióng”.","answer":"+ Truyền thuyết Thánh Gióng kể lại cuộc chiến đấu một mình của Gióng chiến thắng quân thù.+ Truyện có những sự kiện và nhân vật chính: Câu chuyện kể về nhân vật chính Thánh Gióng: Sự ra đời kì lạ của Thánh Gióng. Thánh Gióng biết nói và đòi đi đánh giặc. Gióng lớn nhanh như thổi, vươn vai mặc áo giáo sắt, cưỡi ngựa sắt, cầm roi sắt. Thánh Gióng dẹp tan quân giặc. Sau đó, người cùng với ngựa bay lên trời.+ Diễn biến của câu chuyện (mở đầu, phát triển, kết thúc): Mở đầu: Sự ra đời kì lạ của Thánh Gióng. Phát triển: Thánh Gióng biết nói và đòi đi đánh giặc. → Gióng lớn nhanh như thổi, vươn vai mặc áo giáo sắt, cưỡi ngựa sắt, cầm roi sắt. → Thánh Gióng dẹp tan quân giặc. Kết thúc: Thánh Gióng cùng với ngựa sắt bay lên trời.+ Có thể thêm, bớt những chi tiết, hình ảnh,… của truyện như: Cảnh dân làng nô nức cùng nhau gom góp gạo; Cảnh Thánh Gióng ăn nhiều như thế nào? Miêu tả kĩ hơn hình ảnh Thánh Gióng khi mặc áo giáp; Thêm cảnh Thánh Gióng tạm biệt gia đình và làng;..."},{"question":"Vraag: Hoe heet het lied van de band Bots dat begint met de regel \\"Wat zullen we drinken\\"","answer":"Antwoord: Zeven dagen lang"},{"question":"\\"ඇනබාගෙන \\" අරුත පැහැදිලි කරන්න.","answer":"උක්කුටිකයෙන් සිටීම,ඇනතියාගෙන හිඳීම.දනිස් දෙක උඩට මුහුණ හිටින විදිහට ඉදගෙන ඉන්නවටත් කියනවා  ඇනබාගෙන ඉන්නවා කියලා"},{"question":"வினா: கண்ணாடியை கரைக்கும் அமிலம்?","answer":"விடை: ஹைட்ரோகுளோரிக் அமிலம்"},{"question":"පහත ප්‍රස්තාව පිරුළේ අර්ථය කුමක්ද ? \\"අනුන්ගේ නම් හිසරදෙයත් හොදයි කීවා සේ\\"","answer":"අනුන්ගෙන් ලැබෙන ඕනෑම දෙයක් ඉතා ඉහළින් පිළිගැනීම"},{"question":"Zadzisa dimikara rinotevera:Anokotsira nebadza mumawoko","answer":"aneusimbe"},{"question":"පැරණි කෘෂිකාර්මික ජනවහරේදී \\" හුම්මාර පෙට්ටිය \\" යනුවෙන් හඳුන්වන්නේ කුමක්ද ?","answer":"පැරණි කෘෂිකාර්මික ජනවහරේදී \\" හුම්මාර පෙට්ටිය \\" යනු කමතට ආහාර ගෙනයන පෙට්ටිය"},{"question":"Deprem bolgesinde barajlar ne durumda?","answer":"Tarım ve Orman Bakanlığı yaptığı tüm açıklamalarda barajların kontrol edildiğini ve herhangi bir sorunun olmadığını açıkladı. Depremin yaşandığı bölgelerdeki barajların güvenli olduğunu belirten İnşaat ve Çevre Yüksek Mühendis Su Uzmanı Hasan Akyar'a göre 30 metrenin altındaki göletlere dikkat etmek gerekiyor."},{"question":"Ny rano dia mangotraka amin'ny 100 ° C eo ambanin'ny tsindrin'ny atmosfera mahazatra. Marina sa diso?","answer":"Marina. Eo ambanin'ny tsindrin'ny atmosfera mahazatra, ny rano dia mangotraka amin'ny 100 ° C."},{"question":"Meyasa aka sami Daidatacciyar Hausa?","answer":"kai tsaye muna iya cewa, daidaitaciyyar Hausa, wacce wasu marubutan ke kira karɓaɓɓiyar Hausa, ita ce Hausar da masana Harshen Hausa tun dauri suka haɗu a kan cewa, da ita za a yi amfani wajen yin rubutun Hausa domin samun daidaito.Wannan kuma saboda akwai kare-karen Hausa da dama, da suka haɗa da Kananci, Katsinanci, Zazzaganci, Dauranci, Sakkwatanci, Aranci, da sauransu. Idan aka ce kowa zai yi rubutu da nasa karin kamar yadda ya ke magana da shi, to abin zai zama babu tsari babu kan-gado, wanda kuma hakan za ta hana samun ƙa’ida."},{"question":"ਰਸੋਈ ਦੀ ਬਣਤਰ ਤੋਂ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਕੀ ਸਮਝਦੇ ਹੋ ? ਨਵੀਂ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਰਾਣੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਕੀ ਅੰਤਰ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ?","answer":"ਰਸੋਈ ਦੇ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ੇ ਅਤੇ ਖਿੜਕੀਆਂ ‘ਤੇ ਜਾਲੀ ਲੱਗੀ ਹੋਣੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦਰਵਾਜ਼ਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਹਮੇਸ਼ਾ ਬੰਦ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੱਖੀ ਮੱਛਰ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਵੜ ਸਕੇਗਾ | ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਰੋਸ਼ਨਦਾਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਹੋਣਾ ਲਾਜ਼ਮੀ ਹੈ । | ਰਸੋਈ ਦਾ ਧੂੰਆਂ ਕੱਢਣ ਲਈ ਚਿਮਨੀ ਜਾਂ ਐਗਜ਼ਾਸਟ ਪੱਖਾ ਲੱਗਾ ਲੈਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ । ਆਮ ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਲਈ ਰਸੋਈ ਦਾ ਆਕਾਰ 9′ × 10’ ਫੁੱਟ ਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਪਰ ਇਹ ਘਰ ਦੇ ਆਕਾਰ ਦੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵੀ ਹੋ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਨਵੀਂ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਰਾਣੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਅੰਤਰ-ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਰਸੋਈ ਵਿਚ ਜ਼ਮੀਨ ਤੇ ਬੈਠ ਕੇ ਹੀ ਸਾਰਾ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ | ਪਰ ਨਵੇਂ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀਆਂ ਰਸੋਈਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਖੜੇ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਸਾਰਾ ਕੰਮ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਸ਼ੈਲਫ਼ਾਂ ਪਾਈਆਂ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਸ਼ੈਲਫ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਉਚਾਈ ਆਮ ਕਰਕੇ ਫ਼ਰਸ਼ ਤੋਂ 21/2 ਫੁੱਟ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਤ੍ਰਿਣੀ ਦੀ ਲੰਬਾਈ ਮੁਤਾਬਿਕ ਇਹ ਉਚਾਈ ਵੱਧ-ਘੱਟ ਵੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ ।"},{"question":"කලා ඔය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"කලා ඔය යනු ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පිහිටි තුන් වැනියට දිගම ඔය වේ. එහි දිග ආසන්න වශයෙන් කිලෝ මීටර 145 ක් පමණ වේ. කලා ඔය අසල පන්සලක් හා පල්ලියක් දැක ගත හැක."},{"question":"Cuba jawab teka-teki berikut:  Alat yang boleh membeku setiap benda yang dijumpa.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah kamera. Kamera ialah alat optik yang digunakan untuk menangkap dan menyimpan imej atau video, sama ada secara digital melalui penderia imej elektronik, atau secara kimia melalui bahan sensitif cahaya seperti filem fotografi."},{"question":"നിങ്ങളുടെ പ്രായത്തേക്കാൾ ചെറുപ്പമായി കാണാനുള്ള മികച്ച വഴികളുടെ ഒരു ലിസ്റ്റ് എനിക്ക് തരൂ.","answer":"ഫിറ്റ്നസ് നിലനിർത്താൻ, തെളിഞ്ഞ ചർമ്മം നിലനിർത്തുക, പോസിറ്റീവായിരിക്കുക, എല്ലാ കാര്യങ്ങളിലും എപ്പോഴും കാലികമായിരിക്കുക, ശാന്തത പാലിക്കുക. "},{"question":"Formule una respuesta a esta pregunta elaborada: ¿A qué categoría taxonómica pertenecen tanto Hyacinthoides como Anthriscus?","answer":"A la categoría género."},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Quién es mayor, Britney Spears o Christina Aguilera?","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es comparar edades de dos mujeres famosas y determinar quién de las dos es mayor. "},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegta magacii caalimkii muslinka ahaa ee loo yaqiinay aabihii Cilmiga Kimistiriga (Chemistry) ?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Jaabir Bin Xayaan."},{"question":"Кандай кызыктуу окуяларды билесиз?","answer":"2016-жылы саякатчы Союзбек Салиевдин 🇰🇬 Кыргызстандын желеги менен жер шарын айланып өткөн. Салиев желек менен сапарын 25-августта баштап, кайра 27-октябрда мекенине кайтып келген."},{"question":"Vijf matrozen overleven een schipbreuk en zwemmen naar een klein eiland waar ze alleen een kokosnotenboom en een aap aantreffen. De matrozen verzamelen alle kokosnoten en leggen ze in een stapel onder de boom. Uitgeput besluiten ze om pas de volgende ochtend de kokosnoten te verdelen.Om een uur 's nachts wordt de eerste matroos wakker. Hij realiseert zich dat hij de anderen niet kan vertrouwen en besluit zijn deel alvast te nemen. Hij verdeelt de kokosnoten in vijf gelijke stapels, maar houdt daarbij een kokosnoot over. Hij geeft die kokosnoot aan de aap, verbergt zijn eigen kokosnoten (één van de vijf stapels), en plaatst de rest van de kokosnoten (de andere vier stapels) terug onder de boom.Om twee uur 's nachts wordt de tweede matroos wakker. Zich niet bewust van het feit dat de eerste matroos zijn deel al heeft weggenomen, verdeelt ook hij de kokosnoten in vijf gelijke stapels en houdt daarbij ook een kokosnoot over, die hij aan de aap geeft. Dan verbergt hij zijn kokosnoten (één van de vijf stapels), en plaatst de rest van de kokosnoten (de andere vier stapels) terug onder de boom.Om drie, vier en vijf uur 's nachts worden achtereenvolgens de derde, vierde en vijfde matroos wakker en voeren dezelfde handelingen uit als de eerste twee matrozen.'s Morgens, als ze opstaan, proberen ze allemaal zo onschuldig mogelijk te kijken. Geen van de matrozen maakt een opmerking over de gekrompen stapel kokosnoten, en geen van hen besluit om eerlijk te zijn en toe te geven dat hij zijn deel al genomen heeft. Ze verdelen de kokosnoten voor de zesde maal in vijf gelijke stapels en houden daarbij alweer een kokosnoot over, die ze aan de aap geven.De vraag: Wat is de kleinste hoeveelheid kokosnoten waaruit de oorspronkelijke stapel kan hebben bestaan?","answer":"Elke matroos laat 4/5(n-1) kokosnoten over van de stapel van n kokosnoten. Dit resulteert in een vreselijke formule voor het hele proces (want iedere keer moet een kokosnoot weggehaald worden om de stapel deelbaar door 5 te maken):r = 1/5(4/5(4/5(4/5(4/5(4/5(p-1)-1)-1)-1)-1)-1), waarbij p het aantal kokosnoten in de originele stapel is, en r het aantal kokosnoten is dat iedere matroos bij de laatste verdeling krijgt (wat een geheel getal moet zijn).De truc is om het aantal kokosnoten in de stapel deelbaar door 5 te maken, door 4 kokosnoten toe te voegen. Dit is mogelijk omdat je deze 4 kokosnoten weer weg kan halen, nadat een vijfde deel van de stapel is weggenomen: normaal zijn 4/5(n-1) kokosnoten over van een stapel van n kokosnoten; nu zijn 4/5(n+4) = 4/5(n-1)+4 kokosnoten over van een stapel van n+4 kokosnoten. In de laatste stap zijn er 1/5(n+4) = 1/5(n-1)+1 kokosnoten over van een stapel van n+4 kokosnoten. Op deze manier blijft het aantal kokosnoten in de stapel deelbaar door 5 gedurende het hele proces. We zijn dus op zoek naar een p waarvoor het volgende geldt:r + 1= 1/5×4/5×4/5×4/5×4/5×4/5×(p+4)=(45/56)×(p+4), waarbij r een geheel getal moet zijn.De kleinste (p+4) waarvoor het bovenstaande geldt is 56. Dus er waren p = 56-4 = 15621 kokosnoten in de originele stapel. "},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 香川県高松市で、まちや海の中のごみを少なくするために11日、ごみを拾う大会がありました。家族や高校生など14のグループの40人ぐらいが参加しました。グループは道などに落ちているごみを1時間拾います。そして、燃えるごみやプラスチックなどに分けます。ごみの種類や重さでポイントが決まっていて、スポーツのように競争します。吸い終わったたばこやガムの紙など、1時間で60kgのごみが集まりました。優勝したのは、17kg以上のごみを拾った大学生のグループでした。参加した人は「思っていたよりたくさんのごみがあって、びっくりしました」と話していました。大会を行った団体によると、瀬戸内海では1年に4500tぐらいのごみが見つかっています。この中の60%以上がまちなどから流れたごみだと言っています。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- 大会: 1）多くの人が集まる会。2）ある組織の全員が集まる会。- グループ: 1）仲間。集団。- 参加: 1）仲間に入ること。- 燃える: 1）火がついて、ほのおが上がる。2）燃えているようなようすになる。3）その気持ちが、さかんに起こる。- プラスチック: 1）熱や圧力を加えて、自由に形を作ることができる物質。特に合成樹脂を指す。使い道が広い。- 分け: 1）別々にする。はなす。2）配る。分配する。3）両側に、おし開く。4）引き分けにする。5）筋道を立てる。- 種類: 1）共通する形や性質によって分けたもの。- ポイント: 1）点。要点。2）得点。点数。3）地点。場所。4）線路の分かれ目で、車両を別の線に入れかえる仕かけ。転てつ機。- ガム: 1）かんで味わう菓子。ガム。- 優勝: 1）競技などで、一位で勝つこと。- 団体: 1）大勢の人の集まり。2）同じ目的を持った人々の集まり。- 瀬戸内海: 1）本州・四国・九州に囲まれた海。多くの島々がある。気候は温暖で雨が少ない。- t: 1）メートル法で、重さの単位の一つ。1トンは、1000キログラム。記号は「t」。2）船の大きさを表す単位。- 流れ: 1）液体などが、低いほうへ動く。2）時がたつ。3）物が水で動かされる。4）広がって行く。5）とりやめになる。"},{"question":"බත්කූරන් සහ ඔවුන්ගේ වර්ගීකරණය පිළිබඳ මූලික කරුණු මොනවාද?","answer":"Dragonflies Animalia රාජධානියේ Insecta පන්තියට අයත් වන අතර Odonata ගෝත්‍රයේ Anisoptera යන විද්‍යාත්මක නාමය යටතේ වර්ගීකරණය කර ඇත. ලොව පුරා බත්කූරන් විශේෂ 7,000 ක් පමණ ඇත. Odonata අනුපිළිවෙල පැරණිතම කෘමි ඇණවුම් වලින් එකක් වන අතර, වසර මිලියන 330 කට පෙර, ඩයිනෝසෝරයන්ට පෙර ඉතිහාසයක් ඇත."},{"question":"قم بكتابة مقال يجيب على هذا السؤال من هي الجامعة التي تقوم بمنح جوائز بوليتزر ؟.","answer":"تحظى هذه الجوائز، التي مولت في الأساس بمنحة من رائد الصحافة الأمريكي جوزيف بوليتزر بتقدير كبير. وتمنح جامعة كولومبيا الجوائز بتوصية من هيئة جوائز بوليتزر، المكونة من محكمين تعينهم الجامعة نفسها ويصل عدد الجوائز الممنوحة سنويًا إلى واحد وعشرين جائزة."},{"question":"یک سوال ظرح کنید که پاسخ آن این است: \\"نمی توان گفت\\" و سپس جریان فکری خود را هم در توجیه پاسخ تان بیان کنید.","answer":"سوال: آیا جمله \\"یک مرد در یک نمایش کت و شلوار به یک زن، رنگ سیاه ارائه میکند\\" بدان معنی است که \\"یک فرد اهداف خود را به شخص دیگری ارائه میکند؟\\" گزینه ها: آره - توضیحی ندارم.نميشه گفت - توضیحی ندارم.نه - جریان فکری: ارائه یک ایده در یک نمایش، لزوما نشان دادن اهداف خود به شخص دیگر نیست."},{"question":"రెండు సరూప త్రిభుజ వైశాల్యాల నిష్పత్తి a:9 అయిన , వాని భుజాల నిష్పత్తి ఎంత ?","answer":"భుజాల నిష్పత్తి = √a : 3."},{"question":"ഈ ഖണ്ഡികയ്ക്ക് ഒരു തുടർച്ച എഴുതുക: ഈ മേഖലയിലെ ഏറ്റവും ഉയരമുള്ള പ്രദേശമാണ് ടൈഗർ ഹിൽ. ശ്രീനഗർ മുതൽ കാർഗിൽ വരെ, കാർഗിൽ മേഖലയിൽ നാഷണൽ ഹൈവേ 1D, ബന്ധിപ്പിക്കുന്ന റോഡ് പ്രധാന വിതരണ പാതയാണ് ഇത്. കൊടുമുടിയിലെ ഏതൊരു ശത്രുവിനും പ്രദേശത്തെ പ്രധാന ഇന്ത്യൻ യൂണിറ്റായ 56 ബ്രിഗേഡിന്റെ ആസ്ഥാനത്തേക്ക് നേരിട്ട് കാണാനാകുന്ന ഒരു പ്രദേശം കൂടിയാണ് ഇത് എന്നതിനാൽ, പീരങ്കി വെടിവയ്പ്പിനുള്ള സാധ്യതകൂടിയുണ്ട്. ഇന്ത്യൻ സൈനികരുടെ യാത്രയ്ക്കും വസ്തുക്കളുടെ വിതരണത്തിനും തടസ്സമുണ്ടാകാറുണ്ടായിരുന്ന പ്രദേശം കൂടിയായിരുന്നു ഇത്. കാർഗിൽ യുദ്ധത്തിന്","answer":"ശേഷം ഇന്ത്യൻ പട്ടാളത്തിന് കുറേക്കൂടി നിയന്ത്രണം ലഭിച്ചതിനാൽ, സമീപത്തുള്ള മറ്റ് കൊടുമുടികളിലേക്കും ഒരു നിരീക്ഷണ കേന്ദ്രം ഈ കൊടുമുടി നൽകുന്നുണ്ട്."},{"question":"Apakah terjun lelabah?","answer":"Terjun lelabah adalah satu aktiviti yang melibatkan penerjunan dari bangunan yang tinggi sementara pelompat disambungkan kepada tali elastik besar. Struktur ini biasanya objek yang tetap seperti sebuah bangunan, jambatan atau kren, tetapi lompatan juga boleh dibuat daripada objek bergerak seperti belon udara panas atau helikopter yang mempunyai keupayaan untuk berlegar di atas tanah. Rasa keterujaan sewaktu melakukan aktiviti ini datangnya dari terjunan bebas serta lonjakan semula yang terhasil. Apabila orang yang diikut itu menerjun, tali menjadi tegang lalu si penerjun 'terbang' ke atas lagi akibat pengecutan tali dan terus berayun ke atas dan ke bawah sehingga kesemua tenaga kinetik yang tersimpan akhirnya hilang."},{"question":"Ndiani aive Mambokadzi Nzinga, uye nei achikosha munhoroondo yeAfrica?","answer":"Mambokadzi Nzinga aiva mutongi wezana remakore rechi17 weNdongo neMatamba Kingdoms (yanhasi Angola). Akadzivisa kutorwa kwechiPutukezi, achitungamirira vanhu vake muhondo dzinotyisa kurwisa vapambi."},{"question":"\\"සුරන්ජතු\\" තෙරුම කියන්න","answer":"සු= මානාවරන්ජතු= සිත් ඇලෙත්වා."},{"question":"Qaab Qoraalka Tolmoon?","answer":"Qaab Qoraalka Tolmoon_____________________________Nabad jaallayaal, ku soo dhowaada qaybta koowaad ee casharada taxanaha inoo noqon doona, kuwaasi oo ku saabsan qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee afkeena hooyo. Kadib markii ay farriimo badan iiga yimaadeen asxaab iyo akhyaar badan oo halkan ku jira, doonistooda iyo dadaalkoodana aan arkay, waxa aan go'aansaday in aan halkan idiinka bilaabo casharro taxane inoo noqon doona oo qofku qoraalka tayadiisa ku hagaajinayo.Qoraalku waa xifad ay dad badan ku shaqaystaan meelo badan oo caalamka ka mid ah, waana xirfadaha ugu qaalisan ee xitaa qof kasta oo shaqo codsanaya lagu xidho in uu yaqaan. Walow aanu afkeena wax badan lagu qorin xarumaha dawladda iyo meelihihii ay ahayd in lagu weyneeyo, haddana dal kasta afkiisu waa waxa koowaad ee ay kuwada xidhiidhaan waxna isugu qoraan. Ma jirto dawlad Soomaaliyeed oo xil iyo ahmiyad weyn iska saartay kor u qaaddida iyo dhawridda afkeena si saxan.Maamulada faraha badan ee gayiga Soomaalida ka jira, runtii waa meelaha adeegsiga qoraalka iyo afkeena hoos u liiday, ee luuqaddo kale wax ku qorta. Marka laga yimaado halganka ay ugu jiraan dhallinyarta wax qorta iyo dadka si uun afkeena u ilaasha oo u kaydiya, ma jirto cid kale oo xil iska saarta tayaynta iyo nooleynta afkeena.Aqoondarradaasi waxa ay keentay in aynu aragno boqollaal buug oo dibadda u soo baxay, marka aad akhriso ama aad eegtona aad ka yaxyaxayso tayo-xumada qoraalka buuggaas. Dawlad la'aantu, waxa kale oo ay keentay in aan la dhamaystiran qabyadii ku jirtay qoraalka Soomaaliga, waxana ay illaa maanta sabab u tahay muranno badan iyo aragtiyo badan oo la isku khilaafsan yahay.Khilaafyadaas iyo qabyadaa qoraalka ku jiraa waxa ay dhaleen in lagu kala duwanaado meelaha qaar iyo adeegsiga qoraalada qaar.Nasiib darrooyinka kale ee ina haysta waxa ka mida, in aanay jirin goobo iyo meelo u gaara oo loogu hagaago barashada qoraalka. Dad dadaalay uun baa wixii ay ka yaqaaniin wax ka mida dadka uga sii faa'iideeya mooyee. Madashan akhriska iyo qoraalka runtii qoraallo dhisan waad arkaysaa, laakiin qoraalada u badan ee halkan la soo galiyo waa qaar laga xishoonayo akhriskooda tayo-xumada qoraalkooda, se dhalliil kaliya waxba ma tarayso, waa in isu faa'iidaynaa waxa aan is dheer nahay.HORDHACSida aad la wada socotaan af walba oo dunida ka jira waxa uu leeyahay qaab loo qoro, xeerar iyo qawaaniin la raaco marka la qorayo, haddii laga tagona ka dhigaysa qoraalkaaga mid ma dhalays ah. Af Somaaliguna waa la mid, waxa uu leeyahay xeerar iyo qawaaniin ay tahay in aad isticmaasho marka aad qorayso, ma noqonayso sax in sida aad ugu hadkayso u qorto, balse waxa lagama maarmaan ah in aad barato sida loo qoro, kaliya aanad baran sida loogu dhawaaqo ama loo akhriyo oo qudha.Guddidii farta Soomaaliga dajisay 1972kii, ayaa sida oo kale inoo qeexay qaab qoraalka Soomaaliga iyo xeerarkiisa, metelan shaqallada labanlaabmaya, marka xarafka la weyneeyo iyo adeegsiga calaamadahaba.Waxa aynnu isku dayi doonaa insha Allah, inta aqoonteydan gaabani gaadhsiisan tahay in aan uga faa'iideeyo bulsho-weynta Soomaaliyeed, siiba dhallinyarada jecel barashada qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee afkeena, kuwaasi oo halkan ka qaadan doona casharro taxane ah duhur walba insha Allah.Si lamida sida hadalku ugu baahan yahay marka aad hadlayso, in aad ugu kala samayso meel hakad, meelna joogsi, meel weyddiin, meel dareen muujiso, meel yaab aad muujiso, sidaa iyo si lamida ayaa uu qoraalkuna ugu baahan yahay in aadan isku dhex yaacin waxa aad qorayso, balse ay tahay in aad ukala nidaamiso si qof walba fahmi karo.Qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee afkeena,  marka uu qofku barto ama wax ka yaqaan ugu yaraan,  waxa macne u samaynaya waxa uu qorayo ama akhrinayo, metelan qoraagu marka uu wax qorayo uma qorayo sida uu isagu u fahansan yahay, balse waxa uu u qorayaa si qof kasta oo akhriyaa u fahmi karayo ujeedka qoraalkiisa.Guddidii farta Soomaaligu waxa ay isku afgarteen xilligaas, in toddobo shibbane ay labanlaabmayaan af Soomaliga, kuwaasi oo kala ah M, N, L, G, R, D, B, laguna jamciyo weedha caanka ah ee, \\"MaNaLaGaaraaDBaa,\\" walow ay jiraan weedho kale, haddana tani waa ta ugu caansan. Waxa jira af-aqoollo Soomaali iyo ajaaniib ah, kuwaasi oo ku doodda in ay jiraan xarfo kale oo labanlaabma, balse ay guddidu ka tagtay iyaga oo tusaalayaal usoo qaata xarfo ay ka mid yihiin \\"Q,S,\\" innaguse waqtigan doodda furitaankeeda iyo ka sheekaynteeda taag uma hayno, waxa aynnu kari la'nahayba barashada toddobadii la isku waafaqsanaa.Khaladaadka u waaweyn ee dhallinyarteenan danbe ay ka galaan qoraalka, waa in ay isticmaalaan xarfo aan ku jirin shibbanayaasha Soomaaliga, sida \\"Z, P, V,\\" kuwaasi oo meesha ka saara inta badan xarfaha \\"S, B, F,\\" waa wax lagu tilmaami karo nasiib darro in xarfo aan ku jirin shibbanayaasha khasab ugu darno, walibana aan booska uga saarno kuwii saxda ahaa ee booskaas lahaa. Waxa aan dhallinyarta kula talinayaa in saddexdaas xaraf adeegsigooda loogu daayo luuqadda ay ku jiraan, balse aan lagu dhex wadin Afkeena, maadaama oo aanay meelna kaga jirin.Astaamaha kala duwan ee qoraalku waxa ay qayb ka yihiin qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee qofka wax qoraya looga baahan yahay in uu aad u kala barto calaamadaha kala duwan ee la isticmaalo qoraalka dhexdiisa.Adeegsiga khaldan ee calaamaduhu mararka qaar waxa uu sababi karaa shil dhaca ama arrin dhibaato keeni karta, ay sababtu tahay in aan si saxan loo isticmaalin calaamadaas.Waxa jirta weedh caan ah, \\"Coma can a kill man.\\" Oo macnaheedu yahay, \\"Hakadku waxa uu dili karaa nin.\\" Waan filayaa in qisadeeda aan kawada dharagsanahay, waa sheeko hakad si khaldan loo adeegsaday sabab u noqday in nin la dilo naftana daqiiqado gudahood lagu dhaafiyo. \\"Kill him, not wait for me!” oo macnaheedu yahay: “Dila, aniga ha i sugina!\\" Sidaas ayaa uu sarkaalkii warqada usoo qoray, balse sida saxda ah ee ujeeday waxa ay ahayd,\\"Kill him not, wait for me!” oo macnaheedu yahay “Ha dilina, aniga i suga!\\"Halkii ayaa ninkii lagu dilay, waxana galaaftay noloshiisii dhamayd waa hakad si khaldan loo adeegsaday ama meel aan meeshiisii ahayn la dhigay!.Waxa kale oo aynu isku dul taagi doonaa muddada casharadani inoo socon doonaan haddii Rabbi idmo, xilliyada ay habboon tahay in xarafka la weyneeyo ama xarfaha la weyneeyo, marka aad qoraallo badan aragto ama akhriso waxa aad ku dhex arkaysaa xarfo ay ahayd in la waaweyneeyo oo la yareeyay iyo xarfo ay ahayd in la yareeyo oo la weyneeyay, taasina waa khalad iyo gef cad oo afkeena lagula kacayo. Ugu dambeyn, maanta hordhacaas ayaynu qaadan, insha Allah barri duhur ayay inoo bilaabmi oo aan soo galin doonaa qaybta koowaad, la socod iyo ka faa'iidaysi wanaagsan walaalayaal."},{"question":"අවේලාව යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.. ","answer":"අවේලාව යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය වේලාව වේ"},{"question":"Kush e fitoi Kampionatin Evropian në vitin 1964?","answer":"Në vitin 1964 Kampionatin Evropian e fitoi Spanja."},{"question":"شنو هي اكبر جزيره كاينه فالبحر الابيض المتوسط  ؟","answer":"صقلية."},{"question":"Alerjik sivilce nasıl olur?","answer":"Alerjiler doğrudan bir belirti olarak sivilceye neden olmazken, ikincil bir şekilde olabilir. Alerjiler vücutta iltihaplanmaya neden olur, bu da şişmeye ve cilt tahrişine yol açabilir. Bu iltihaplanma daha sonra bir bağışıklık tepkisini tetikleyerek akneyi kötüleştirebilecek hormonların salınmasına neden olabilir."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਗਉੜੀ ਮਹਲਾ ੧ ॥ਡਰਿ ਘਰੁ ਘਰਿ ਡਰੁ ਡਰਿ ਡਰੁ ਜਾਇ ॥ਸੋ ਡਰੁ ਕੇਹਾ ਜਿਤੁ ਡਰਿ ਡਰੁ ਪਾਇ ॥ਤੁਧੁ ਬਿਨੁ ਦੂਜੀ ਨਾਹੀ ਜਾਇ ॥ਜੋ ਕਿਛੁ ਵਰਤੈ ਸਭ ਤੇਰੀ ਰਜਾਇ ॥੧॥ਡਰੀਐ ਜੇ ਡਰੁ ਹੋਵੈ ਹੋਰੁ ॥ਡਰਿ ਡਰਿ ਡਰਣਾ ਮਨ ਕਾ ਸੋਰੁ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਨਾ ਜੀਉ ਮਰੈ ਨ ਡੂਬੈ ਤਰੈ ॥ਜਿਨਿ ਕਿਛੁ ਕੀਆ ਸੋ ਕਿਛੁ ਕਰੈ ॥ਹੁਕਮੇ ਆਵੈ ਹੁਕਮੇ ਜਾਇ ॥ਆਗੈ ਪਾਛੈ ਹੁਕਮਿ ਸਮਾਇ ॥੨॥ਹੰਸੁ ਹੇਤੁ ਆਸਾ ਅਸਮਾਨੁ ॥ਤਿਸੁ ਵਿਚਿ ਭੂਖ ਬਹੁਤੁ ਨੈ ਸਾਨੁ ॥ਭਉ ਖਾਣਾ ਪੀਣਾ ਆਧਾਰੁ ॥ਵਿਣੁ ਖਾਧੇ ਮਰਿ ਹੋਹਿ ਗਵਾਰ ॥੩॥ਜਿਸ ਕਾ ਕੋਇ ਕੋਈ ਕੋਇ ਕੋਇ ॥ਸਭੁ ਕੋ ਤੇਰਾ ਤੂੰ ਸਭਨਾ ਕਾ ਸੋਇ ॥ਜਾ ਕੇ ਜੀਅ ਜੰਤ ਧਨੁ ਮਾਲੁ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਆਖਣੁ ਬਿਖਮੁ ਬੀਚਾਰੁ ॥੪॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 151 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਤੇਰੇ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਵਿਚ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਉਹ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਮਿਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਿਥੇ ਮਨ ਤੇਰੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਇਹ ਯਕੀਨ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈਂ ਤੇ ਸਭ ਵਿਚ ਵੱਸਦਾ ਹੈਂ । ਤੇਰੇ ਡਰ ਵਿਚ ਰਿਹਾਂ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦਾ ਹਰੇਕ ਕਿਸਮ ਦਾ) ਸਹਮ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਤੇਰਾ ਡਰ ਐਸਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੰੁਦਾ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਡਰ ਵਿਚ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਸਹਮ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹੇ ।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਤੈਥੋਂ ਬਿਨਾਂ ਜੀਵ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਥਾਂ-ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ।ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਸਭ ਤੇਰੀ ਮਰਜ਼ੀ ਨਾਲ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ !) ਤੇਰਾ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਟਿਕਣ ਦੇ ਥਾਂ) ਜੇ ਜੀਵ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਡਰ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹੇ, ਤਾਂ ਜੀਵ ਸਦਾ ਸਹਮਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਮਨ ਦੀ ਘਬਰਾਹਟ ਮਨ ਦਾ ਸਹਮ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਬਣਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਵਿਚ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਹੀ ਇਹ ਯਕੀਨ ਬਣ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜੀਵ ਨਾਹ ਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਨਾਹ ਕਿਤੇ ਡੁੱਬ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਨਾਹ ਕਿਤੋਂ ਤਰਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੇਹੜਾ ਕਿਤੇ ਡੁਬਦਾ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਤਰਨ ਦਾ ਸਵਾਲ ਹੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੰੁਦਾ) ।(ਇਹ ਯਕੀਨ ਬਣਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਜਗਤ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ ਉਹੀ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ,ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਜੀਵ ਜੰਮਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ,ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਹੁਕਮ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕੇ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਜਿਸ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ, ਮੋਹ ਹੈ, ਅਹੰਕਾਰ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਦੀ ਕਾਂਗ ਨਦੀ ਵਾਂਗ (ਠਾਠਾਂ ਮਾਰ ਰਹੀ) ਹੈ ।ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਹੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੀ ਖ਼ੁਰਾਕ ਹੈ, ਆਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਆਸਰਾ ਹੈ;ਜੋ ਇਹ ਖ਼ੁਰਾਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਖਾਂਦੇ ਉਹ (ਦੁਨੀਆ ਦੇ) ਸਹਮ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਕਮਲੇ ਹੋਏ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ! ਤੇਰੇ ਡਰ-ਅਦਬ ਵਿਚ ਰਿਹਾਂ ਹੀ ਇਹ ਯਕੀਨ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ) ਜਿਸ ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਸਹਾਈ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਹੀ ਬਣਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਕਿਸੇ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਸਾਥੀ ਸਹਾਇਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਣ ਸਕਦਾ),ਪਰ ਹਰੇਕ ਜੀਵ ਤੇਰਾ (ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ) ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਸਭ ਦੀ ਸਾਰ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈਂ ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ ! ਜਿਸ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਜੀਵ ਜੰਤ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ (ਜੀਵਾਂ ਵਾਸਤੇ) ਉਸੇ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਇਹ ਧਨ-ਮਾਲ (ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ) ਹੈ ।(ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਵਧ ਇਹ) ਵਿਚਾਰਨਾ ਤੇ ਆਖਣਾ (ਕਿ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪਣੇ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਸੰਭਾਲ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ) ਔਖਾ ਕੰਮ ਹੈ । ।੪।੨।\\""},{"question":"Ahoana ny fomba atao hitsaboana ny aphte ?","answer":"Sitrana ho azy ny aphte ary afaka tanteraka ny aphte eo amin’ny 10 hatramin’ny 15 andro eo. Noho izany dia tsy dia misy fitsaboana atao hanatsitranana azy ireny. Ny tokony atao kosa nefa dia ny mampitony ny fanaintainana ary misoroka ny hipoitrany amin’ny ho avy.Misy ireo fomba natoraly azo atao ampitoniana ankizy misy aphte. Anisan’izany ohatra ny fanaovana gararaka amin’ny rano iray vera nasiana karibonetra 2 tsongon-tanana. Azo atao ihany koa ny manosotra tantely eo amin’ilay ratra kely mba ampitoniana ilay marary. Atao indroa isan’andro ireo torohevitra ireo. A"},{"question":"යුරෝපයේ එකම බෞද්ධ රාජ්‍යය වන කල්මිකියාවේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"කල්මිකියාවේ අගනුවර එලිස්ටාය."},{"question":"आर्टिफिसियल इन्टेलिजेन्स भनेको के हो?","answer":"आर्टिफिसियल इन्टेलिजेन्स भनेको एल्गोरिदम र डेटाको प्रयोग मार्फत सिकाइ, समस्या समाधान, र निर्णय लिने जस्ता कार्यहरू गर्न सक्षम कम्प्युटर प्रणालीहरूको विकास हो जसलाई सामान्यतया मानव बुद्धिको आवश्यकता पर्दछ।"},{"question":"Inona no ilàna ny lalamby Antananarivo - Toamasina?","answer":"ny lalamby Antananarivo - Toamasina dia itaterana ny vokatry ny tany halefa amin'ny sambo sy itondrana ireo entam-barotra avy any ivelanyary ny solitany voadio tao Toamasina"},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Келе жаткан жылдар сиздин жашооңузга акылмандык, жылуулук жана ийгилик кошсун. Жүзүңүздөгү жылмаюу түбөлүккө кала берсин! Туулган күнүңүз менен куттуктайм!"},{"question":"Sheeg magaca ninkii uu Nabiga (scw) u bixiyey Seeyfulaahil masluul?","answer":"wuxuu ahaa Khaalid Ibnu Waliid."},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү эң чоң сүт эмүүчү жаныбар","answer":"Көк кит."},{"question":"為什麼植物會生長？","answer":"植物進行光合作用，利用陽光和水合成養分，促進生長。"},{"question":"পৃথিবীর ম্যাঙ্গেটিক খুঁটির কারণ কী","answer":"পৃথিবীর চৌম্বক মেরুগুলি পৃথিবীর কেন্দ্রে পদার্থের চলাচলের কারণে তৈরি হয় যা একটি শক্তিশালী চুম্বকের মতো কাজ করে এবং দক্ষিণ মেরু এবং উত্তর মেরুকে সারিবদ্ধ করে। চুম্বকের উত্তর মেরু উত্তর দিকে নির্দেশ করে কারণ পৃথিবীর চুম্বকের দক্ষিণ মেরু উত্তর দিকে নির্দেশিত"},{"question":"Kodi Malawi ndi dziko losauka kapena lolemera?","answer":"Dziko la Malawi ndi limodzi mwa mayiko osauka kwambiri padziko lonse lapansi ndipo lili pa nambala 174 mwa mayiko 189 pa ndondomeko ya chitukuko cha anthu. Oposa theka la anthu amakhala mu umphawi, ndipo gawo limodzi mwa magawo asanu ali umphawi wadzaoneni."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"பெண்களுக்கும் ஆண்களுக்கும் சமத்துவமான கல்வி அளிக்க ஏற்பாடு செய்வதே மக்கள் முன்னேற்றத்திற்கு ஏற்றதாகும்."},{"question":"விரும்பிய இலக்கை அடைய இந்தியாவில் முதல் முறையாக மகாத்மா காந்தி எந்த ஆண்டு உண்ணாவிரதப் போராட்ட முறையைப் பயன்படுத்தினார்?","answer":": 1918 ஆண்டு"},{"question":"\\"අසහාය\\" කියන වචනෙ තේරුම මොකක්ද ? කොහොම වචනයක් ද ඒක කොහොම හැදුණු එකක් ද?අ+සහය ද?භාවිතය කොහොමද?","answer":"අසහාය සංස්කෘත තත්සම පදයකි.असहायතනියම වැඩ කරන, උදව්වට කිසිවකු නැති යන අරුත් දෙයි.අසහාය ගායකයා, අසහාය නායකයා, වැනි තැන්වල යෙදෙනා අසහාය යන්නේ ඇත්තේද, සහායක් නැති යන අරුතමයි.කිසිවෙකුගේ සහායක් නැතිව තම කාර්‍යය කිරීමට ශක්තිය ඇත්තෙකු හෝ එසේ කරගත් තැනැත්තෙකු හෝ අසහාය පුද්ගලයෙකු ලෙස හැඳින්වේ.ඒ අනුවයි, අසහාය ගායකයා, අසහාය බුද්ධිමතා ආදී යෙදුම් භාවිත වන්නේ.එවැන්නන්ට සමානයන් දුර්ලභ හෙයින්, ඔවුන් අසමානයන් ලෙසද හැඳින්වීමට හැකියි."},{"question":"Kas yra klausimas: \\"Žmonių matuoklis yra auditorijos matavimo įrankis, naudojamas TV ir kabelinės televizijos žiūrovų žiūrėjimo įpročiams matuoti.\\" Tema yra \\"Žmonių matuoklis\\".","answer":"\\"Kur naudojamas žmonių matuoklis?\\""},{"question":"டாக்டர் வந்தாரு, ஊசி போட்டாரு, காசு வாங்காமல் போனாரு.அது என்ன ?","answer":"கொசு. மெல்லிய உடல் கொண்ட கொசுக்கள் ஓர் இணை இறக்கைகளையும் மூன்று இணை நீண்ட கால்களையும் கொண்டன. பொதுவாக ஆண் கொசுக்கள் தாவரச் சாற்றைப் பருகும். பெண் கொசுக்களே மனிதர்களிடமிருந்தும் பிற உயிரினங்களிலிருந்தும் இரத்தத்தை உறிஞ்சும் என்றாலும் பெண் கொசுக்களுக்குக்கூட இரத்தம் முதன்மையான உணவல்ல."},{"question":"இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரஸ் எந்த வட்டமேசை மாநாட்டில் பங்கேற்றது?","answer":"1931 இல் இரண்டாவது வட்ட மேசை மாநாடு"},{"question":"Idibo wọọdu l‘Ọṣun: Awọn ọdọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC fẹhonu han, wọn ni Oyetọla ko le yan le awọn lori","answer":"Ṣe lawọn ọdọ kan ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, fọn soju titi nirọlẹ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọgbọnjọ, oṣu keje yii, lati fẹhonu han si ohun ti wọn pe ni ọgbọn alumọkọrọyin ti Gomina Oyetọla ati alaga ẹgbẹ naa, Ọmọọba Gboyega Famọdun, n lo lati ma ṣe jẹ ki eto idibo wọọdu waye lọla.Lati bii oṣu kan ni igbimọ afun-n-ṣọ apapọ ẹgbẹ naa lorileede yii ti kede ọjọ Abamẹta,       Satide, ọjọ kọkanlelọgbọn, oṣu keje, gẹgẹ bii ọjọ ti idibo wọọdu yoo waye, latigba naa ni awọn ti wọn jẹ ‘The Osun Progressives’ ti n fẹsun kan awọn Ileri Oluwa pe ṣe ni wọn fẹẹ yan le gbogbo ọmọ ẹgbẹ lọwọ.Lọsẹ to kọja ni awọn TOP kegbajare si awọn alakooso ẹgbẹ lorileede yii pe Gomina Oyetọla ko gbogbo fọọmu ti wọn ko ranṣẹ lati Abuja sabẹ, ti wọn ko si jẹ ki awọn miiran lanfaani si fọọmu ọhun ju awọn ti wọn n pe ara wọn ni Ileri Oluwa lọ.Nigba ti ọrọ ti di bayii lawọn naa mori le Abuja lati gba fọọmu wọn, eleyii ti wọn ni o fa a ti gomina tun fi ko awọn ti Abuja ran wa lati ṣakoso idibo ọjọ Ẹti naa pamọ, ti wọn ko si jẹ ki wọn lọ si sẹkiteriati ẹgbẹ to wa ni Ogo-Oluwa, l’Oṣogbo.Gẹgẹ bi ọkan lara awọn olufẹhonu han naa, Rasheed Raji, ṣe wi, “Iwa to le tu ẹgbẹ ni Gomina Oyetọla ati Ọmọọba Famọdun n hu lọwọlọwọ bayii, inu otẹẹli ni wọn ko awọn ti ẹgbẹ ran wa lati ta fọọmu fun wa si, wọn ko jẹ ka lanfaani si fọọmu bo tilẹ jẹ pe ogunlọgọ awọn eeyan wa ni wọn ti sanwo fọọmu tipẹ.“A ko mọ idi ti idibo fi n ba wọn lẹru, a sọ fun wọn pe ki wọn jẹ ka dibo yan awọn to ba wu wa, awọn ti wọn yoo ṣeto idibo lọla tun ti de, wọn tun ti ti wọn mọ inu ile-ijọba dipo sẹkiteriaati to yẹ ki wọn wa.“A n fi asiko yii ke si igbimọ ti Mai Mala Buni n dari lati da si wahala to n ṣẹlẹ lọwọ bayii nipinlẹ Ọṣun ko too ṣe akoba to pọ fun ẹgbẹ wa.”Bakan naa ni Arabinrin Ọpẹyẹmi Awotipẹ bu ẹnu atẹ lu iwa ko sẹni ti yoo mu mi ti alaga ẹgbẹ naa l’Ọṣun, Ọmọọba Famọdun n hu. O ni ẹgbẹ alaafia ni wọn mọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu APC si tẹlẹ, ṣugbọn iwa ti alaga naa n hu bayii n kọ awọn lominu.O ṣalaye pe wọn ti pinnu lati maa na ẹnikẹni to ba bọ sipo lati dibo lọla nitori ṣe ni wọn fẹẹ maa buwọ lu orukọ awọn ti wọn ri bii oloootọ si wọn, ti wọn yoo maa lo lati dari ẹgbẹ bo ṣe wu wọn.Adetipẹ waa ke si awọn alakooso ẹgbẹ lati ke si awọn to n da wahala silẹ ninu ẹgbẹ naa l’Ọṣun pe ki wọn ki ọwọ ọmọ wọn bọ’ṣọ, ki awọn oṣiṣẹ alaabo si ṣiṣẹ wọn lọna to ba ofin orileede yii mu."},{"question":"Unsa ang hinagiban nga gipili ni David sa pagpildi kang Goliath","answer":"Usa ka bato ug usa ka lambuyog"},{"question":"من هم الثلاثة من الصحابية الذين تشتاق إليهم الجنة؟ .","answer":"الجواب علي بن أبي طالب، سلمان الفارسي، عمار بن ياسر"},{"question":"Njengoba senizizwele osopolitiki bekhuluma nani, naphinde nezwanoDuma exolisa ngokushayisa kwakhe, manje-ke ngizonifundelaumbiko wenkosi. (alungise ipheshana aliphethe maqede aqaleafunde) Ithi inkosi yesizwe sakithi, 'Ngibingelela isikhulusikaHulumeni, osopolitiki bezinhlangano zabantu kanye nesizwesonke. Sizwe sami engisithandayo, okwenzekile kufana nentoesingeke sisakwazi ukuyiguqula. Asebefile ngeke sibavuse kodwangethemba ukuthi sifunde lukhulu kukho konke osekwenzekile.Ngabe angiyazi into engiyiphilelayo uma ngingababongi laba bantubesifazane ababili umkami uMaNgema, kanye noMaShezi,umkaDuma. Bobabili babambe iqhaza elibaluleke kakhulu ekucishenilo mlilo. Ngempela baqinisile abathi, abantu besimame bayimbokodo.Kusukela manje ikhansela lizoqhubeka nohlelo lokuletha intuthukoesizweni sami. Nalo liqaphele ukuthi lisebenzisana nabantu abanjani.Mina-ke ngizolisiza ikhansela. Njengoba alikabi nayo indluyokusebenzela, mina nginikela ngendlu elaphaya emzini wami. Leyondlu iseduze kwesango. Yiyo-ke ezoba yigunjana azohlelela kulokonke okuqondene nemisebenzi yakhe. Ngizovala ngokubongaamaphoyisa asebenze ngokuzikhandla ukubhula lo mlilo. Yiminainkosi yenu, uShandu.'1. Ukuba wena wawunguMbandlwa yiziphi izeluleko ezakhayoowawungazinikeza uDuma? Bhala amaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo:Ngangingamtshela ukuthi:• Emhlabeni kuyahlonishwana, kuyaboniswana.• Akafunde ukulalela.• Akafunde ukusebenzisana nabo bonke abaholi emphakathini.• Akukuhle ukubamba igqubu, kuhle ukuxola uqhubeke nempilo."},{"question":"බුදුන් වදාළ ධර්මය තුළ වැඳලා ඉල්ලූ විට ලැබෙන කිසිවක් නැත.ප්‍රායෝගිකව අනුගමනය කිරීම තුළ පමණක් ප්‍රතිඵල ඇත. මේ ප්‍රකාශය ධර්මානුකූලද?","answer":"ඔය හැම එකක් එක්කම හිත පවත්වාගන්න දන්නවානම් ලාභයක්මයිවන්දනාව පාවිච්චි කරන්නේ හිත සන්සුන් කරගන්න මිස ඉල්ලන්න, ප්‍රාර්ථනා කරන්න නෙවෙයිඅනිත් එක ඒක සරණාගමනයේ සංඛේතයක්ඒ වගේමයි සජ්ජායනාව. හැබැයි මේකට අර්ථය ගැන යම් අවබෝධයක් තියෙන්ම ඕනවිපස්සනාභාවනාව කරන කෙනාගේ වෙහෙස අඩුකරගන්න ඔය දෙකම ඉතා වටිනවාඔය අජාන් බ්‍රහම්, අජාන් සුමේධෝ වගේ යතිවර ස්වාමීණ්වහන්සෙලා පවා වන්දනාව සහ සජ්ජායනාව තවම කරලා ආදර්ශය දෙනවා බටහිර අයට වුනත් (එයාලා සාමාන්‍යයෙන් වන්දනාමාන වලට හුරු අය නෙවෙයි නේ)ප්‍රයෝජනය කියලා යමක් කරලා බලන්න කිව්වාම ඕන කෙනෙක් කරනවා."},{"question":"ප්‍රතිභානය යන්නෙහි අර්ථය කුමක්ද ?","answer":"ප්‍රතිභානය (Intuition) යනු සාමාන්‍යයයෙන් සවිඥානක තර්කනය හෝ පැහැදිලි කිරීමකින් තොරව යම් දැනුමක් කරා ක්ෂණයකින් ප්‍රවේශ වීමට ඇති අද්විතීය සහජ මානසික හැකියාවයි.මෙය අවිඥානික දැනුමට සෘජු ප්‍රවේශය ,අවිඥානික සංජානනය, අභ්‍යන්තර සංවේදනා ,අවිඥානික රටාව-හඳුනාගැනීම සඳහා ඇති අභ්‍යන්තර අවබෝධය ආදී වශයෙන් විවිධ ක්ෂේත්‍ර වල භාවිතා වේ .කෙසේ වෙතත් ආගමික ඉගැන්වීම් තුල මෙම හැකියාව උත්තර මනුෂ්‍ය හැකියාවක් ලෙස පෙනෙන අවස්ථා එමටය ."},{"question":"Python හි අංකයක් ප්‍රථමක දැයි පරීක්ෂා කරන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"def is_prime(num):    if num <= 1:        return False    for i in range(2, int(num0.5) + 1):        if num % i == 0:            return False    return Trueprint(is_prime(7))  # Outputs: True"},{"question":"اكتب مقالة تصف الخبر التالي: اليمن: مقتل 3 في قصف حوثي لمدرسة في دماج","answer":"يمنيون من دماج يحتجون على الهجمات الحوثية على بلدتهم، ويسيطر الحوثيون على معظم محافظة صعدة الشمالية المحاذية للحدود مع السعودية، ويستخدمونها معقلا لهم في صراعهم مع الحكومة اليمنية. ويساهم الصراع الطائفي في دماج في عرقلة جهود المصالحة بين الحوثيين والحكومة المركزية في صنعاء. وكان القتال بين الحوثيين والسلفيين قد تصاعد في الشهر الماضي بعد ان اتهم الحوثيون السلفيين بتجنيد الآلاف من المقاتلين الاجانب استعدادا لمهاجمتهم. وقتل في المعارك التي تلت ذلك اكثر من 100 شخص في صفوف السلفيين، ولم يعلن الحوثيون عن خسائرهم."},{"question":"Cad is brí le bogearraí saora? ","answer":"Is éard atá i gceist le bogearraí saora ná cód foinseach a bheith ar fáil go réidh don úsáideoir agus é a bheith saor le hathruithe a dhéanamh don chód is a roinnt le daoine eile gan coinníollacha ceadúnais a rialacha. Ní cheist airgid atá á phlé leis an gcur síos seo, ní gá na bogearraí a bheith saor in aisce. Mar a deir Richard Stallman, bunaitheoir an Free Software Foundation, é “saoirse cainte” atá i gceist, seachas “beoir saor in aisce”."},{"question":"Sheeg sanadkii uu dhashay General Maxamed Faarax Ceydiid?","answer":"General Maxamed Faarax Ceydiid wuxu dhashay sanadkii 1934-kii, isla sanadkaan waxaa dhashay Cabdullaahi Yuusuf Axmed."},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Am tiit daldi ko roofu.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Am tiit daldi ko roofu.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Am: DETtiit: NOUNdaldi: ADVko: PRONroofu: VERB.: PUNCT"},{"question":"በአንድ ሊትር የተለመደው የባህር ውሃ ውስጥ ስንት ግራም ጨው (ሶዲየም ክሎራይድ) አለ?","answer":"ምንም"},{"question":"\\"क्वान्टम मेसिन लर्निङ\\" र जटिल गणनालाई गति दिने यसको सम्भावनाको व्याख्या गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"क्वान्टम मेसिन लर्निङले क्वान्टम कम्प्युटिङ र मेसिन लर्निङ प्रविधिहरूलाई शास्त्रीय कम्प्युटरहरू भन्दा छिटो जटिल समस्याहरू समाधान गर्नका लागि अनुकूलन र डेटा विश्लेषणका अनुप्रयोगहरू संयोजन गर्दछ।"},{"question":"آیا می‌توان از کوکوپیت به عنوان بستری برای پرورش حلزون استفاده کرد؟","answer":"بله، کوکوپیت می تواند به عنوان بستری برای پرورش حلزون استفاده شود. حلزون‌ها به بستر مناسبی نیاز دارند که رطوبت را حفظ کند و محیطی راحت داشته باشد. کوکوپیت ظرفیت نگهداری آب خوبی دارد و محیطی پایدار و غنی از رطوبت را فراهم می‌کند که می تواند برای سلامت و رشد حلزون مفید باشد."},{"question":"أعطني مثالاً على المعلومات العامة في هذه الفئة: الأفلام","answer":"ما هو أطول فيلم حائز على جائزة الأوسكار؟ War and Peace"},{"question":"Odpowiedz na następujące pytanie: w jakim kraju uprawia się najwięcej kawy na świecie?","answer":"W Brazylii."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੩ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਵਿਚਿ ਵਡੀ ਵਡਿਆਈ ॥ਚਿਰੀ ਵਿਛੁੰਨੇ ਮੇਲਿ ਮਿਲਾਈ ॥ਆਪੇ ਮੇਲੇ ਮੇਲਿ ਮਿਲਾਏ ॥ਆਪਣੀ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਆਪੇ ਪਾਏ ॥੧॥ਹਰਿ ਕੀ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਕਿਨ ਬਿਧਿ ਹੋਇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਅਪਰੰਪਰੁ ਅਗਮ ਅਗੋਚਰੁ ਗੁਰ ਕੈ ਸਬਦਿ ਮਿਲੈ ਜਨੁ ਕੋਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਕੀਮਤਿ ਜਾਣੈ ਕੋਇ ॥ਵਿਰਲੇ ਕਰਮਿ ਪਰਾਪਤਿ ਹੋਇ ॥ਊਚੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਊਚਾ ਹੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਸਬਦਿ ਵਖਾਣੈ ਕੋਇ ॥੨॥ਵਿਣੁ ਨਾਵੈ ਦੁਖੁ ਦਰਦੁ ਸਰੀਰਿ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰੁ ਭੇਟੇ ਤਾ ਉਤਰੈ ਪੀਰ ॥ਬਿਨੁ ਗੁਰ ਭੇਟੇ ਦੁਖੁ ਕਮਾਇ ॥ਮਨਮੁਖਿ ਬਹੁਤੀ ਮਿਲੈ ਸਜਾਇ ॥੩॥ਹਰਿ ਕਾ ਨਾਮੁ ਮੀਠਾ ਅਤਿ ਰਸੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਪੀਵਤ ਰਹੈ ਪੀਆਏ ਸੋਇ ॥ਗੁਰ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤੇ ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਪਾਏ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਗਤਿ ਪਾਏ ॥੪॥੩॥੪੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 361 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਮਰਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਵਾਰਾਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਵਿਚ ਇਹ ਵੱਡਾ ਭਾਰਾ ਗੁਣ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਜਨਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਛੁੜੇ ਹੋਏ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।  ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਗੁਰੂ) ਮਿਲਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਾ ਕੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੋੜਦਾ ਹੈਤੇ (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ) ਆਪਣੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਕਿਸ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ (ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ (ਦੇ ਨਾਮ) ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਵੇ? ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਪਰੇ ਤੋਂ ਪਰੇ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਅਪਹੰੁਚ ਹੈ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤਕ ਗਿਆਨ-ਇੰਦ੍ਰਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਹੰੁਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਸਕਦੀ । (ਬੱਸ!) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ (ਹੀ) ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੰੁਦੀ ਹੈ) ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦੀ ਕਦਰ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿਸੇ ਵਿਰਲੇ ਨੂੰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮੇਹਰ ਨਾਲ (ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ) ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਉੱਚੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉੱਚੇ ਜੀਵਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਕੋਈ (ਵਿਰਲਾ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ) ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸ਼ਬਦ ਦੀ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਵਿਚ (ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦਾ) ਦੁੱਖ ਰੋਗ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ,  ਜਦੋਂ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤਦੋਂ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਦੁੱਖ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਨਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਹੀ ਕਰਮ ਕਮਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਜੋ ਦੁੱਖ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਨ, (ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ) ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਦੇ ਪਿਛੇ ਤੁਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਸਦਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਮਿਲਦੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ ।੩।(ਹੇ ਭਾਈ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ (ਇਕ ਐਸਾ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਹੈ ਜੋ) ਮਿੱਠਾ ਹੈ, ਬੜੇ ਰਸ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।ਪਰ ਉਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਇਹ ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ ਪੀਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਆਪ ਪਿਲਾਏ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ-ਜਲ ਦਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਹੈ, ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਨਾਮ-ਰੰਗਿ ਵਿਚ ਰੰਗੀਜ ਕੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉੱਚੀ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਵਸਥਾ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੩।੪੨।\\""},{"question":"Mene ne Wasan Kwaikwayo?","answer":"Kamar yadda sunan ya nuna; Wasan Kwaikwayo wasa ne da ake kwaikwayar wani abu wanda ka iya zama hali, ko wani aiki da wani mutum, jama’a, ko wata al’umma ke yi. Masana da dama sun yi rubutu a wannan fage na wasan kwaikwayo.Yahaya I.Y., Zariya M.S., Gusau S.M., da ‘Yar’aduwa T.M (1992), sun fassara shi da cewa, “Wasan kwaikwayo kamance ne na halaye ko yanayin rayuwa da mutane masu hikima su ke shirya gudanar da shi don jama’a su gani da idonsu, su samu nishaɗi da jin daɗi”.Wato shi wasan kwaikwayo wasa ne da ake shirya shi ta hanyar kwaikwayar yadda wasu jama’a ke yin wani abu, ko dai da nufin shi wasan ya zama hanyar gargaɗar mutane dangane da wani abu da zai cutar da su, ko kuma ya nishaɗantar da su, ko kuma ya ilimantar da su game da wani abu. Misali, idan muka ɗauki littafin wasan marafa na Abubakar Tunau, za mu ga cewa yana karantar da tsafta ne; wanda a ciki aka bayyana muhimmancin tsafta da kuma hatsarin rashin tsafta."},{"question":"Ngelinye ilanga ubaba wagqoka ihembe lakhe lishwabene ngobaengenakulilungiselwa noma engenakunikwa insimbi alilungise. Kwala noma ethi ucelaindodana yakhe ukuba imcelele umakoti amlungiselele, wathi usejahe emsebenziniyena. Uma ephumela ngaphandle abantu bayamangala ukubona uyise wabantuabagwilike kangaka, abahlala bebahle ngaso sonke isikhathi, engcole ngalolu hlobo.Abanye babaze bazibuze ukuthi ngabe akaqambi yini amanga uma ethi unguyisewabo na. Bayambona futhi ukuthi lo muntu uya ngokuya eguga kube sengathi akasadlinakudla lapho ehlala khona.Ngelinye ilanga ubaba ezihambela nje emgwaqeni bude buduze nalapho ehlala khonaedolobheni laseThekwini, abonwe omunye umuntu ohlala ngalapho ehlala khona,ambingelele maqede bese ethi wamuzwa exoxa indaba yakhe, wasecabanga ukuthiamfundise ukudlala ilotho.Wabe esemcela ukuba ake afike kuyena. Lavuma-ke leli khehla, wayeselinikainombolo yomuzi wakhe. Ngemuva kwezinsuku ezine, babonana. Baxoxa.Bavumelana. Wameluleka ukuthi idlalwa kanjani ilotho nokuthi kusetshenziswa maliniuma ufakela izinombolo ezingaki nokuthi idlalelwaphi.Wabuye wamtshela ukuthi kuvulwa nini kuvalwe nini nezinsuku okudlalwa ngazo.Wambuza ukuthi wake wawadlala yini amahhashi, waphendula ngokuthi: Qha! Kwasekusho ukuthi kufanele adlale naye izinsukwana ezimbalwa aze afunde kahle impela. 1. Kungani umlungu omkhulu athatha isinqumo sokufaka amakhamera efeminiuThusheleni ayengunogada kuyo?","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo:• UThusheleni wabamba imenenja ihamba nezimpahla ngaphandlekwemvume yomlungu omkhulu.√√/• Umlungu omkhulu wayefuna ukubamba izisebenzi ezingamasela."},{"question":" வினா: தமிழ் நாட்டின் வால்டர்ஸ்காட்டு என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர்.","answer":"வினா: தமிழ் நாட்டின் வால்டர்ஸ்காட்டு என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் கல்கி.கல்கி: கல்கி (9 செப்டம்பர் 1899 – 5 திசம்பர் 1954) புகழ் பெற்ற தமிழ் எழுத்தாளர் ஆவார். இரா. கிருஷ்ணமூர்த்தி என்ற இயற்பெயர் கொண்ட இவர் 35 சிறுகதைத் தொகுதிகள், புதினங்கள், கட்டுரைகள், பயணக்கட்டுரைகள் மற்றும் வாழ்க்கை வரலாற்று நூல்களை எழுதியுள்ளார். எனினும், மிகச் சிறந்த சமூக மற்றும் வரலாற்றுப் புதினங்களை எழுதியதற்காக பரவலாக அறியப்படுகிறார். இவர் எழுதிய பொன்னியின் செல்வன் புதினம் மிகப் புகழ் பெற்றதாகும். தன் படைப்புகள் மூலம் இந்திய தேசிய விடுதலை போராட்டத்திற்கும் பங்களித்திருக்கிறார். தியாகபூமி புதினம் திரைப்படமாகவும் எடுக்கப்பட்டது.வாழ்க்கைக் குறிப்புகல்கி 1899-ஆம் ஆண்டு செப்டம்பர் மாதம் 9-ம் தேதி பழைய சென்னை மாகாணத்தில் ஒன்றிணைந்த தஞ்சாவூர் மாவட்டத்தில் உள்ள மயிலாடுதுறை அருகே அமைந்த பட்டமங்களம் எனும் ஊரில் ஒரு பிராமணக் குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்தார். ஆரம்பப்பள்ளிப் படிப்பைத் தனது கிராமத்தில் முடித்த பிறகு அவர் திருச்சியில் உள்ள தேசிய உயர்நிலைப் பள்ளியில் சேர்ந்தார். 1921-இல் மகாத்மா காந்தியடிகள் ஒத்துழையாமை இயக்கத்தைத் துவக்கிய போது, அவரது கருத்துக்களால் ஈர்க்கப்பட்டு கல்கி தனது பள்ளிப்படிப்பைப் பாதியில் துறந்து இந்திய தேசிய காங்கிரசு கட்சியில் சேர்ந்தார். 1922-இல் சுதந்திரப் போராட்டத்தில் பங்கு பெற்றதற்காக ஓராண்டு சிறைத் தண்டனை அனுபவித்தார். 1923-இல் அவர் நவசக்தி என்னும் பத்திரிகையின் துணை ஆசிரியராகப் பணியாற்றினார். அவருடைய முதல் புத்தகம் ஏட்டிக்குப் போட்டி 1927-இல் வெளியானது.‘கல்கி’யின் படைப்புகள் நாட்டுடைமை ஆகிவிட்டமையால், அவருடைய பல படைப்புகள் இணையத்தில் பல தளங்களில் கிடைக்கின்றன.தமிழிசை வளர்ச்சிக்குப் பங்கு:சமசுகிருதமும் தியாகராஜரின் தெலுங்கு கீர்த்தனைகளும் பிரபலமாக இருந்து வந்த அக்காலகட்டத்தில் தமிழிசைக்காகக் கல்கி சதாசிவம் மற்றும் எம். எஸ். சுப்புலட்சுமியுடன் இணைந்து பாடுபட்டார் கல்கி. தமிழ் இசை குறித்த கல்கியின் சிந்தனைகளைத் \\"தரம் குறையுமா\\" எனும் புத்தக வடிவில் வானதி பதிப்பகம் வெளியிட்டுள்ளது.படைப்புகள்:புதினங்கள்:விக்கிமூலத்தில் பின்வரும் தலைப்பிலான எழுத்தாக்கம் உள்ளது:கல்கியின் படைப்புகள்:கள்வனின் காதலி (1937)தியாகபூமி (1938-1939)மகுடபதி (1942)அபலையின் கண்ணீர் (1947)சோலைமலை இளவரசி (1947)அலை ஓசை (1948)தேவகியின் கணவன் (1950)மோகினித்தீவு (1950)பொய்மான் கரடு (1951)புன்னைவனத்துப் புலி (1952)அமரதாரா (1954)வரலாற்று புதினங்கள்சிவகாமியின் சபதம் (1944 – 1946)[1]பார்த்திபன் கனவு (1941 - 1943)பொன்னியின் செல்வன் (1951 – 1954)[2]சிறுகதைகள்:சுபத்திரையின் சகோதரன்ஒற்றை ரோஜாதீப்பிடித்த குடிசைகள்புது ஓவர்சியர்வஸ்தாது வேணுஅமர வாழ்வுசுண்டுவின் சந்நியாசம்திருடன் மகன் திருடன்இமயமலை எங்கள் மலைபொங்குமாங்கடல்மாஸ்டர் மெதுவடைபுஷ்பப் பல்லக்கு"},{"question":"Trả lời câu hỏi sau, số đối của 8 là:A. – 8B. 0C. 8D. 16","answer":"Lời giảiTa có số đối của 8 là – 8.Chọn đáp án A."},{"question":"问题：冰块是如何制作的？","answer":"回答：冰块可以通过将水倒入冰盒或冰格中，然后放入冰箱冷冻而制作。"},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Togo nékk","answer":"Réwum Tchad mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Afrique"},{"question":"નીચેના શબ્દસમૂહ માટે એક શબ્દ આપો:આંખ સાથે આંખ મળી થતી પ્રીતિ","answer":"તારામૈત્રક "},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 最低賃金は、会社などが働く人に払ういちばん低い賃金です。厚生労働省の会議で7月、1時間の最低賃金を都道府県の平均で41円上げる目標が決まりました。この会議のあと、都道府県は会議を開いて、働く人と会社の代表などが最低賃金について話し合っています。東京都は7日に会議を開いて、最低賃金を41円上げて、１時間1113円にすることを決めました。41円上がるのは、東京都で初めてです。今年の10月から上がる予定です。この会議の会長は「最低賃金で働く人たちの生活のために、上げる必要があると考えました。払う賃金が増えて困る会社のことを東京都が助けてほしいと思います」と話していました。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- 賃金: 1）働いた人が、その働きに対してもらうお金。- 厚生労働省: 1）国民の健康や生活を守る仕事や、労働者が仕事を見つけるのを助けたり、労働者を保護したりする国の役所。厚労省。- 都道府県: 1）全国を47に分けた区画。東京都・北海道・大阪府・京都府と、43の県。- 平均: 1）多い少ないや高い低いなどの差がないようにすること。2）二つ以上の数や量の中間の数や量。3）つり合いがとれること。バランス。- 目標: 1）ものごとをなしとげるための目当て。2）行きつくための目じるし。- 代表: 1）多くの人に代わって何かをすること。また、その人。2）一部分で全体の特色を表すこと。また、そのもの。- 話し合っ: 1）たがいに話す。おたがいに相手の話を聞き、自分も話す。2）意見を出し合う。- 会長: 1）会を代表する人。- 助け: 1）危ないことや苦しいことから救う。2）力を貸す。手伝う。"},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Ngày 31/7, Cơ quan CSĐT Công an tỉnh Cà Mau khởi tố bị can, bắt tạm giam Đặng Hải Đăng (sinh năm 1966, Giám đốc CDC Cà Mau); Hồ Quang Nhu, Phó trưởng Phòng Kế hoạch – Nghiệp vụ thuộc CDC Cà Mau và Lê Ngọc Định, Trưởng Phòng Kế hoạch - Tài chính, Sở Y tế Cà Mau để điều tra về hành vi \\"Vi phạm quy định về đấu thầu gây hậu quả nghiêm trọng\\" quy định tại khoản 3 Điều 222 BLHS. Theo Công an Cà Mau, từ tháng 1/2020 đến tháng 10/2021, Sở Y tế, CDC Cà Mau và Bệnh viện đa khoa tỉnh thực hiện 11 gói thầu mua kit xét nghiệm COVID-19, máy tách chiết DNA/RNA tự động, hóa chất, sinh phẩm và thiết bị phục vụ công tác phòng chống dịch COVID-19 của Công ty Việt Á, với số tiền hơn 49 tỷ đồng. Quá trình thực hiện hồ sơ đấu thầu, Lê Ngọc Định, Đặng Hải Đăng và Hồ Quang Nhu thực hiện không đúng quy định về đấu thầu \\"không bảo đảm công bằng, minh bạch\\", vi phạm các hành vi bị cấm trong đấu thầu quy định tại khoản 6 Điều 89 Luật Đấu thầu; gây thiệt hại cho ngân sách nhà nước. Trong đó, Sở Y tế Cà Mau mua kit xét nghiệm COVID-19 của Công ty Việt Á cao hơn so với chi phí sản xuất (đã bao gồm 5% lợi nhuận và chi phí khác), dẫn đến thiệt hại khoảng hơn 9,1 tỷ đồng. CDC Cà Mau mua kit xét nghiệm COVID-19 của Công ty Việt Á cao hơn so với giá của chi phí sản xuất (đã bao gồm 5% lợi nhuận và chi phí khác), dẫn đến thiệt hại khoảng hơn 3 tỷ đồng. Hiện vụ án đang được Công an tỉnh Cà Mau tiếp tục điều tra làm rõ.","answer":"Bắt tạm giam Giám đốc CDC tỉnh Cà Mau"},{"question":"பின்வரும் மின்னஞ்சல் ஸ்பேமா அல்லது உண்மையான அஞ்சலா என கண்டறியவும். ஆம் அல்லது இல்லை என பதிலளிக்கவும்.\\"நீங்கள் 100 ஆயிரம் டாலர்களை வென்றுள்ளீர்கள். அந்தத் தொகையைப்பெற உங்கள் கிரெடிட் கார்டு எண்ணை எங்களுக்கு அனுப்புங்கள்.\\"","answer":"ஆம்."},{"question":"Mabisa ba ang pag-ubo sa paghinto ng atake sa puso?","answer":"Hindi. Walang ebidensiya na mababawasan ng pag-ubo ang mga panganib ng atake sa puso."},{"question":"ગિજુભાઈ બધેકાની \\"આ તે શી માથાફોડ !\\" પુસ્તકનુ એક લેખન નીચે મુજબ આપેલ છે.\\"મારી બચલી ! કાંઇ ડાહી છે બા ! ઘરનું એક રમકડુંય પાડોશીને ત્યાં જવા ન દે. ઊલટું ત્યાં ગઇ હોય તો એકાદ ઉપાડી આવે !⁠બા, કાંઇ હોશિયાર છે ! કદીયે ઘરની એકે વાત કોઇ ને ન કહે. પૂછે તો ઊલટું ઊંધું કહે !⁠બા કાંઇ સમજુ ! પારકાં ઇ પારકાં ને પોતાનાં ઇ પોતાનાં. બરાબર પોતા-પારકાનો ભેદ સમજે છે.⁠બા, કાંઇ ચતુર ! આપણે કહીએ કે કાકીમાને કહેજે કે ઘરમાં કોઇ નથી તો એવું ઠાવકું મોં રાખીને બોલે કે એમ જ લાગે કે બચલી સાવ સાચું બોલતી હશે !\\"આજ રીતની \\"માથાફોડ\\" પર આવુ જ બીજુ લેખન લખો. ","answer":"મારી બચલી તો બા, સાવ ભાન વગરની છે. આટલાં બધા રમકડાં આણ્યાં, પણ ભાઇબંધોને જ આપી દે છે !⁠બા, એ તો સાવ ભોટ જેવી; સમજે જ ત્યારે કે ? ઘરમાં જે થાય તે બહાર જઇને કહી આવે; પેટમાં શું રખાય, બીજાને શું કહેવાય એની ખબર જ પડે તો કે ?⁠બા, ઇ તો સાવ અજડ જેવી; આ આપણું ને આ નહિ, એટલીયે ખબર ન મળે ! કો'ક આવે તો આ પાથરીને બેસે ને જે માગે તે આપે.⁠બા, ઇ તો તમારે સાવ ભોળી ભટાક ! જરા ય ખોટું ​બોલતાં આવડે તો કે ? જેવું મનમાં એવું મોઢે. ઊલટાં આપણને પાડોશી આગળ ખોટાં પાડે !"},{"question":"Күңгөй","answer":"Тоонун кун тийген тарабын күңгөй деп аталат"},{"question":"Cite um criatura marinha que tem a capacidade de se clonar.","answer":"Água-viva. Quando as águas-vivas são cortadas ao meio, elas têm a capacidade de regenerar suas células e criar outras águas-vivas."},{"question":"Tusidee to n bọ ni wọn yoo sinku ọmọ Baba Adeboye","answer":"Bi gbogbo nnkan ba lọ bi wọn ṣe ṣeto rẹ, ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ to n bọ ni wọn yoo sinku Pasitọ Deji Adeboye, ọmọ Olori ijọ Ridiimu, Pasitọ Adejare Adeboye.Ninu atẹjade kan ti aburo oloogbe naa to tun jẹ oluranlọwọ pataki fun Baba Adeboye, Leke Adeboye, fi sita lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, opin ọsẹ yii, lo ti ni ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọjọ kẹsan-an, oṣu yii, ni isin pataki yoo waye fun oloogbe naa ni City of David Youth Church, Eket, nipinlẹ Akwa Ibom.Ni Mọnde, ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu yii, kan naa ni isin pataki ati ọrọ iwuri nipa oloogbe yoo waye ni RCCG, House of Favour, Redemption Camp.Ọjọ kọkanla, oṣu yii, ni deede aago mẹwaa aarọ, ni isin idagbere yoo waye Youth Centre, Redemption Camp, nipinlẹ Ogun. Lẹyin eyi ni wọn yoo fi eeru fun eeru, yeepẹ fun yeepẹ.Leke fi ẹmi imoore rẹ han fun adura, aduroti ati atilẹyin ti awọn eeyan n fi ranṣẹ latigba ti iṣẹlẹ ibanujẹ naa ti ṣẹlẹ. O ni awọn mọ riri atilẹyin awọn eeyan. Ohun to si dun mọ awọn ninu ni pe arakunrin awọn ti lọ sọdọ Olugbala lati sinmi laya Ẹledaa rẹ.O ni igbe aye rere ti Dare gbe ati fifi ara jin fun iṣẹ Ọlọrun jẹ ohun idunnu fun awọn."},{"question":"ආවේණික ලක්ෂණ පරම්පරාගත වන බව සොයාගැනීම නිසා , \\" ප්‍රවේණි විද්‍යාවේ පියා \\" ලෙස බුහුමන් ලබන විද්‍යාඥයා කවුද ?","answer":"ආවේණික ලක්ෂණ පරම්පරාගත වන බව සොයාගැනීම නිසා , \\" ප්‍රවේණි විද්‍යාවේ පියා \\" ලෙස බුහුමන් ලබන විද්‍යාඥයා වන්ඔනේ ස්ට්‍රියානු ජාතික , ග්‍රෙගරි මෙන්ඩල් පියතුමා ය. "},{"question":"Nitori ere asapajude, ajọ ẹsọ oju popo mu mọto akero marundinlogoji","answer":"Ileeṣẹ ijọba to n mojuto irinna ọkọ loju popo (FRSC), Ọgbẹni Oluṣẹgun Ogungbemide, ti sọ pe awọn mọto akero marundinlogoji (35) lọwọ awọn ti ba bayii, nitori ti awọn to ni wọn ko tẹle aṣẹ ijọba nipa lilo ẹrọ to le din ere asapajude ku.Ogungbemide ṣalaye ọrọ yii  fawọn oniroyin lẹyin ipade to ṣe pẹlu awọn onimoto ti wọn n na Eko si Ibadan. O ni o ṣe pataki fun wọn lati maa lo ẹrọ ti yoo maa ṣadinku ere asapajude to wọpọ laarin awọn onimọto ero.Ogungbemide fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe aṣẹ ti ajọ naa n tẹle bayii ni i ṣe pelu ohun ti ọga agba ajọ to n ri si irinna oju popo, Dokita Boboye Oyeyẹmi, sọ, paapaa lori akiyesi bi ọpọ ẹmi ṣe n ṣofo latari ere isakusa lasiko ayẹyẹ ọdun.O ni, “A ko ni i gbe mọto yẹn fawọn to ni wọn ti wọn ko ba fi ẹrọ ti yoo maa din ere asapajude ku si i, koda, ki wọn sanwo itanran fun ijọba. O ṣe pataki ki gbogbo mọto akero ni in, bẹẹ la o ni i faaye gba aitẹle ofin ọhun latọwọ ẹnikẹni.”Bakan naa lo rọ awọn onimọto lati ṣe pẹlẹ, ki wọn si tun pa ofin ati ilana itankalẹ àrùn koronafairọọsi mọ dáadáa lẹnu iṣẹ wọn."},{"question":"Qual foi a música de estreia de Kelly Clarkson?","answer":"O single de estreia de Kelly Clarkson foi \\"A Moment Like This\\""},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari biyu da arba'in a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 240"},{"question":"ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਵਾਕ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਨਾਂਵ ਚੁਣੋ । ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਕਿਸਮ ਵੀ ਦੱਸੋਹਰ ਚਮਕਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਚੀਜ਼ ਸੋਨਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ।","answer":"ਚੀਜ਼, ਸੋਨਾ ।"},{"question":"السؤال: من النبي الذي قام بكفالة مريم بنت عمران؟","answer":"الجواب: نبي الله زكريا عليه السلام."},{"question":"Како се зове српски кошаркаш који је први освоијо титулу најбољег играча (МВП) НБА лиге?","answer":"Никола Јокић је први српски кошаркаш освајача признања за најбољег играча НБА лиге. Он је награду за најбољег играча регуларне сезоне освајао у сезонама 2020-21 и 2021-22, док је награду за најбољег играча финалне серије освоијо у сезони 2022-23."},{"question":"Question: The instrument which is used for the measurement of blood pressure is known as what?a. Oxymeterb. Thermometerc. Sphygmomanometerd. Glucometer","answer":"Answer:(c) SphygmomanometerFurther notes:A sphygmomanometer is used for the measurement of blood pressure."},{"question":"Кибер коопсуздук деген эмне?","answer":"Кибер коопсуздук - бул компьютердик тутумдарды, тармактарды жана данныйларды кылмышкерлерден, вирустардан жана башка коркунучтуу күчөтүүлөрдөн коргоо иш-аракеттеринин жыйындысы.Кибер коопсуздук төмөнкү негизги элементтерди камтыйт:Данныйлардын конфиденциалдуулугу - данныйларды уруксатсыз колдонуудан коргоо.Данныйлардын жеткиликтүүлүгү - маалыматка уруксаты бар колдонуучулар гана жете алышын камсыз кылуу.Данныйлардын туруктуулугу - данныйлардын толуктугун жана аныктыгын сактоо.Тармактын иштеликтүүлүгү - тармактын узакка созулган бөгөттөрсүз иштешин камсыз кылуу.Кибер коопсуздук системасы бузуучулардан коргоо үчүн төмөнкү чараларды камтыйт: фаерволдор, антивирустук программалар, кирүүнү башкаруу системалары, шифрлөө ж.б.Кибер коопсуздук маселелери учурда өтө маанилүү жана аларды чечүү зарыл."},{"question":"ब्याज दरले अर्थतन्त्रमा उधारो र खर्चलाई कसरी असर गर्छ?","answer":"ब्याज दरहरूमा परिवर्तनहरूले उधारो लागत, उपभोक्ता खर्च, व्यापार लगानी, र समग्र आर्थिक गतिविधिलाई असर गर्छ।"},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： アフガニスタンの人のために長い間活動していた中村哲さんは、3年前の12月4日、銃で撃たれて亡くなりました。73歳でした。東京にあるアフガニスタン大使館で4日、中村さんのために祈る式がありました。中村さんが活動していたNGOの「ペシャワール会」や大使館の人など70人ぐらいが集まりました。式では、中村さんがアフガニスタンの人と一緒に、乾いた土地を畑に変える活動をしているビデオを見ました。アフガニスタンのアブダリ大使は「今、私たちの国は難しい時代になっていますが、中村さんの活動を続けなければなりません」と話しました。アフガニスタンを支配しているタリバンは、中村さんの事件について調べていると言っています。しかし、誰が撃ったのかまだわかっていません。","answer":"中村哲さんが亡くなって3年　東京の大使館で多くの人が祈る"},{"question":"Toko-toko di dalam mallnya bagus, tapi toilet dan mushalanya sangat mengerikan. Toilet di setiap lantai hanya 1 sehingga selalu ada antrian panjang, drainase air yang buruk, toilet dan musala yang sangat kotor dan bau. Ini sangat mengecewakan untuk apa yang disebut mal kelas atas.Apakah klasifikasi sentimen dari kalimat ulasan di atas (Positif/Negatif/Netral)?Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya.Jawaban:","answer":"Kalimat tersebut dapat diklasifikasikan sebagai sentimen negatif. Alasannya adalah terdapat kata-kata bermakna negatif seperti: sangat mengerikan; buruk; kotor dan bau; mengecewakan."},{"question":"Ответьте на вопрос: какие республики входили в состав Советского Союза?","answer":"Советский Союз включал в себя 15 союзных республик:- РСФСР (Российская Советская Федеративная Социалистическая Республика) - современная Российская Федерация,- Украинская ССР (Украинская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Украина,- Белорусская ССР (Белорусская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Республика Беларусь,- Грузинская ССР (Грузинская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Грузия,- Азербайджанская ССР (Азербайджанская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современный Азербайджан,- Армянская ССР (Армянская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Армения,- Казахская ССР (Казахская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современный Казахстан,- Узбекская ССР (Узбекская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современный Узбекистан,- Таджикская ССР (Таджикская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современный Таджикистан,- Туркменская ССР (Туркменская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Туркмения,- Киргизская ССР (Киргизская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Киргизия (Кыргызстан),- Молдавская ССР (Молдавская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Молдова,- Литовская ССР (Литовская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Литва,- Латвийская ССР (Латвийская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Латвия,- Эстонская ССР (Эстонская Советская Социалистическая Республика) - современная Эстония."},{"question":"Ny “tendry” dia baiko na didy manondro olona hanatanteraka asa mazava iray, na manondro andraikitra horaisina, na manondro toerana haleha. Anjara manokana azon’ny olona ka mahatonga azy hiavaka amin’ny hafa ao anaty fiarahamonina.  Avy amin’Andriamanitra ny tendry; antso manokana mba hanatanterahana andraikitra. Eo amin’ny fiarahamonina ankehitriny: dia hita ihany fa misy ny fanendrena ataon’ny manam-pahefana eo amin’ireo ambany fifehezany.  Na ihany koa avy amin’ny feon’ny vahoaka ny tendry.Misy hevi-dehibe roa ao amin'io lahatsoratra io , inona  avy izany ?","answer":"Ireto avy ny hevi-dehibe roa ao amin'io lahatsoratra io : 1) Famaritana ny atao hoe Tendry. 2) Ny loharano nipoirany Tendry ."},{"question":"السؤال: ما الفرق بين القاعدتين السابقتين؟","answer":"الإجابة: الشخص الذي يقع في غلط بالقانون يريد تطبيق النص القانوني لكنه أخطأ بالحكم الصحيح بسبب توهم، بينما الذي يدفع بالجهل بالقانون يريد استبعاد النص القانوني وعدم تطبيقه بحجة كونه يجهل النص."},{"question":"\\"एक चिहान\\" उपन्यासका आधारमा दिइएका पात्रको चरित्र चित्रण गर्नुहोस् : नानीथकुँ।","answer":"नानीथकुँ उपन्यासमा प्रमुख नारी पात्रका रुपमा परिचित छे । ऊ अष्टनारानकी छोरी र शिवनारानहरुकी बहिनी हो। गोरो अनुहार १७ वर्षे सारै हिसी परेकी बैंसले धप्प बलेकी सुन्दरी छे। सरल र निश्चल भएकीले डा. गोदत्तप्रसादको बलात्कारको सिकार भएकी छे। ऊ सकारात्मक छे। उसले तराईबासी खेलावन राउतसँग अन्तर जातीय विवाह गर्छे। ऊ बलात्कृत भई कुमारीत्वबाट नानीथकुँ बञ्चित भएकी छ।"},{"question":"ගඟක් මුහුදට වැටෙන ස්ථානය  යන්නට තනි වචනයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"මෝය "},{"question":"கேள்வி : நரி, முதலையிடம் என்ன கூறியது?","answer":"பதில் :  1. “இதற்கு முன் ஒரு முதலை, விலங்குகளைச் சாப்பிட்டதால் செரிமானம் ஆகாமல் இறந்துவிட்டது.”2. “விஷ முறிவுச் செடிகளை நாங்கள் தின்றுள்ளதால், எங்களை யார் கடித்தாலும் அவர்கள் இறந்துவிடுவர்” என்று நரி முதலையிடம் கூறியது."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Sau khi lực lượng Bắc Triều Tiên tấn công xuống lãnh thổ Nam Triều Tiên vào ngày 25 tháng 6 năm 1950, khiến","answer":"xung đột bùng nổ, Hoa Kỳ và các nước Đồng Minh đã can thiệp nhân danh lực lượng Liên Hợp Quốc. Sau khi bị bất ngờ, Tổng thống Harry S. Truman đã nhanh chóng phản ứng, ra lệnh gửi lực lượng và phương tiện đang trú đóng tại Nhật Bản đến giúp đỡ lực lượng Nam Triều Tiên, cùng với một lực lượng hải quân lớn đế khu vực để hỗ trợ. Như một phần của việc huy động lực lượng hải quân, \\"Iowa\\" được cho hoạt động trở lại vào ngày 14 tháng 7 năm 1951 và chính thức nhập biên chế vào ngày 25 tháng 8 năm 1951 dưới quyền chỉ huy của Hạm trưởng, Đại tá hải quân William R. Smedberg, III. Chiếc thiết giáp hạm đi đến vùng biển Triều Tiên vào tháng 3 năm 1952, nơi nó thay phiên cho tàu chị em vào ngày 1 tháng 4, và trở thành soái hạm cho Phó đô đốc Robert P. Briscoe, Tư lệnh Đệ Thất hạm đội."},{"question":"第一句:它是紫色灯光和戏剧性的阳光的精彩演变. 第二句:这是紫色灯光和<unk>烂的阳光的戏剧性复制. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"Iza no nahazo Loka Oscar tamin'ny alalan'ny African Queen ? ","answer":"I Bogart no nahazo ny loka oscar tamin'ny alalan'ny african queen. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ayam pemikat\\"?","answer":"Orang yang dijadikan sebagai umpan"},{"question":"Zer dira antiossidanteak eta zein da beren funtzioa?","answer":"Antiossidanteak kimika konposatuak dira, zelula kaltetuei erresistentzia ematen dutenak. Hauen funtzio nagusia radikal libreak neutralizatzea da, gaixotasun batzuk prebenitzeko."},{"question":"వెజిటబుల్ రైస్ తయారీ ప్రక్రియను రాయండి.","answer":"వెజిటబుల్ రైస్ కి కావలసిన పదార్ధాలు మరియు తయారీ విధానం:కావలసిన పదార్థాలు : బియ్యం, ఉల్లిపాయ, టమోటా, పచ్చి బఠానీలు, క్యారెట్, దాల్చిన చెక్క లవంగాలు, పసుపు పొడి, కారం పొడి, మసాలా పొడి, కొత్తిమీర, నూనె, నెయ్యి, ఉప్పు మరియు నీరు.తయారీ విధానం :1. బియ్యం కడిగి 10 నుండి 15 నిమిషాలు నానబెట్టండి.2. మంట మీద పాత్రను ఉంచండి. అందులో రెండు చెంచాల నెయ్యి, నూనె పోయాలి.3. దాల్చిన చెక్క, లవంగం మరియు ఉల్లిపాయ వేసి గోధుమ రంగు వచ్చేవరకు వేడి చేయాలి.4. తరిగిన టమోటా, గ్రీన్ బఠానీలు, క్యారెట్ జోడించండి.5. కదిలిస్తూ రెండు లేదా మూడు నిమిషాలు వేయించాలి.6. నానబెట్టిన బియ్యం, గరం మసాలా పొడి, పసుపు పొడి, కారం పొడి మరియు ఉప్పు కలపండి.7. కదిలిస్తూ 2 లేదా 3 నిమిషాలు వేయించాలి.8. తరువాత 1 లేదా 2 కప్పులు నీరు వేసి బాగా కలపాలి.9. కుక్కర్ ను మూతతో మూసివేసి, 2 విజిల్స్ కోసం మీడియం మంట మీద ఉడికించాలి.10. మంటను ఆపివేయండి. గది ఉష్ణోగ్రత వద్ద చల్లబరచండి.11. మూత జాగ్రత్తగా తెరిచి, వడ్డించే గిన్నెకు బదిలీ చేసి, తాజా కొత్తిమీరతో అలంకరించండి."},{"question":"ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසියේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය පිහිටා  ඇත්තේ කොහේද? ","answer":"ජාත්‍යන්තර පොලිසියේ ප්‍රධාන කාර්යාලය ප්‍රංශයේ පිහිටා  ඇත."},{"question":"2022 ඩි වෛද්‍ය විද්‍යාව සඳහා නොබෙල් ත්‍යාගය දිනා ගත්තේ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"Svante Pääbo විද්‍යාඥයා"},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా పద్యం రాయండి:చూసేవారు భయపడేటట్లుగా నీటిలో భయంకరంగా ఒక మొసలి కంటికి కనపడకుండా వచ్చి శిష్యులంతా బెదిరేటట్లుగా ద్రోణుని పిక్కను వెంటనే పట్టుకుంది.","answer":"క. వెఱచఱవ నీరిలో నాక్కె నొక మొసలి చూడ్కికి నగోచర మైపఱతెంచి కుంభసంభవుచిఱుతొడ వడిఁ బట్టిఁ కొనియె శిష్యులు బెదరన్."},{"question":"সবুজ আলোতে হলুদ ফুলের রঙ কি?","answer":"একটি হলুদ ফুল হলুদ দেখায় কারণ এটি শুধুমাত্র হলুদ আলো প্রতিফলিত করে এবং অন্য সব তরঙ্গদৈর্ঘ্যের আলো শোষণ করে। তাই যদি সবুজ আলো এটির উপর পড়ে তবে এটি সবুজ আলোকে শোষণ করবে এবং কোন তরঙ্গদৈর্ঘ্যের আলো প্রতিফলিত করবে না তাই সবুজ আলোর নীচে একটি হলুদ ফুল কালো দেখাবে।"},{"question":"Belém é capital de qual estado brasileiro?","answer":"Pará."},{"question":"දෙසැම්බර් 27 ගැන කථා කරමු.","answer":"දෙසැම්බර් 27, ග්‍රෙගරි දින දසුනට අනුව අවුරුද්දේ 361 වන දිනය වේ (අධික අවුරුද්දක නම් 362 වන දිනය). අවුරුද්ද අවසන් වීමට තවත් දින සතරක් ඇත."},{"question":"Ṣe àpilẹ̀kọ àyọkà fún àkòrí yìí: T.B Joshua: Ọjọ́ ìbí ayọ̀ fún mi àmọ́ ń kò ní lè ṣe ayẹyẹ ọjọ́ ìbí náà.","answer":"Ọjọ́ kejìlá, oṣù Òkudù, ló yẹ kí Wòlíì Tèmítọ́pẹ́ Balógun Joshua ṣe ọjọ́ ìbí ọdún méjìdínlọ́gọ́ta rẹ̀ lókè eèpẹ̀. Ṣùgbọ́n ó ṣeni láànú pé ó kú ní ọjọ́ karùn-ún, oṣù Òkudù, ṣáájú ọjọ́ náà, nígbà tó ku ọ̀sẹ̀ kan péré kí ọjọ́ náà kò. Àmọ́ ǹkan tó tún jẹ́ ìyàlẹ́nu ni pé, wòlíì náà ti sọ nípa ọjọ́-ìbí rẹ̀ pé òun kò ní ṣe ayẹyẹ kankan ní ọdún yìí. Nínu fídíò kan tó jáde sórí ayélujára lẹ́yìn ikú rẹ̀, Joshua ń kọ orin ọjọ́ ìbí fún ara rẹ̀ pé \\"Happy Birthday to you....\\" Níbẹ̀ náà ló sì ti kéde pé òun kò ní ṣe ayẹyẹ ọjọ́-ìbí kankan ní ọdún yìí nítorí pé àwọn ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ tó ń wáyé ní àgbáyé kò dùn mọ́ òun nínú. Ó ní \\"kò ní rọrùn fún mi láti ṣe àjọyọ̀ ọjọ́-ìbí mi, nítorí pé ọ̀pọ̀ èèyàn tó fẹ́ẹ̀ wà ní wàhálà àti ìdàmú tó ń ṣẹlẹ̀ ní àgbáyé ń bani nínú jẹ́. Ìbànújẹ àti ìbẹ̀rù wọ́n kàn mí. Nítorí náà, ẹ jẹ́ kí á fi ọjọ́ náà ṣe ọjọ́ àwẹ̀ àti ádùrá, kẹ́ẹ má sì gbàgbé àwọn aláìní.\\" Ó ní \\"lágbára Ọlọ́run, ọ̀pọ̀ ayẹyẹ ọjọ́-ìbí sì wà níwájú fún mi táa máa ṣe.\\" Bó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé ó kọ orin ọjọ́-ìbí fún ara rẹ̀ nínu fídíò náà, olóògbé T.B Joshua sọ pé ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ọjọ́-ìbí ló sì wà níwájú láti ṣe. Nígbà ayé rẹ̀, ẹlẹ́yinjú àánú, olóore àti olùfifúnni ni ọ̀pọ̀ èèyàn mọ̀ọ́ sí, pàápàá àwọn olólùfẹ́ rẹ̀. Ǹkan yìí náà sì ni àwọn èèyàn kan ń sọ nípa rẹ̀ l'órí ayélujára."},{"question":"Qual foi o maior goleador do Brasileirão no ano de 2022?","answer":"No Campeonato Brasileiro de 2022, o maior goleador foi Germán Cano conhecido como Cano, do Fluminense. Ele marcou um total de 26 gols durante o torneio."},{"question":"ฟ้าผ่าเกิดจากอะไร","answer":"เกิดจากการปลดปล่อยประจุไฟฟ้าออกจากเมฆฝนฟ้าคะนอง หรือ เมฆคิวมูโลนิมบัส (cumulonimbus)"},{"question":"வினா : கீழ்க்கடவற்றுள் ஆவி என்ற சொல்லின் பொருள் யாது? அ) உயிர்ஆ) மரம்இ) குதிரைஈ) உடல்","answer":"விடை : அ) உயிர்"},{"question":"అతిశయోక్త్యలంకారం గురించి వివరించి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"అతిశయోక్త్యలంకారం :లక్షణం :ఒక వస్తువు గురించి గాని, ఒక సందర్భాన్ని గురించి గాని, ఉన్నదానికంటే ఎక్కువగా చేసి చెప్పినట్లయితే దాన్ని ‘అతిశయోక్త్యలంకారం’ అని అంటారు.ఉదాహరణ 1:నగరంలోని భవనాలు నక్షత్రాలను తాకుతున్నాయి.సమన్వయం :పై ఉదాహరణ వాక్యంలో నగరంలోని మేడలు మిక్కిలి ఎత్తయినవి అని చెప్పడానికి బదులుగా నక్షత్రాలను తాకుచున్నాయని ఎక్కువగా చేసి చెప్పడం జరిగింది. అందువల్ల దీన్ని ‘అతిశ యోక్త్యలంకారం’ అని అంటారు.ఉదాహరణ 2:మా చెల్లెలు తాటిచెట్టంత పొడవుంది.దేవాలయ గోపురాలు ఆకాశానికంటుతున్నాయి.పై వాక్యాల్లో చెల్లె ఎత్తును, గోపురాల ఎత్తులను ఉన్న ఎత్తు కంటే ఎక్కువచేసి చెప్పడం జరిగింది కదా! అంటే అతిశయంగా చెప్పడం అన్నమాట. ఇలా చెప్పటాన్ని అతిశయోక్తి అంటారు.ఉదాహరణ 3 :కం. చుక్కలు తల పూవులుగాఅక్కజముగ మేనుపెంచి యంబర వీధిన్ వెక్కసమై చూపట్టినఅక్కోమలి ముదము నొందె ఆత్మస్థితిలోన్.ఇక్కడ చుక్కలను తల పూలుగా చేసుకొని, ఆకాశమంత ఎత్తు పెరిగాడని, హనుమంతుడిని గూర్చి ఎక్కువగాచేసి చెప్పడం జరిగింది. అందువల్ల ఇక్కడ అతిశయోక్తి అలంకారం ఉన్నది.ఉదాహరణ 4:మా పొలంలో బంగారం పండింది. సాధారణంగా పొలంలో పంట పండుతుంది. కాని బాగా పంట పండిందనే విషయాన్ని తెలియ జేయడానికి బంగారం పండిందని ఎక్కువగా చేసి చెప్పడం జరిగింది. అందువల్ల ఇక్కడ అతిశయోక్తి అలంకారం ఉన్నది."},{"question":"Mubvunzo: zita guru remapfupa ose ari mumusoro nderekuti Mhinduro:","answer":"dehenya"},{"question":"නිදහස් අධ්‍යාපනයේ පියා නම් කරන්න.","answer":"නිදහස් අධ්‍යාපනයේ පියා සී. ඩබ්ලිව්. ඩබ්ලිව්. කන්නන්ගර මහතාය."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి:వాయు అణువుల స్వేచ్ఛాంశ అనగా ఏమి?","answer":"ఒక వ్యవస్థలోని కణములు మొత్తము ఎన్ని స్వతంత్ర పద్ధతులలో శక్తిని గ్రహించగలవో ఆ సంఖ్యను స్వేచ్ఛాంశలు అని అంటారు.ఉదా: అంతరాళములో స్వేచ్ఛగా చలించగల కణమునకు 3 స్థానాంతర స్వేచ్ఛాంశలు ఉండును.ఏక పరమాణుక వాయువుల లోని అణువులకు 3 స్థానాంతర స్వేచ్ఛాంశలు మాత్రమే ఉండును. ద్విపరమాణుక వాయువులలోని అణువులకు 3 స్థానాంతర, 2 భ్రమణ చలన అనగా మొత్తము 5 స్వేచ్ఛాంశలు ఉండును."},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay fiara be mpividy izay tsy maintsy novaina ny anarany vao afaka novarotana tao espana noho ny dikan'ilay anarana amin'ny fiteny tany ?","answer":"Ny anaran'ilay fiara nalaza sy be mpividy izay tsy maintsy novaina ny anarany vao afaka novarotana tao espana dia ny 'Nova' izay midika hoe tsy mandeha raha adika amin'ny fiteny espaniola. "},{"question":"ما هي السورة التي تسمى (الساهرة) أو (الطامة)؟","answer":"سورة النازعات"},{"question":"Quelle est une astuce pour mieux dormir la nuit ?","answer":"Manger des noix, du miel ou un yogourt ! Ces aliments ont des composantes qui favorisent le sommeil."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital de Caldas, Colombia?","answer":"La capital del departamento de Caldas es la ciudad de Manizales."},{"question":"வினா:தான் அறியாத ஒன்றை அறிந்து கொள்வதற்காக வினவுவது ……………………………..அ) அறிவினாஆ) அறியாவினாஇ) ஐயவினாஈ) ஏவல் வினா","answer":"விடை :ஆ) அறியாவினா"},{"question":"Milloin jogurttia saa mainostaa kreikkalaiseksi?","answer":"Jogurttia saa mainostaa kreikkalaiseksi, josjogurtti on valmistettu Kreikassa, jolloin se kuvaa elintarvikkeen alkuperämaata taijogurtin ainesosan koostumus ja maku muistuttaa kyseisessä maassa yleisesti valmistettua ja nautittua jogurttia. Tällöin esimerkiksi kreikkalaisenjogurtin nimi on yleiseen käyttöön vakiintunut nimi, jonka valmistukseen on käytetty mikrobiviljelmää, hapatetta, joka antaa kyseisen maan jogurtille ominaisen luonteen."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Salaada Faralka (Waajib) Ah Oo Haweenka Waajib Ku Ahayn?","answer":"Jawaab: Waa Salaada Jimcaha Ah."},{"question":"వర్తకము అంటే ఏమిటి?","answer":"వస్తువుల కొనుగోలు, అమ్మకాల ప్రక్రియను వర్తకము అంటారు. వర్తకము వాణిజ్యములో ప్రధాన భాగము. వస్తు సేవల ఉత్పత్తిదారులు వాటిని వినియోగించే వినియోగదారుల వద్దకు చేర్చి వారి మధ్య సంబంధాలను నెలకొల్పేటట్లు చేస్తుంది. అనగా ఉత్పత్తిని వినియోగములోనికి తేవటమే వర్తకము, వాణిజ్య కార్యకలాపాలన్నీ వర్తకము చుట్టూ తిరుగుతాయి."},{"question":"కింది వాక్యముని సంయుక్త  వాక్యంగా మార్చండి.ఆయన కవి. ఆయన గాయకుడు. ఆయన విద్యావేత్త.","answer":"ఆయన కవి, గాయకుడు మరియు విద్యావేత్త. ప్రాతాది సంధి"},{"question":"Aarẹ Buhari ko gbọdọ pa SARS rẹ, gbọn-in gbọn-in la wa lẹyin wọn-Awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa","answer":"Lasiko ti gbogbo araalu n pariwo, to fi mọ awọn ọmọ Naijiria ti wọn wa loke okun, pe ki wọn fopin si ẹka ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ti wọn ya sọtọ lati maa gbogun ti idigunjale ati iwa ọdaran gbogbo ti wọn n pe ni SARS, ọtọ ni ibi ti awọn gomina ilẹ Hausa sun, ti wọn dori kọ. Awọn gomina to wa lawọn ipinlẹ kaakiri ilẹ Hausa ti sọ pe awọn fara mọ SARS ni tawọn, wọn ni ko maa lọ bẹẹ, ijọba ko gbọdọ fagi le e.Nile ijọba, niluu Abuja, lawọn gomina ilẹ Hausa ọhun kora wọn lọ l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, ohun ti wọn si lawọn n fẹ lọwọ ijọba Buhari ni pe ko da ajọ SARS pada, ko ma ṣe da awọn to n ṣewọde kiri pe awọn ko fẹ wọn mọ lohun rara.Bi wọn ṣe pari ipade wọn pẹlu Aarẹ ni alaga awọn gomina Hausa yii Gomina Lalong, ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ, ohun to si sọ ni pe ipa nla ni awọn ẹṣọ ọhun n ko ti a ba n sọ nipa eto idaabobo awọn eeyan ati dukia lagbegbe awọn.Lalong fi kun ọrọ ẹ pe ki i ṣe gbogbo awọn ẹṣọ to wa ninu SARS naa ni iwa wọn ko dara, ati pe awọn kan wa ninu wọn ti wọn wulo gidi, ti wọn si n ṣiṣẹ wọn bo ti yẹ.Gomina yii waa kadii ọrọ ẹ nilẹ pẹlu alaye pe bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn eeyan kan lorile-ede yii fara mọ ki wọn fagi le awọn ẹṣọ ọhun, sibẹ, ohun ti ẹka agbofinro ọhun nilo ni atunto gidi, eyi ti yoo jẹ ki wọn le jawọ ninu iwa ibajẹ, ti wọn yoo si mu iṣẹ wọn bii iṣẹ."},{"question":"दिइएको टुक्काको अर्थ पहिल्याई तेस्लाई वाक्यमा प्रयोग गर्नुहोस् :आँखा चिम्लिनु ","answer":"आँखा चिम्लिनु : देखेको नदेखी गर्नुसंविधानको संरक्षक राष्ट्रपतिले आँखा चिम्लिनु विडम्बना कुरा छ । "},{"question":"Velona tsy misy fofonaina aho, ary mangatsiaka toy ny fahafatesana. Tsy mangetaheta mihitsy aho fa misotro foana. Inona moa aho?","answer":" trondro. Velona tsy mifoka rivotra,, miaina anaty rano ary \\"misotro\\" rano amin'ny osmosis."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagaimana ditanam, begitulah dituai\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tiap-tiap kejahatan itu, kejahatan jugalah akan balasannya."},{"question":"እ.አ.አ በ1927 እስር ስድስት የምስል ገጽታዎችን በአንድ ሰከንድ ከዋሽንግተን ዲሲ ወደ ኒውዮርክ ከተማ በሽቦ የላከው ኸርበርት አይቭስ የየትኛው ድርጅት ሰራተኛ ነበር?","answer":"የቤል ላብራቷር(ላቦራቶሪ)"},{"question":"वाच्यं श्रद्धासमेतस्य पृच्छकस्य विशेषतः |प्रोक्तं श्रद्धाविहीनाय ह्यरण्यरुदितं भवेत्‌ ||","answer":"अर्थ : ज्याचा [आपल्यावर] विश्वास आहे आणि जास्तकरून ज्याने आपल्याला [त्याबद्दल] विचारलेले आहे अशा [माणसालाच उपदेश] सांगावा पण विश्वास नसणाऱ्याला सांगितले तर ते कष्ट व्यर्थ जातील."},{"question":"ما هو الشئ الذي كان النبي صلى الله عليه وسلم لا يرده؟","answer":"الطيب "},{"question":"Imaamu ilẹ Ibadan tako aṣẹ awọn olori Islam, o kirun yidi l’Agodi","answer":"Pẹlu bi igbimọ National Supreme Council for Islamic Affairs (NSCIA) ṣe kede pe aawẹ Ramadan gbọdọ tẹsiwaju l’Ọjọruu, ọjọ kejila, oṣu karun-un, ọdun 2021, nitori awọn ko ti i ri oṣu Shawal to kan lẹyin Lamulana yii, Imaamu Ilẹ Ibadan, Alaaji AbdulGaniu Abubakry Agbọtọmọkekere, ti ṣaaju irun yidi fawọn eeyan l’Agodi, wọn ni aawẹ tawọn ti pari lọdun yii na.Olubadan ilẹ Ibadan, Ọba Saliu Adetunji, naa wa lara awọn to kirun lẹyin Imaamu yii, bẹẹ ni Igbakeji gomima ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Alaaji Rauf Ọlaniyan, naa kirun Yidi laaarọ oni, lẹyin Imaamu Agbọtọmọkekere.Ana ode yii ti i ṣe ọjọ Iṣẹgun ni Imaamu ilẹ Ibadan ti kede loju opo Fesibuuku rẹ, pe oun yoo kirun lowurọ Ọjọruu, nitori mọkandinlọgbọn laaawẹ, o si ti pe.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe Yidi Agodi naa ko kun to bo ṣe maa n kun tẹlẹ, nitori ọpọ eeyan ṣi n gbaawẹ Ramadan gẹgẹ bii aṣẹ awọn olori ẹsin Islam, sibẹ, awọn araalu kọọkan naa ti wọn lawọn ko gbaawẹ mọ, darapọ mọ wọn l’Agodi, wọn si kirun.Ẹ oo ranti pe lọdun kẹta sẹyin, nigba ti wọn ni ọgbọn (30) ni aawẹ ọdun naa, Imaamu Agbọtọmọkekere ko duro gba ọgbọn, lẹyin ọjọ kọkandinlọgbọn lo ṣiwaju irun yidi fawọn to tẹle e."},{"question":"Bendera Pusaka Sang Saka Merah Putih adalah Bendera Merah-Putih yang pertama kali dikibarkan adalah bendera yang dijahit oleh Ibu Fatmawati pada proklamasi Kemerdekaan Indonesia tanggal 17 Agustus 1945.Apakah bendera yang dikibarkan pada upacara kemerdekaan Republik Indonesia ke-78, 17 Agustus 2023, adalah Bendera Pusaka Sang Saka Merah Putih? Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya.Jawaban:","answer":"Tidak. Bendera Pusaka Sang Saka Merah Putih terus dikibarkan pada upacara peringatan hari kemerdekaan Indonesia di Istana Merdeka hingga tahun 1968, kemudian diganti dengan bendera replika dari bahan sutera. Bendera replika itulah yang terus dikibarkan hingga kini, sementara Bendera Pusaka yang asli disimpan di Monumen Nasional karena sudah pudar dan rapuh."},{"question":"في أي قارة يوجد جنوب كوريا؟","answer":"يوجد جنوب كوريا في قارة آسيا."},{"question":"Shin batun me ake a wannan jumlar mai zuwa? \\"Ana sa ran mahaukaciyar guguwar teku ta maria zata ratsa a martinique da kuma dominica\\":(a) Lafiya(b) Najeriya(c) Duniya(d) Siyasa(e) Afirka","answer":"Jumlar \\"Ana sa ran mahaukaciyar guguwar teku ta maria zata ratsa a martinique da kuma dominica\\" na batu ne a kan (c) Duniya."},{"question":"Midika inona ny vodiondry eo amin'ny fanambadiana Malagasy?","answer":"Ny dikan'ny vodiondry eo amin'ny fanambadiana Malagasy dia : -Fatoram-panam-badiana.-Fanajana ny ray aman-dreny sy ny fianakaviana"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira da Venezuela.","answer":"A bandeira da Venezuela é composta por três faixas horizontais: amarela na parte superior, azul no meio e vermelha na parte inferior, com sete estrelas brancas no meio da faixa azul."},{"question":"தமிழ்தாய் வாழ்த்து எழுதியவர் யார்?","answer":"தமிழ்தாய் வாழ்த்து எழுதியவர் மனோன்மணியம் சுந்தரம் பிள்ளை ."},{"question":"Waa maxay macnaha  \\"lihid\\" ee Af-soomaaliga? ","answer":" Lihid:macnaheedu waa eray ku tusaya kuuna sheegaya qof walax leh."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو أكبر محيط في العالم؟","answer":"الإجابة: المحيط الهادي"},{"question":"Apakah soalan kepada: \\"Pada 11 Mei 2012, siri ini diperbaharui untuk musim kesembilan, yang ditayangkan pada 27 September 2012\\"? Topiknya ialah Anatomi Grey.","answer":"\\"berapakah musim Grey's Anatomy?\\""},{"question":"වං ඇපල යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"\\"ආඩතෝඩා \\" හෙවත් \\"වං ඇපල\\" ලෙස හඳුන්වන්නේ ඉන්දියානු උප මහාද්වීපයේ බොහෝ  ප්‍රදේශවල වැවෙන ඖෂධීය ශාකයකි.මෙම ශාකය ආඩතෝඩා, වං ඇපල, අගල් අාදාර හා පාවට්ටා වන නම් වලින් ලංකාවේ විවිධ පලාත්වලදී හැඳින්වේ. මෙය අඩි 3-10 දක්වා අතර උසට වැඩෙන බහුවාර්ෂික පඳුරකි. මෙම ශාකය බෙහෙවින් වැවෙන්නේ පහතරට වියළි ප්‍රදේශවලයි. මෙම ශාකය ඉන්දියාවේ හා මලයාවේද වැවේ. ආඩතෝඩා කොළය අඟල් 6-12 දක්වා දිගැතිය. ලන්සාකාරය. එහි කෙලවර තියුණුය. කෙටි හා දැඩි කක්ෂිය ශුකිවල කුඩා සුදු මල් හටගනී. නිපත්‍ර අඟලක් පමණ දිගය. මලේ මුකුටය ද්වීකෝෂ්ටීය වේ. මල් වැඩි වශයෙන් හටගනුයේ නොවම්බර් හා දෙසම්බර් යන මාස වලයි. ආඩතෝඩා ඵලය ස්ඵෝටිකාවකි. එය අඟල් 3/4 පමණ දිගය.ඖෂධීය වටිනාකමඑය සෙම් රෝග, රත් පිත් රෝග, ස්වසන අපහසුතා ඇතිකරවන රෝග, උණ, වමනය, ප්‍රමේහ රෝග හා කුෂ්ට රෝග නසයි. දේශීය වෛද්‍ය කර්මවලදී තැම්බුම්, මැල්ලුම්, පත්තු, ඉසකුඩිච් හා කෂාය සඳහා ආඩතෝඩා කොළ ගනු ලැබේ. බොහෝ විට “ආඩතෝඩා පංචාංගය“ හෙවත් කොළ, මුල්, මල්, පොතු හා නැටි යන පස් පංගුවම ගනු ලැබේ. ආඩතෝඩා යොදාගෙන නිපදවනු ලබන ප්‍රකට ඖෂධ රැසක් ඇත. වාසාවලේහය, වාසාහරිතක්‍යාදී ලේහය, වාහක පංචාංගය, වාසකාරිෂ්ටය ඉන් සමහරක්ය. මේවා රත්පිත් රෝග, ක්ෂය රෝග සහ ශ්වසන රෝග වලදී භාවිත කෙරේ. මෙහි සඳහන් “වාසක“ යන වදන ආඩතෝඩා සඳහා භාවිත වන සංස්කෘත වචනයයි."},{"question":"\\"මල්ගුඩි දවස්\\" හි පරිච්ඡේද ලැයිස්තුගත කරන්න.","answer":"ආර් කේ නාරායන් විසින් රචිත \\"මල්ගුඩි දවස්\\" හි පරිච්ඡේද ලැයිස්තුව මෙසේය:1. \\"ජ්‍යොතිෂවේදියෙකුගේ දිනය\\"2. \\"අතුරුදහන් තැපෑල\\"3. \\"වෛද්‍යවරයාගේ වචනය\\"4. \\"ගේට්මන්ගේ තෑග්ග\\"5. \\"අන්ධ බල්ලා\\"6. \\"සහෘද හැඟීම\\"7. \\"කොටි නිය\\"8. \\"ඊස්වරන්\\"9. \\"එවැනි පරිපූර්ණත්වය\\"10. \\"පියාගේ උදව්\\"11. \\"සර්ප-ගීතය\\"12. \\"එන්ජින් කරදර\\"13. \\"මාසයකට හතළිස් පහක්\\"14. \\"ව්‍යාපාරයෙන් බැහැර\\"15. \\"ඇටිලා\\"16. \\"The Axe\\"17. \\"ලෝලි පාර\\"18. \\"ග්‍රීන් බ්ලේසර් ට්‍රේල්\\"19. \\"ප්‍රාණ පරිත්‍යාගිකයාගේ කොන\\"20. \\"බිරිඳගේ නිවාඩුව\\"21. \\"සෙවණැල්ලක්\\"22. \\"කැමැත්ත ඇති වහලෙක්\\"23. \\"ලීලාගේ මිතුරා\\"24. \\"මව සහ පුතා\\"25. \\"නාගා\\"26. \\"සෙල්වි\\"27. \\"දෙවන මතය\\"28. \\"Cat Within\\"29. \\"ද එජ්\\"30. \\"දෙවියන් වහන්සේ සහ කොබ්ලර්\\"31. \\"බඩගිනි දරුවා\\"32. \\"ඇම්ඩන්\\""},{"question":"ශ්‍රී පාදස්ථානයේ නායක ධුරයට පත්වූ , පළමුවැනි ස්වාමීන් වහන්සේ කවුද ?","answer":"මඩගම්මන සාමණේර හිමි "},{"question":"Awọn janduku kọ lu eégún Olóòlù n’Ibadan, eeyan marun-un ni wọn pa","answer":"Eeyan marun-un ni wọn pa nífọnná-fọnṣu nigba tawọn ọmọ iṣọta kọ lu Olóòlù, àgbà eégún ilu Ibadan, nirọlẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, to kọja.ALAROYE gbọ pe lasiko ti eégún náà n ṣe ètùtù ọlọdọọdun to máa n ṣe lọwọ lawọn tọọgi ya bo oun atawọn ọmọ ẹyìn ẹ̀ laduugbo Òjé, n’Ibadan.O ti fẹẹ pari etutu ọhún lawọn ọmọ iṣọta naa ti wọn fẹẹ tó ọgọrin (80) niye ya dé pẹlu ibọn ada, kùmọ̀, eegun ẹran nla nla ati oriṣiiriṣii awọn nnkan ìjàmbá mi-in, tí ọrọ sì di bó-ò-lọ, yàgò lọ́nà.Yatọ s’awọn marun-un ti awọn ipata wọnyi yìn nibọn, ti wọn sì kú loju ẹsẹ, Ọlọrun lo mọ iye èèyàn tó ṣee ṣe kó tún padà gbẹ́mì-in mi lẹyin ikọlu ọhun ninu awọn ọmọ ẹyin eegun naa.Ìdí ni pé ọpọ eeyan lo fara gbọgbẹ nla, ti wọn sì n ti ileewosan kan gbe lọ sí òmí-ìn, ṣugbọn ti ko sí ẹni tó lè sọ ẹni tó máa kú tabi yè ninu wọn.Nigba to n sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii, Aarẹ ẹgbẹ àwọn ọdẹ Sọ̀lúdẹ̀rọ̀ jake-jado ilẹ Yorùbá, Ọba Wahab Ajijọla-Anabi, ẹni tí ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ naa ṣoju ẹ̀ fìdí ẹ̀ mulẹ pe wọ́ọ́rọ́wọ́ leto ti agba eegun naa n ṣe n lọ ko too di pe awọn ọmọ iṣọta naa ya de toguntogun lai jẹ pe eegun tabi awọn ọmọ ẹyin ẹ kankan tọ wọn.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Lọdọọdun l’Olóòlù máa n ṣètùtù yẹn, to máa n gbẹ́bọ kaakiri igboro Ibadan lati wúre fún gbogbo ipinlẹ Ọyọ pe kí ilu le máa rójú, ki alaafia sí máa jọba. Lẹyin ètùtù yẹn ni wọn ṣẹṣẹ máa mú ọjọ ti ọdun eégún máa bẹrẹ n’Ibadan. Eegun Olóòlù naa lo maa n jade gbẹyin lẹyin ti gbogbo eegun ba jade tan lasiko odun eégún.“Pẹlu bi mo ṣe foju wo awọn tọọgi yẹn, wọn tó ọgọrin (80). Olóòlù ti lọ kaakiri gbogbo ibi to yẹ kó dé gẹgẹ bíi iṣe ẹ̀ lọdọọdun. O ku diẹ ko pari eto yẹn lawọn tọọgi yẹn kọ lu u laduugbo Òjé, n’Ibadan, pẹlu ọpọlọpọ ibọn, ada, àpólà igi atawọn nnkan ija oloro mi-in.“Ọmọkùnrin kan ti wọn n pe ni Star Boy lo ṣaaju awọn tọọgi yẹn. Niṣe ni wọn n yinbọn lákọlákọ, ti wọn sì tún ju òkò ati igi, ṣugbọn kò sí nnkan kan to de ọdọ Olóòlù ninu gbogbo nnkan ìjà wọnyẹn.“O pẹ ti ọmọkùnrin ti wọn n pe ni Star Boy yii ti maa n huwa idaluru. Oun lo pa ààfáà wá kan nitori ọrọ tíkẹ́ẹ̀ẹ̀tì mọ́tò nitori ọmọ ẹyin Auxiliary (ọga ẹgbẹ awọn awakọ ni ipinlẹ Ọyọ) ni.‘‘Lanaa (ọjọ keji ikọlu akọkọ lawọn tọọgi yẹn tun bẹrẹ si i lọọ ka awọn eeyan mọle. Wọn lọọ ka Iyalọja Oje mọ ṣọọbu ẹ, wọn ni awọn maa dana sun un.“Emi ni mo pe awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn fi waa kòòré àǹbílíì.  Ọpẹlọpẹ DPO Agugu ni ko jẹ ki wọn rí iya yẹn dana sun. Koda, awọn tọọgi yii tun lẹko mọ awọn ọlọpaa.”ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn eleto aabo ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ ta a mọ si Operation Burst naa sare lọọ kun awọn ọlọpaa lọwọ ninu akitiyan wọn lati pẹtu sí làásìgbò naa.Meji ninu awọn afurasi ọdaran ọhun la gbọ pe awọn Operation Burst ri mu ninu wọn. Àhámọ́ awọn Operation Burst ni wọn wà titi ta a fi parí akojọ iroyin yii."},{"question":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚 Уйгур манасчы кайсы элде жашайт? а) Оогандарда б) Кытайда в) Туркияда г) Венгрияда","answer":"🇰🇬 Манас эпосу 📚б) Кытайда"},{"question":"Tóm tắt đoạn văn bản sau: 14% thu nhập của Samsung là từ thị trường Trung QuốcPhóng sự chiếu trên truyền hình Trung ương Trung Quốc nói các điện thoại lỗi bị hỏng chip điện tử, đồng thời chỉ trích chính sách bảo hành của Samsung.14% thu nhập của hãng điện tử này là từ Trung Quốc. Samsung nay nói sẽ sửa chữa miễn phí bảy model điện thoại mà phóng sự truyền hình nhắc đến.Samsung là một trong các hãng nước ngoài mới đây bị truyền thông Trung Quốc công kích.Hãng này ra thông cáo với lời 'xin lỗi chân thành' tới người tiêu dùng Trung Quốc vì những sự bất tiện mà các \\"vấn đề quản lý\\" của hãng gây ra; và hoan nghênh truyền thông tiếp tục theo dõi hoạt động của hãng.Trong các model điện thoại di động mà kênh truyền hình CCTV nói là bị lỗi, có các loại Galaxy S3 và Note2.'Ngạo mạn'Trung Quốc là nền kinh tế đứng thứ hai thế giới, cũng là quốc gia đông dân nhất hiện nay.Nền kinh tế tăng trưởng mạnh, mức thu nhập đi lên và lượng người tiêu dùng lớn đã khiến Trung Quốc trở thành thị trường chủ chốt cho các hãng sản xuất hàng tiêu dùng trên toàn cầu.Tuy nhiên, trong quá trình mở rộng kinh doanh ở Trung Quốc, các hãng nước ngoài cũng ngày càng bị soi mói.Hồi đầu tuần này, một phóng sự khác trên CCTV cho hay Starbucks, mạng lưới cửa hàng cà phê lớn nhất thế giới, nâng giá bán ở Trung Quốc cao hơn ở các nước khác.CCTV nói Starbucks thu lãi nhiều hơn ở Trung Quốc chính vì giá mắc.Tháng Tư năm nay, Tổng giám đốc điều hành của tập đoàn Apple, Tim Cook, đã phải xin lỗi người tiêu dùng Trung Quốc sau hai tuần liền hãng này bị truyền thông nhà nước đả phá về dịch vụ bảo hành.Báo chí Trung Quốc cáo buộc Apple là ngạo mạn và tham lam.","answer":"Một phóng sự trên truyền hình Trung Quốc đã tiết lộ rằng điện thoại của Samsung gặp sự cố về chip điện tử, và chỉ trích chính sách bảo hành của hãng. amsung đã cam kết sửa chữa miễn phí bảy model điện thoại bị lỗi như được đề cập trong phóng sự. Các hãng nước ngoài, trong đó có Samsung, đang gặp áp lực từ truyền thông Trung Quốc khi mở rộng kinh doanh ở đây. Tương tự, Starbucks cũng bị chỉ trích vì nâng giá bán cà phê ở Trung Quốc. Đây là dấu hiệu cho thấy sự gia tăng của truyền thông nhà nước Trung Quốc trong việc kiểm soát hoạt động của các công ty nước ngoài trên thị trường của họ."},{"question":"Ọmọ ọdún mélòó ni Noam Chomsky?","answer":"Ọmọ ọdún mẹ́rinléláàdọ́rùn-ún"},{"question":"Qual o nome do estádio do Morumbi?","answer":"O nome do estádio do Morumbi é Cícero Pompeu de Toledo."},{"question":"வினா :தமிழ்நாட்டில் உள்ள மொத்த நாடாளுமன்ற தொகுதிகள்A. 21B. 20C. 25D. 39","answer":"விடை : D. 39"},{"question":"Apa yang berlaku apabila Beneden Merwede bercabang? Berdasarkan soalan sebelumnya, tulis konteks yang mengandungi jawapannya. Konteks boleh mengandungi 1 - 20 ayat. Konteks:","answer":"Dua pertiga daripada jumlah aliran air Rhine mengalir ke barat, melalui Waal dan kemudian, melalui Merwede dan Nieuwe Merwede (De Biesbosch), bergabung dengan Meuse, melalui muara Hollands Diep dan Haringvliet, ke Laut Utara. Beneden Merwede bercabang, berhampiran Hardinxveld-Giessendam dan terus sebagai Noord, untuk menyertai Lek, berhampiran kampung Kinderdijk, untuk membentuk Nieuwe Maas; kemudian mengalir melepasi Rotterdam dan meneruskan melalui Het Scheur dan Nieuwe Waterweg, ke Laut Utara. Percabangan Oude Maas, berhampiran Dordrecht, lebih jauh ke bawahnya bergabung dengan Nieuwe Maas untuk membentuk Het Scheur."},{"question":"Quem foi o líder pacifista indiano que desempenhou um papel fundamental na conquista da independência da Índia do domínio britânico?","answer":"O líder pacifista indiano que desempenhou um papel fundamental na conquista da independência da Índia do domínio britânico foi Mahatma Gandhi."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਃ ੪ ॥ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਸੇਤੀ ਗਣਤ ਜਿ ਰਖੈ ਹਲਤੁ ਪਲਤੁ ਸਭੁ ਤਿਸ ਕਾ ਗਇਆ ॥ਨਿਤ ਝਹੀਆ ਪਾਏ ਝਗੂ ਸੁਟੇ ਝਖਦਾ ਝਖਦਾ ਝੜਿ ਪਇਆ ॥ਨਿਤ ਉਪਾਵ ਕਰੈ ਮਾਇਆ ਧਨ ਕਾਰਣਿ ਅਗਲਾ ਧਨੁ ਭੀ ਉਡਿ ਗਇਆ ॥ਕਿਆ ਓਹੁ ਖਟੇ ਕਿਆ ਓਹੁ ਖਾਵੈ ਜਿਸੁ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਸਹਸਾ ਦੁਖੁ ਪਇਆ ॥ਨਿਰਵੈਰੈ ਨਾਲਿ ਜਿ ਵੈਰੁ ਰਚਾਏ ਸਭੁ ਪਾਪੁ ਜਗਤੈ ਕਾ ਤਿਨਿ ਸਿਰਿ ਲਇਆ ॥ਓਸੁ ਅਗੈ ਪਿਛੈ ਢੋਈ ਨਾਹੀ ਜਿਸੁ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਨਿੰਦਾ ਮੁਹਿ ਅੰਬੁ ਪਇਆ ॥ਜੇ ਸੁਇਨੇ ਨੋ ਓਹੁ ਹਥੁ ਪਾਏ ਤਾ ਖੇਹੂ ਸੇਤੀ ਰਲਿ ਗਇਆ ॥ਜੇ ਗੁਰ ਕੀ ਸਰਣੀ ਫਿਰਿ ਓਹੁ ਆਵੈ ਤਾ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਅਉਗਣ ਬਖਸਿ ਲਇਆ ॥ਜਨ ਨਾਨਕ ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਇਆ ਹਰਿ ਸਿਮਰਤ ਕਿਲਵਿਖ ਪਾਪ ਗਇਆ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 307 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਰਾਮਦਾਸ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਸਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਲ ਕਿੜ ਰੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਦਾ ਲੋਕ ਤੇ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਸਮੁੱਚੇ ਹੀ ਵਿਅਰਥ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ (ਉਸ ਦੀ ਪੇਸ਼ ਤਾਂ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ, ਇਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਉਹ) ਸਦਾ ਕਚੀਚੀਆਂ ਵੱਟਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਦੰਦ ਪੀਂਹਦਾ ਹੈ (ਤੇ ਅੰਤ ਨੂੰ) ਖਪਦਾ ਖਪਦਾ ਨਸ਼ਟ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਸਹੇੜ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ) ।:—(ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦਾ ਉਹ ਦੋਖੀ) ਸਦਾ ਮਾਇਆ ਲਈ ਵਿਓਂਤਾਂ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਅਗਲਾ (ਕਮਾਇਆ ਹੋਇਆ) ਭੀ ਹੱਥੋਂ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਝੋਰਾ ਤੇ ਸਾੜਾ ਹੋਵੇ, ਉਸ ਨੇ ਖੱਟਣਾ ਕੀਹ ਤੇ ਖਾਣਾ ਕੀਹ? (ਭਾਵ, ਉਹ ਨਾ ਕੁਝ ਖੱਟ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਨਾ ਖੱਟੇ ਹੋਏ ਦਾ ਆਨੰਦ ਲੈ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ) ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨਿਰਵੈਰ ਨਾਲ ਵੈਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਦੇ ਪਾਪਾਂ (ਦਾ ਭਾਰ) ਆਪਣੇ ਸਿਰ ਤੇ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਲੋਕ ਪਰਲੋਕ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਆਸਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਦੇਂਦਾ । ਜਿਸ ਦੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਤਾਂ ਨਿੰਦਾ ਹੋਵੇ, ਪਰ ਮੂੰਹ ਵਿਚ ਅੰਬ ਪਿਆ ਹੋਵੇ (ਭਾਵ, ਜੋ ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਮਿੱਠਾ ਬੋਲੇ),  ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਖੋਟਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਜੇ ਸੋਨੇ ਨੂੰ ਹੱਥ ਪਾਏ ਉਹ ਭੀ ਸੁਆਹ ਨਾਲ ਰਲ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਫਿਰ ਭੀ (ਭਾਵ, ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਪਾਪੀ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਭੀ) ਜੇ ਉਹ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਚਰਨੀਂ ਢਹਿ ਪਵੇ ਤਾਂ ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਅਉਗੁਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਸਤਿਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਣਿ ਪੈ ਕੇ) ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਨਾਮ ਜਪਦਾ ਹੈ, ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਦਿਆਂ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਾਪ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।੨।\\""},{"question":"‘இளைதாக முள்மரம்’ எனத் தொடங்கும் குறளில் ஈற்றடி ஈற்றுச்சீர், என்னும் வாப்பாட்டால் முடிந்துள்ளது.அ) நாள்ஆ) மலர்இ) காசுஈ) பிறப்பு","answer":"விடை: ‘இளைதாக முள்மரம்’ எனத் தொடங்கும் குறளில் ஈற்றடி ஈற்றுச்சீர், என்னும் வாப்பாட்டால் ஈ) பிறப்பு முடிந்துள்ளது."},{"question":"北朝鮮の核兵器開発を防ぐために設けられた「朝鮮半島エネルギー開発機構」をアルファベット４文字で何というでしょう？","answer":"ＫＥＤＯ"},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra an'ilay boky mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Twilight\\"?","answer":"Ny mpanoratra an'ilay boky mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Twilight\\" dia i Stephenie Meyer."},{"question":"வினா: மின்சாரத்தைக் கடத்தும் அலோகம் எது ?1.கிராபைட்2.மெக்னீசியம் சல்பேட்3.பாலியெஸ்டர்4.நைலான்","answer":"விடை:1.கிராபைட்"},{"question":"次の文章に書かれている内容に基づいて、少なくとも200語の段落を書いてください。： 災害のとき役に立つ　水道や電気を使わない料理を紹介","answer":"今年は関東大震災から100年です。首都直下地震などの大きな地震もこれから起こると言われています。クックパッドという会社は、災害で水道や電気、ガスなどが止まったときでも作ることができる料理をウェブサイトで紹介しています。料理は250以上あります。家に用意しておいた水やカセットコンロ、熱に強いポリエチレンの袋を使ってごはんを炊く 方法や、缶詰を使ったパスタなどを紹介しています。会社は「食事は生活の中でとても大切です。災害のときも、少しでも安心できるように、おいしい食事を作ってほしいです」と話しています。"},{"question":"Apakah tema sambutan Hari Kebangsaan 2017?","answer":"Tema sambutan Hari Kebangsaan 2017 ialah Negaraku Sehati Sejiwa."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada umur ada rezeki\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud asal masih hidup, tentu akan beroleh rezeki"},{"question":"Wace jam'iyar siyasa ce mafi girma a Amruka?","answer":"Democratic Party da Republican Party"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai bersahabat dengan ular bisa\\"?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini adalah berkawan dengan orang jahat."},{"question":"audio blog-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"ஒலிதப்பதிவு"},{"question":"\\"Мезгил учат\\" повести кимге таандык?\\"Мезгил учат\\" повести ким жөнүндө жазылган?","answer":"\\"Мезгил учат\\" повестинин автору Аалы Токомбаев.\\"Мезгил учат\\" повестиндеги башкы каарман Жапардын прототиби — Гапар Айтиев. Жапардын атасы Айтике болсо Гапардын атасы Айтинин прототиби. Бул чыгарманы жазууда автор Гапар Айтиев менен көп жолу сүйлөшкөн, анын балалыгы, жаштыгы, ата-энеси, жакындары, кыскасы, атактуу сүрөтчү болгонго чейинки басып өткөн жолун өз оозунан уккан, архивдик-документалдык маалыматтар менен таанышкан, балким, китеп болуп чыга элек кезде прототиптин өзүнө да окутуп тургандыр."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na to pytanie: Ed Oxenbould gra Tylera w filmie reżyserowanym przez jakiego słynnego reżysera?","answer":"Przez M. Night Shyamalana"},{"question":"Awọn afọbajẹ pariwo: Ẹ gba wa o, Oluwoo ti dẹ awọn tọọgi si wa","answer":"Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, to kọja, ni ina ọrọ ọhun ru jade, ọjọ yẹn ni mejila lara awọn afọbajẹ ilu Iwo fi ọwọ si iwe kan, wọn si mu un lọ sọdọ gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Alhaji Gboyega Oyetọla.Ohun to wa ninu lẹta naa ni pe ki gomina ba awọn yọ Oluwoo, Ọba Abdulrasheed Adewale, lori oye. Ẹsun mọkanla ni wọn ka si ọba yii lẹsẹ, wọn ni ọba naa ko yẹ nipo nitori oniruuru iwa idojuti to n hu kaakiri, eyi to n ba orukọ ilu naa jẹ.Lara awọn ti wọn fọwọ si iwe naa ni Oloye Raufu Murana Olorunlampe (Balogun), Oloye Fatai Alani Olaoye (Onto), Oloye Yekeen Bello Orobimpe (Oosa), Oloye Sunday Oyetunde Oyeniyi (Olosi), Oloye Ganiyu Kazeem Ayinde (Jagun) ati Oloye Moses Akanmu Ajao (Ọlọya).Awọn to ku ni Oloye Baṣiru Ajani Akinṣọla (Olukọtun), Oloye Lamidi Mọrufu Oyeleke (Ọḍọfin), Oloye Suraju Bello (Onju), Oloye Lateef Ishọla (Agoro), Oloye Moshood Amọo (Aṣape), Oloye Rasaki Akanmu Tijani (Olukosi) ati Oloye Amao Ọlaoṣebikan Taiwo (Aro).Lara awọn ẹsun ti wọn fi kan Ọba Adewale ni pe o ba ọba ẹgbẹ rẹ ja titi ti igbimọ lọbalọba ipinlẹ Ọṣun fi da a duro fodidi oṣu mẹfa. Wọn ni Oluwoo ti Iwo-Oke tun ti figba kan gbe e lọ sile-ẹjọ, ṣugbọn ti ko lọ, to si jẹ pe awọn eeyan bii Oloye Oluṣẹgun Ọbasanjọ lo yọ ọ lọwọ aṣẹ ti kootu pa.Wọn ni lọdun 2016, Ọba Adewale tun sọ pe gbogbo ọmọ Yoruba lo le di Ọọni ti Ifẹ, eleyii to le da wahala silẹ nilẹ Yoruba. Bakan naa lo tun gba iṣẹ Imaamu Agba ilu Iwo ṣe lọjọ ọdun Ileya lọdun naa.Awọn afọbajẹ fi kun ọrọ wọn pe Oluwoo tun ti figba kan sọrọ to le da wahala silẹ niluu Ibadan, nipinlẹ Ọyọ. Wọn lo sọ ninu ifọrọwerọ kan pe ilu Iwo lo maa n yan ẹni ti yoo jẹ Olubadan.Wọn ni ija igboro wa ninu ẹjẹ Oluwoo, ko si si eeyan nla nla ti ko ti i ba ja tan. Lara wọn ni Ọọni ti Ifẹ, Alaafin ti Ọyọ, Ọrangun ti Ila, Oloye Abiọla Ogundokun, Imrah Adio ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ.Ju gbogbo rẹ lọ, awọn afọbajẹ yii sọ pe o jẹ nnkan ibanujẹ fun awọn pe ẹni to ti ṣẹwọn ri lorileede United States of America (USA) ati Canada ni Oluwoo.Wọn ni ki Gomina Oyetọla gba ilu Iwo lọwọ idojuti ti Ọba Adewale n mu ba a nipa yiyọ ọ nipo ọba to wa ko too di pe yoo ba ilu Iwo jẹ.Ṣugbọn ọrọ naa ko ti i balẹ ti Akọwe iroyin Ọba Adewale, Alli Ibrahim, fi fun awọn baba naa lesi. O ni atamọ lasan ni ọrọ awọn baba naa ati pe ariwo ọja lasan ni wọn n pa, eleyii ti ko si le tu irun kankan lara Oluwoo.Alli ṣalaye pe ọmọọba kan to du ipo Oluwoo pẹlu Ọba Adewale Akanbi lo wa nidii wahala naa, o ni wọn n ṣe bẹẹ lati le jẹ ki awọn eeyan ro pe ko si alaafia niluu Iwo, ṣugbọn ero wọn ko le jọ.O ni ko si bi idunkukulaja naa ṣe le le to, ko le di awọn iṣẹ rere ti Oluwoo n ṣe fun awọn eeyan ilu naa lọwọ rara, ati pe ẹni to n lo awọn oloye oun lati ṣiṣẹ tako oun kan n ṣe e lasan ni, ṣe ni ko lọ gba fun Ọlọrun.Lọjọ keji, iyẹn Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, Igbakeji Oluwoo, to si jẹ olori awọn afọbajẹ niluu Iwoo, Oosa ti ilu Iwo, Oloye Yekeen Bello, ba ALAROYE sọrọ nile rẹ, o ni ọrọ rirun gbaa ni Alli sọ lorukọ Oluwoo, ati pe ti awọn ba fẹẹ gba owo lọwọ ẹnikẹni lati lo awọn tako Oluwoo, ọrọ naa ko ni i le to bayii.Oloye Bello ni “Nitori iwa ati iṣe Oluwoo lo jẹ ka kọ iwe ẹhonu naa si gomina. Ihuwasi rẹ ti n ko idojuti ba ilu Iwo, ti ẹ ba ri nnkan ti awọn eeyan maa n sọ nipa rẹ lori ẹrọ ayelujara, ẹ maa mọ pe o buru jai.“Nigba ti ọba ko ba ka awọn ijoye si, ti ko ka awọn agbaagba si, ki lẹ ro pe o le ṣẹlẹ? A ti gbiyanju pupọ lati mu iwa rẹ mọra, ṣugbọn a ko le tẹsiwaju mọ bayii, a ti gba a nimọran, a pe e jokoo, sibẹ, ko ni i gbọ, idi niyẹn ti awa afọbajẹ fi pinnu pe a gbọdọ gbe igbesẹ kan.“Fun apẹrẹ, Ọlaoluwa ati Ayedire wa labẹ ilẹ Iwo, ṣugbọn awọn da loni-in? Ṣe ohun to bojumu ni ki awọn igbimọ lọbalọba da ọba duro gẹgẹ bo ṣe ṣẹlẹ si Oluwoo? Aanu Alli ṣe mi pẹlu irọ buruku to n pa kaakiri, a si ti fun un ni ọjọ meje lati sọ ẹni to sọ pe o gbe owo fun wa lati maa daamu Oluwoo, lai jẹ bẹẹ, yoo ba wa ni kootu.“Dipo ko fun awa oloye ni ẹtọ wa ninu alokesan to n gba loṣooṣu, ṣe lo sọ pe ka lọọ wa iṣẹ ṣe. O ni ọba nikan lo ni alokesan, ẹrin pa mi, ṣe ara-oko lo pe wa ni? Ki odidi oloye maa mu ẹgbẹrun mẹta, ẹgbẹrun mẹrin lọ sile loṣooṣu, o ṣe ni laaanu.“Ko too di pe a fi Adewale jọba, yatọ si pe ko gbe ninu ilu, ṣe lo dibọn fun wa, iwa oniwa lo n hu, o fiwa pamọ fun wa, ṣugbọn nitori pe ọrẹ lemi ati baba rẹ, mo ti i lẹyin. Nigba to fẹẹ joye, mo ti ra bulọọku ti mo fẹẹ fi kọle silẹ, ṣugbọn mo na owo yẹn lori ọrọ oye ọba yii ni, ti bulọọku si ṣofo, ṣugbọn bayii, emi ni olori awọn ọta rẹ.“Awa mẹrinla ni afọbajẹ, ẹni kan ti ṣalaisi laarin wa, a ko si mu iwe lọ sọdọ ẹni kẹtala nitori idi pataki to han si wa. Ohun ti a fẹ bayii ni pe ki gomina ba wa yọ Ọba Adewale nipo, ọrọ rẹ ti su wa”ALAROYE gbiyanju lati ba ẹni ti Oluwoo sọ pe o ba oun du ipo ọba, Alhaji Abdulazeez Inaọlaji, sọrọ lori ẹsun ti Oluwoo fi kan an pe oun lo wa nidii igbesẹ awọn afọbajẹ sọrọ, ṣugbọn pabo lo ja si. Awọn ti wọn sun mọ baba naa jẹ ko di mimọ pe o ṣee ṣe ko jẹ nitori ẹjọ to wa ni kootu ni baba naa ko ṣe fẹẹ ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ.Ṣugbọn Oloye Sunday Oyeniyi, Olosi ti ilu Iwo, ẹni to jẹ afọbajẹ kẹtala ti ko sọrọ ni tiẹ sọ pe ko ṣee ṣe lati rin ki ori ma mi. O ni oun gbagbọ pe Ọlọrun nikan lo le fi ọba jẹ, Oun nikan naa si lo le yọ ọba loye, ati pe oun ko mọ nnkan kan nipa iwe ti awọn afọbajẹ yooku mu lọ sọdọ gomina.Oloye Oyeniyi waa rọ Oluwoo lati tubọ ni ikomọra, ko yago fun nini ọta kun ọta, bẹẹ lo si ni Ọlọrun nikan ni gbogbo ilu gbọdọ ke pe bayii lati da si ọrọ naa.Bo ṣe di ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ni awọn afọbajẹ mejila yii gba ile-ẹjọ giga ipinlẹ Ọṣun lọ, wọn wọ Oluwoo lọ si kootu, wọn ni ko gbọdọ yọ awọn, bẹẹ ni ko gbọdọ fi ẹlomi-in rọpo awọn gẹgẹ bii afọbajẹ ati oloye.Ninu iwe ipẹjọ naa to ni nọmba HIW/M.18/2020, eleyii ti Oosa ṣebura le lori pẹlu agbẹjọro wọn, John Enworo, ti ALAROYE si ri lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ni wọn ti sọ pe lẹyin ti awọn kọ iwe iyọnipo Oluwoo si gomina ni ọba naa dẹ awọn tọọgi si awọn, inu ibẹrubojo ni gbogbo awọn si wa latigba naa.Oosa fi kun ọrọ rẹ ninu iwe ipẹjọ naa pe Oluwoo ti ranṣẹ si gbogbo awọn agboole awọn afọbajẹ naa lati fi orukọ ẹlomi-in ranṣẹ, eleyii ti yoo fi rọpo awọn afọbajẹ ti wọn fẹ yọ ọ nipo.Idi niyi ti wọn fi sa di kootu lati da Oluwoo duro ninu igbesẹ to fẹẹ gbe. Bi ẹjọ naa ba si ṣe n lọ si, ALAROYE yoo maa fi to yin leti."},{"question":"දෙසැම්බර් යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"දෙසැම්බර් යනු ග්‍රෙගරි දින දසුන අනුව අවුරුද්දේ දොළොස්වැනි (අවසන්) මාසය වේ."},{"question":"كم عدد خلفاء الدولة العباسية؟","answer":"(37 خليفة)"},{"question":"Najite Dede","answer":"Najite Dede jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin àti adarí fíìmù ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó jẹ́ arábìnrin Michelle Dede àti Richard Mofe Damijo, àwọn mẹ́tẹ̀ta jẹ́ òṣèré.Orúkọ bàbá Najite ni Ogbeni Brownson Dede, aṣojú Nàìjíríà tẹ́lẹ̀rí sí orílẹ̀-èdè Ethiopia."},{"question":"東海道五十三次で、宮から桑名までのあいだ海の渡る道のりを、その距離から「何の渡し」というでしょう？","answer":"（海上）七里の渡しです。"},{"question":"How does MLOps support the monitoring of model inference latency and response times?","answer":"MLOps monitors model inference latency by tracking the time it takes for models to process requests, ensuring that response times meet predefined performance criteria."},{"question":"Marina sa diso: tsy mety maty ny olona ","answer":"Tsia, diso io fanambarana io. Ny olona dia mety maty."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: പ്രതിനിധിസഭയിലെ ഏറ്റവും ദൈർഘ്യമേറിയ അംഗം ആരാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"ഹൌസ് ഓഫ് റെപ്രസന്റേറ്റീവ്സിലെ ഏറ്റവും കൂടുതൽ കാലം സേവനമനുഷ്ഠിച്ച അംഗമാണ് ജോൺ ഡിംഗൽ"},{"question":"बि.स.१९९२ को एस. एल. सी परिक्षामा कति जना पास भएका थिए ?","answer":"बि.स.१९९२ को एस. एल. सी परिक्षामा  १९ जना पास भएका थिए |"},{"question":"我が国の年号で、「感宝(かんぽう)」「勝宝 (しょうほう)」「宝字 (ほうじ)」「神護 (じんご)」といえば、共通して上に付く漢字二文字は何でしょう？","answer":"天平(てんぴょう)です。"},{"question":"Лондон, Англия Жүдонун үчүнчү сессиясы Лондондогу ExCeL Түндүк Арена 2де он алты раунддун бирден жок кылуу турнири менен башталды","answer":"2012-жылкы жайкы Паралимпиада оюндары."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் சிலவற்றை தரவும்.","answer":"ஐம்புலன்களுக்குத் தட்டுப்படாத விஷயம், பொருள், நடப்பு, எதுவானாலும் அது பொய் என்பதே பகுத்தறிவாளனின் கொள்கை.நம் பெண்கள் குறைந்த பட்சம் 20 வயது வரை படிக்க வைக்க வேண்டும். அவர்களுக்குக் கல்வியளிக்க வேண்டும். வாழ்விற்கு ஏற்ற வருவாயுள்ள தொழிலை அவர்களுக்குக் கற்பிக்கவேண்டும். அதன்பின் அவர்களாகத் தங்களுக்கேற்ற துணைவர்களை ஏற்றுக் கொள்ள அனுமதிக்க வேண்டும். வாழ்க்கையில் கவலையற்ற வாழ்வு வாழ வேண்டும். மனிதன் என்றால்-பகுத்தறிவுள்ளவன் என்றால், அதற்குப் பொருள் கவலையற்று வாழ்வதேயாகும்.மானமும் அறிவும் மனிதனுக்கு அழகு.பகுத்தறிவு என்பது மனிதனுக்கு உயிர்நாடிமூடநம்பிக்கையும் குருட்டுப் பழக்கமும் சமூகத்தின் முதல் பகைவன்விதியை நம்பி மதியை இழக்காதே!மக்களின் ஒழுக்கத்தையும் மதியையும் கெடுப்பது மது.மனிதப் பண்பை வளர்ப்பதே என் வாழ்நாள் பணி.பிறருக்கு தொல்லை தராத வாழ்வே ஒழுக்க வாழ்வு.பக்தி என்பது தனிச் சொத்து. ஒழுக்கம் என்பது பொது சொத்து.பக்தி இல்லாவிட்டால் இழப்பில்லை. ஒழுக்கம் இல்லாவிட்டால் பாழ்."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：加拿大的「意大利移民」主要集中在哪些城市？","answer":"答案：加拿大的意大利移民主要集中在多倫多、溫哥華、蒙特利爾和愛德蒙頓等城市。許多意大利移民在20世紀初期和後期來到加拿大，並在這些城市建立了繁榮的意大利社區。"},{"question":"હર્ષ બ્રહ્મભટ્ટ ની \\"શબ્દમાંથી અર્થ છૂટા થાય છે\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"શબ્દમાંથી અર્થ છૂટા થાય છે,વેદના શું એ હવે સમજાય છે.કોણ એને ઝાંઝવા સીંચ્યા કરે,રોજ રાતે સ્વપ્ન એક ફણગાય છે.આંખ મારી એક એવો કોયડો,જામ ખાલી છે છતાં છલકાય છે.મારી ભીતર કેટલું વરસ્યાં તમે,આખેઆખું અંગ લીલું થાય છે.ચીર હરપળ કેટલા ખેંચાય છે,કૃષ્ણને પણ ક્યાં કશુંયે થાય છે."},{"question":"ગ્રેની એનાટોમીમાં કેટલા સ્પિન-ઓફ છે?","answer":"ગ્રેની એનાટોમીમાં ત્રણ સ્પિન-ઓફ છે: ખાનગી પ્રેક્ટિસ (2007-2013), સ્ટેશન 19 (2018-હાલ), અને ગ્રેની એનાટોમી: બી-ટીમ (2021-હાલ)."},{"question":"ઝીણાભાઈ દેસાઈ ‘સ્નેહરશ્મિ’ની \\"સાંજ પડીને\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"સાંજ પડીને ઘેર જવા હું સાથ રહ્યો તો ખોળીદીઠી મેં ત્યાં આવતી સામે બાળા એક ભોળીદીઠાં તેના નેણ સુહાગી, સુહાગી નેણ તેનાધીમે રહીને પૂછ્યું તેને કોની કહે તું બહેનાલજામણીના છોડ સમીપે નમણી નાજુક વેલબોલ સુણીને આંખ ઢાળી તે આંખ તે ના મેલીસાંજ પડીને ઘેર જવા હું..કાળા કાળા કેશ તારા, કેશ કાળા કાળાદિન સાથે બેસી રજનીએ ગૂંથ્યા ક્યારે બાળાગૌર ભરેલા બાળાને તેને ગોરા મુગ્ધ ગાલેનાનકડા બે ગુલાબ ખીલ્યા, ઉષા ખીલી કંઈ ભાલેસાંજ પડી ને ઘેર જવા હું..અસ્થિર ડગલા ભરિયા આગળ, ડગ ભરિયા મેં ચારઉંચી નીચી થતી મેં તેને હૈયે દીઠી માળછાનીમાની શરમાતી ત્યાં આવી રાત કાળીહૈયે મારે ઢળી રહી મેં આતુર આંખ ભાળીસાંજ પડી ને ઘેર જવા હું..વેણી માટે ફૂલ ગૂંથ્યા મેં, ફૂલ ગૂંથ્યા મેં સાતકાંઠે મારે રહ્યા વીંટાયી નાજુક એ બે હાથ."},{"question":" Sheeg Imisa Ayey Ahaayeen Muslimiinta Dagaalkii Mu’ta","answer":"  Dagaalkii Mu’ta Muslimiinta Waxay Ahaayeen 3000."},{"question":"ਮੌਸਮੀ ਫੁੱਲਾਂ ਦੀ ਬੀਜਾਈ ਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਦੱਸੋ ।","answer":"ਮੌਸਮੀ ਫੁੱਲ ਇਕ ਸਾਲ ਜਾਂ ਇਕ ਮੌਸਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਪਣਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਚੱਕਰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਬਿਜਾਈ ਦਾ ਸਮਾਂ ਗਰਮੀ ਰੁੱਤ ਦੇ ਫੁੱਲ-ਫ਼ਰਵਰੀ-ਮਾਰਚ, ਵਿਚ ਪਨੀਰੀ ਤੇ ਖੇਤਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜਦੋਂ ਪਨੀਰੀ ਚਾਰ ਹਫਤੇ ਦੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਵੇ । ਬਰਸਾਤ ਰੁੱਤ ਦੇ ਫੁੱਲ-ਜੂਨ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ਪਨੀਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਖੇਤਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜੁਲਾਈ ਦੇ ਪਹਿਲੇ ਹਫ਼ਤੇ ॥ ਸਰਦੀ ਰੁੱਤ ਦੇ ਫੁੱਲ-ਸਤੰਬਰ ਦੇ ਅੱਧ ਵਿਚ ਪਨੀਰੀ ਤੇ ਖੇਤਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਅਕਤੂਬਰ ਦੇ ਅੱਧ ਵਿਚ ।"},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： 消費生活センターなどには去年、SNSのトラブルについての相談が6万552ありました。おととしより約1万増えて、今までの10年でいちばん多くなりました。40歳以上の人からの相談がとても増えました。特に50代の人からの相談は、おととしより2574増えて、1万2521でした。初めて20代より多くなりました。「SNSの広告を見て注文したが、うそのウェブサイトだった」とか「SNSで知った人の紹介で暗号資産を送って取られた」などの相談がありました。65歳以上の人からは「健康にいい食べ物」についての相談がいちばん多くて、年齢が上がると「家の修理など」の相談が増えています。河野大臣は「トラブルは年齢で違うことがわかりました。消費者庁は、トラブルについて伝えて、気をつけるように言っていきたいと考えています」と話していました。","answer":"SNSのトラブル相談　今までの10年でいちばん多い"},{"question":"Qual é o papel de um mecânico automotivo?","answer":"Um mecânico automotivo faz reparos e manutenção em veículos, garantindo que funcionem corretamente."},{"question":"ਮੈਂ ਹਥੌੜੇ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਖ ਗੱਡ ਦਿੱਤੀ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੇਖ ਲੱਕੜ ਵਿਚ ਠੋਕ ਹੋ ਗਈ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਮੇਖ ਨੂੰ ਜੰਗਾਲ ਲੱਗ ਗਿਆ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਮੇਖ ਲੱਕੜ ਵਿਚ ਠੋਕ ਹੋ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"Ndeipi nzira yakanakisa yekutsanangura data & AI zano?","answer":"\\"Shandura bhizinesi rako nedhijitari mudhata rako uye AI chiono uye zano rinoratidza nzvimbo dzemikana mikuru inokwenenzvera bhizinesi rako razvino pamwe nemabhizinesi matsva anoshandisa AI uye data.Ziva maitiro ebhizinesi (kuvandudzwa kwechigadzirwa, kugadzira, kutengesa & kushambadzira, cheni yekugovera, mitengo, HR, mari, nezvimwewo) kwaunoda kushandisa data neAI.Nzwisisa mamiriro azvino e data rako uye kugona kweAI.Rondedzera mamiriro akatarwa ebhizinesi rako maitiro kana data uye AI kugona zvaiswa.Tsanangura bhizinesi idzva rinofambiswa nedata uye mazano echigadzirwa.Tsanangura nzira yako yekuuraya, kusanganisira mari.Ita iyo yekutanga data uye AI shandisa makesi nekugadzira yako AI playbook, yakanangana nekugadzirira kugadzira.Automate uye wedzera mashandiro\\""},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுக:தென் கொரியத் திரைப்படத்துறை என்பது 1945 ஆம் ஆண்டு முதல் தென் கொரியா நாட்டில் வெளியாகும் திரைப்படங்களையும், அதைச் சார்ந்த தொழிலாளர்களையும் உள்ளடக்கிய திரைப்படத்துறை ஆகும். கொரியாவின் ஜப்பானிய ஆக்கிரமிப்பு, கொரியப் போர்,","answer":"அரசாங்க தணிக்கை, வணிகத் துறை, உலகமயமாக்கல் மற்றும் தென் கொரியாவின் ஜனநாயகமயமாக்கல் போன்ற நிகழ்வுகள் மற்றும் பிரச்சனைகளால் தென் கொரிய திரைப்படத்துறை பெரிதும் பாதிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளன. 20 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் நடுப்பகுதியில் தென் கொரியத் திரைப்படத்துறையின் பொற்காலம் எனலாம். 1960 களில் வெளியான 'தி ஹவுஸ்மெய்ட்' (1960) மற்றும் 'ஓபல்டன்' (1961) போன்ற திரைப்படங்கள் எல்லா காலங்களிலும் சிறந்த படங்கள் என கருதப்பட்டது. 1990 களின் பிற்பகுதியிலிருந்து இன்றுவரை 'தி அட்மிரல்: ரோரிங் கரண்ட்ஸ்' (2014) மற்றும் 'எக்ஸ்ட்ரீம் ஜாப்' (2019) போன்ற திரைப்படங்கள் தென் கொரியாவில் அதிக வசூல் செய்த படங்கள் மற்றும் கோல்டன் லயன் விருது வென்ற திரைப்படங்களும் ஆகும். 2012 ஆம் ஆண்டு வெளியான 'பியட்' என்ற திரைப்படம் பாம் டி ஆர் என்ற விருதும் 2019 ஆம் ஆண்டு வெளியான பாரசைட்டு என்ற திரைப்படம் சிறந்த திரைப்படத்திற்கான வெளிநாட்டு படத்திற்காக அகாதமி விருது வென்றுள்ளது."},{"question":"Một mảnh vườn có dạng hình vuông với chiều dài cạnh bằng 25m. Người ta để một phần của mảnh vườn làm lối đi rộng 2m, phần còn lại để trồng rau. Hãy trả lời hai câu hỏi sau:a) Tính diện tích phần vườn trồng rau.b) Người ta làm hàng rào xung quanh mảnh vườn trồng rau và ở một góc vườn rau có để cửa ra vào rộng 2m. Tính độ dài của hàng rào đó.","answer":"a) Vì người ta để một phần của mảnh vườn làm lối đi rộng 2 m nên phần vườn trồng rau là mảnh đất hình vuông và có độ dài cạnh là: 25 – 2 = 23 (m)Diện tích phần vườn trồng rau là: 23 . 23 = 529 (m2) b) Chu vi của phần vườn trồng rau hình vuông là: 4 . 23 = 92 (m)Độ dài của hàng rào chính là chu vi của phần vườn trồng rau trừ đi phần cửa ra vào rộng 2 m. Do đó độ dài của hàng rào là: 92 – 2 = 90 (m)Vậy diện tích của phần vườn trồng rau là 529 m2, và độ dài của hàng rào là 90 m."},{"question":"निम्नलिखित वाक्यांशको आधारमा, मलाई केहि प्रश्नहरू लेख्नुहोस्:मानव विवेकशील प्राणी हो । मानवको विकास सभ्यताको विकास हो । समयसँगसँगै क्रमश धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य र मान्यताको विकास हुँदै गइरहेको छ । धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य र मान्यता मानव निर्मित कुराहरु हुन् । इतिहासको कालखण्डमा जीवन पद्धतिमा परिस्कार गर्ने ध्येयले मानिसले विभिन्न धर्महरुको सुरुवात गरेको थियो । यही धर्मले पाप र पुण्यका बारेमा मानिसलाई सचेत गराउँदै गयो र सत्यको बाटोमा लाग्न प्रोत्साहन गर्दै गयो । धर्मको मुख्य आधार भनेकै धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य र मान्यता थियो । मानव सभ्यतालाई जगैदेखि बलियो बनाउन यिनीहरुको ठूलो योगदान रहेको छ । मानव सभ्यताको विकासका लागि धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य र मान्यता भनेका विकासका पूर्वाधार हुन् । मानव सभ्यताको विकाससँगै धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य र मान्यताको विकास भएको छ । ","answer":"1. मानवले के के विकास गरेको छ र ती कसरी विकास गरेको छ?2. समयको साथै कसरी धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य, र मान्यताको विकास हुँदै गइरहेको छ?3. धर्मले मानवलाई कसरी सचेत गराउँछ र सत्यको बाटोमा लाग्न प्रोत्साहन गर्दछ?4. मानव सभ्यताको विकासका लागि कसरी धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य, र मान्यता प्राधिकरण भनेको छ?5. कसरी धर्म, संस्कृति, सामाजिक मूल्य, र मान्यता ले मानव सभ्यताको विकासमा योगदान गरेका छन्?"},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheeg Magaalada Ugu Qadiimsan Caalamka?","answer":"Jawaab: Magaalada Caalamka Ugu Qadiimsan Waa Magadala Arriixa Waxay-Na Ku TaalaaDalka Falastiin."},{"question":"Which was the first radio service in Asia?","answer":"The first radio service in Asia was established in India. It began as a private venture known as the \\"Indian Broadcasting Company (IBC)\\" and was initiated in Bombay (now Mumbai) on July 23, 1927. This was followed by a station in Calcutta (now Kolkata), which started broadcasting later that year. However, the IBC was not financially successful and was dissolved in 1930.Subsequently, the government of British India took over the broadcasting facilities and started the \\"Indian State Broadcasting Service\\" on April 1, 1930, which was later renamed \\"All India Radio (AIR)\\" in 1936. AIR played a significant role in the development of radio broadcasting in India and across Asia."},{"question":"క్రింది వానిలో హిమాలయ నది కానిది.గంగా, సింధు, బ్రహ్మపుత్ర, మహానది, గండక్.","answer":"మహానది"},{"question":"Hafiriana no matory isan'andro ny saka?","answer":"Environ 12 à 16 heures par jour."},{"question":"Joxeel péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Ña'y tàxawe kaaraange ga ca dig u Poloñ wa dëggal na ñu ne ña yor kaaraange gu njiit u réew u Àfrig di Sidd ca fëx-naaw ga la'ñ fanaan fa Warsowi.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Ña'y tàxawe kaaraange ga ca dig u Poloñ wa dëggal na ñu ne ña yor kaaraange gu njiit u réew u Àfrig di Sidd ca fëx-naaw ga la'ñ fanaan fa Warsowi.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Ña: PRON'y: AUXtàxawe: VERBkaaraange: NOUNga: DETca: ADPdig: NOUNu: ADPPoloñ: PROPNwa: DETdëggal: VERBna: AUXñu: PRONne: SCONJña: PRONyor: VERBkaaraange: NOUNgu: PRONnjiit: NOUNu: ADPréew: NOUNu: ADPÀfrig: PROPNdi: ADPSidd: PROPNca: ADPfëx-naaw: NOUNga: DETla: AUX'ñ: PRONfanaan: VERBfa: ADVWarsowi: PROPN.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Sheeg Goorma Ayuu Dhacay Dagaalkii Qandala?","answer":"Waxa uu dhacay sanadkii 8-aad ee Hijriyada."},{"question":"\\"Aquela pessoa é do piorio\\"O que significa \\"do piorio\\"?","answer":"A expressão \\"do piorio\\" significa ser terrível, portar-se muito mal."},{"question":"రక్షకకణాలు లేదా రక్షకనిర్మాణాలు కలిగిన జననస్తరానికి సంబంధించి హైడ్రోజోవన్స్, ఇతర నిడేరియన్లకు గల ప్రధాన భేదమేమిటి?","answer":"రక్షకకణాలు లేదా రక్షక నిర్మాణాలు అయిన దంశ కణములు బాహ్య త్వచము నుండి ఏర్పడును. మిగిలిన నిడేరియా జీవులలో బాహ్యత్వచము నుండి అంతస్త్వచం నుండి ఏర్పడును."},{"question":"英語のアルファベットを小文字の筆記体で書いた時、一筆書きできないのは、Ｉ、Ｊ、Ｔともう１つは何でしょう？","answer":"Ｘです。"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de Papua-Nova Guiné? ","answer":"O IDH de Papua- Nova Guiné em 2021 foi 0,558."},{"question":"క్రింది పదాలను సరయిన ఉదాహరణలతో వివరించండి.ఎ) ఏరోసాల్ బి) హైడ్రోసాల్","answer":"ఎ) ఏరోసాల్ :ఏ కొల్లాయిడ్ ద్రావణంలో విక్షిప్త ప్రావస్థ ఘనపదార్థం విక్షేపణ యానకం గాలి (వాయువు) ఉంటుందో వాటిని ఎరోసాల్ అంటారు.ఉదా : పొగ : విక్షిప్తప్రావస్థ : కార్బన్ కణాలు (ఘన)విక్షేపణ యానకం : గాలి (వాయువు)బి) హైడ్రోసాల్ :ఏ కొల్లాయిడ్ ద్రావణంలో విక్షేపం యానకం నీరుగా ఉంటుందో వాటిని హైడ్రోసాల్ అంటారు.ఉదా : పాలు : విక్షిప్తప్రావస్థ : ద్రవరూప క్రొవ్వువిక్షేపణ యానకం : నీరు"},{"question":"\\tவினா:         கருப்பொருள் வகைகளை  விளக்குக?","answer":"விடை:ஐந்து திணைகளுக்கும் உரிய நிலங்களில் வாழும் உயிரினங்களும் வழங்கும் பொருள்களும் ‘கருப்பொருள்’ என வழங்கப்படுகின்றன. அந்தந்த நிலங்களுக்கு ஏற்ப வேறு வேறாக விளங்கும் அக்கருப்பொருள்களை இலக்கண நூல்கள் பலவாறு வகைப்படுத்தும். நம்பியகப் பொருள் 14 வகையான கருப்பொருள்களைப் பட்டியல் இட்டுக் காட்டுகிறது. அவையாவன1.ஆரணங்கு (தெய்வம்)2.உயர்ந்தோர்3.உயர்ந்தோர் அல்லோர்4.புள் (பறவை)5.விலங்கு6.ஊர்7.நீர்8.பூ9.மரம்10.உணவு11.பறை12.யாழ்13.பண்14.தொழில்"},{"question":"Ibinzana 1: UYesu wachitha iintsuku ezintathu esiswini sentlanzi, uYona uza kuchitha iintsuku ezintathu engcwabeni. Ibinzana lesibini: UYona wachitha iintsuku ezintathu esiswini sentlanzi; uYesu uza kuchitha iintsuku ezintathu engcwabeni. Umbuzo: Ingaba ibinzana 1 nebinzana 2 zithetha into enye? Ewe okanye Hayi?","answer":"Hayi"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai besi dengan penempa\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah orang lemah dikuasai orang kuat"},{"question":"এই লেখাটি কোন গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ঘটনা সম্পর্কে ?রুহুল কুদ্দুস হলেন বাংলাদেশের একজন প্রখ্যাত রাজনীতিবিদ। মুক্তিযুদ্ধে অনন্য সাধারণ অবদানের জন্য ২০০১ সালে তাকে “স্বাধীনতা ও মুক্তিযুদ্ধে স্বাধীনতা পুরস্কার” প্রদান করা হয়।","answer":"বাংলাদেশের মুক্তিযুদ্ধ |"},{"question":"ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩාව සසඳහා ඉදි කළ ලොව ප්‍රථම ක්‍රීඩාංගනය වන ලෝඩ්ස් ක්‍රීඩාංගනය පිහිටා ඇති රට?","answer":"එංගලන්තය"},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙම පෞරාණික ගස් වැදගත් වන්නේ ඇයි, සහ රටේ සංස්කෘතික හා  ස්වභාවික උරුමයන් තුළ ඒවා  ඉටු කරන කාර්යභාරය කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ මෙම පැරණි ගස් ඒවායේ ලේඛනගත ඉතිහාසය, හොඳින්  ඔරොත්තු දීමේ හැකියාව සහ සංස්කෘතික වැදගත්කම හේතුවෙන් වැදගත් වේ. ඔවුන් ඓතිහාසික සිදුවීම් සඳහා  ජීවමාන සාක්ශිකරුවන් වන අතර රටේ සංස්කෘතික හා ස්වභාවික උරුමයේ කොටසකි. දේශගුණික දුෂ්කරතා  මධ්‍යයේ සියවස් ගණනාවක් පුරා  මෙම ගස් විරාජමානව පවතින්නේ රටේ ඓතිහාසික සිදුවීම් වලට සාක්ශ්‍ය සපයමිනි."},{"question":"¿Qué es el valor absoluto de un número?","answer":"El valor absoluto de un número es el valor del número sin considerar el signo, sea este positivo o negativo."},{"question":"Inona no marika mifandray matetika amin'ny Kristianisma?","answer":"Ny lakroa no famantarana matetika mifandray amin'ny Kristianisma."},{"question":" \\"Мона Лиза\\" жана \\"Акыркы кечки тамак\\" сүрөттөрү менен белгилүү италиялык белгилүү сүрөтчү ким?","answer":"Жооп: Леонардо да Винчи - \\"Мона Лиза\\" жана \\"Акыркы кечки тамак\\" сүрөттөрү менен белгилүү италиялык атактуу сүрөтчү."},{"question":"پوښتنه: که یو ډاکټر تاسو ته درې ګولۍ درکړي او تاسو ته ووایي چې په هر نیم ساعت کې یوه ګولۍ وخورئ، ګولۍ به څومره وخت ونیسي؟","answer":"ځواب: یو ساعت. که تاسو لومړی ګولۍ سمدلاسه وخورئ، دویمه ګولۍ 30 دقیقې وروسته، او دریم ګولۍ بل 30 دقیقې وروسته، تاسو ټول درې ګولۍ په یو ساعت کې وخورئ."},{"question":"‘Both Belgium and Sri Lanka are democracies, but they follow different systems of power sharing’. Support the statement by giving three points of difference.","answer":"In Belgium, communities have an equal share in the government, while in Sri Lanka, leaders of the Sinhala community sought to secure dominance over the government by virtue of their majority.• In Belgium, there is provision of special government called ‘Community government’ to look after cultural, educational and language-related issues, while In Sri Lanka, none of the major political parties led by the Buddhist Sinhala leaders were sensitive to language and culture of Tamils"},{"question":"\\"Адам өлбөсө айыл башы...\\"  деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакап мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Адам өлбөсө айыл башы, соодагер өлбөсө кербен башы.\\""},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਮਾਝ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਤੇ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਧਿਆਵਉ ॥ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਇਆ ਤੇ ਮੰਗਲੁ ਗਾਵਉ ॥ਊਠਤ ਬੈਠਤ ਸੋਵਤ ਜਾਗਤ ਹਰਿ ਧਿਆਈਐ ਸਗਲ ਅਵਰਦਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੧॥ਨਾਮੁ ਅਉਖਧੁ ਮੋ ਕਉ ਸਾਧੂ ਦੀਆ ॥ਕਿਲਬਿਖ ਕਾਟੇ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਥੀਆ ॥ਅਨਦੁ ਭਇਆ ਨਿਕਸੀ ਸਭ ਪੀਰਾ ਸਗਲ ਬਿਨਾਸੇ ਦਰਦਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੨॥ਜਿਸ ਕਾ ਅੰਗੁ ਕਰੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ ॥ ਸੋ ਮੁਕਤਾ ਸਾਗਰ ਸੰਸਾਰਾ ॥ਸਤਿ ਕਰੇ ਜਿਨਿ ਗੁਰੂ ਪਛਾਤਾ ਸੋ ਕਾਹੇ ਕਉ ਡਰਦਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੩॥ਜਬ ਤੇ ਸਾਧੂ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਪਾਏ ॥ ਗੁਰ ਭੇਟਤ ਹਉ ਗਈ ਬਲਾਏ ॥ਸਾਸਿ ਸਾਸਿ ਹਰਿ ਗਾਵੈ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਸਤਿਗੁਰ ਢਾਕਿ ਲੀਆ ਮੇਰਾ ਪੜਦਾ ਜੀਉ ॥੪॥੧੭॥੨੪॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 101 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਹਾਂ, ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਹੀ ਕਿਰਪਾ ਨਾਲ ਮੈਂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦਾ ਗੀਤ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹਾਂ । (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਉਠਦਿਆਂ ਬੈਠਦਿਆਂ ਸੁੱਤਿਆਂ ਜਾਗਦਿਆਂ ਸਾਰੀ (ਹੀ) ਉਮਰ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਹੈ ।੧। ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦਾ ਨਾਮ ਦਾਰੂ (ਮੈਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਨੇ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ)(ਇਸ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਰੇ) ਪਾਪ ਕੱਟੇ ਗਏ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਪਵਿਤ੍ਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ । (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਤਮਕ) ਸੁਖ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ) ਸਾਰੀ ਪੀੜਾ ਨਿਕਲ ਗਈ, ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁਖ-ਦਰਦ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਏ ।੨। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿਆਰਾ (ਗੁਰੂ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ) ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਸਹੈਤਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ (ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ) ਤੋਂ ਮੁਕਤ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੇ ਸਰਧਾ ਧਾਰ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾ ਲਈ, ਉਸ ਨੂੰ (ਇਸ ਸੰਸਾਰ-ਸਮੁੰਦਰ ਤੋਂ) ਡਰਨ ਦੀ ਲੋੜ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਰਹਿ ਜਾਂਦੀ ।੩। (ਹੇ ਭਾਈ !) ਜਦੋਂ ਤੋਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਮਿਲੀ ਹੈ, ਗੁਰੂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਿਆਂ (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ) ਹਉਮੈ ਦੀ ਬਲਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਈ । ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾ ਕੇ) ਮੇਰੀ ਇੱਜ਼ਤ ਰੱਖ ਲਈ ਹੈ । ਹੁਣ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰੇਕ ਸੁਆਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੇ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।੪।੧੭।੨੪।\\""},{"question":"Thợ may cần dùng đến vật dụng nào?A – Máy khâuB – Kim tiêmC – Nhiệt kếD – Súng","answer":"Đáp án: A"},{"question":"வினா: தமிழக விளையாட்டுகள் குறித்து ஒரு கட்டுரை வரைக. ","answer":"விடை: கலைகளைப் பல்வேறு வகைகளாகப் பகுத்தறிந்துள்ளனர் நம் முன்னோர். அவற்றினுள் விளையாட்டுக் கலை வாழ்வோடு பிணைந்த ஒன்றாகும். “அந்தந்த நாட்டின் இயற்கை அமைப்பு, சுற்றுப்புறச் சூழல், மக்களின் சிந்தனைகள், பழக்க வழக்கங்கள், சமயங்கள் முதலியவற்றின் தன்மைக்கேற்ப கலைகள் வளர்ச்சி பெறும்” என்று மயிலை. சீனி. வேங்கடசாமி (தமிழர் வளர்த்த அழகு கலைகள்) அவர்கள் குறிப்பிடுகிறார். அவ்வாறே விளையாட்டுகளும் மக்களின் வாழ்வியல் சூழலுக்கு ஏற்ப தனித்தன்மைகளுடன் திகழ்கின்றன. அவ்விளையாட்டுக் கலையானது தமிழக நிலப்பரப்பினுள் தொடக்கக் காலம் முதல் இன்று வரை எவ்வாறெல்லாம் வழங்கப்பட்டு வருகின்றன என்பதைக் குறித்ததாக இக்கட்டுரை அமைகிறது.மனிதன் இயற்கையோடு இயைந்து வாழ்ந்தபோது பல சவால்கள் அவன் முன் இருந்தன. அவை அவனுக்கு ஆற்றலைப் பெருக்கிக் கொள்ளவும், இயற்கையை எதிர் கொள்ளவும் அவனுக்குக் கற்றுத்தந்தது. தொடக்கத்தில் தற்பாதுகாப்புக்காக ஓடவும், சாடவும், தாண்டவும், நீந்தவும் செய்வதன் சமூகவளர்ச்சியில் நிலையான வாழ்க்கைக்கு வந்த போது அவற்றினைத் தன் ஆற்றலின் அடையாளமாகவும், விளையாட்டாகவும் மாற்றியிருக்க வேண்டும். இவ்விளையாட்டுகளின் தோற்றம் குறித்து, “வீரத்தை வளர்க்க, பயத்தைவிரட்ட, நம்பிக்கையை ஊட்ட, நண்பர்களைப் பெருக்க, பொழுது போக்கை வரவேற்க, முரண்பாட்டை உணர்ந்த, வாழ்க்கையினையும், தொழிலினையும் எதிரொலிக்க, போலச் செய்ய எனப் பல நிலைகளில் விளையாட்டுகள் தோன்றலாயின” என்கிறார். சு. சிவசாமிசுந்தரி (சங்க இலக்கிய விளையாட்டுக் களஞ்சியம்)மனித சமூகம் சிந்திக்கும் ஆற்றலாலும் உழைப்பாலும் தன்னை தகவமைத்துக் கொண்ட  உயர்த்திக் கொண்ட பெருமையுடையது. தொடக்கக் காலத்தில் தமது உழைப்பு – தொழில் சார்ந்ததாக விளையாட்டுகள் அமைந்திருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் பின்னர் சமுதாய வளர்ச்சிப் படிநிலையில் விளையாட்டுகள் தனித்தன்மை பெற்றிருக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அறிஞர்கள் கருதுகின்றனர்.மிகத் தொன்மையான பதிவுகளாக நமக்குக் கிடைக்கக் கூடிய சங்க இலக்கியங்களில் இவ்விளையாட்டுகள் குறித்த செய்திகள் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன. இதனை, “பண்டைய தமிழகத்தில்  சங்க காலத்தில் – ஆடவரும் பெண்டிரும் விளையாட்டுகளில் மிகுதியாக ஈடுபட்டிருந்தனர் என்பதைச் சங்க இலக்கியங்கள் எடுத்துரைக்கின்றன. ‘விளை’ என்ற சொல் பொருள் பொதிந்தது. ‘விளைக’, ‘பொலிக’ என பரிபாடல் (10-86) குறிப்பிடுகிறது. ‘விளைக’, என்பது வாழ்த்துவதாகும். நச்சினார்க்கினியர் சீவகசிந்தாமணி 260 ஆம் பாடலுக்கு வரைந்த உரையில்  “விளைக, பொலிக ஒரு வழக்கு என்பாரும் உளர்” எனக் குறிப்பிடுவதிலிருந்து நல்லதே ஆகுக என வாழ்த்துவது விளைதலாகும் என்று  தெரியலாம். எனவே ‘விளை’ என்ற வேர்ச்சொல் நல்லதான இன்பம் பயப்பது என்று பொருள்படும். ‘விளையாட்டாய மொடு ஓரையாடாது’ (நற்றிணை – 68), ‘விளையாட்டு ஆயமொடு’ வெண்மணல் அழுத்தி (நற்றிணை – 172) என்னும் வரிகளிலிருந்து விளையாட்டின் கூட்டுத்தன்மை அஃதாவது பலர் கூடிப் பங்கு பெறும் தன்மை புலனாகிறது. பண்டைத் தமிழகத்தில் சிறார்க்கென்றும், ஆடவர்க்கென்றும், பெண்டிர்க்கென்றும், இருபாவார்க்கென்றும், இருபாவார்க்கென்றும் பலவகை விளையாட்டுக்கள் இருந்தன. அவை நாநிலப் பாகுபாட்டை ஒட்டி அமைந்ததனையும் காணலாம். குறிஞ்சியில் கிளி ஓட்டுதலும் முல்லை, மருதத்தில் ஏறு தழுவுதலும் நெய்தலில் அலவன் ஆட்டலும் எடுத்துக்காட்டுகள்.” என்பதன் (பதிப்புரை, சங்க இலக்கிய விளையாட்டுக் களஞ்சியம்) மூலம் அறியலாம்.சு.சிவகாமிசுந்தரி அவர்கள் சங்க இலக்கிய விளையாட்டுக் களஞ்சியம் என்னும் தமது ஆய்வு நூலில் ‘37’ வகையான விளையாட்டுகள் பற்றிய குறிப்புகள் சங்க இலக்கியங்களில் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளதாகக் குறிப்பிடுகின்றார். அவை,அசதியாடல் –அம்புலி அழைத்தல் – அலவன் ஆட்டல் உலாவல்ஊசல் எண்ணி விளையாடல் எதிரொலி கேட்டல் ஏறு கோள்கண் பதைத்து ஒளித்தாடல் கவண் கழங்குகுதிரை ஏற்றமும் யானை ஏற்றமும் குரவை (கூத்து) குறும்பு விளையாட்டுகள் சாம விளையாட்டு சிறு சோறு ஆக்கல் சிறுதேர் சிறு பறைசிற்றில் செய்தல்சுண்ண விளையாட்டு செடி கொடி வளர்ப்புநீர் விளையாட்டுபந்துபறவைகளைக் காணலும் அவற்றின் செயல்கள் போல் செய்தலும் பறவை வளர்ப்பும் விலங்கு வளர்ப்பும்  பறவை விலங்குகளுடன் விளையாடல் பாவை விளையாட்டுபிசி – நொடி விளையாட்டுபுள் ஓட்டல் மணற் குவியலில் மறைத்தாடல் மலர் கொய்தலும் மாலை தொடுத்தலும்  வட்டுவள்ளை வில் விளையாட்டு வேட்டைதொ. இரா. நஞ்சுண்டன் அவர்கள் காப்பியங்களில் விளையாட்டுகள் என்னும் நூலில் இதே போன்று 34 விளையாட்டுகளை அட்டவணைப்படுத்தியுள்ளார். அதில் மேல்குறிப்பிட்டுள்ளவற்றில் இல்லாத பத்து விளையாட்டுகள் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன. அவைஅம்மானைஇடுதேளிடல்உகிரால் பற்பல உருவம் கிள்ளல்கருவுற்ற பெண்போல் நடித்து விளையாடல்கள்வர் – காப்பவர் – மறிகள் என நடித்து விளையாடல்சம்மங்கோரை கொண்டு விளையாடல்’சிவம்பம்செண்டாடல்பட்டம் படகு விளையாட்டுசங்க இலக்கிய விளையாட்டுகளுள் அசதியாடல், அம்புலி அழைத்தல், அலவன் ஆட்டல், உலாவல், ஊசல், எண்ணி விளையாடல், சுண்ண விளையாட்டு, சூது, நீர்விளையாட்டு, பந்து, பறவைகளைக் காணலும் அவற்றின் செயல்கள் போல் செய்தலும், பறவை, விலங்குகளுடன் விளையாடல் என்றும் பன்னிரெண்டு விளையாட்டுகளும் இருபாலாரும் விளையாடும் விளையாட்டுகளாம். அதே போன்று, ஏறுகோள், குதிரை ஏற்றமும் யானை ஏற்றமும், குறும்பு விளையாட்டுகள், சாமவிளையாட்டு, சிறுதேர், சிறுபறை, மல், வில் விளையாட்டு, வட்டு, வேட்டை முதலானவை ஆண்பாலாருக்கும், எதிரொலி கேட்டல், கண்பதைத்து ஒளிந்தாடல், கவண், கழங்கு, குரவை, சிறுசோறு, சிற்றில் செய்தல், செடி – கொடி வளர்ப்பு, பறவை வளர்ப்பும் விலங்கு வளர்ப்பும், பாவை விளையாட்டு, பிசி – நொடி விளையாட்டு, புள் ஓட்டல், மணற் குவியலில் மறைத்தாடல், மலர் கொய்தலும் மாலை தொடுத்தலும், வள்ளை முதலானவை பெண்பாலாருக்கு உரியனவாகக் குறிப்பிடப்படுகிறது.இதே போன்று இன்றளவிலும் நம்மவர்கள் விளையாடும் விளையாட்டுகளை ஆண்களுக்கு உரியன, பெண்களுக்கு உரியன, இருபாலருக்கும் உரியன என்றும் குழந்தைகளுக்கான விளையாட்டு, பெரியவர்களுக்கான விளையாட்டுகள் என்றும் பகுத்தறியலாம்.தமிழ் நாட்டு விளையாட்டுகளுள் இன்று சிறார்களால் மிகுதியாக விளையாடப்படும் விளையாட்டுகளான கோலி, கில்லி (கிட்டிப்புள்) அல்லது சில்லாங்குச்சு, எறிபந்து, காயா பழமா, பம்பரம், கிளித்தட்டு, சடுகுடு(கபடி), பூக்குதிரை, பாய்ச்சல் குதிரை ஆகியன உள்ளன.கோலிகண்ணாடியாலும் கல்லாலும் ஆன சிற்றுருண்டைகளை விரல்களால் சுண்டியும், உருட்டியும், எறிந்தும் ஆடும் ஆட்டம் கோலி ஆட்டம் எனப்படும்.கில்லிகில்லி ஆட்டத்திற்குக் கிட்டிப்புள், சில்லாங்குச்சு ஆகிய பெயர்களும் உள்ளன. சிறு குச்சு ஒன்றை ஒரு கோலால் தட்டி ஆடும் ஆட்டமாக இது அமைகிறதுஎறிபந்துபந்தினை ஒருவர் மேல் ஒருவர் எறிந்தாடும் ஆட்டமாகும்.காயா பழமா?நீர் நிலைகளில் நின்று கொண்டு காயா பழமா? என்று கேட்டு தண்ணீரில் விரலால் சுண்டி ஓசை எழுப்பி ஆடும் ஆட்டமாகும்.பம்பரங்களை ஆடவிட்டு ஆடும் பம்பர ஆட்டம் ஓயாக்கட்டை, உடைந்த கட்டை, பம்பர குத்து, இருவட்டக் குத்து, தலையாரி என்றும் முறைகளில் விரும்பிய வகையில் ஆடப்படுகிறது.கிளித்தட்டுநீள் நாற்கோண வரப்புக் கோடுகள் அமைக்கப்பட்டு அவற்றின் குறுக்கே விளையாடுபவரின் எண்ணிக்கையைப் பொறுத்து குறுக்காகத் தட்டுக் கோடுகள் அமைத்து விளையாடுவர். இரு அணியாகப் பிரிந்து ஒரு அணியின் தட்டுள். இறங்குவர் மறு அணியினர் மறிப்பர். பிடி கொடாமல் தப்பிப்பதற்குப் பயிற்சியாக அமையும் இவ்விளையாட்டு.சடுகுடு (கபடி)தமிழர் விளையாட்டுகளுள் முதன்மையான ஒன்றாக சடுகுடு திகழ்கிறது. ஏறு தழுவுதலுக்கு (ஜல்லிகட்டு) தயாராவதற்கு முன் மேற்கொள்ளும் பயிற்சியாகவும் இதனை சிலர் குறிப்பிடுகின்றனர். கை + பிடி = கபடி என்று இதற்கு பெயர் வந்திருக்க வேண்டும் என்பாரும் உளர். இரு அணிகளுக்கு இடையே நிகழும் ஆட்களைப் பிடிக்கும் போட்டியாக இது திகழ்கிறது.பூக்குதிரைஒரு பூவின் பெயரைச் சொல்லி ஒருவர் மேல் ஒருவர் குதிரையேறி விளையாடுவது பூக்குதிரை.பாய்ச்சல் குதிரைஒருவர் கீழே அமர்ந்தும், பின் குனிந்தும் தன் உயரத்தைப் படிப்படியாக உயர்த்திக் கொண்டே இருப்பார். வரிசையாக தாண்டுபவர்கள் எந்நிலையிலேனும் தாண்ட முடியாது நின்றால் அவர் குனிந்து நிற்க, பிறர் அவ்வாறே தாண்டி விளையாடுவது பாய்ச்சல் குதிரை.அதே போன்று பெண்களால் ஆடப்படுவனவற்றுள் கழங்கு, பாடல் ஆட்டம், பாண்டி, கண்ணாம்பொத்தி போன்றவை சிறப்பிடம் பெறுவனவாகும்.கழங்குபெண்கள் விளையாடும் விளையாட்டுகளுள் கழங்கு சிறப்பிடம் பெற்றுள்ளது.  பெண்கள் சிறு கற்களைக் கைகளால்  தட்டிப்பிடிக்கும் விளையாட்டாக இது அமைகிறது.  கழங்கு வீட்டினுள்ளும் வீட்டு முற்றத்திலும் விளையாடப்படும்.  இவ்விளையாட்டானது பயன்படுத்தப்படும் சிறு கற்களின் எண்ணிக்கையைப் பொறுத்து பல பெயர்களால் அழைக்கப்படுகின்றன.  அவை மூன்றாங்கல், ஐந்தாங்கல், ஏழாங்கல், பல நாலொருகல், பன்னிருகல், பலகல், பதினாறாங்கல் என்பனவாகும். தட்டாங்கல் என பொதுவாகவும் அழைப்பதுண்டு.பாடல் ஆட்டம்சிறுமியர் இருவராகவோ, இரு அணியினராகவோ நின்று கொண்டு புதிர்பாடல்கள் பாடி ஆடும் ஆட்டம் பாடல் ஆட்டம் எனப்படும்.உதாரணமாக ஆடும் – ஓநாயும் ஆட்டம்.இதில் வரிசையாக ஒருவர் இடுப்பை மற்றவர் பிடித்தபடி நிற்பார்கள்.   இவர்கள் ஆடுகள், ஒருவர் மட்டும் சுற்றிவந்து வரிசையில் இருந்தது பிரிபவரைப் பிடிக்க முயல்வார்.  அவர் ஓநாய். கீழ் உள்ளது போல், தங்களின் உள்ளம் போல் பாடிக்கொண்டே ஆடுவர்.ஓநாய்:என்னாட்டைக் காணோமேஆடு: தேடிப் பிடிச்சுக்கோஓநாய்: அடுப்பு மேல ஏறுவேன்ஆடு: துடுப்பைக்கொண்டு சாத்துவேன்ஓநாய்: நெல்லைக் கொறிப்பேன்ஆடு: பல்லை உடைப்பேன்ஓநாடு: வடி தண்ணியைக் கொட்டுவேன்ஆடு:வழிச்சு வழிச்சு நக்கிக்கோஓநாய்:கோட்டை மேலே ஏறுவேன்ஆடு: கொள்ளிக் கொண்டு சாத்துவேன்ஓநாய்:என்னாட்டைக் காணோமே?ஆடு: தேடிப் பிடிச்சுக்கோ.இவ்வாறு கேள்வி-பதில் வடிவில் தொடரும். குழந்தைகள் கேள்விகளுக்குச் சட்டென்று(உடனடியாக) பதிலளிக்கும் பழக்கத்தை இவை போன்ற விளையாட்டுகள் உருவாக்கும்.  சிறுவர், சிறுமியர் இருபாலரும் இத்தகைய பாடல் ஆட்டத்தை ஆடுவர்.கண்ணாம்பொத்திஒருவர் கண்களைப் பொத்தி கொண்டிருக்கும்போது மற்ற சிறார்கள் ஓடி ஒளிவர்.  பின்னர் கண்களைப் பொத்திக்கொண்ட சிறுவர் ஓடிப்போய் அங்கும் இங்கும் பார்த்து ஒளிந்து கொண்டிருக்கும் சிறுவர்களுள் ஒருவரைத் தொடமுயல்வார்.  முதலாவது தொடப்பட்ட சிறுவர் அடுத்த முறை கண்களைப் பொத்த ஆட்டம் தொடரும்.குலைகுலையாய் முந்திரிக்காய்சிறார் பலரும் வட்டமாய் உள்நோக்கி உட்கார்ந்திருப்பர்.  ஒருவர் திரிபோல முறுக்கிய துணியொன்றைக் கையில் வைத்துக்கொண்டு ‘குலைகுலையாய் முந்திரிக்காய்’  என்று கூறியபடி சிறாரைச் சுற்றி வலமாக ஓடிவரும்போது யாருக்கும் தெரியாமல் கையில் உள்ள திரியை ஒருவர் பின்னே வைத்து விடுவார்.  வைக்கப்பட்ட திரியின் நேரே உள்ளவர் உடனே கண்டு எடுக்காவிடின் சுற்றி வருபவர்  அருகில் வரும்போது அவர் முதுகில் திரியால் மெதுவாகத் தட்டி எழுப்பிவிடுவார்.  ஓடிவந்தவர் அங்கு அமர்ந்துவிடுவார். எழும்பியவர் திரியுடன் ஓடிவர வேண்டும்.  இவ்விளையாட்டிற்குத் திரித்திரி பந்தம் என்ற பெயரும் உண்டு.நொண்டிகட்டமாகவோ, சதுரமாகவோ கீறப்பட்ட கோட்டினுள் அணியாக நிற்பர்.  ஒருகாலை மடக்கி நொண்டி செல்பவர் ஒருவரையோ, பலரையோ தொட்டு வெளியேற்றவேண்டும்.கும்மிசிறுமியர் கைகளைக் குவித்து தட்டி ஓசையெழுப்பி பாடலோடு ஆடும் ஆட்டம் கும்மியாகும்.  இதற்கென தனியாகப் பாடல்கள் உள்ளன.தாயம்தாயம் மிகத்தொன்மையான விளையாட்டுகளுள் ஒன்றாகப் பார்க்கப்படுகிறது.  தமிழில் கிடைக்கப்பெற்றுள்ள முதல் நூலான தொல்காப்பியத்திலும் இது குறித்தக் குறிப்புகள் இடம் பெற்றுள்ளன.  இது பலவகைப்படும்.  நாயும், புலியும், பரமபதமம், குறுக்குக் கட்டத்தாயம் போன்றவையும் இதன் வழிவந்தவையே என்பர்.இதே போன்ற விளையாட்டுகள் மட்டுமல்லாமல் ஏறுதழுவுதல், சிலம்பாட்டம், களரி போன்ற வீர விளையாட்டுகளும் தொன்மையான காலந்தொட்டே தமிழர்களால் விளையாடப்பட்டு வருகின்றன.ஏறுதழுவுதல்காளைகளை அடக்கும் வீரவிளையாட்டாக இது திகழ்கிறது.  தொன்மையான இலக்கியங்கள் பலவற்றிலும் இது தொடர்பான செய்திகள் காணப்படுகின்றன. இன்றைய ஜல்லிக்கட்டு இதனோடு தொடர்புபடுத்திப் பார்க்கக் கூடியதாக உள்ளது. ஆநிரைகளை அடக்குதல், காளைகளை அடக்கும் முன் குரவைக்கூத்து நிகழ்த்துதல் போன்ற தகவல்கள் பழந்தமிழ் இலக்கியங்களில் காணப்பட்டாலும் இவ்விளையாட்டு குறித்த விரிவான தகவல்கள் அவற்றில் இடம்பெறவில்லை.  இருப்பினும் தொன்றுதொட்டு நிகழ்ந்து வருகின்ற ஒன்றாக இதனைக் கருதுகின்றனர்.சிலம்பம்இது தமிழர்களின் தற்பாதுகாப்புக்கலை.  வீரவிளையாட்டாகவும் திகழ்கிறது.  கம்பு சுற்றுதல் என்றும் கூறுவதுண்டு. இதில் கம்பு சுற்றும் முறை, கால் மற்றும் உடல் அசைவுகள் முதன்மை இடம் பெறுகின்றன.  கலிங்கத்துப் பரணியில் “வீசு தண்டிடை கூர்மழு ஒக்குமே” என்று வரும் இடத்தில் தண்டு எனக்குறிப்பிடுவது சிலம்பக்கம்பினையே என்பர். கம்புசூத்திரம், குறுந்தடி சிலம்பம் என்றும் சுவடிகள் சிலம்பப்பயிற்சி தொடர்பானவை என்றும் கூறுகின்றனர்.களரிகளரிக் கலையும் பழந்தமிழகத்தில் தோன்றிய வீரவிளையாட்டுகளுள் ஒன்றாகும். இது வடக்கன்களரி,  தெக்கன் களரி என இரு வகைப்படும்.  தமிழகத்தின் தென்பகுதியிலும் இன்றைய கேரளாவான சேரநாட்டிலும் இக்கலை வடிவம் இன்றும் சிறப்புடன் திகழ்கின்றது.  வாள், கத்தி, மான்கொம்பு, சுருள்வாழ், மழு, கோடாலி போன்ற ஆயுதங்களைப் பயன்படுத்தி ஆடும் ஆட்டமாகும்.இதே போன்ற எண்ணிடலங்காத விளையாட்டுகளுக்கு உரிமையுடையவர்களாக நம்மவர்கள் திகழ்கின்றனர்.  நமது இயற்கைச் சூழல், பண்பாடு போன்றவற்றிற்கு ஏற்ப இவ்விளையாட்டுகள் இடம் பெறுகின்றன.இவ்விளையாட்டுகளைக் குறித்து நுணுகி ஆய்வுகள் மேற்கொண்டால் தமிழக மக்கள் எத்தகைய விளையாட்டுகளை எல்லாம் தொடர்ந்து ஆடிவந்தனர் என்பது வெளிப்படும்.  மேலும் தொன்மையான விளையாட்டுகள் பலவும் எவ்வாறெல்லாம் மாற்றம் பெற்று ஆடப்படுகின்றன என்பதையும் அறிந்துகொள்ள முடியும்."},{"question":"લગન ગીત \\"મંગળ ફેરા…\\"  લખો.","answer":"પહેલું પહેલું મંગળીયું વરતાય રેપહેલે મંગળ ગાયોનાં દાન દેવાય રેઅગ્નિદેવની સાક્ષીએ ફેરા ફરાય રેસૌને હૈયે આનંદ અતિ ઉભરાય રેબીજું બીજું મંગળીયું વરતાય રેબીજે મંગળ રૂપાનાં દાન દેવાય રેમાંડવડાનાં મંગળ ગીતો ગવાય રેશુભદિન આજે શુકનનો કહેવાય રેત્રીજું ત્રીજું મંગળીયું વરતાય રેત્રીજે મંગળ સોનાનાં દાન દેવાય રેફુલડાં કેરી ફોરમ બધે પ્રસરાય રેબન્ને પક્ષે આનંદ અતિ ઉભરાય રેચોથું ચોથું મંગળીયું વરતાય રેચોથે મંગળ કન્યાનાં દાન દેવાય રેઅગ્નિદેવની સાક્ષીએ ફેરા ફરાય રેમાંડવડાનાં મંગળ ગીતો ગવાય રે"},{"question":"The Umbilical Cord","answer":"The Umbilical Cord is a tube that connects you to your baby during pregnancy. It has three blood vessels: one vein that carries food and oxygen from the placenta to your baby, and two arterials that carry waste from your baby back to the placenta. For short \\"AVA\\"."},{"question":"ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਕੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ? ਇਹ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਲਈ ਕਿਉਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ ?","answer":"ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ -ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਰਸਾਇਣਿਕ ਪਦਾਰਥ ਹਨ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੇ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਲਈ ਲੋੜ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਹੁਣ ਤਕ ਕਈ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਖੋਜ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਮੁੱਖ ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਛੇ ਹੀ ਮੰਨੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਹਨ : ‘ਏ’, ‘ਬੀ’, ‘ਸੀ’, ‘ਡੀ’, ‘ਬੀ’ ਅਤੇ ‘ਕੇ’ । ਇਹਨਾਂ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ‘ਬੀ’ ਤੇ ‘ਸੀ ਪਾਣੀ ਵਿਚ ਘੁਲਣਸ਼ੀਲ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਬਾਕੀ ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ‘ਏ’ ‘ਡੀ’ ਤੇ ‘ਕੇ ਚਰਬੀ ਵਿਚ ਘੁਲਣਸ਼ੀਲ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਨ । ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਕਈ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਖ਼ੁਰਾਕ ਪਦਾਰਥਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਏ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ । ਭੋਜਨ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਉੱਚਿਤ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਦਾ ਹੋਣਾ ਜ਼ਰੂਰੀ ਹੈ । ਭੋਜਨ ਦੀ ਜੀਵਨ ਲਈ ਬਹੁਤ ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾ ਮਹੱਤਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਅਨੁਭਵ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਜੀਵਨ-ਦਾਤਾ ਵੀ ਆਖਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਡੀ ਧੁੱਪ ਤੋਂ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਹੈ । ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਦੀ ਸਰੀਰ ਲਈ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ  –ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਦੀ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਲਈ ਜ਼ਰੂਰਤ ਅੱਗੇ ਲਿਖੇ ਤੱਤਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਸਪੱਸ਼ਟ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ –    * ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਸਾਡੀ ਸਿਹਤ ਨੂੰ ਠੀਕ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਨ ।    * ਇਹ ਸਾਡੇ ਸਰੀਰਕ ਵਾਧੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।    * ਇਹ ਸਾਡੀ ਪਾਚਨ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਵਧਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।    * ਇਹ ਸਾਡਾ ਖੂਨ ਸਾਫ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ਅਤੇ ਖੂਨ ਦੀ ਮਾਤਰਾ ਵਿਚ  ਵਾਧਾ ਕਰਦੇ       ਹਨ ।    * ਇਹ ਹੱਡੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਦੰਦਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਜ਼ਬੂਤ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।    * ਇਹ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਬਿਮਾਰੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਮੁਕਾਬਲਾ ਕਰਨ ਦੇ ਯੋਗ ਬਣਾਉਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।    * ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਰਾਹੀਂ ਚਮੜੀ ਦੇ ਰੋਗ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਹਨ ।    * ਵਿਟਾਮਿਨ ਸਰੀਰ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਵਿਚ ਵਾਧਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹਨ ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'daripada bersahabat dengan orang yang bodoh, baik berseteru dengan orang berakal'?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini ialah lebih berbaloi untuk bermusuh dengan orang berakal daripada berkawan dengan orang yang bodoh, kerana kita boleh bermanfaat daripada tindak balas dengan orang yang cerdik."},{"question":"Qual das seguintes frases está no modo imperativo: A - João, pintaste as figuras para o espetáculo rapidamente.B - O João pintava as figuras para o espetáculo rapidamente.C - João, pinta as figuras para o espetáculo rapidamente.D - O João pinta as figuras para o espetáculo rapidamente.","answer":"A resposta é C."},{"question":"Limal ma diwaan yi ame ci senegaal ","answer":"Diwaan yi ame ci senegaal ño ngii:Dakar, Thies, Diourbel, Kaolack, Kaffrine, Louga, Ndarr, Tambacounda, Siguithior, Matam, Kolda, Sedhiou, Kedougou ak Fatick"},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو نظام الكمبيوتر؟","answer":"الإجابة: نظام الكمبيوتر هو مزيج من الذاكرة ووحدة المعالجة المركزية والأجهزة الطرفية المتصلة به ونظام التشغيل (نظام التشغيل)."},{"question":"මුල්ම පාප් වහන්සේ කවුරුන් ද?","answer":"කතෝලික සම්ප්‍රදායට අනුව කතෝලික සභාවේ හෙවත් පල්ලියේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ පාප් වහන්සේ ය. කතෝලික සභාවේ ආරම්භයේ සිට ම විවිධ පාප් වහන්සේවරු මෙම ධූරය හෙබවූ සේක. කතෝලික විශ්වාසයන්ට අනුව සභාවේ පළමු පාප්වහන්සේ වන්නේ ජේසුස් වහන්සේගේ අපෝස්තුළුවරයෙකු වූ ශාන්ත පීතර පාප් වහන්සේ ය. ශුද්ධ වූ බයිබලයට අනුව ජේසුස් වහන්සේ ඔහුට ස්වර්ගයේ යතුර පිරිනමනු ලැබූ සේක. "},{"question":"வினா: ஏழைகளின் ஊட்டி என்று அழைக்கப்படும் இடம் எது?","answer":"விடை: ஏற்காடு"},{"question":"Ajọ WAEC gbẹsẹ le esi idanwo awọn akẹkọọ to jiwee wo lasiko idanwo","answer":"Awọn akẹkọọ bii igba o le diẹ (215,149), ni ajọ to n ṣeto idanwo WAEC ti sọ pe oun ko ni i ti i fun ni esi idanwo wọn bayii.Ọga agba fun ajọ naa, Patrick Areghan, lo sọrọ yii nipinlẹ Eko nigba to n ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ pe ajọ naa ti ṣetan lati gbe esi idanwo ọhun jade.Ẹsun ti wọn fi kan awọn ti wọn ko gbe esi idanwo wọn jade ni pe wọn ji iwe wo lasiko ti idanwo ọhun waye.O ni bii ida mẹtala-o-le (13.98%) ninu awọn ti wọn jokoo ṣe idanwo ọhun ni wọn ko ni i ti i ri esi idanwo ọhun gba latari oriṣiiriṣii ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn.Bakan naa lo sọ pe iwadii ti waye lori ẹsun ti wọn fi kan wọn pe wọn ji iwe wo atawọn ohun mi-in to ṣẹlẹ lasiko idanwo. O ni awọn yoo fi abajade awọn ṣọwọ si igbimọ to yẹ, nibi ti aṣaro yoo ti waye lori ọrọ ọhun. Bẹẹ gẹgẹ lo sọ pe gbogbo awọn ileewe ti ọrọ ba kan pata lawọn yoo kan si.Akẹkọọ tiye wọn le ni miliọnu kan aabọ ni wọn ṣedanwo ọhun, nigba ti awọn ti wọn le diẹ ni miliọnu kan ṣe daadaa ninu iṣẹ bii marun-un, ninu eyi ti ẹkọ ede oyinbo ati imọ iṣiro ti wa.O ni apapọ akẹkọọ bii miliọnu kan ati ẹgbẹrun lọna ọọdunrun-o-le diẹ ni wọn ṣe daadaa ninu iṣẹ marun-un, yala wọn jokoo tabi wọn ko jokoo ṣedanwo fun ẹkọ iṣiro ati ẹkọ ede gẹẹsi ninu idanwọ ọhun.Ọjọ kẹtadinlogun, oṣu kẹjọ ọdun yii ni idanwo ọhun bẹrẹ, ti wọn si kadii ẹ nilẹ lọjọ kejila, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii"},{"question":"வினா:பின்வரும் பாடலுக்கு இலக்கிய நயம் பாராட்டு எ ழுதுக:”எத்துணையும் பேதமுறாது எவ்வுயிரும்தம்முயிர்போல் எண்ணி உள்ளேஒத்துரிமை உடையவராய் உவக்கின்றார்யாவர் அவர் உள்ளம்தான் சுத்தசித்துருவாய் எம்பெருமான் நடம்புரியும்இடம் என நான் தெரிந்தேன் அந்தவித்தகர்தம் அடிக்கேவல் புரிந்திட என்சிந்தை மிக விழைந்த தாலே” – வள்ளலார்","answer":" விடை: இலக்கிய நயம் பாராட்டுதல்: முன்னுரை:வள்ளலார் எனப் போற்றப்படும் இராமலிங்க அடிகள் சமத்துவமும், சமதர்மமும் வளரவும், சமயம் என்பது பிறர்நலன் போற்றுவதாக அமையவும் குரல் கொடுத்தவர் ஆவார். இறைவனை எண்ணி இவர் பாடிய பாடல்கள் சிறப்புடன் விளங்குகின்றன. அந்த வகையில் இவரது பாடலில் அமைந்துள்ள இலக்கிய நயங்களைக் காண்போம்.திரண்ட கருத்து:எந்த ஒரு வேறுபாட்டையும் வெளிப்படுத்தாது எல்லா உயிர்களையும் தம் உயிர் போல எண்ணி, தன் உள்ளத்துள்ளே ஒத்த அன்புடையவராய் இருப்பவரை இறைவன் உவந்து ஏற்கிறார் அத்தகைய உள்ளம் உடையவர்களே சித்துருவாய்த் திகழும் எம்பெருமான் நடம்புரியும் இடம் ஆகும். எல்லா வல்ல இறைவன் அடிக்கு ஏவல் புரியும் சிந்தைமிக இருந்ததால் எவ்வுயிரிடத்தும் அன்புடன் வாழ விழைந்தேன்.மையக்கருத்து:அனைத்து உயிர்களிடத்தும் அன்பு பாராட்டி உயிர்களுக்கு ஏவல் செய்வதே இறைவனுக்குச் செய்யும் தொண்டு. அவர் உள்ளத்துள்ளே இறைவன் உள்ளான் என்ற கருத்தை மையமாக வைத்து வள்ளலார் இப்பாடலைப் புனைந்துள்ளார்.மோனை நயம்:செய்யுளில் அடியிலோ சீரிலோ முதல் எழுத்து ஒன்றி வரத் தொடுப்பது மோனை ஆகும்.சான்று: எத்துணையும் எவ்வுயிரும் உடையவராய் உவக்கின்றார் என மோனை நயம் அமைந்துள்ளது.எதுகை நயம்:செய்யுளில் அடியிலோ சீரிலோ இரண்டாவது எழுத்து ஒன்றி வரத் தொடுப்பது எதுகை ஆகும்.சான்று:எத்துணையும், ஒத்துரிமை, சித்துரு, வித்தகர் என எதுகை நயம் மிக்குள்ளது.சந்த நயம்:“சந்தம் தமிழுக்குச் சொந்தம்” என்பதை உணர்த்தும் வகையில் அறுசீர்க்கழிநெடிலடி ஆசிரிய விருத்தம் பெற்று அகவல் ஓசையுடன் மையம் பொருந்த அமைந்துள்ளது.அணி நயம்:“எவ்வுயிரும் தம்முயிர் போல” என்பதில் உவமையணி இடம்பெற்றுள்ளதுமுடிவுரை:பக்தி உணர்வு சொட்ட பாடப்பட்டுள்ள இப்பாடல் பக்திச்சுவையும் இலக்கியச் சுவையையும் ஒருங்கே பெற்றுள்ளது."},{"question":"ቢል ክሊንተን ወደዚህ ምድር ከመምጣታቸው ከስንት ጊዜ በፊት ነው አባታቸው የሞቱት?","answer":"ሶስት ወር"},{"question":"O que é o super bowl?","answer":"Super bowl é o jogo final da temporada da NFL que ocorre, desde 2002, no segundo domingo do mês de fevereiro. Neste jogo se enfrentam os times campeões da Conferência Nacional (NFC) e da Conferência Americana (AFC). O time vencedor do super bowl é consagrado campeão da temporada e recebe o troféu Vince Lombardi. "},{"question":"নিচের বাক্যটির উপর ভিত্তি করে একটি সম্পূর্ণ পাঠ্য লিখুন।২০০২ খ্রিষ্টাব্দের গুজরাত দাঙ্গার ঘটনায়","answer":"২০০২ খ্রিষ্টাব্দের গুজরাত দাঙ্গার ঘটনায় তার প্রশাসন সমালোচিত হওয়ায় ভারত ও বিদেশে তার সমালোচনা হয়। কিন্তু গুজরাটের অর্থনৈতিক উন্নতির বৃদ্ধিতে সহায়ক পরিবেশ গঠনের জন্য তিনি তার আর্থিক নীতির জন্য প্রশংসিত হয়েছেন। অন্যদিকে তার রাজ্যের মানবোন্নয়নের ওপর গঠনমূলক প্রভাব বিস্তারে তার প্রশাসনের অক্ষমতার জন্য তিনি সমালোচিতও হয়েছেন।"},{"question":"Ekwughi ekwu mèrè ọnụ .","answer":"Egeghi ege mere ntị"},{"question":" چرا هنگام استفاده از خاک‌برگ برای تعویض گلدان نباید آن را فشار داد؟","answer":"به‌این‌علت که فشردگی زیاد خاک‌برگ سبب می‌شود که خاک‌برگ‌ها به هم بچسبند و از ورود هوا و تنفس ریشه که برای رشد گیاه بسیار مهم و ضروری است جلوگیری نماید."},{"question":"فين كاين الجبل الاخضر؟","answer":"سلطنة عمان."},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :পারস্যের মুসলিম বিজয়ের সময় আফগানিস্তানের মুসলিম বিজয় শুরু হয় যখন আরব মুসলমানরা পূর্ব দিকে খোরাসান, সিস্তান এবং ট্রান্সক্সিয়ানায় অভিবাসী হয়। নাহাভান্দ যুদ্ধের","answer":"১৫ বছর পর তারা দক্ষিণ ও পূর্ব আফগানিস্তান ছাড়া সকল সাসানীয় ডোমেইন নিয়ন্ত্রণ করে। মুসলিম ধর্মীয় প্রতিষ্ঠানগুলোকে পৃষ্ঠপোষকতা কারী গজনাভিদ ও ঘুরিদ রাজবংশের শাসনামলে দশম থেকে দ্বাদশ শতাব্দীর মধ্যবর্তী সময়কাল পর্যন্ত পূর্ণ ইসলামীকরণ হয়নি।"},{"question":"Como é que Saramago retratou a morte e a mortalidade nas suas narrativas?","answer":"Na obra \\"As Intermitências da Morte\\", Saramago imagina um mundo onde a morte deixa de existir. Ele explora as implicações sociais e pessoais desse cenário incomum, iluminando as complexidades do ciclo da vida e da transitoriedade."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε το κείμενο:  Είχε συμμετάσχει σε μία σειρά από προκριματικούς γύρους της χώρας του για την εκπροσώπηση στην Eurovision. Το 2009 με το τραγούδι \\"I Still Carry On\\", το","answer":"2011 με το τραγούδι \\"Bistvo skrito je očem\\", το 2014 με το τραγούδι \\"I Won't Give Up\\" καθώς και επίσης σε ελβετικό προκριματικό γύρο το 2016 με το τραγούδι \\"Take Me Far\\"."},{"question":"waan ku salaamay","answer":"waan kaa qaaday"},{"question":"Umbuzo othi: \\"Iavocado noma ialligator pear nayo ibhekisela esithelweni (ngokwezitshalo iberry enkulu equkethe imbewu eyodwa) somuthi.\\"? Isihloko sithi iAvocado.","answer":"\\"Yisiphi ingxenye yesitshalo okuyiavocado?\\""},{"question":"Между какими двумя организмами наиболее вероятно возникновение конкуренции? Доступные варианты: - олени и бабочки; - совы и бактерии; - золотые рыбки и кролики; - трава и клубника.","answer":"Из приведенных вариантов, наиболее вероятно возникновение конкуренции между травой и клубникой. Они обитают в одной и той же среде обитания и используют одни и те же ресурсы, в отличие от других вариантов. Например, рыбы обитают в воде, а кролике на земле - поэтому маловероятно, что они столкнутся."},{"question":"Sự kiện quan trọng nào được nói tới trong văn bản này? - Đới bắt đầu viết cho tờ Trung ngoại nhật báo (中外日報) của Thượng Hải và tờ Thiên Đạc báo (天鐸報) ở tuổi 19. Ông lấy tên hiệu Đới Thiên Cừu (天仇) để thể hiện sự căm hận với nhà Thanh. Chính quyền Mãn Thanh đe dọa tống giam ông, nên năm 1911, ông trốn sang Nhật Bản rồi Penang, tại đó ông gia nhập Đồng minh hội (同盟會) và viết bài cho tờ Quang Hoa báo (光華報) của hội. Cùng năm, ông trở về Thượng Hải sau Khởi nghĩa Vũ Xương và lập ra Dân quyền báo (民權報).","answer":"Sự kiện quan trọng được nói tới trong văn bản này là cuộc đời và hoạt động của người có tên hiệu Đới Thiên Cừu (天仇), người đã đóng góp tích cực vào các hoạt động báo chí và phong trào cách mạng tại Trung Quốc vào thời kỳ kháng Mãn Thanh. Ông bắt đầu viết cho các tờ báo như Trung ngoại nhật báo và Thiên Đạc báo, và sử dụng tên hiệu để thể hiện sự căm hận với nhà Thanh."},{"question":"Inona no maha samy hafa ny vola sy ny harena?","answer":"Ny vola dia manondro manokana ny vola na loharanon-karena ara-bola azo ampiasaina hividianana entana sy serivisy. Izy io dia fitaovam-panakalozana eken'ny maro amin'ny toe-karena. Ny harena kosa dia fepetra mivondrona kokoa izay tsy ny vola ihany fa ahitana ny fananana materialy. Ny fananana vola dia afaka manampy amin'ny harena, fa ny harena dia ahitana ny fananana, fampiasam-bola ary fananana hafa azo tsapain-tanana sy tsy azo tsapain-tanana."},{"question":"#දිවෙල්ගම් යනු මොනවාද?","answer":"\\"ජීවිතර්ථං දේයං...\\"\\"ඔවුන් එකිනෙකාට දිවෙල් පිණිස කිරි එක හමාරක වපසරිය දිය යුතුය\\" (ජේතවනාරාම (අභයගිරි) සංස්කෘත සෙල්ලිපිය)ජීවිතර්ථං - දිවෙල්. ජීවිතය පවත්වාගැනීම පිණිස දෙන දෙය - දිවෙල්.දිවෙල් - යම් මෙහෙවරක් වෙනුවෙන් ජීවත් වීමට දෙන ගම් බිම් ආදිය.දිවෙල්ගම- රාජ සේවය වෙනුවෙන් ලබා දුන් ගම."},{"question":"Geef me een voorbeeld van trivia in deze categorie: geschiedenis","answer":"Hier is een voorbeeld: Wanneer is de eerste wereldoorlog begonnen? Antwoord: 1914"},{"question":"A cikin wanne nau'in ra'ayi za ku rarraba tweet mai zuwa? Mai kyau, Marar kyau, ko tsaka tsaki?wannan ba har zuciyar sa ba siyasa ce kawai a hakan ma","answer":"Zan rarraba tweet ɗin da aka bayar a matsayin: Marar kyau"},{"question":"أجب عن السؤال التالي: \\"كم عظمة توجد في جسم الإنسان  ؟\\"","answer":"حسنا إجابة السؤال هي: \\"206 عظمة\\"."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _ :\\" Ny tsiny izany dia fanamelohana ataon’ny mpiara-belona amin’ny olona iray noho ny fahadisoana nataony na tandrina na tsy tandrina izany. Mety tsy fahafaham-po na tsy fahafenoana na kilema ihany koa ny tsiny, araka ny fitenenana hoe: “Indrokelin’ny mpandrafitra” sy ny hoe “tovovavy tsara tarehy _ ka voatandro iray no tsininy.”\\"","answer":" Ny tsiny izany dia fanamelohana ataon’ny mpiara-belona amin’ny olona iray noho ny fahadisoana nataony na tandrina na tsy tandrina izany. Mety tsy fahafaham-po na tsy fahafenoana na kilema ihany koa ny tsiny, araka ny fitenenana hoe: “Indrokelin’ny mpandrafitra” sy ny hoe “tovovavy tsara tarehy petak’orona ka voatandro iray no tsininy.”"},{"question":"What does FAS, MTO and ATO stand for? Final Assembly Schedule, often abbreviated as FAS and sometimes referred to as finishing schedule, is a schedule of end items to finish the product for specific customer orders in a make to order (MTO) or assemble-to-order (ATO) environment.","answer":"\\"FAS = Final Assembly ScheduleMTO = make to orderATO = assemble-to-order\\""},{"question":"प्रश्न :  भूत कालका अभ्यस्त पक्षका क्रियापदको प्रयोग गरी आफ्नो बाल्यकालका बारेमा वर्णन गर्नुहोस्‌ ।","answer":"उत्तर :  म बाल्यकालमा साथीहरूसँग खुब खेल्थेँ । म प्रायः घुम्न जान्थेँ । म जङ्गलमा कटुस टिप्थँ, दमौरा टिप्यै, लिची टिप्थँ। आँप टिप्यँ, काफल टिप्थँ, तिजु टिप्थेँ अनि साथीहरूसँगै रमाउँदै खान्थेँ । मलाई पौडी खेल्न असाध्यै मन पर्थ्यो । म हर्पन खोलामा खुब पौडी खेल्थेँ । मलाई पुलबाट तल खोलामा हाम फाल्न खुब मज्जा आउँथ्यो । कोही साथीहरू डुबेको खण्डमा मैले नै निकाल्थेँ । म कालिका मा. वि. मा पढ्थेँ । म कहिलेकाहीँ कश्यप तालमा पनि पौडी खेल्न जान्थेँ । म कश्यप ताल पूरै एक फन्का हान्थेँ । म तिब्र गतिमा पौडी खेल्न सक्थेँ । मलाई पौडी खेलमा कसैले जित्न सक्दैनथ्यो । म अनुशासित, मिहिनेती विद्यार्थी भनेर चिनिन्थेँ । म परीक्षामा प्रायः प्रथम नै हुन्थेँ ।"},{"question":"Kí ni ẹṣin ọ̀rọ̀?","answer":"Òwe ni."},{"question":"Kaynakçı Sertifikası kaç TL?","answer":"Aday, sınavdan önce T.C. kimlik numarası bulunan kimlik belgesini ibraz etmeli ve sınav başvuru formunu doldurmalıdır. Sınavı takiben ilgili standarda göre yapılan değerlendirme sonucunda başarılı bulunan adaylar sertifika almaya hak kazanırlar. (Kaynakçı Sertifikası ücreti, her bir sertifika için 500TL+KDV(%20)'dir)."},{"question":"Réwum Soudan mu ngi nékk ci kembaar bi ñuy wakh Afrique","answer":"Ci ban kembaar la réwum Soudan du Sud nékk"},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny HJRA?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny HJRA dia: Hopitaly Joseph Ravoahangy Andrianavalona"},{"question":"Baboy sa lasang, ang tunok puro lansang.","answer":"nangka"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga:\\"\\tAza dia atao fatra-pandefitra toy ny mpivaro-tantely :_\\"","answer":"\\" ny tompony indray no milela-tanana.\\""},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Andriy Yarmolenko. ","answer":"Is imreoir sacair Rúiseach é Andriy Yarmolenko a rugadh ar an 23 Deireadh Fómhair 1989 i Saint Petersburg. Imríonn sé faoi láthair le West Ham."},{"question":"Amelia Earhart කවුද, සහ ඇයගේ කැපී පෙනෙන ගුවන් ජයග්‍රහණ මොනවාද?","answer":"Amelia Earhart යනු පුරෝගාමී කාන්තා ගුවන් නියමුවරියක් වන අතර ගුවන් ඉතිහාසයේ වඩාත් ප්‍රසිද්ධ චරිතයක් විය. ඇය අත්ලාන්තික් සාගරය හරහා තනිව පියාසර කළ පළමු කාන්තාව බවට පත් වූ අතර, ඇය එක්සත් ජනපදය හරහා පළමු ඒකල, නොනවතින ගුවන් ගමන ද සම්පූර්ණ කළාය. "},{"question":"Өрүкзарга кетели - обондуу ырынын сөзү кайсы?","answer":"ӨРҮКЗАРГА КЕТЕЛИСөзү М.Тураеваныкы,обону А.ЖайнаковдукуЖүр ээрчишип кетели өрүкзарга,Сунушумду суранам четке какпа.Сүйүүбүзгө жолугуп айлуу түндө,Сыйыналы бир келген бактыбызга.Мөл булакка барабыз Ай тосконуАт жалында шамалдай ойношкону.Кечикпейли бир келген бактыбыздан,Өрүкзарга кетели макул болчу.Каректерге жашырып сүйүүбүздү,Мөл булакка сүртөлү жүзүбүздү.Жылдыздарды чакырып койнубузгаӨткөрөлү экөөлөп түнүбүздү.Айлуу түндө жетелеп сүйүүбүздү,Өрүкзарга чачалы күлкүбүздү.Жылдыздардын терели чачыласын,Булактарга сүйдүрүп жүзүбүздү."},{"question":"Apakah tsunami?","answer":"Tsunami merupakan satu siri ombak yang berlaku selepas gempa bumi , tanah runtuh(di dasar laut), aktiviti gunung berapi, letupan, atau hentaman meteor yang berlaku di dalam atau berhampiran laut."},{"question":"බ්‍රේකින් බෑඩ් කතා මාලාවේ ප්‍රධාන අධ්‍යක්ෂකවරයා කවුද?","answer":"බ්‍රේකින් බෑඩ් කතා මාලාවේ ප්‍රධාන අධ්‍යක්ෂකවරයා, වින්ස් ගිලිගන් මහතා විය."},{"question":"Desmond Elliot","answer":"Desmond Elliot ni wọ́n bí ní ọjọ́ Kẹrin oṣù Kejì ọdún 1974. Jẹ́ òṣèré orí-ìtàgé, adarí eré àti olóṣèlú ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà. Ó ti kópa nínú eré àti àwọn eré àtìgbà-dégbà onípele orí ẹ̀tọ amóhùn-máwòrán tí ó ti jú igba lọ ní orílẹ̀-èdè baba rẹ̀ ati ní òkè òkun. Ó ti gba amì-ẹ̀yẹ fún amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ ẹ̀dá ìtàn tí ó peregedé jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ ti Africa Magic Viewers Choice Awards ẹlẹ́kejì irú rẹ̀, ó sì tún ti gba amì-ẹ̀yẹ fún amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ ẹ̀dá ìtàn tí ó peregedé jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ ti Africa Movie Academy Awards ẹlẹ́kẹwàá irú rẹ̀. Wọ́n tún yàn án kí ó lọ ṣojú àwọn ènìyàn agbègbè ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Súrùlérè ní Ilé ìgbìmọ̀ Aṣòfin ti Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó nínú ìdìbò tí ó wáyé ní ọjọ́ kọkànlá oṣù Kẹrin ọdún 2015.Wọ́n bí Desmond ní agbègbè Olówógbowó ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó, bàbá rẹ̀ jẹ́ ọmọ Yorùbá tí wọ́n bí ní agbègbè Lagos Island, ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó tí ìyá rẹ̀ jẹ́ ọmọ ìlú Illah ní ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Oshimili North, ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Delta; Ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ jáde ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ alákọ̀ọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ ológun ojú òfurufú tí ó sì pada lọ sí ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ St John's College, ní ìlú Jos. Ó kẹ́kọ̀ó gboyè nínú ìmọ̀ okòwò ní iléẹ̀kọ́ gíga ti Yunifásitì Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó tí ó sì jáde ní ọdún 2003.Kíkópa nínú eré oníṣẹ́ orí-ìtàgé Demond ni ó jẹ́ wípé ọ̀rẹ́ rẹ̀.kan ni ó ṣokùnfà rẹ̀. Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ń kópa nínú awọn eré onípele àtìgbà-dégbà ti Everyday People, One Too Much ati Saints and Sinners. Ó jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára awọn lààmì-laaka òṣèré ní ilé-iṣẹ́ Nollywood, nígbà tí ó ti kópa nínú awọn eré tí ó ti tó ọgọ́rùn ún tí a ti rí Men Who Cheat, Yahoo Millionaire àti Atlanta. Ní ọdún 2006, wọ́n yàn án fún Òṣèrékùnrin amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ tó peregedé jùlọ nínú amì-ẹ̀yẹ African Movie Academy Award nínú eré \\"Behind closed doors\\". Ní ọdún 2018, Desmond pawọ́pọ̀ gbé eré tí akọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Reloaded. Eré tí wọ́n yàn fún amì-ẹ̀yẹ mẹ́ta ọ̀tọ̀tọ̀ bíi: African Movie Academy Awards ní ọdún 2009. Wọ́n yàn án fún amì-ẹ̀yẹ Òṣèrékùnrin tí ó peregedé jùlọ ní ọdún 2009 àti ọdún 2010. Ní ọdún 2014, wọ́n yan Elliot fún àmì-ẹ̀yẹ \\"African Movie Academy Award\\" fún amì-ẹ̀yẹ Òṣèrékùnrin amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ tó peregedé jùlọ nínú eré \\"Finding Mercy\\"Elliot kéde ìfẹ́ rẹ̀ láti gbégbá ìbò sí Ilé ìgbìmọ̀ aṣòfin Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó ní àsìkò ọdún 2014 lábẹ́ ẹgbẹ́ òṣèlú All Progressives Congress. Ó díje sí ipò yí, ó sì wọlé láti ṣojú agbègbè ìjọba ìbílẹ̀ Sùúrùlérè nínú ìdìbò tí ó wáyé ní ọjọ́ kọkanlá oṣù Kerin ọdún 2015. Ní inú oṣù Kẹwàá ọdún 2020 lásìkò rògbòdìyàn End SARS, Wọ́n sọ̀rọ̀ sí Demond látàrí wípé ó fọwọ́ sí kí wọ́n fagi lé àwọn ìròyìn orí ìkanì ìbánidọ́rẹ̀ẹ́ gbogbo tabí kí wọ́na ṣe àgbéyẹ̀wọ̀ gbogbo ìròyìn tí yóò gba ibẹ̀ kọjá. Nínú àwọn fọ́nrán fídíò tí ó ń kọjá nígboro lórí ìkanì ayélujára, wọ́n rí Desmond nínú fọ́rán yí wípé ó ń sọrọ̀ kíkan kíkan tako ìròyìn orí ìkanì ayélujára gbogbo. Bí kò bá rí bẹ́ẹ̀, orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà yóò bàjẹ́.Desmond Elliot àti ìyàwó rẹ̀ ti bímọ mẹ́rin. si tun je agbẹnu sọ fún ilé-iṣẹ́ ì̀bánisọ̀rọ̀ Globacom. Desmond àti ìyawó rẹ̀ ṣe ayẹyẹ ọdún kẹẹ̀dógún lórí ìgbéyàwó wọn ní ọjọ́ Kẹrìndínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2018.Falling (2015)Black Val (2015)The Department (2015)[25]When Love Happens (2014)30 Days in Atlanta (2014)Okon Goes to SchoolKamara's Tree (2013)Kiss and Tell (2011)I'll Take My Chances (2011)Bursting Out (2010)Holding Hope (2010)Nollywood Hustlers (2010)Before the Light (2009)EdikanUyai (2008)Final Tussle (2008) (V)Guilty Pleasures (2008)Black Night in South America (2007)A Better Place (2007)Caught-Up (2007)Double Game (2007)Fine Things (2007)Ghetto Queen (2007)Secret Pain (2007)Men Who Cheat (2006)A Time to Love (2007) .... HankYahoo Millionaire (2007) .... JerryPut It on Me (2006)Asunder (2006)Behind the Plot (2006)Divided Attention (2006)Efficacy (2006)EkaetteExtreme Measure (2006) ... FestusFinal Point (2006)The Greatest Sacrifice (2006)King of the Town (2006)Love Wins (2006) .... AustinMarried to the Enemy (2006)My Little Secret (2006)My Sister My Love (2006) .... JarNaked Sin (2006)Romeo (2006)Strange Love (2006)Supremacy (2006)Too Late to Claim (2006)Traumatised (2006)Unbreakable Affair (2006)Up to Me (2006)Without Apology (2006)The Wolves (2006)Zoza (2006)A Night in the Philippines (2005)2 Face (2005)Behind Closed Doors (2005)The Bet (2005)Broadway (2005)Destiny's Challenge (2005)Flying Without Wings (2005)Fools in Love (2005)Games Women Play (2005)Girls in the Hood (2005)Hold Me Down (2005)It's Juliet or No One (2005)Just Me (2005)The King's Son (2005)Knowing You (2005)Men Do Cry (2005)My Precious Son (2005)My Sister My Child (2005)My Sister's Act (2005)Now & Forever (2005)Orange Groove (2005)The Price of Love: Life Is Beautiful (2005)Shackles of Death (2005)Wedding Gift (2005)Wheel of Change (2005)Images in the Mirror (2004) .... DejiAbove Love (2004)Atlanta (2004)Big Pretenders (2004)Cinderella (2004)Danger Signal (2004)Deep Loss (2004)Died to Save (2004)Discord (2004)For Real (2004)A Kiss from Rose (2004)Lake of Fire (2004) .... Brother EmmanuelLife in New York (2004)Magic Moment (2004)Melody of Life (2004)Missing Angel(2004)Passion of Mind (2004)Power of Trust (2004)Promise & Fail (2004)True Romance (2004)Great Change (2003)Magic Love (2003)My Faithful Friend (2003)Passion & Pain (2003)Tunnel of Love (2003)Fire Love (2002)Jesu Mushin (2002)FISHERS OF MEN"},{"question":"Trình bày thế mạnh về tự nhiên và hiện trạng phát triển thuỷ điện của vùng Trung du và miền núi Bắc Bộ.","answer":"Vùng Trung du và miền núi Bắc Bộ có nhiều tiềm năng phát triển thuỷ điện do có địa hình đồi núi phong phú và hệ thống sông ngòi dồi dào. Các thế mạnh của vùng này bao gồm:Địa hình đồi núi: Vùng Trung du và miền núi Bắc Bộ có địa hình đồi núi cao, đồi núi trung bình và đồi núi thấp, tạo điều kiện thuận lợi cho việc xây dựng các công trình thuỷ điện.Hệ thống sông ngòi phong phú: Vùng này có nhiều con sông lớn như Sông Hồng, Sông Đà, Sông Lô, Sông Thương, Sông Lục Nam, tạo điều kiện thuận lợi cho việc khai thác năng lượng thuỷ điện.Tiềm năng phát triển lớn: Với hệ thống sông ngòi dồi dào, vùng Trung du và miền núi Bắc Bộ có tiềm năng phát triển thuỷ điện lớn, đáp ứng nhu cầu năng lượng của khu vực và cả nước.Tuy nhiên, hiện trạng phát triển thuỷ điện ở vùng này còn hạn chế do một số nguyên nhân:Chưa khai thác hết tiềm năng: Mặc dù có nhiều tiềm năng, nhưng hiện tại vẫn chưa khai thác hết được tài nguyên năng lượng thuỷ điện của vùng Trung du và miền núi Bắc Bộ.Các công trình thuỷ điện cũ: Một số công trình thuỷ điện đã được xây dựng từ lâu và đã qua thời kỳ khai thác hiệu quả, cần đầu tư để nâng cấp và cải thiện hiệu suất.Tác động môi trường: Xây dựng các công trình thuỷ điện có thể gây tác động tiêu cực đến môi trường, như thay đổi dòng chảy sông, ảnh hưởng đến sinh thái và đời sống của người dân địa phương.Tổng quan, vùng Trung du và miền núi Bắc Bộ có tiềm năng phát triển thuỷ điện lớn nhưng cần đầu tư và quản lý hợp lý để khai thác hiệu quả và bảo vệ môi trường."},{"question":"Inona avy no teny nahazoana ny hoe fari-bolana?","answer":"ny teny nahazoana ny teny hoe fari-bolana dia faritra sy volana"},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para este parágrafo - Em 2016, após a demissão de Rafa Benítez, o Real Madrid anunciou Zidane como novo treinador. Assim começaria uma das eras mais vitoriosas do Real Madrid, com grandes títulos sendo conquistados. Com um belo trabalho dentro de campo, conseguiu conduzir a equipe até a final da Liga dos Campeões de 2015-16 onde enfrentou o arquirrival Atlético de Madrid, na qual o Real Madrid empatou no tempo regulamentar e venceu nos pênaltis, assim conquistando a Undécima no San Siro em Milão na Itália. Logo após conquistou a","answer":"Supercopa da Uefa de 2016, na qual derrotou o Sevilla e se sagrou campeão. Conquistou a Copa do Mundo de Clubes da FIFA de 2016 no qual enfrentou o Kashima Anlters na final e sagrou-se campeão ao vencer por 4x2. Com a gloriosa campanha na La Liga de 2016-17 foi campeão e conquistou assim o 33° título do Campeonato Espanhol. Também na mesma temporada , conquistou a Liga dos Campeões de 2016-17 com uma bela campanha eliminando Bayern Munchen e Atlético de Madrid nas fases eliminatórias e derrotando a Juventus na final por 4x1 e assim conquistando a Duodécima no Millenium Stadium em Cardiff no País de Gales. Iniciando a temporada de 2017/18, conquistou a Supercopa da UEFA de 2017 derrotando o Manchester United por 2x1 e logo em seguida conquistou a Supercopa da Espanha de 2017 , derrotando o rival Barcelona por 5x1 na soma do placar agregado. Sagrou-se campeão da Copa do Mundo de Clubes da FIFA de 2017 após derrotar o Grêmio por 1x0. Conquistou também a Liga dos Campeões de 2017-18, chegando assim ao seu décimo terceiro título, após bater o Liverpool por 3x1 no estádio Olímpico em Kiev na Ucrânia. Após a conquista, Zidane encerra seu ciclo como treinador do Real com uma passagem bastante vitoriosa, ganhando 11 títulos como treinador da equipe."},{"question":"දසය යන්නෙන් කුමන ඉලක්කමක් හැදින්වේද?","answer":" දසය යන්නෙන්  10 ඉලක්කම හැදින්වේ"},{"question":"Completa la seguente frase:\\"Il Commonwealth delle nazioni o Commonwealth (acronimo CN) è ...\\"","answer":"\\"... un'organizzazione intergovernativa di 56 Stati indipendenti, quasi tutti (eccetto Mozambico, Ruanda, Gabon e Togo) accomunati dalla passata appartenenza all'Impero britannico, del quale esso rappresenta una sorta di sviluppo su base volontaria. La popolazione complessiva degli Stati che vi aderiscono è di oltre due miliardi di persone. La parola Commonwealth deriva dall'unione di common (comune) e wealth (benessere), cioè benessere comune.\\""},{"question":"THUNDERSTORMChapter 1","answer":"THUNDERSTORMChapter 1My back aches. I don't know what's wrong with me, auntie. Chika complained to her madam.Since when did it start? When did you start feeling it? Mrs. Ikemike askedSince yesterday, Auntie, it really hurts. She cried.Chika,your nose is getting bigger, and you're gaining weight recently despite all the stress you go through. Are you pregnant? She asked again, dropping the booklet on the table.Errrm, no, ma, I'm not pregnant; the pain has ceased, auntie; I'll be fine. Chika replied, turning to leave.Chika!!! You're pregnant, Chika... Mrs. Ikemike shouted, dragging her closer.No, auntie, I'm not pregnant. It's just a backache, she said, trying to free herself.Mrs. Ikemike stared into her eyes, smiled to herself, released her from the grip, and sat on the bed.Can you tell me who's responsible for this pregnancy? The symptoms are all over you, Chika. Can't you see your breasts? Now tell me who the hell is responsible... Mrs. Ikemike asked calmly.Auntie, nobody is responsible. I'm not pregnant; I'm still a virgin auntie. You can check if you want to. Chika defendedYou're just confused. Now take this money,rush to the chemist across the road, and get me a test strip immediately. Said Mrs. Ikemike, throwing money at her.Chika zoomed off. She cried her eyes out and regretted telling her madam about her backache.Hello dear.. Mr. Ikemike said as he picked up his wife's call.Chika, Diamond, is expecting a child. Mrs. Ikemike shouted from the phone.Babe, calm down. I'll call you later. Mr. Ikemike replied and dropped the call.Chika came back, and her madam ran a test for her, and the result came out positive.For the last time, who's responsible? How come, Chika? Start talking right now. She shouted, hitting her hard on the face.Auntie, please, I'll talk. Chika replied, crying.Who's responsible? She questioned me again.Your husband, auntie..."},{"question":"Allah Ya ambaci garin Madina da sunanta na farko kafin a canza ta koma Madina, Yaya sunan nata na farkon","answer":"(a) Magriba (b) Da'ifa (c) Yasriba"},{"question":"ෆ්ලෝරන්ස් නයිටිංගේල් කවුද?","answer":"ෆ්ලොරන්ස් නයිටිංගේල් ඉංග්‍රීසි සමාජ ප්‍රතිසංස්කරණවාදියෙක් සහ සංඛ්‍යාලේඛනඥයෙක් වූ අතර නූතන හෙද සේවයේ නිර්මාතෘවරයා ද විය. ඇය ප්‍රසිද්ධියට පත් වූයේ ක්‍රිමියානු යුද්ධයේදී ඇය තුවාල ලැබූ සොල්දාදුවන් සඳහා සත්කාර සංවිධානය කළ හෙදියන්ගේ කළමනාකරුවෙකු සහ පුහුණුකරුවෙකු ලෙස සේවය කරමින් සිටියදීය."},{"question":"Ndoa ni nini?","answer":"Ndoa ni muunganiko wa watu wawili wenye jinsia mbili tofauti, yaani mwanamke na mwanamme waliopendana na kukubali kwa hiari yao kuishi pamoja kama mke na mume. Ndoa hufungwa kanisani na msikitini kama watu ni wa dini au mahakamani kama watu hao hawana dini. Ndoa pia japo ilianzishwa na Mungu, inalindwa na kanuni za kidini na sheria za nchi."},{"question":"Napoléon est-il en adéquation avec la liberté individuelle ?","answer":"Non, Napoléon s'appuie sur une police toute-puissante qui procède à des arrestations arbitraires et ne respecte pas la liberté individuelle."},{"question":"句子1: 在Werderaner Wachtelberg有一个大陆气候, 从北方和西部受到大西洋气候的影响, 东方气候温和. 句子2: 韦德拉纳瓦赫特尔伯格的气候温和, 气候以大西洋气候为特征, 从北部和西部, 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"Aşağıdaki ifadeyi tamamlayın: Timur,","answer":"1402 Ankara Muharebesi'nden dönerken bu bölgeye de uğramış. Timur'un askerlerinin buraları da talan ettikleri, askerlerin baskılarından kaçanların \\"Gümüş oluk\\" mevkine saklandıkları ve ilk defa burada yerleştikleri rivayet edilmektedir. Çevre köylerin or­tasında merkezi bir yerde yolların birleştiği toplanma yeri olarak kuytu yer anlamında \\"Peyke\\" adını vermişler. Bu isim zamanla \\"Peyik\\" olarak söylene gelmiş."},{"question":"Inona no voalohan-karena amin'ny Malagasy ?","answer":"Amin'ny Malagasy dia ny zanaka no voalohan-karena. "},{"question":"வினா: கீழ்கண்ட நாடுகளில் சந்தை பொருளாதாரம் நடை பெறும் நாடு எது? \\t1. சீனா2. சிங்கப்பூர்3. சுவீடன்4. பிரான்ஸ்","answer":"விடை: 2. சிங்கப்பூர்.விளக்கம் : சந்தைப் பொருளாதாரம் அல்லது கட்டற்ற சந்தைப் பொருளாதாரம் என்பது ஒரு பொருளியல் முறை ஆகும். இதில் பொருட்களினதும், சேவைகளினதும் உற்பத்தியும், விநியோகமும் கட்டற்ற விலை முறைமையினால் நெறிப்படுத்தப்படும் கட்டற்ற சந்தைப் பொறிமுறையினால் நடைபெறுகின்றது. ஒரு சந்தைப் பொருளாதார அமைப்பில் வணிகத்துறையும், நுகர்வோரும் எதை வாங்குவது எதை உற்பத்திசெய்வது போன்ற முடிவுகளைத் தாங்களாகவே எடுக்கின்றனர். இம்முறையில் வளங்களின் ஒதுக்கம் அரசின் தலையீடுகள் இன்றி நடைபெறும். கோட்பாட்டு அடிப்படையில் இம் முறையின் கீழ், எதனை உற்பத்தி செய்வது, எவ்வளவு உற்பத்தி செய்வது, என்ன விலை விற்பது, தொளிலாளருக்கு எவ்வளவு ஊதியம் வழங்குவது போன்ற முடிவுகளை உற்பத்தியாளரே எடுப்பார், அரசு அல்ல. சந்தைப் பொருளாதாரத்தில் இம் முடிவுகள், போட்டி, தேவையும் வழங்கலும், போன்றவற்றால் உண்டாகும் அழுத்தங்களின் செல்வாக்கிற்கு உட்படுகின்றன. இது என்ன பொருளை எவ்வளவு உற்பத்தி செய்வது போன்றவற்றை அரசே தீர்மானிக்கும் திட்டமிட்ட பொருளாதார முறைக்குப் புறம்பானது. திட்டமிட்ட பொருளாதாரம்போல் விரிவாக இல்லாவிட்டாலும், முற்றிலும் கட்டற்ற முறையில் இல்லாமல் ஓரளவு அரசின் கட்டுப்பாடுகளைக் கொண்டுள்ளதால் கலப்புப் பொருளாதார முறையும், சந்தைப் பொருளாதாரத்தில் இருந்து வேறுபடுகின்றது. நடைமுறையில் எந்த நாட்டிலும் உண்மையான சந்தைப் பொருளாதாரம் இருப்பதாகக் கூறமுடியாது."},{"question":"అమీబా సంకోచ రిక్తికల ద్వారా ద్రవాభిసరణ క్రమతను చూపుతాయి. మరో ఉదాహరణ ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"పారామీషియం"},{"question":"வினா:தண்ணீர் எவ்வாறு உருவாகிறது?","answer":"விடை :தண்ணீர் ஹைட்ரஜன் மற்றும் ஆக்சிஜன் என்ற இரண்டு அடிப்படை மூலக்கூறுகளால் உருவாகிறது. தண்ணீர் இயற்கையில் பல்வேறு வடிவங்களில் காணப்படுகிறது. கடல், ஆறுகள், ஏரிகள், பனிக்கட்டிகள் போன்றவை தண்ணீரின் பல்வேறு வடிவங்கள்."},{"question":"சு. தியோடர் பாஸ்கரன் அவர்களின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றினை தரவும்.","answer":"தேவைக்கு இயற்கையைப் பயன்படுத்தாமல் பேராசைக்கு இயற்கையைச் சுரண்ட ஆரம்பித்த பிறகுதான், மனிதன் உணவைக் கொஞ்சமாகவும், மாத்திரைகளை அதிகமாகவும் எடுத்துக்கொள்ள வேண்டியதாகிவிட்டது."},{"question":"کوردەکان لە جەژنی نەورۆزدا چی دەکەن لە چیاکان؟ ","answer":"لە سەر چیاکاندا ئاگار دەکەنەوە "},{"question":"本の最初に書く文章を序文というのに対し、最後に書く文章を何文というでしょう？","answer":"跋文（ばつぶん） ※跋（ばつ）のみでＯＫです。"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Nhan sắc Hoa hậu Hoàn vũ Thái Lan 2022","answer":"Anna Sueangam-iam vượt 29 thí sinh đăng quang trong chung kết tại True Icon Hall ở Bangkok tối 30/7. Cô nhận vương miện được thiết kế theo chủ đề \\"Sức mạnh phục hồi\\" của thương hiệu trang sức Mouawad, một triệu baht (642 triệu đồng), căn hộ và xe hơi. Á hậu 1 thuộc về Nicolene Limsnukan, á hậu 2 là Kanyalak Nookaew. Anna Sueangam-iam vượt 29 thí sinh đăng quang trong chung kết tại True Icon Hall ở Bangkok tối 30/7. Cô nhận vương miện được thiết kế theo chủ đề \\"Sức mạnh phục hồi\\" của thương hiệu trang sức Mouawad, một triệu baht (642 triệu đồng), căn hộ và xe hơi. Á hậu 1 thuộc về Nicolene Limsnukan, á hậu 2 là Kanyalak Nookaew. Tân hoa hậu sinh năm 1998 ở Bangkok, tốt nghiệp ngành Nghệ thuật và Khoa học, Đại học Kasetsart. Trong khuôn khổ cuộc thi, cô cho biết trải qua cuộc sống khó khăn, tuổi thơ gắn liền bãi rác vì cả bố và mẹ đều làm công việc thu gom rác thải ở Bangkok. Đồ chơi của cô đều được bố mẹ nhặt về và sửa lại. \\"Tôi không thể thay đổi số phận khi sinh ra nhưng tôi nỗ lực để thay đổi cuộc đời mình sau này\\", cô nói. Tân hoa hậu sinh năm 1998 ở Bangkok, tốt nghiệp ngành Nghệ thuật và Khoa học, Đại học Kasetsart. Trong khuôn khổ cuộc thi, cô cho biết trải qua cuộc sống khó khăn, tuổi thơ gắn liền bãi rác vì cả bố và mẹ đều làm công việc thu gom rác thải ở Bangkok. Đồ chơi của cô đều được bố mẹ nhặt về và sửa lại. \\"Tôi không thể thay đổi số phận khi sinh ra nhưng tôi nỗ lực để thay đổi cuộc đời mình sau này\\", cô nói. Người đẹp được đánh giá cao ở khả năng hùng biện, thuyết trình. Trong phần thi ứng xử, khi được hỏi: \\"Trước tình hình thế giới hiện nay bị tác động bởi chiến tranh, dịch bệnh, suy thoái kinh tế toàn cầu, nhiều người đang rơi vào trạng thái tuyệt vọng. Nếu được trao danh hiệu hoa hậu, bạn sẽ gửi thông điệp gì đến mọi người?\\", cô trả lời: \\"Tôi muốn nói rằng bạn không phải người duy nhất từng tuyệt vọng. Tôi cũng là một trong số đó. Nhưng chúng ta phải học cách thích nghi, có thể vấp ngã nhưng rồi sẽ đứng dậy. Bất kể trong tình huống nào, hãy tin vào bản thân. Tôi đã làm được và các bạn cũng vậy\\". Người đẹp được đánh giá cao ở khả năng hùng biện, thuyết trình. Trong phần thi ứng xử, khi được hỏi: \\"Trước tình hình thế giới hiện nay bị tác động bởi chiến tranh, dịch bệnh, suy thoái kinh tế toàn cầu, nhiều người đang rơi vào trạng thái tuyệt vọng. Nếu được trao danh hiệu hoa hậu, bạn sẽ gửi thông điệp gì đến mọi người?\\", cô trả lời: \\"Tôi muốn nói rằng bạn không phải người duy nhất từng tuyệt vọng. Tôi cũng là một trong số đó. Nhưng chúng ta phải học cách thích nghi, có thể vấp ngã nhưng rồi sẽ đứng dậy. Bất kể trong tình huống nào, hãy tin vào bản thân. Tôi đã làm được và các bạn cũng vậy\\". Cô cao 1,75 m, có nhiều năm hoạt động trong lĩnh vực người mẫu. Ngoài ra, cô là diễn viên của kênh Channel 8. Cô cao 1,75 m, có nhiều năm hoạt động trong lĩnh vực người mẫu. Ngoài ra, cô là diễn viên của kênh Channel 8. Anna Sueangam-iam có nhiều kinh nghiệm thi sắc đẹp. Cô từng đăng quang Miss Mobile Thailand 2018, Á khôi 2 Miss Thin Thai Ngarm 2020. Người đẹp từng thi Hoa hậu Thái Lan 2020 nhưng không đoạt giải cao. Anna Sueangam-iam có nhiều kinh nghiệm thi sắc đẹp. Cô từng đăng quang Miss Mobile Thailand 2018, Á khôi 2 Miss Thin Thai Ngarm 2020. Người đẹp từng thi Hoa hậu Thái Lan 2020 nhưng không đoạt giải cao."},{"question":"Ìpínlè mélòó ni wọ́n ti ń lo òfin Sharia ní orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà?","answer":"Ìpínlè Méjìlá ni."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:तथापि अवघा दासबोध । दशक फोडून केला विशद ।जे जे दशकींचा अनुवाद । ते ते दशकीं बोलिला ॥ १४॥अर्थ:","answer":"तथापि एवढे म्हणता येईल की, हा ग्रंथ वीस दशकांत विभागला गेला आहे व प्रत्येक दशकात दहा समास आहेत. ज्या दशकात जो विषय सांगितला गेला आहे, त्याचे विवरण त्या त्या दशकात केले आहे. (१४)"},{"question":"¿Cuántos presidentes ha tendio México?","answer":"Alrededor de 60 presidentes ha tenido México."},{"question":"色の三原色は赤・青・黄。では光の三原色は赤・青ともう一つは何？","answer":"緑です。"},{"question":"Waxaad  Sheegtaa kumuu ahaa ninkii uu Rasuulka (NNKH) uu Ku dagay markuu madiina Tagay?","answer":" Wuxu ahaa abuu ayuub Al-Ansaari (RC)"},{"question":"અહીં નરસિંહ મહેતા રચિત કૃતિ એક \\"મોહ્યુંરે લટકે\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"મોહ્યુંરે લટકે, મારૂં મન મોહ્યુંરે લટકે.ગાતર ભગ કીધાં ગિરધારી, જેમરે માર્યાં ઝટકે; મારૂં મન.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"મોહ્યુંરે લટકે, મારૂં મન મોહ્યુંરે લટકે.ગાતર ભગ કીધાં ગિરધારી, જેમરે માર્યાં ઝટકે; મારૂં મન.વેણ વજાડી વહાલે મારે વનમાં, રગતણે કટકે; મારૂં મન.મન મારૂં મોળીડેરે અટક્યું, પેલે પીતાંબર પટકે; મારૂં મન.નરસઈના સ્વામીની સંગે રમતાં, રસ વાધ્યો ચટકે; મારૂં મન."},{"question":"\\" બીરબલની ખીચડી \\" વાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક દિવસ નગરમાં એક યુવાન હઠયોગી આવ્યો.તેનું શરીર ભારે કસાયેલું હતું. તે જાતજાતના શારીરિક કરતબ કરતો હતો. તે પ્રોત્સાહન મેળવવા માટે અકબર બાદશાહના દરબારમાં આવ્યો. તેણે બાદશાહને પોતાની આવડત વિશે જણાવ્યું. ત્યારે એક લુચ્ચા દરબારીએ કહ્યું, \\"એવા શારીરિક દાવપેચ તો કોઈપણ અભ્યાસુ કરી શકે. જો તું કંઈક નવું કરવા માગતો હો તો આ કડકડતી ઠંડીમાં ચોવીસ કલાક નદીમાં છાતી સુધી પાણીમાં ઊભો રહી શકે તો તું સાચો હઠયોગી!\\" તેના જવાબમાં તે યુવાને કહ્યું, \\"જો જહાંપનાહ, મને મંજૂરી આપે તો હું નદીમાં ચોવીસ કલાક ઊભો રહીશ. મને કોઈ તકલીફ નહીં પડે.\\"અકબર બાદશાહે રજા આપી. તે યુવાન એવી કડકડતી ઠંડીના દિવસોમાં, છાતી સુધી પાણીમાં ચોવીસ કલાક ઊભો રહ્યો. લોકોએ તથા બાદશાહે પણ તે જોયું. ચોવીસ કલાક પૂરા થયા એટલે તે યુવાન ઈનામ મળવાની આશાએ ફરીથી દરબારમાં આવ્યો. ત્યારે અકબર બાદશાહે સહજ ભાવે પૂછયું, \\"યુવાન, તેં ખરેખર કમાલ કરી છે. દિવસના તો ઠીક પણ તેં આખી રાત કેવી રીતે પસાર કરી?'\\"\\"અન્નદાતા. રાત્રે હું નદીમાં ઊભો ઊભો આપના મહેલમાં સળગતો દીવો જોતો રહ્યો અને મારી રાત કયારે પસાર થઈ ગઈ તે મને ખબર જ ન પડી!\\" યુવાને આ જવાબ આપ્યો ત્યારે પેલા લુચ્ચા દરબારીએ કહ્યું, \\"લો, જહાંપનાહ, આ યુવાને તો કંઈ કમાલ નથી કરી. એ તો આપના મહેલના દીવામાંથી મળતી ગરમીને કારણે ઠંડીમાં રાત પસાર કરી શક્યો છે. એ તો સાવ સામાન્ય વાત છે.\\" અકબર બાદશાહ પણ લુચ્ચા દરબારીની વાતમાં આવી ગયા એટલે તેમણે યુવાનને કંઈ પણ ઈનામ ન આપ્યું. યુવાન નિરાશ થઈ ચાલ્યો ગયો. આ બધું બન્યું ત્યારે બીરબલે ચૂપચાપ જોયા કર્યું. પરંતુ બીજા દિવસથી બીરબલે દરબારમાં આવવાનું બંધ કર્યું. બે-ત્રણ દિવસ થઈ ગયાં છતાં બીરબલ દરબારમાં ન આવ્યો એટલે અકબર બાદશાહે બીરબલને તેડાવવા માણસ મોકલ્યો. થોડીવાર પછી તે માણસ પાછો આવ્યો અને કહ્યું, \\"જહાંપનાહ, બીરબલે કહ્યું કે હું ખીચડી બનાવું છું. જેવી મારી ખીચડી બની જાય, પછી તરત જ ખીચડી ખાઈને હું દરબારમાં આવીશ.\\"ફરી બે દિવસ થઈ ગયા છતાં બીરબલ દરબારમાં ન આવ્યો, એટલે બાદશાહે નોકરને ફરી બીરબલને બોલાવવા મોકલ્યો. નોકરે પાછા આવી કહ્યું, \\"જહાંપનાહ, બીરબલ કહે છે કે મારી ખીચડી હજી સુધી પાકી નથી. જ્યારે ખીચડી પાકી જશે ત્યારે હું તે ખાઈને દરબારમાં આવીશ.\\"આ જવાબ સાંભળી બાદશાહ વિચારમાં પડી ગયા. થયું કે \\"લાવ હું જ જઈને જોઈ આવું કે બીરબલ કેવી ખીચડી બનાવે છે!\\"અકબર બાદશાહ દરબારીઓને લઈ બીરબલ જ્યાં બેઠો હતો ત્યાં ગયાં. ત્યાં જઈ તેમણે જોયું તો ત્રણ લાંબા વાંસની ઘોડી બનાવી બીરબલે વાંસની ઉપર ખીચડીની હાંડલી લટકાવી હતી અને નીચે જમીન ઉપર આગ સળગાવી હતી. આ જોઈ બાદશાહે કહ્યું, \\"આ શું ખેલ કરી રહ્યો છે! બીરબલ, આગથી આટલી અદ્ધર રાખીને ખીચડી કોઈ દિવસ પાકતી હશે?'\\"'\\"હજૂર, જરૂર પાકી જશે.\\" બીરબલે કહ્યું.\\"કેવી રીતે?\\" બાદશાહે કહ્યું.\\"જહાંપનાહ, જેમ તમારા મહેલમાં સળગતા દીવાની ગરમીથી દૂર નદીમાં ઊભેલો પહેલો હઠયોગી ઠંડી ઉડાડી રહ્યો હતો, તેની સરખામણીમાં તો આ ઘણું ઓછું અંતર છે. આગથી આટલી જ અદ્ધર રાખેલી ખીચડી જરૂર પાકી થઈ જશે.\\" બીરબલે મોઢું ગંભીર રાખી જવાબ આપ્યો. અકબર બાદશાહ બીરબલની આ દલીલ સાંભળી ઘણા શરમાયા. બીજે દિવસે તેમણે પેલા હઠયોગીને તેડાવી તેને યોગ્ય ઈનામ આપ્યું."},{"question":"Nitori to n ta ẹran to ti bajẹ fawọn araalu, sifu difensi mu alapata kan ni Kwara","answer":"Ajọ ẹsọ alaabo ṣifu difẹnsi, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, ti mu ẹlẹran maaluu kan, Nawali Bala, niluu Patigi, nijọba ibilẹ Patigi, nipinlẹ Kwara, fẹsun pe o n ta ẹran ti ko daa fun awọn eeyan.Ọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọṣẹ yii, ni Agbẹnusọ ajọ naa ni Kwara, Ọgbẹni Babawale Afolabi, fọrọ naa lede niluu Ilọrin. O ni ni kete ti ọwọ tẹ afurasi ọhun, Bashiru Bala Zuru, to n ta ẹran to ti bajẹ, to si lewu fun alaafia awọn araalu lo jẹwọ pe ọkunrin kan torukọ rẹ n jẹ Dantani Jayewu, to n gbe Okoloke, nipinlẹ Kogi, lo gbe ẹran naa foun ki oun maa ta a. Lẹyin ayẹwo ti wọn ṣe si ẹran naa finnifinni latọwọ ileeṣẹ to n ri si ọrọ ayika nipinlẹ Kwara ni wọn sọ pe o le ṣe akoba fun alaafia araalu.Ọga agba ajọ ọhun, Ọgbẹni Makinde, ti waa sọ pe awọn yoo foju afurasi naa ba ile-ẹjọ lẹyin ẹkunrẹrẹ iwadii."},{"question":"కింద ఇచ్చిన మొదటి పేరా మరియు చివరి పేరా అనుసరించు మధ్య పేరా రాయండి:మొదటి పేరా:నిజాం నియంతృత్వ పాలనకు వ్యతిరేకంగా విముక్తిపోరాటకాలం నాటి పరిస్థితులను కళ్ళకు కట్టినట్లు చూపించిన కథ ఇది. నిజాం పోలీసులకు, రజాకార్లకు వ్యతిరేకంగా ఉద్యమించిన ఒక స్టేట్ కాంగ్రెస్ ‘వాలంటీరును, విప్లవ కారుడిని ఒక సామాన్య వృద్ధురాలు రక్షించిన అపూర్వ ఇతివృత్తం గొల్లరామవ్వకథ. తెలంగాణపోరాట చరిత్రలో ఈ కథ ఒక సృజనాత్మక డాక్యుమెంట్చివరి పేరా:గొల్లరామవ్వ తన గుడిసెలో చీకటిలోనే కూర్చొని ఉంది. ఆమె వడిలో భయం భయంగా పదిహేనేండ్ల బాలిక తలదాచుకుని ఉంది.","answer":"తెలంగాణలో అదో పల్లె. ఆ పల్లెలోకి ఉద్యమకారులు ప్రవేశించి రజాకార్లను, పోలీసులకు, నవాబులకు వ్యతిరేకంగా ప్రజల్ని చైతన్యం చేస్తున్నారని నిజాం ప్రభుత్వవాదన. ఆ రోజు ఇద్దరు పోలీసుల్ని చంపినట్లు సమాచారం. అర్ధరాత్రి ప్రశాంత వాతావరణాన్ని చిన్నాభిన్నం చేస్తూ బాంబులమోత."},{"question":"අභිධර්මයේ එන චිත්තය යනු කුමක්ද ?","answer":"චිත්තය හෙවත් සිත යනු පරමාර්ථ වශයෙන් හා අපරමාර්ථ වශයෙන් ද ඇත්තා වූ අනේක ප්‍ර‍කාරාර්ථයන් පිළිබඳ වූ දැනීම ය, “චේත, මන, විඤ්ඤාණ, හදය, මානස,” යන මේවා ද චිත්තය ම දක්වන පාළි වචනයෝ ය. ඇසය, කනය, නාසයය, දිවය, කයය, හෘදයය යන මේ ස්ථානයන්හි සිත පහළ වේ. එය ක්‍රියාවක් වුවද ව්‍යවහාර පහසුව පිණිස දැනීම කරන කර්තෘ ශක්තිය ඇති ද්‍ර‍ව්‍යයක් සේ ද කරණ ශක්තිය ඇති ද්‍ර‍ව්‍යයක් සේ ද ව්‍යවාහර කරනු ලැබේ. දැකීමය, පෙනීමය, ඇසීමය යනාදි වශයෙන් ඒ ඒ ආකාරයෙන් උපදනා සිත් හැඳින්වීමට පාවිච්චි කරන වචන ව්‍යවහාර භාෂාවේ බොහෝ ගණනකි. ඇසෙහි රූපයක් ගැටුණු කල්හි එය පිළිබඳ දැනුමක් හෙවත් සිතක් පහළ වේ. එය ප්‍ර‍කාශ කිරීමේ දී දැනීමය යන වචනය ව්‍යවහාර නො කොට පෙනීමය දැකීමය යන වචන ව්‍යවහාර කරති. ඇසට හමුවීමෙන් යමක් දත් කල්හි පෙනුණේය කියා හෝ දුටුයේය කියා හෝ කියති. වචනය අනෙකක් වුවද එයින් හඟවන්නේ දැනීම මය, හෙවත් සිත ම ය. කනෙහි ශබ්දයක් ගැටුණු කල්හි, ඒ හඬ දැන ගන්නා සිතක් උපදී. එයට හඬ දැනුම ය යි නො කියා ඇසීමය යි කියනු ලැබේ. ඇසීම යන වචනයෙන් දැක්වෙන්නේ හඬ දන්නා වූ සිතය. නාසයට දුඟඳක් පිවිසි කල්හි සමහර විට ගඳක් දැනේය යි කියති. සමහර විට දැනීමය යන වචනය නො ගෙන ගඳයයි ම කියති. එබඳු අවස්ථාවලදී ගඳය යන වචනයෙන් හඟවන්නේ ද ගඳ දැන ගන්නා සිත ම ය. රසයක් මුඛයට පැමිණි කල්හි ද සමහර විට රසක් දැනේයයි කියති. සමහර විට එසේ නො කියා තිත්තය ඇඹුල්ය යනාදීන් රසයේ නම ම කියති. එබඳු අවස්ථාවල දී රසයේ නමින් පවසන්නේ ද ඒ රසය දන්නා සිත ම ය. ශරීරයෙහි යම් කිසිවක් සැපුණු කල්හි සමහර විට සැපෙන බව දැනේය යි කියති. සමහර විට එසේ නො කියා සැපීමෙන් වන ඵලය හඟවන රිදීමය, ශීතලය, උෂ්ණය යන වචන කියති. එබඳු අවස්ථාවල දී ඒ වචනවලින් කියැවෙන්නේ ද ස්ප්‍ර‍ෂ්ටව්‍යය දන්නා සිතය. පඤ්චප්‍ර‍සාද සම්බන්ධයක් නැතිව සිතක් ඇති වූ කල්හි සමහර විට සිතුණේය යි කියති. සමහර විට දැනුණේය, කල්පනා වුණේය, ඕනෑ වුනේය, වැටහුණේ ය, තේරුණේය, හැඟුණේය යනාදි වචන කියති. ඒ සියල්ලෙන් ම කියැවෙන්නේ සිත ම ය. කරුණු මෙසේ හෙයින් දැකීමය, පෙනීමය, ඇසීමය, ගඳය, සුවඳය, තිත්තය, කසටය, ශීතය, උෂ්ණය, කල්පනාවය, ඕනෑකමය යනාදි වචනවලින් දැක්වෙන්නා වූ අර්ථය චිත්තපරමාර්ථය යි දත යුතුය. මේ වචනයන් අතුරෙන් ඇතැමකින් අධිකාර්ථ ද කියැවේ. නිවැරදිව ම සිතා ගැනීමට අධිකාර්ථ හළ යුතුය.රථයේ ගමන ක්‍රියාව රථයෙන් ම එන වේගයකි. මිනිසකුගේ ගමන ක්‍රියාව ශරීරයෙන් නැඟෙන වේගයකි. අතක එසවීම් ක්‍රියාව අතින් නැගෙන වේගයකි. එමෙන් සිතය යි කියන ආරම්මණ විජානන ක්‍රියාව ආරම්මණ ග්‍ර‍හණ ක්‍රියාව චිත්ත පරම්පරාවේ අගින් නැග එන වේගයකි. පෝර ලැබෙන ලැබෙන සැටියට වැලක අගින් දලු ලියලන්නාක් මෙන් අරමුණු ලැබෙන ලැබෙන සැටියට ඒ ඒ අරමුණු ගැනීම් වශයෙන් චිත්ත පරම්පරාවේ අගින් අළුත් අළුත් සිත් පහළ වේ. සිත් පහළ වනුයේ චක්ෂුරාදි වස්තූන්හි ය. එහෙත් සිත ඒවායින් නැඟ එන්නක් සැටියට නො ගත යුතු ය. සිත චක්‍ෂුරාදි වස්තූන්ගෙන් නැඟ එන්නක් නම් වස්තු කීපයක එකවර රූප ශබ්දාදි අරමුණු ගැටුණු කල්හි ඒ ඒ වස්තුවල එකවර ම ඒ ඒ අරමුණු පිළිබඳ සිත් පහළ විය යුතු ය. එක් සන්තානයක එකවර සිත් දෙකක් පහළ නොවන බැවින් ශරීරයේ කොතැනක සිත පහළ වුව ද පහළ වන සෑම සිතක් ම චිත්ත පරම්පරාවේ අගින්ම පහළ වන බව දත යුතුය. සිත: චිත්ත පරම්පරාවේ අගින්ම නැඟ නැඟ එන වේගයක් සැටියට නො ගෙන ශරීරයෙන් හෙවත් නිඃශ්‍ර‍ය වස්තූන්ගෙන් නැගෙන වේගයක් සැටියට ගතහොත් අරූප භූමියක් ඇති බව ඔප්පු කළ නො හැකි වන්නේ ය. පුනරුත්පත්තියක් ඇති බව ද ඔප්පු කළ හැකි නො වන්නේ ය. සිත: චිත්ත සන්තතියේ අගින් ම නැඟෙන දෙයක් සැටියට දක්නා තැනැත්තා හට පුනරුත්පත්තියක් ඇති බව ද පහසුවෙන් ම පෙනෙන්නේ ය.ඇතැමෙක් සිත් ඇතිවීමේ ප්‍ර‍ධාන හේතුව අරමුණයයි කියති. අරමුණු සෑම තැන ම ඇත. කොතෙක් අරමුණු ඇතත් පැවත එන සිත් පරම්පරාවක් නැති නම් සිතක් නූපදී. ආරම්මණාදි හේතූන්ට සිත ඉපද විය හැකි වන්නේ පැවත එන සිත් පරම්පරාවක් ඇති කල්හි පමණෙකි. එබැවින් සිත් ඇති වීමේ ප්‍ර‍ධාන හේතුව ආරම්මණය නොව පැවත එන සිත් පරම්පරාව බව දත යුතුය. අරමුණක් නැති ව සිතට ඇති විය නොහෙන බැවන් අරමුණ ද සිත් ඇති වීමේ බලවත් හේතුවක් බව කිය යුතුය."},{"question":"வினா:  பெரியாழ்வார் எந்த பாண்டிய மன்னரின் ஆட்சிக் காலத்தில் வாழ்ந்தார்?1. சுந்தரபாண்டியன்2. ஸ்ரீமாற ஸ்ரீவல்லபன்3. விக்ரம பாண்டியன்4. வீர பாண்டியன்","answer":"விடை: 2. ஸ்ரீமாற ஸ்ரீவல்லபன்"},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Dân mạng Trung Quốc phẫn nộ vì một nữ shipper bị khách mạt sát. Nội dung chính của đoạn văn kể về một nữ sinh viên làm công việc giao hàng tại thành phố Uy Hải, Trung Quốc. Trong quá trình giao hàng, cô phải đối mặt với một khách hàng không lịch sự và thô lỗ. Khách hàng này ban đầu yêu cầu cô sử dụng thang máy, sau đó lại thay đổi ý và gây rối. Sau khi cô đã giao hàng, khách hàng này thậm chí ném tô mì xuống sàn, làm nước súp nóng bắn lên người cô. Nữ shipper đã cố gắng giải quyết tình huống nhưng vẫn bị khách hàng coi thường. Cô đã quay video về sự việc này và đăng tải lên mạng xã hội, gây sự phẫn nộ từ cộng đồng mạng. Tuy nhiên, sau đó, cô phải kêu gọi không tấn công khách hàng và nhấn mạnh rằng có nhiều khách hàng có thái độ xấu tính và không tôn trọng tài xế giao hàng. Điều này bật mí về tình trạng bạo hành và thái độ không tôn trọng đối với người giao hàng trong ngành giao đồ ăn trực tuyến ở Trung Quốc.","answer":"Một nữ sinh viên (giấu tên) làm thêm công việc giao hàng tại thành phố Uy Hải, tỉnh Sơn Đông, Trung Quốc. Ngày 24/7, cô giao tô mì thịt bò giá 17 nhân dân tệ (tương đương 2,5 USD) cho một thực khách. Shipper này gọi điện, nhờ khách chỉ dẫn cách sử dụng thang máy của tòa nhà. Đáp trả cô, nữ khách hàng cho biết thang máy không phục vụ tài xế giao hàng. \\"Cô không xứng đáng đi thang máy, leo thang bộ đi!\\", người phụ nữ nói qua điện thoại. Shipper chấp nhận di chuyển bằng cầu thang bộ. Cô đặt phần ăn trước cửa nhà thực khách, sau đó rời đi. Tuy nhiên, ngay sau đó, vị khách hàng gọi điện yêu cầu cô quay trở lại. Người phụ nữ này cho rằng đơn hàng của mình bị lỗi đóng gói, sau đó thẳng tay ném tô mì xuống sàn khiến nước súp nóng bắn lên người nữ shipper. Tài xế giao hàng cố gắng trấn an và giải thích rằng sự cố có thể xuất phát từ nhà hàng. Cô đề nghị tự chi tiền và giao lại cho khách hàng một tô mì khác. Người phụ nữ đáp lại: \\"Tôi cho cô 5 phút để giao lại suất mì mới. Nếu không, tôi sẽ khiếu nại với công ty của cô\\". Đoạn video ghi lại sự việc nêu trên được nữ shipper đăng tải lên mạng xã hội. \\"Khi tôi quay lại với đơn hàng mới trên tay, vị khách đó vẫn rất thô lỗ. Chị ta nói tôi không học hành chăm chỉ, lại còn không làm tốt công việc của mình\\", cô bật khóc trong video. Cộng đồng mạng tỏ ra bức xúc, bất bình trước thái độ coi thường của nữ khách hàng. Họ tìm kiếm người này trên Internet và không ngớt lời chỉ trích. Đến ngày 30/7, nữ shipper này phải kêu gọi cư dân mạng không tìm kiếm hoặc tấn công người phụ nữ. \\"Một số khách hàng rất xấu tính. Họ xúc phạm, thậm chí cản trở công việc của những tài xế giao hàng\\", một người bình luận. Một người khác cho rằng: \\"Người phụ nữ cư xử mà không có chút tôn trọng nào. Chắc chị ta nghĩ mình có quyền xúc phạm người khác\\". Theo SCMP, các nền tảng giao đồ ăn trực tuyến tại Trung Quốc chỉ cung cấp chức năng khiếu nại dành cho khách hàng. Những trường hợp shipper bị bạo hành thường xảy ra, nhưng chưa có chế tài bảo vệ. Tháng 5 vừa qua, khách hàng ở tỉnh Giang Tô yêu cầu shipper mua giúp một thùng bia không có trong đơn đặt hàng ban đầu, sau đó yêu cầu anh leo bộ 6 tầng nhà để giao hàng. Năm ngoái, một khách hàng khác ở miền Nam Trung Quốc đe dọa khiếu nại khi nữ shipper từ chối quan hệ tình dục với anh ta."},{"question":"Amaka Igwe","answer":"Amaka Igwe (tí a bí ní ọjọ́ kejì oṣù Ṣéẹ́rẹ́ ọdún 1963 - ó di olóògbé ní ọjọ́ kejìdínlọ́gbọ̀n oṣù Igbe, ọdún 2014). Amaka Igwe jẹ́ òṣèré ọmọ orílẹ̀èdè Nàìjíríà àti ọ̀gá sọ̀rọ̀sọ̀rọ̀. Òun ni aláṣẹ iléeṣẹ́ rédíò Top 90.8 Èkó àti iléeṣẹ́ Amaka Igwe Studio. Ipa rẹ̀ lásìkò ìgbédìde fíìmù àgbéléwò láyé sinimá ní Nàìjíríà kò ṣé é fọwọ́ rọ́ sẹ́yìn. Èèkàn ní ni agbo òṣèré nígbà ayé rẹ̀ kí ó tó di wí pé àìsàn ikọ́ sémìísémìí mú ẹ̀mí rẹ̀ lọ.Ní ọjọ́ kejì, Oṣù Ṣéẹ́rẹ́ wọ́n dá ṣe ìrántí ọjọ́ọ̀bí rẹ̀, wọ́n sì fi Google Doodle da lọ́la.Uzomaka Audrey \\"Amaka\\" Igwe jẹ́ ọmọ Isaac àti Patience Ene ní ìlú Port-Harcourt. Ipo karùn-ún ni Igwe nínú àwọn ọmọ méje, ó sì jẹ́ ọmọbìnrin kẹrìn nínú obìnrin mẹ́fà. \\"GCO\\" Ọ̀gá Apàṣẹ̀ ni bàbá rẹ̀ máa  ń pè é, tí ìyà rẹ̀ sì ń pè é ni \\"ìjì\\" (storm) torí pé ọwọ́ rẹ̀ kì í dilẹ̀. Ó lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ All Saints àti Iléẹ̀kọ́ Gíga Awkunanaw àwọn obìnrin ní Enugu.Ó ja ẹ̀ṣẹ́, ó gba bọ́ọ̀lù àfọwọ́gbá, òun sì ni olórí ikọ̀ agbábọ́ọ́lù àwọn obìnrin. Nígbà tí ó ń ṣe A-level ní Kọ́lẹ́jì Idia, ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní ṣe àwárí ẹ̀bùn rẹ̀. Ó kọ́ àwọn èèyàn ní ijó Atilogwu,ó sì díjé orílẹ̀èdè. Ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní kọ eré-onítàn àti orin. Ẹ̀kọ́ Ìmọ̀ òfin ló wu Amaka Igwe láti ṣe ṣùgbọ́n àwọn òṣìṣẹ́ Ajọ́ JAMB fún ní *Ìmọ̀ Ẹ̀kọ́ àti Ẹ̀sìn (Theology). Fún ìdí èyí, ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ Ìmọ̀ Ẹ̀kọ́ àti Ẹ̀sìn náà ní Yunifásítì Ifẹ̀ (Yunifásítì Ọbáfẹ́mi Awólọ́wọ̀ báyìí)Láti OAU, Igwe darapọ̀ mọ́ MNET short celluloid film \\"Barbers Wisdom\\" gẹ́gẹ́ bíi olùdarí, ó tẹ̀síwájú láti lọ sí Yunifásítì Ìjọba Àpapọ̀ tí ìlú Ìbàdàn, níbi tí ó ti gba òye EM-EE (MA) nínú Ìmọ̀ Library and Information Sciences. Lásìkò tí ó jẹ́ àgùnbánirọ̀ ó jẹ́ akọ̀wé arìnrìn-àjò fún Scripture Union. Ó sì ṣíṣe gẹ́gẹ́ bíi Aláṣẹ olùdarí ní Iléẹ̀kọ́ Yunifásítì Ìmọ̀ Èrọ Anambra ni Eida Information Systems kí ó tó fi àdàgbà ètò rọ̀ sí agbo àwọn alátinúdáà. Ó fẹ́ ọkọ rẹ̀ Charles Igwe ní Oṣù Igbe ni ọdún 1993, wọ́n sì bí ọmọ mẹ́ta.Aláṣeyorí òǹkọ̀wé, olótùú, olùdarí, oníṣòwò àti olùkọ́ ni Igwe. Aṣáájú Fíìmù àti Dirama ayé òde òní tí Nàìjíríà ni. Ó di gbajúgbajà gẹ́gẹ́ bí òǹkọ̀tàn àti olótùú eré \\"Checkmate\\" àti *Fuji House of Commotion\\". Lára àwọn iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ ni Nollywood ni Rattle snake àti Violated tí ó ya iléeṣẹ́ Amaka Igwe Studio sọ́tọ̀ lásìkò fíìmù àgbéléwò láyé sinimá ní Nàìjíríà. Òun ló dá BOBTV Exp sílẹ̀, Òun sì ni olùdásílẹ̀ àti Aláṣẹ Rédíò TOP 90.9Fam tó wà ní ìgboro Èkó, The quality content production House, Amaka Igwe Studios àti Q Entertainment Networks and ìkànnì DSTV.Àwùjọ kò ní gbàgbé ipa ribiribi tí Igwe kò láti mú ìgbéga bá fíìmù ṣíṣe, bí ó tilẹ̀ jẹ́ pé wọ́n kò ka agbo òṣèré sí pàtàkì nígbà kan, síbẹ̀ Iléeṣẹ́ Amaka Studio gbìyànjú púpọ̀ láti mú ìdàgbàsókè ba, àti àṣeyọrí kí wọ́n sì jẹ́ ìwúrí fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ nínú àwọn òṣèré nílẹ̀ Nàìjíríà, àwọn ọmọ orílẹ̀èdè Nàìjíríà àti àgbáyé lápapọ̀.Ìbẹ̀rù àti ìbọ̀wọ̀ fún Ọlọ́run, àwọn ẹbì rẹ̀, àṣeyege, iṣẹ́ gidi rẹ̀, àti àṣà lákòótán jẹ́ àbùdá pàtàkì Amaka. Ó fẹ́ràn àwọn ẹ̀bí rẹ̀, ó sì pinnu láti má fi wọ́n sílẹ̀ nígbà kankan. Amaka Igwe mú ìdàgbàsókè ba awon èèyàn, àwọn sì ni ẹ̀rí rẹ̀ dòní. Ó sábà máa ń sọ fún àwọn tí ó ń kọ́ níṣẹ́ tààrà pé òun yóò fi ohunkóhun tí òun bá ní ṣe àlékún òun ti o wà lọ́wọ́ tiwọn kí wọ́n lè dára ju òun lọ. Kò hùwà àfèmi-àfèmi, ó sì farajìn fún ìdàgbàsókè àti ìsọlọ́jọ agbo àwọn alátinúdá.Igwe gba àwọn àmì-ẹ̀yẹ nígbà ayé rẹ̀. Ní ọdún 2011, Orílẹ̀èdè Nàìjíríà fi oyè MFR - Ọmọ Ẹgbẹ́ Orílẹ̀èdè Nàìjíríà (Member of the Federal Republic of Nigeria) da lọ́lá fún ìmọrírì akitiyan àti ipa pàtàkì rẹ̀ sí àwùjọ àwọn alátinúdá.Ni ọjọ́ kejì, Oṣù Ṣéẹ́rẹ́, Google fi Google Doddle ṣe àjọyọ ọjọ́ọ̀bí Kẹtàdínlọ́gọ́ta fún-un.Igwe kú ní Enugu ní ọjọ́ kẹtàdínlọ́gbọ̀n, Oṣù Igbe ọdún 2014, ni alẹ́ aago mẹ́jọ àbọ̀. Gbogbo ìgbìyànjú láti dóòlà ẹmí rẹ̀ lọ́wọ́ pípeléke ikọ́-sèmìí-sèmìí tí ó ń bá fínra ló já sí pàbó. Gómìnà Ìpínlẹ̀ Imo nígbà náà Rochas Okorocha lọ sí ètò ìsìnkú rẹ̀, bákan náà ni àwọn èèkàn ní agbo àwọn òṣèré."},{"question":"Эл жомогунан: Хандын Карачач сураган калыңдын табышмактын чечмелениши кандай?","answer":"Аталар, агалар, мен жырткыч айбандарды сураган эмес элем. Кан башыма боштондук берсе экен деп, боштондук сураган элем. Мен айткан калың мал эмес, силер өзүңөр ойлоп көрсөңүздөр, кан экөөбүздүн башыбызга келе турган табышмак. Калың малга он улак берсин дегеним, менин жашым ондо, улактай ойногон кыз кезим, жыйырма түлкү берсин дегеним, киши жыйырмага чыкканда түлкүдөй булактабайбы, отуз карышкыр дегеним, адам отузга чыкканда карышкырдай жүткүнбөйбү. Кырк арстан дегеним, кыркка чыккан адам арстандай күчүнө келбейби, элүү ат берсин дегеним, элүүдө адам ат болбойбу. Алтымыш чидер дегеним, алтымыштагы адамдын бутуна чидер түшүп, өзүнчө басып кете албайт дегеним. Жетимиш аркан берсин дегеним адам жетимишке чыкканда аркандалбайбы. Сексен каны жок жүрөк берсин дегеним, сексенге чыккан адам каны жок жүрөктөй кургабайбы. Муңу жок картаң молдого никемди кыйдырсын дегеним, картаң адамдын ичинен капа- кайгысы жок, бир да адам болбойт. Ошондуктан, менин никемди кыйдыра албай, мага уруксат бербейби,- деп менин канга карата айткан табышмактуу суроом болучу. Ушул олтурган аксакалдар, кан баш болуп, менин суроомду текшерип көргүлөчү, айткан сөзүмдүн катасы болсо кайта алайын. Болбосо, канга тийбеймин! Кан мени албайт деген сөзүм эмеспи. Бул сөзүмдү ойлоп чечип, мени кыйноодон бошотуп, уруксат берүүңүздөрдү сураймын,- деп кыз айткан экен.Ошондо олтурган элдердин ичинен бир аксакал адам:- Балам, кыз Карачач, бактың ачылсын, жолуң болсун,- деп кандан уруксатсыз эле, кызга бата бере кетет.Кан аксакалдын сөзүн кубаттап, отурган бардык эддер чурулдап кошо бата кылат. Кан көпчүлүк элден чыга албай кызга уруксат берүүгө амалсыздан макул болот. Ошол кыз Акыл Карачач деп акылдуулугунан айтылып, эл оозунда сөз болуп калган дейт."},{"question":"السؤال: الاسم الحديث لأرض فان ديم التي أصبحت الآن جزءًا من جزيرة من أراضي أستراليا؟","answer":"الإجابة: تسمانيا"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Gearóid Mac Gearailt. ","answer":"Ba é an Dr. Gearóid Mac Gearailt (Béarla: Garret Fitzgerald; 9 Feabhra 1926 - 19 Bealtaine 2011) an seachtú Taoiseach ar Phoblacht na hÉireann. Bhí sé mar Aire Gnóthaí Eachtracha ó 1973 go 1977, nuair a ceapadh mar cheannaire ar Fhine Gael é. Chaith sé dhá théarma mar Thaoiseach, an chéad cheann idir Iúil 1981 agus Feabhra 1982, agus an dara ceann idir mí na Nollag 1982 agus mí an Mhárta 1987.Ceaptar go forleathan san 1980idí gurbh eisean an ceannaire ab fhearr de chuid Fhine Gael le blianta. Le linn a shaoil mar pholaiteoir bhí an-ghnaoi air - ghlaoigh gach taobh an t-ainm 'Garret' air, mar shampla. Lena nádúr cuideachtúil, an cumas a bhí aige labhairt níos tapúla ná mar a cheap daoine a d'fhéadfaí a dhéanamh agus an dealramh a bhí aige le hollamh dearmadach, ba pholaiteoir feidhmiúil é ó tháinig sé isteach sa saol polaitiúil i lár na 1960í go dtí gur éirigh sé as sa bhliain 1992.Ba mhac le Desmond Mac Gearailt é, a bhí ina Aire Gnóthaí Seachtracha (an seanainm a bhí ar an Roinn Gnóthaí Eachtracha roimh 1972) i rith na 1920idí. Bhí Desmond ar dhuine de bhunaitheoirí Chumann na nGaedhael, páirtí polaitiúil a bunaíodh chun tacaíocht a thabhairt don Chonradh Angla-Éireannach a síníodh i 1921 idir an Bhreatain agus Éire chun Saorstát Éireann a bhunú.Cé gur dhuine sinsearach é a athair ar thaobh an chonartha i ndeighilt pholaitiúil na hÉireann (troideadh Cogadh Cathartha idir lucht an chonartha agus an dream a bhí ina choinne i 1922 agus 1923), choinnigh sé a chuid cairde i measc an dreama a bhí i gcoinne an chonartha, leithéidí Seán Mac an tSaoi, a bhí ina Aire i rialtas Éamoin de Valera. I gcontrárthacht lena athair, ba Phrotastúnach í a mháthair Mabel, a bhí ní ba phoblachtaí ná a athair. Is isteach sa mheascán sin, trasna na deighilte polaitiúla, a rugadh Gearóid."},{"question":"Siapakah Chelsia Ng? ","answer":"Chelsia Ng ialah seorang pelakon dan penyanyi wanita Malaysia yang berasal dari Pulau Pinang."},{"question":"હાઈકુ એટલે શુ ?","answer":"હાઈકુ અથવા સત્તરાક્ષરી એ પાંચ, સાત અને પાંચ અક્ષરોની અનુક્રમે ત્રણ પંક્તિઓનો બનેલો જાપાની કવિતાનો અતિટૂંકો અને અતિ પ્રતિષ્ઠા પામેલો કાવ્યપ્રકાર છે. સત્તર અક્ષરોનો બનેલો આ કાવ્યપ્રકાર કોઈ એક ભાવ, કલ્પન કે સંવેગ જગાડે છે. અંગ્રેજી સાહિત્યમાં પણ આ કાવ્યપ્રકાર ખેડાયો છે. ગુજરાતી અને અન્ય ભારતીય ભાષાઓમાં પણ એના પ્રયોગો થયા છે. ગુજરાતી સાહિત્યમાં હાઈકુ કાવ્યપ્રકારને પ્રતિષ્ઠિત કરવામાં સ્નેહરશ્મિનો મહત્વનો ફાળો છે. સ્નેહરશ્મિનો હાઈકુ સંગ્રહ સોનેરી ચાંદ રૂપેરી સૂરજ ૧૯૬૬માં પ્રગટ થયો હતો."},{"question":"Ολοκλήρωσε την ακόλουθη φράση: O Piquet Jr. συνετρίβη στο 2008 Grand Prix της Σιγκαπούρης","answer":"Αμέσως μετά από μια πρόωρη στάση για τον Φερνάντο Αλόνσο, βγάζοντας το αυτοκίνητο ασφαλείας. Καθώς τα αυτοκίνητα μπροστά από τον Αλόνσο πήγαν για καύσιμα κάτω από το αυτοκίνητο ασφαλείας, προχώρησε στην ομάδα για να πάρει τη νίκη. Ο Πικέ Τζούνιορ απολύθηκε μετά το 2009 στο Grand Prix της Ουγγαρίας."},{"question":"Ki sa fotosentèz ye?","answer":"Gen plizyè milya kreyati ki absòbe oksijèn e ki rejte diyoksid kabòn. Malgre sa, toujou gen oksijèn, e gaz yo rejte a, anpalan de diyoksid kabòn nan, pa janm toufe atmosfè a. Sa k fè sa? N ap jwenn repons lan nan yon pwosesis estrawòdinè ki rele fotosentèz. Grasa pwosesis sa a, plant ki vèt yo pran nan diyoksid kabòn, nan dlo, nan limyè solèy la ak nan bagay ki pèmèt plant yo grandi a e yo pwodui idrat kabòn ak oksijèn. Nou konplete sik la lè nou respire oksijèn nan."},{"question":"Ọwọ ọlọpaa ti tẹ mẹta ninu awọn Fulani to fibọn fọ ẹnu iya oniyaa n’Ijẹbu-Oru","answer":"Kọmandi ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun ti mu mẹta ninu awọn Fulani to kọ lu iya kan, Morounkeji Salami, lopin ọsẹ to kọja yii, ti wọn yinbọn fun un, ti wọn tun ṣa a ladaa kari ara lagbegbe Ijẹbu-Oru, nipinlẹ Ogun.Nigba to n sọ bi ọwọ ṣe ba wọn, Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, ṣalaye f’ALAROYE pe lẹyin tawọn Fulani naa yinbọn mọ iya yii tan ni wọn sa wọgbo lọ, ti wọn si fi awọn maaluu wọn silẹ. O ni nigba ti olobo ta awọn ọlọpaa agbegbe yii lori ikọlu naa, wọn lọ sibẹ, wọn si fara ṣoko sibi kan lati mọ boya awọn Fulani naa yoo tun yọju lati waa ko awọn maaluu wọn nigba ti ilẹ ba rọ.Bẹẹ naa lo si ri, awọn Fulani ọhun pada wa lati ko maaluu wọn, nigba naa lọwọ ba mẹta ninu wọn. Alukoro ti ni awọn yoo ri i daju pe ọwọ ba awọn marun-un yooku laipẹ.Ṣe ṣaaju ni iroyin ti tan kalẹ pẹlu fidio kan to ṣafihan Abilekọ Morunkeji pẹlu bandeeji lori, ati ọgbẹ oriṣiiriṣii lara rẹ.Lasiko yii si ree, Alukoro sọ pe boya yoo ku tabi yoo ye ni mama naa wa lọsibitu (Danger list), nitori yatọ si pe wọn yinbọn fun un ti atanpako osi rẹ si ge danu lori ere, awọn Fulani naa tun ṣa a ladaa kaakiri ara, iyẹn lo si fa ọgbẹ oriṣiiriṣii to wa lara obinrin naa.Oko ni iya yii n lọ nigba to ṣalabapade awọn Fulani ọhun, inu mọto rẹ lo wa lasiko to ri awọn maaluu rẹpẹtẹ. Ara fu u, o si fẹẹ ṣẹri mọto rẹ pada, ṣugbọn niṣe lawọn Fulani naa ya jade lati inu igbo, wọn yinbọn si taya mọto rẹ mẹrẹẹrin ko maa baa le lọ mọ, awọn taya naa jo lẹsẹkẹsẹ, nigba naa lawọn Fulani ọhun dana ibọn bo iya yii, ti wọn tun ṣa a ladaa mọ ọn.Atanpako osi pẹlu àgbọǹ iya to n jẹ Morunkeji yii ni wọn yinbọn mọ ọn, bi ko si jẹ pe Ọlọrun ni ẹmi rẹ i lo ni, awọn to yinbọn fun un ko fẹ ko ye rara, nitori wọn tun n yẹ ẹ wo ninu mọto naa pe boya o ti ku, bẹẹ naa ni wọn si n pe e wo lati mọ boya ẹmi ti bọ lara ẹ.Nitori mama yii pirọrọ fun wọn bii ẹni to ti ku loootọ ni wọn ṣe fi i silẹ ti wọn sa wọgbo lọ, ko too di pe iya naa pada ri aanu gba latọwọ awọn ọlọkọ mi-in to n kọja, ti wọn gbe e lọ sọsibitu bii meji n’Ijẹbu, ti wọn ko gba a nibẹ, ki wọn too waa gba a l’Ekoo, ni jẹnẹra to wa n’Ikẹja.Ṣugbọn titi ta a fi pari iroyin yii, ẹsẹ kan aye, ẹsẹ kan ọrun, ni Abilekọ Morounkeji Salami wa."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe demokrasia?","answer":"Rafitra fitondrana izay ampiasain’ny vahoaka ny fahefana, matetika amin’ny alalan’ny solombavambahoaka voafidy."},{"question":"බුදුන්වහන්සේ සාමුක්කංසික ( පරමාර්ථ ) දේශනාවක් සිදුකරන්නේ ඉන්ද්‍රිය ධර්ම වැඩී ඇති අයට පමණි .\\" ඉන්ද්‍රිය ධර්ම \\" යනු මොනවාද ?","answer":"සද්ධා , විරිය , සති , සමාධි , ප්‍රඥා ."},{"question":"Siapakah Pete Teo? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 480 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Pete Teo (Cina: 张子夫, lahir 26 Disember 1972 di Tawau, Sabah), ialah seorang penyanyi-penggubah lagu Malaysia, dan juga seorang penerbit filem dan penerbit muzik yang tersanjung dalam persada 'Perfileman Malaysia Alaf Baru'.Selama kerjayanya, beliau telah menghasilkan dua buah album - Rustic Living for Urbanites (2003, diterbit oleh Ronan Chris Murphy) dan Television (2006, diterbit oleh Nick Lee dan Pete Teo) di bawah naungan label yang didirikan beliau sendiri Redbag Music. Kini bertapak di Kuala Lumpur, Teo kini merupakan salah seorang penyanyi-komposer paling dikenali di Malaysia. Beliau juga menceburi bidang lakonan dalam persada yang dikenali sebagai \\"Sinema Malaysia Gelombang Baru\\" (New Wave Malaysian Cinema).Album pertamanya Rustic Living For Urbanites memenangi kategori Kulit Album Terbaik manakala salah satu daripada lagunya Arms of Marianne merangkul gelaran Video Muzik Terbaik di Anugerah Industri Muzik pada tahun 2004. Album keduanya, Television - album berunsur lagu rakyat alternatif yang diisi dengan refleksi terhadap dunia yang kuat dipengaruhi media dan gelombang Americana - memenangi ketiga-tiga kategori yang mencalonkannya pada AIM 2007, iaitu Kulit Album Terbaik, Video Muzik Terbaik dan Album Bahasa Inggeris Terbaik - yang mana beliau paling banyak menerima anugerah pada malam itu, menjadikan beliau artis indie bukan berarus perdana yang memenangi anugerah terbanyak dalam sejarah AIM.Tambahan pula, video muzik bagi salah satu lagu dari Television, Carnival Hall, membawa kejayaan kepada Kamal Sabran yang memenangi pertandingan merakam video muzik serantau You Make It Reel! (peringkat negara, Malaysia) anjuran Nokia pada awal tahun 2006.Teo juga kerap bermain di konsert-konsert muzik di luar negara. Beliau ialah pemuzik Malaysia yang pertama sekali untuk dijemput untuk membuat persembahan di Konsert South By Southwest (2007). Selain itu dia juga kerap mengunjungi Jepun untuk menjalankan jelajah.Pada tahun 2008, Teo mengelola satu inisiatif bernama \\"Malaysian Artistes for Unity\\" yang disertai 52 artis Malaysia kesemuanya untuk tujuan memupuk perpaduan yang merentasi sempadan kaum dan rasa setia kepada negara di kalangan rakyat Malaysia. Ini disusuli pada tahun seterusnya oleh projek 15Malaysia yang memaparkan 15 buah filem pendek dari pengarah terkenal negara yang mencerminkan isu sosiopolitik semasa. Pada tahun 2009 juga, Teo menyumbangkan beberapa buah lagu untuk filem Talentime.In November 2009, on the strength of the influential 'Malaysian Artistes For Unity' music video and the seminal '15Malaysia' project, CNN listed Teo as amongst the top 135 People To Watch in Asia.Pada Januari 2010, lagu \\"Pergi\\" iaitu versi bahasa Melayu untuk I Go nyanyian Aizat Amdan memenangi Anugerah Juara Lagu 2009.Pada September 2011, Teo melancarkan satu lagi kempen iaitu Undilah! yang menyeru rakyat Malaysia, khususnya golongan belia, supaya berdaftar sebagai pengundi dan bersedia untuk pilihan raya umum yang seterusnya. Kempen ini mengundang kontroversi apabila berdepan dengan sekatan oleh media arus perdana.Teo memegang watak sebagai Tony dalam filem Amerika Syarikat 2017, Ghost in the Shell, arahan Rupert Sanders lakonan Scarlett Johansson, yang ditayangkan di seluruh dunia pada Mac 2017."},{"question":"Дүйнөдө эң көп эгиздерди төрөгөн аял ким болгон?","answer":"Надя Сулейман 2009- жылы 8 эм эгиздерди төрөп дүйнөгө даңкы тарап маалымат каражаттарынан ( телевизор) айтылып турган. Надянын буга чейин 6 баласы бар болчу 8 эгиздери менен 14 баланын энеси болуп калды. Догдурдун адашып көп эмбрион коюп алганына байланыштуу, андан кийин өзү чечим кабыл алып баарын төрөймүн деп чечим кабыл алган. Догдурга дооматы жок бул менин тандоом деп айтат, болбосо догдур адашканы үчүн камалмак. \\"Ошончо эгизди кайсы акылы менен төрөдү акылынан ажыраптыр, кантип камсыздайт\\"- деген ар түркүн сындар айтылган. \\" Мен жөн гана сүйүктүү мээримдүү эне болгум келди бул жашоодо, менин тандоом жана эчким тоскоол боло албайт\\"-деп айткан. Эң көп эгиздерди төрөгөн аял деп Гиннес китебине кирген. Азыркы учурда Надя  эгиз балдары 14 жашта сак саламатта чоңоюп калышты."},{"question":"Schreiben Sie eine Fortsetzung für diesen Absatz. Der Kontext ist die Geschichte der \\"Academia Sinica\\", eine taiwanesische Universität:Initiiert durch Li Shizeng, wurde die Academia Sinica am 9. Juni 1928 in der Republik China (mit Niederlassungen in Peking und Shanghai) offiziell gegründet. Sein Weggefährte Cai Yuanpei, der nach der Revolution von 1911 erster Erziehungsminister der Republik gewesen war, wurde ihr Präsident.","answer":" Im Zuge des Bürgerkrieges und dem Einmarsch japanischer Streitkräfte, zog die Academia Sinica mehrmals um. Nachdem im Jahre 1949 die Kommunisten die Kontrolle über das Festland gewonnen hatten, wurde die Academia Sinica von der republikanischen Regierung in Taiwan neu etabliert. In den folgenden Jahren der politischen Instabilität ging ihre Entwicklung nur schleppend voran."},{"question":"\\"Адамга эң оору - күн сайын адам болуу\\" деген сөз кимге таандык?","answer":"\\"Адамга эң оору - күн сайын адам болуу\\" деген сөз Чынгыз Айтматовго таандык."},{"question":"ಮುಂದಿನ ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆಗೆ ಉತ್ತರಿಸಿ :  ಮೊದಲ ಪರ್ಷಿಯನ್ ಗಲ್ಫ್ ಯುದ್ಧ ಎಲ್ಲಿ ನಡೆಯಿತು?","answer":"ಮೊದಲ ಪರ್ಷಿಯನ್ ಗಲ್ಫ್ ಯುದ್ಧವು ಇರಾಕ್‌ನಲ್ಲಿ ನಡೆಯಿತು"},{"question":"வினா:தமிழ்நாட்டின் இலக்கிய பாரம்பரியம் எந்த வகையில் சிறப்பு வாய்ந்தது?","answer":"விடை :தமிழ்நாட்டின் இலக்கிய பாரம்பரியம் மிகவும் சிறப்பு வாய்ந்தது. தமிழ்நாட்டில் பல பழமையான இலக்கியங்கள் உள்ளன. தமிழ்நாட்டின் இலக்கியங்கள் தமிழ் மக்களின் வாழ்க்கை முறை, பண்பாடு, சமூகம், அரசியல் ஆகியவற்றை பிரதிபலிக்கின்றன. தமிழ்நாட்டின் இலக்கியங்கள் உலகெங்கிலும் படிக்கப்பட்டு வருகின்றன."},{"question":"అకౌంటింగ్ సమీకరణ గురించి సంక్లిప్తంగా వివరించండి","answer":"అకౌంటింగ్ సమీకరణ ద్వందరూప భావనపై (డెబిట్, క్రెడిట్) ఆధారపడి ఉన్నది. అకౌంటింగ్ సమీకరణ సంస్థ ఆస్తుల మొత్తానికి, అప్పుల మొత్తానికి మధ్య ఉన్న సంబంధాన్ని వ్యక్తపరుస్తుంది.ఆర్థిక వనరులు (ఆస్తులు) = బాధ్యతలు (అప్పులు)సమీకరణ దిగువ విధముగా ఉంటుంది.ఆస్తులు = సంస్థకున్న బాధ్యతలులేదాఆస్తులు = మూలధనము + అప్పులు"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"எவன் ஒருவன் மக்களை வஞ்சிக்கிறானோ, தனது தேவைக்கு மீறிய சொத்து சேர்க்கிறானோ அவன்தான் திருடன்."},{"question":"కవికి – శిల్పికి గల పోలికలు ఏమిటి?","answer":"కవి కలములో అలంకార రచన ఉంటుంది. అటువంటి అలంకార రచన శిల్పి ఉలిలో కూడ ఉంటుంది. ఆ . అందువల్లనే శిల్పి, రాతిస్తంభాలపై పూలగుత్తులు చెక్కుతాడు.శిల్పి బొమ్మలు చెక్కి ఒక రాజు కథను చూపరులచే చెప్పించగలడు. కవిత్వంలో చిత్రాలు కూర్చే కవికీ, శిల్పికీ నిజంగా తేడా లేదు. కవిత్వం ద్వారా కవి రాజు కథ రాయగలడు. శిల్పి తన శిల్పం ద్వారా రాళ్ళపై రాజుకథ చెక్కగలడు."},{"question":"கீழே கொடுக்கப்பட்டுள்ள பொருட்களைவைத்து முட்டை 65 செய்வது எப்படி?தேவையான பொருட்கள்:6 முட்டை100 கிராம் சோள மாவு50 கிராம் மைதா மாவு6 மேஜைக்கரண்டி தயிர்1 குடை மிளகாய்3 பூண்டு பல்1 இஞ்சி துண்டு2 மேஜைக்கரண்டி 65 மசாலா½ மேஜைக்கரண்டி மிளகு தூள்தேவையான அளவு மிளகாய் தூள்தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய்தேவையான அளவு உப்புசிறிதளவு ஸ்பிரிங் ஆனியன்","answer":"செய்முறை:1. முதலில் குடை மிளகாய் மற்றும் ஸ்பிரிங் ஆனியனை நறுக்கி, மற்றும் இஞ்சி பூண்டை பேஸ்ட் ஆக்கி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.2. அடுத்து ஒரு கிண்ணத்தை எடுத்து அதில் முட்டைகளை ஒவ்வொன்றாக உடைத்து ஊத்தி அதனுடன் தேவையான அளவு உப்பு மற்றும் மிளகு தூளை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு அடித்து கொள்ளவும்.3. பின்பு ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் நன்றாக எண்ணெய்யை தடவி நாம் அடித்து வைத்துள்ள முட்டையை அதில் ஊற்றவும்.4. பிறகு ஒரு குக்கரையோ அல்லது இட்லி பாத்திரத்தையோ மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் கால் பாகம் அளவு தண்ணீர் ஊற்றி நாம் முட்டையை ஊற்றி வைத்திருக்கும் கிண்ணத்தை அதனுள் வைத்து மூடி போட்டு அதை சுமார் 15 லிருந்து 20 நிமிடம் வரை வேக விடவும்.5. 20 நிமிடத்திற்கு பிறகு மூடியை திறந்து ஒரு பல் குத்தும் குச்சியை வைத்து முட்டை நன்கு வெந்ததை உறுதி செய்த பின் அதை எடுத்து வெளியே வைத்து சிறிது நேரம் ஆற விடவும்.6. முட்டை ஆறியவுடன் அதை அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப வடிவில் சிறு சிறு துண்டுகளாக நறுக்கி வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.7. இப்பொழுது ஒரு கிண்ணத்தில் சோள மாவு, மைதா மாவு, தயிர், அவரவர் விருப்பத்திற்கேற்ப மிளகாய் தூள், மற்றும் நாம் அரைத்து வைத்திருக்கும் இஞ்சி பூண்டு பேஸ்ட்டை சேர்த்து அதை நன்கு கலந்து விடவும்.8. பின்னர் அதில் கொஞ்சம் கொஞ்சமாக தண்ணீர் சேர்த்து அதை பஜ்ஜி மாவு பதத்தை விட சிறிது தண்ணியாக கலந்து கொள்ளவும்.9. அடுத்து ஒரு கடாயை மிதமான சூட்டில் அடுப்பில் வைத்து அதில் முட்டை துண்டுகளை போட்டு பொரித்து எடுப்பதற்கு தேவையான அளவு எண்ணெய் ஊற்றி அதை சுட வைக்கவும்.10. எண்ணெய் சுட்ட பின் அதில் நாம் வெட்டி வைத்திருக்கும் முட்டை துண்டுகளை ஒவ்வொன்றாக எடுத்து நாம் செய்து வைத்திருக்கும் மாவில் முக்கி எண்ணெய்யில் போடவும். (முட்டை துண்டுகளை மாவில் லேசாக அமுக்கினால் போதும் அதிக மாவுடன் எண்ணெய்யில் போட்டால் அது பஜ்ஜி போல் ஆகிவிடும்.)11. பின்பு முட்டை ஒரு புறம் வெந்ததும் அதை மறு புறம் திருப்பி விட்டு அது நன்கு பொன்னிறமானதும் அதை ஒரு கரண்டியின் மூலம் எடுத்து எண்ணெய்யை நன்கு வடித்து எடுத்து ஒரு தட்டில் வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.12. இவ்வாறே மீதமுள்ள முட்டை துண்டுகளையும் கடாயின் அளவிற்கேற்ப 2 அல்லது 3 முறையாக போட்டு பொரித்து எடுத்து வைத்து கொள்ளவும்.13. பிறகு அடுப்பை அணைத்து விட்டு அதில் நாம் நறுக்கி வைத்திருக்கும் குடை மிளகாய் மற்றும் ஸ்பிரிங் ஆனியனை போட்டு வறுத்தெடுத்து நாம் பொரித்து வைத்திருக்கும் முட்டையோடு சேர்த்து நன்கு கிளறி அதை சுட சுட பரிமாறவும்.14. இப்பொழுது உங்கள் சூடான மற்றும் மொறு மொறுப்பான முட்டை 65 தயார். இதை கட்டாயம் உங்கள் வீட்டில் செய்து பார்த்து உங்கள் குடும்பத்தாருடன் சேர்ந்து உண்டு மகிழுங்கள்."},{"question":"তাড়িতচৌম্বক বলের বর্ণনা দাও।","answer":"দুটি আহিত কণা তাদের আধানের কারণে একে অপরের ওপর যে আকর্ষণ বা বিকর্ষণ বল প্রয়োগ করে তাকে তাড়িতচৌম্বক বল বলে। তড়িৎ বল এবং চৌম্বক বল ঘনিষ্ঠভাবে সম্পর্কিত। যখন দুটি আহিত কণা স্থির থাকে তখন তাদের ওপর কেবল তড়িৎ বল ক্রিয়া করে। যখন আহিত কণাগুলো গতিশীল থাকে তখন তড়িৎ বলের অতিরিক্ত ক্রিয়াশীল আর একটি বল হচ্ছে চৌম্বক বল।সাধারণভাবে তড়িৎ প্রভাব ও চৌম্বক প্রভাব অবিচ্ছেদ্য সে কারণে বলটিকে তাড়িতচৌম্বক বল নামে অভিহিত করা হয়। মহাকর্ষ বলের ন্যায় তাড়িতচৌম্বক বলের পাল্লাও অসীম পর্যন্ত বিস্তৃত এবং এ বলের ক্রিয়ার জন্য কোনো মাধ্যমেরও প্রয়োজন হয় না। কিন্তু মাধ্যম থাকলে এই বল মাধ্যম দ্বারা প্রভাবিত হয়। তাড়িতচৌম্বক বল মহাকর্ষ বলের চেয়ে অনেক বেশি শক্তিশালী। উদাহরণস্বরূপ দুটি প্রোটনের মধ্যকার তাড়িতচৌম্বক বল এদের মধ্যকার মহাকর্ষ বলের ১০৩৬ গুণ।আমরা জানি পদার্থ ইলেকট্রন, প্রোটন নামক আহিত কণা এবং নিউট্রন নামক অনাহিত কণা দিয়ে গঠিত। এদের মধ্যে ইলেকট্রন মৌলিক কণা। যেহেতু তাড়িতচৌম্বক বল মহাকর্ষ বলের চেয়ে অনেক বেশি শক্তিশালী তাই পারমাণবিক ও আণবিক ক্ষেত্রের সকল ঘটনা এই বল দ্বারাই নিয়ন্ত্রিত হয়। অবশ্য অন্য দুটি বল কেবলমাত্র নিউক্লিয় ক্ষেত্রে প্রযোজ্য। তাই বলা যায়, অণু পরমাণুর গঠন, রাসায়নিক বিক্রিয়া, পদার্থের তাপীয় ও অন্যান্য ধর্ম তাড়িতচৌম্বক বলের ফল। লক্ষ্যণীয় যে, আমাদের এই স্থুল জগতের যাবতীয় বলসমূহ (মহাকর্ষ বল ব্যতীত) তড়িৎ বলেরই বহিঃপ্রকাশ। ঘর্ষণ স্পর্শ বল, স্প্রিং বল, বা অন্যান্য বিকৃত বস্তুর মধ্যকার বল আহিত কণাগুলোর তড়িৎ বলেরই ফলশ্রুতি। ফোটন নামক এক প্রকার. ভরহীন ও আধানহীন কণার পারস্পরিক বিনিময়ের ফলে এই বল কার্যকর হয়।মহাকর্ষ বল সর্বদা আকর্ষণধর্মী। পক্ষান্তরে তাড়িতচৌম্বক বল আকর্ষণ বিকর্ষণ উভয়ধর্মী হতে পারে। আবার কোনো বস্তুর ভর কেবলমাত্র ধনাত্মক হতে পারে কিন্তু আধান ধনাত্মক বা ঋণাত্মক উভয় হতে পারে। বেশিরভাগ ক্ষেত্রে পদার্থ তড়িৎ নিরপেক্ষ অর্থাৎ তড়িৎ বল শূন্য আর ভূ-পৃষ্ঠীয় ঘটনাবলির ক্ষেত্রে মহাকর্ষ বলই প্রাধান্য পায়।"},{"question":"Inona avy ny vokatra ratsy ateraky ny finonana ny anjara?","answer":"Ny finona ny anjara dia mety mahatonga fisarahana sy fialonan’ny fiarahamonina ireo manana lafim-piainana tsaratsara; Mitarika finoanoam-poana; Fanomezan-tsiny ny Razana; Fanararaotam-pahefana ataon’ny tsara fari-piainana; Miteraka tsy fandraisana andraikitra; Miteraka famoizam-po; Mahatonga fanilikilihana."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Nhạc sĩ đàn guitar, thể hiện ca khúc với bản phối rộn ràng hơn. Một đêm say được Thịnh Suy sáng tác khi mới 19 tuổi, anh thể hiện ca khúc với tâm thế chàng trai trẻ còn nhiều e dè, gửi gắm khát vọng đến người mình thầm thích. Đức Huy hát lả lơi, tình tứ hơn, với tâm thế của người đàn ông trưởng thành. Đức Huy nói: \\"Tôi cảm thấy như được trẻ lại với ca khúc của Thịnh Suy. Tôi phần nào tìm lại được mình trong cốt cách âm nhạc của cậu. Một đêm say chứa đựng những điều giản dị, tinh tế trong cuộc sống, không có sự màu mè\\". Thịnh Suy nói Đức Huy là thần tượng của anh. Anh và nhạc sĩ có sự gần gũi bởi đều có cái nhìn trong trẻo, vô tư về tình yêu. Hai nghệ sĩ cùng thể hiện bản mash-up Và tôi cũng yêu em (Đức Huy) - Tình yêu màu xanh lá (Thịnh Suy). Bản nhạc mang đến cảm xúc vui tươi cho người nghe. Ca sĩ trẻ còn cover hit Yêu em dài lâu của nhạc sĩ Đức Huy, mash-up một đoạn điệp khúc trong bài Chuyện rằng của chính anh. Sự kết hợp cho thấy điểm chung trong âm nhạc của hai nghệ sĩ hơn kém nhau 52 tuổi. Họ đều yêu hết mình, thẳng thắn bộc lộ tâm trạng, cảm xúc qua ca từ ngắn gọn, trực tiếp. Kết thúc chương trình, hai nghệ sĩ hát Lemon tree của Fool's Garden. Ca khúc nói về nỗi buồn của một chàng trai khi tình yêu, cuộc đời liên tục đổi thay. Nhạc sĩ Đức Huy nói: \\"Sau dịch bệnh, nhiều người trẻ sa sút tinh thần. Chúng tôi muốn nhắn nhủ với khán giả rằng cuộc sống vẫn vận hành bình thường, có lúc thịnh lúc suy. Hãy ra đường, ngắm nhìn cuộc sống, trò chuyện với người này, người kia để thấy ồ cuộc đời vẫn ổn đấy chứ\\". Đức Huy sinh năm 1947 ở Hà Nội. Thập niên 1980, anh bắt đầu viết nhạc và biểu diễn trên các sân khấu hải ngoại. Những ca khúc nổi tiếng của nhạc sĩ là Và tôi cũng yêu em, Bay đi cánh chim biển, Đừng xa em đêm nay, Đường xa ướt mưa, Và con tim đã vui trở lại, Yêu em dài lâu... Thịnh Suy sinh năm 1999 tại TP HCM, theo đuổi âm nhạc từ cấp ba. Năm 2019, khi đang học Đại học Sư phạm Kỹ thuật TP HCM, anh trở thành hiện tượng với nhạc phẩm Một đêm say. Hai MV của ca khúc đạt tổng cộng hơn 70 triệu lượt xem. Sau đó, anh tiếp tục gây chú ý với các bản hit Chuyện rằng, Thắc mắc... Giao lộ thời gian do nhạc sĩ Dương Cầm phụ trách âm nhạc, phát sóng lúc 20h tối thứ bảy tuần thứ hai và tuần cuối mỗi tháng, trên ứng dụng FPT Play. Ban biên tập chương trình chọn các nghệ sĩ thuộc hai thế hệ khác biệt, có nét tương đồng về âm nhạc để kết hợp như Thanh Hà - Lân Nhã, Thanh Lam, Bùi Công Nam, Thu Minh - Orange...","answer":"Đức Huy hát nhạc Thịnh Suy"},{"question":"১৯৯০-এর গণঅভ্যুত্থান কী? ব্যাখ্যা কর।","answer":"স্বৈরাচারী এরশাদবিরোধী ১৯৯০ সালের গণআন্দোলনকে নব্বই-এর গণঅভ্যুত্থান বলা হয়।১৯৮২ সালের শেষ দিকে জেনারেল হুসেইন মুহম্মদ এরশাদের শিক্ষানীতি বাতিলের দাবিতে সামরিক শাসনের বিরুদ্ধে সর্বপ্রথম আন্দোলন শুরু করে ছাত্র সমাজ। ১৯৯০ সালের ২০শে নভেম্বর গুলিবিদ্ধ মিলনের মৃত্যু এবং ঢাকা বিশ্ববিদ্যালয়ে শিক্ষকদের একযোগে পদত্যাগ এবং রাজনৈতিক দলগুলোর অভিন্ন কর্মসূচির কারণে ১৯৯০ সালের ৪ঠা ডিসেম্বর এরশাদ পদত্যাগ করেন। আর তার বিরুদ্ধে সংঘটিত ১৯৯০ সালের আপামর জনতার এ আন্দোলনই ১৯৯০-এর গণঅভ্যুত্থান নামে পরিচিত।"},{"question":"Pananya: Saha anu ngarumuskeun kawijakan fiskal di Amérika Serikat?","answer":"Anu ngarumuskeun kawijakan fiskal di Amérika Serikat nyaéta Kongrés."},{"question":"Ko le ṣẹlẹ laelae, Amọtẹkun ko ni i si labẹ ijọba apapọ -Makinde","answer":"Gomina ipinlẹ Ọyọ, Ẹnjinnia Ṣeyi Makinde, naa ti darapọ mọ awọn to sọ pe ala ti ko le ṣẹ ni ki ikọ Amọtẹkun wa labẹ ọga ọlọpaa patapata nilẹ wa.Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, ni gomina sọrọ naa lasiko to n ṣepade pẹlu gbogbo awọn alaga ijọba ibilẹ mejidinlaaadọrin to wa nipinlẹ Ọyọ. Makinde, ẹni ti Akọwe iroyin rẹ, Taiwo Adisa, gbẹnu rẹ sọrọ sọ pe ‘’Eto aabo jẹ ọkan ninu awọn afojusun ijọba yii, gbogbo ohun to ba wa nikaapa wa la si maa ṣe lati ri i pe eto aabo fun ẹmi ati dukia to fẹsẹ rinlẹ wa fun awọn olugbe ipinlẹ Ọyọ. A si fẹ ki gbogbo wa sun, ka le han-an-run lai si ibẹru tabi ifoya kankan. Ipinlẹ Ọyọ jẹ ipinlẹ to tobi, to si paala pẹlu oriṣiiriṣii ilu, nitori naa la ṣe gbọdọ mu eto aabo ni pataki.‘‘Laipẹ yii ti awọn adigunjale ṣọṣẹ niluu Okeho, awọn ọdẹ agbegbe naa ni wọn dide, ti wọn koju awọn oniṣẹ ibi naa. Awọn ni wọn fọ gbogbo inu igbo kaakiri, ti wọn si ri i pe ọwọ tẹ wọn.Idi niyi ti mo fi n sọ ọ, ti mo n tẹnu mọ ọn, ti mo si n pariwo fun gbogbo aye pe mimi kan ko le mi ikọ Amọtẹkun, bẹẹ ni wọn ko ni i si labe akoso tabi idari ọga ọlọpaa ilẹ wa. Awa la oo maa dari rẹ, aabo awọn eeyan wa ṣe pataki si wa, nitori ko si aṣeyọri kankan ta a le ṣe nibi ti ko ba ti si aabo to daju.Bakan naa ni gomina rọ awọn alaga ijọba ibilẹ yii lati pada si agbegbe wọn, ki wọn lọọ mojuto eto aabo ibẹ, ki awọn araalu le fẹdọ lori oronro. Makinde ni eto aabo jẹ ọkan pataki ninu ipenija ti ipinlẹ Ọyọ ni. O waa rọ awọn eeyan naa ki wọn lọọ da igbimọ alakooso eleto aabo silẹ lawọn ijọba ibilẹ wọn kaakairi ni kiakia, pẹlu ileri pe oun yoo ṣeto owo to yẹ lati ṣe atilẹyin fun wọn lati mu ki eleyii ṣeeṣe.O waa kilọ fun awọn alaga naa pe bi ilu ati awọn agbegbe wọn ba ṣe lalaafia si, ti aabo to dara si wa nibẹ ni yoo sọ boya wọn yoo tun fa wọn kalẹ lati dije dupo tabi bẹẹ kọ."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਅਸਟਪਦੀ ॥ਆਪਿ ਕਥੈ ਆਪਿ ਸੁਨਨੈਹਾਰੁ ॥ਆਪਹਿ ਏਕੁ ਆਪਿ ਬਿਸਥਾਰੁ ॥ਜਾ ਤਿਸੁ ਭਾਵੈ ਤਾ ਸ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਉਪਾਏ ॥ਆਪਨੈ ਭਾਣੈ ਲਏ ਸਮਾਏ ॥ਤੁਮ ਤੇ ਭਿੰਨ ਨਹੀ ਕਿਛੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਆਪਨ ਸੂਤਿ ਸਭੁ ਜਗਤੁ ਪਰੋਇ ॥ਜਾ ਕਉ ਪ੍ਰਭ ਜੀਉ ਆਪਿ ਬੁਝਾਏ ॥ਸਚੁ ਨਾਮੁ ਸੋਈ ਜਨੁ ਪਾਏ ॥ਸੋ ਸਮਦਰਸੀ ਤਤ ਕਾ ਬੇਤਾ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਸਗਲ ਸ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਕਾ ਜੇਤਾ ॥੧॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 292 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਆਪ ਬੋਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸੁਣਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ, ਆਪ ਹੀ ਇੱਕ ਹੈ,ਆਪ ਦਾ ਹੀ ਸਾਰਾ ਪਸਾਰਾ ਹੈ,ਤੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ ਸ਼੍ਰਿਸਟੀ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰਦਾ ਹੈ । ਤੇ ਆਪ ਹੀ (ਜਗਤ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਵਿਚ) ਸਮੇਟ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ!) ਤੈਥੋਂ ਵੱਖਰਾ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ (ਆਪਣੇ ਹੁਕਮ-ਰੂਪ) ਧਾਗੇ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰੋ ਰੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ ।ਜਿਸ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਜੀ ਆਪ ਸੂਝ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦਾ ਸਦਾ-ਥਿਰ ਰਹਿਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਨਾਮ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਹੈ ।ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਭ ਵਲ ਇਕ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਤੱਕਦਾ ਹੈ, ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦਾ ਮਹਰਮ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਜਗਤ ਦਾ ਜਿੱਤਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ ।੧।\\""},{"question":"Ramai saintis berpendapat bahawa pembakaran bahan api fosil telah meningkatkan jumlah karbon dioksida di atmosfera. Apakah kesan peningkatan karbon dioksida yang paling ketara pada planet ini? Pilihan yang ada: 1) iklim yang lebih sejuk 2). iklim yang lebih hangat 3). kelembapan relatif yang lebih rendah 4). lebih banyak ozon di atmosfera","answer":"2). iklim yang lebih hangat"},{"question":"香港的地理位置？","answer":"答：香港位于中国的南部，地处珠江口以东，南临南海，东接大鹏湾，西界珠江口，北与深圳市接壤。"},{"question":"Inona no bibikely haingam-pandeha amin'ny fanidinana indrindra eto an-tany?","answer":"Ny angidina no bibikely haingam-pandeha indrindra amin'ny fanidinana  eto an-tany."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai.  Juliana gemar memakai pakaian yang berwarna __. Pilihan:  A) nipis-nipisB) segar-segarC) mahal-mahal D) garang-garang","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah D) garang-garang"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي تزوج اثنتين من بنات الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: عثمان بن عفان."},{"question":"EFCC lọọ jalẹkun ile awọn ọmọ yahoo loru, lawọn yẹn ba kọju ija si wọn l’Ọṣogbo","answer":"Ọrọ di bo o lọ o ya lọna laaarọ ọjọ Iṣẹgun lagbegbe Lameco, kọja si Oke-fia, niluu Oṣogbo, lasiko ti awọn ọmọ Yahoo ti wọn to ọgọrun-un fọn soju titi pẹlu onuruuru nnkan ija lọwọ wọn.Wọn dana sun taya, bẹẹ ni wọn wọ oriṣiiriṣii nnkan soju popo, ti gbogbo awọn onimọto ti wọn n gbe awọn ọmọ lọ sileewe atawọn onikorope si n lọri pada sẹyin.Ohun ti a gbọ ni pe ṣe lawọn ajọ to n gbogun ti jibiti ori ẹrọ ayelujara, Economic and Financial Crimes Commission, lọ sile awọn kan laago kan aabọ oru, ti wọn si jalẹkun wọle.Bi wọn ṣe ja geeti awọn ile kan pẹlu okuta, ni wọn yọ bulọọku ferese awọn kan wọle, ti wọn si n ko wọn sinu mọto, bẹẹ ni wọn gba mọto wọn.Idi niyẹn tawọn ọmọ Yahoo ọhun fi pe ara wọn jọ, ti wọn si lọọ dana soju ọna ti wọn yoo gba kọja. Pẹlu ibọn, igi, ada, okuta ati bẹẹ bẹẹ lọ lawọn ọdọ naa fi koju awọn EFCC.Nigba tawọn EFCC ri i pe ọrọ naa kọja agbara, wọn fi diẹ silẹ lara awọn mọto ti wọn gba, wọn si sa lọ pẹlu mọto diẹ ti wọn fi gbe awọn ọmọ ti wọn ko.Awọn ọdọ naa pejọ si Freedom Park, ni Old Garage, ariwo ti wọn n pa ni pe kijọba Ọṣun lọọ gba awọn ara wọn ti EFCC ko lọ ti wọn ko ba fẹ wahala nla niluu Oṣogbo.A gbọ pe ijọba ti ran Kọmiṣanna fọrọ ọdọ ati ere idaraya, Yẹmi Lawal, lọ si ọfiisi awọn EFCC lati le wa ojutuu si ọrọ naa."},{"question":"Συμπλήρωσε αυτήν την πρόταση. \\"Ο Όμηρος είναι ένας από τους δύο μεγάλους επικούς ποιητές της αρχαίας\\"","answer":"Απάντηση: \\"Ελλάδας\\""},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Ratusz został wybudowany w latach 1561–1565 i otwarty 27 lutego 1565 roku. Autorem projektu był Cornelis Floris de Vriendt we współpracy z innymi, w tym z Włochem Nicolo Scarinim. Pierwotnie budowę ratusza planowano już około roku 1540 (wówczas miał powstać w stylu gotyckim), jednak z powodu braku środków do prac nie przystąpiono. W 1576 roku, podczas hiszpańskiej furii","answer":"budynek został podpalony; ze zniszczeń odbudowano go trzy lata później. Obiekt reprezentuje cechy renesansu flamandzkiego i włoskiego, choć jego środkowa część nawiązuje jeszcze do architektury gotyckich ratuszy Flandrii i Brabancji. Ryzalit na fasadzie przedniej zawiera rzeźbę Maryi, poniżej której znajdują się dwie kolejne kobiece sylwetki reprezentujące roztropność i sprawiedliwość, a także herby księstwa Brabancji, Filipa II Habsburga i markizatu antwerpskiego. Statua Maryi została ustawiona przez Jezuitów w okresie kontrreformacji, wcześniej w jej miejscu mieściła się rzeźba Silviusa Brabo. Wnętrze budynku zostało ukształtowane podczas przebudowy w XIX wieku. Jedną ze znaczących zmian było zadaszenie wewnętrznego dziedzińca, który dotąd pozostawał otwarty."},{"question":"அன்பளிப்பு (சிறுகதைகள் )எனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர்? ","answer":" விடை : கு. அழகிரிசாமி"},{"question":"අපේ කය සහ වචනය යන දෙක හීලෑ කරන්නේ,","answer":"අපේ කය සහ වචනය යන දෙක හීලෑ කරන්නේ ශීලයයි. "},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டில் பாய் தயாரிப்பில் புகழ் பெற்ற இடம் யாது ?","answer":"விடை :  பத்தமடை"},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: Curling zaczął uprawiać w 2003, wcześniej grał m.in. w koszykówkę i racquetball. Na arenie międzynarodowej zadebiutował jako rezerwowy w zespole Chrisa Dawa na Mistrzostwach Świata 2005. W następnym sezonie był na trzeciej pozycji, reprezentował Kanadę na","answer":"Zimowych Igrzyskach Paraolimpijskich 2006. Drużyna zajęła 1. miejsce w fazie grupowej wygrywając pięć a przegrywając dwa spotkania. W półfinale zespół Klonowego Liścia pokonał 5:4 Norwegię (Geir Arne Skogstad), zdobył złote medale triumfując w ostatnim meczu turnieju 7:4 nad Wielką Brytanią (Frank Duffy)."},{"question":" Qual país tem a maior linha costeira do mundo?","answer":"118 elementos químicos (92 naturais e 26 artificiais)."},{"question":"أمتى كانت أول بداية لجوايز الجولدن جلوب؟","answer":"كانت أول بداية لجوايز الجولدن جلوب سنة 1944.جوايز جولدن جلوب هيا جوايز بتمنحها جمعية الصحافه الاجنبيه فى هوليوود فى امريكا علشان الاعتراف بالانجازات البارزة فى صناعة الترفيه، على المستويين المحلى و الأجنبى. جوايز جولدن جلوب بتركز اهتمام الجمهور على أحسن الاعمال فى افلام السينما و فى برامج التلفزيون."},{"question":"Marina ve fa i Madagasikara no nosy lehibe indrindra maneran-tany?a) Eny, marina.b) Tsia, diso.","answer":"Tsia, mitana ny laharana fahaefatra i Madagasikara raha ny angezany no jerena."},{"question":"\\"අතේ තිබුනු රන් සුලැඟිලි තණ්ඩිය අත්තෙං අත්තට මාරු වෙනා\\"මෙහි තණ්ඩිය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"මෙහි නියම වචනය තණ්ඩිය ( දණ්ඩ යන්නෙන් ආවකි) යන්නයි. දණ්ඩ, කඳ ,ලීය එහි අරුතයි.බාලදක්ෂයින් ලෙස පුහුණු වූ අය දන්නවා ඇති ඔවුන්ට තණ්ඩි ගැටය නම් ගැටයක් උගන්වන බව. එය ගස් කපන්නන් භාවිත කරනා ගැටයක්. ඔවුන් එයට කියන්නේ කඳන් ගැටය කියායි.මේ සුළඟිලි තණ්ඩිය කියවෙන්නේ ගීතයකයි. එහි එන ආකාරයට අර්ථය දෙල් කැඩීමට ගන්නා සුළඟිල්ලක් තරම් හීන් ලීය.කලවාවලටද තණ්ඩිය යයි කියන අය ඇත. එය කඳ කලවා යන යෙදුමටම සමානය."},{"question":"విచక్షణారహితంగా పెస్టిసైడ్లు వాడటం వలన కలిగే నష్టాలు ఏమిటి?","answer":"పెస్టిసైడ్లు విచక్షణారహితంగా ప్రభావాన్ని చూపుతూ, ఎక్కువ సంఖ్యలో ఇతర జంతువులను నాశనం చేస్తాయి. వీటిలో ఈ క్రిములను ఆహారంగా తీసుకొనే జంతువులు మరియు ఇతరులకు ఆహారమయ్యే జంతువులూ ఉంటాయి. ఫలితంగా పెస్టిసైడ్లు ఆహారపు గొలుసులలో అనూహ్యమైన మార్పులకు దారితీస్తూ, ఆవరణ వ్యవస్థ యొక్క సమతుల్యతను దెబ్బతీస్తాయి. ఇవి నేలలో కలిసిపోయినపుడు అవి కలిగించే ప్రభావం ఇంకా అపాయకరంగా ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"ਗਾਂਧੀ ਨੇ ਸੂਟ-ਬੂਟ ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ‘ਅਧਨੰਗਾ ਫ਼ਕੀਰ’ ਬਣਨ ਦਾ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਕਿਉਂ ਲਿਆ?","answer":"“ਮਿਸਟਰ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਵਰਗੇ ਰਾਜਧ੍ਰੋਹੀ, ਮਿਡਲ ਟੈਂਪਲ ਵਕੀਲ ਦਾ ਅਰਧ ਨਗਨ ਹਾਲਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਾਇਸਰਾਏ ਦੇ ਮਹਿਲਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਪੌੜੀਆਂ ਚੜ੍ਹਨਾ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਜੇ ਦੇ ਨੁਮਾਇੰਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਬਰਾਬਰੀ ਦੇ ਪੱਧਰ ’ਤੇ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਨਾ ਬਹੁਤ ਖ਼ਤਰਨਾਕ ਅਤੇ ਘ੍ਰਿਣਾ ਭਰਿਆ ਸੀ।”ਬਰਤਾਨੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਤਤਕਾਲੀ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਚਰਚਿਲ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਬਿਆਨ ਇਤਿਹਾਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਦਰਜ ਹੈ।ਇਹ ਉਦੋਂ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਮੋਹਨ ਦਾਸ ਕਰਮ ਚੰਦ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਬਰਤਾਨੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿੰਗ ਜਾਰਜ ਪੰਜਵੇਂ ਦੇ ਸੱਦੇ ਤੇ ਬਕਿੰਘਮ ਪੈਲੇਸ ਗਏ ਸਨ। ਉਦੋਂ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਜਾਣੀ-ਪਛਾਣੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਧੋਤੀ ਲਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ ‘ਲਾਇਨਕਲਾਥ’ ਜਾਣੀ ਲੰਗੋਟ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਸਨ।ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦੇ ਪੜਪੋਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਈ ਕਿਤਾਬਾਂ ਲਿਖ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਤੁਸ਼ਾਰ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਮੰਨਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਆਪਣੀ ਛੋਟੀ ਧੋਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਨੇ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਇੱਕ ਰਣਨੀਤੀ ਵਜੋਂ ਵਰਤਿਆ ਸੀ। ਉਹ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, “ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਦਤ ਹੋ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਜਦੋਂ ਕੋਈ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਆਗੂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਣ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਸੀ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ੀ ਤੌਰ ਤਰੀਕੇ ਨਾਲ ਆਉਂਦਾ ਸੀ। ਇਸ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ ਕਾਫ਼ੀ ਸਹਿਜ ਮਹਿਸੂਸ ਕਰਦੇ ਸੀ।”ਉਹ ਅੱਗੇ ਦੱਸਦੇ ਹਨ,  “ਜਦੋਂ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਨੇ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ਤਾਂ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ ਪ੍ਰੇਸ਼ਾਨ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਤਾਂ ਸਾਡੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਦਿਸਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ।”“ਰਾਊਂਡਟੇਬਲ ਕਾਨਫ਼ਰੰਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਤਾਂ ਅੰਗਰੇਜ਼ ਸਦਮੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਹੀ ਆ ਗਏ ਸਨ। ਸਾਡੇ ਰਾਜੇ ਦੇ ਸਨਮੁੱਖ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਅਧਨੰਗੇ ਜਾਣਗੇ। ਗਾਂਧੀ ਇੱਕ ਮਨੋਵਿਗਿਆਨਕ ਦਾਅ ਵੀ ਖੇਡ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ। ਜਦੋਂ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਵਿਚਾਰ-ਵਟਾਂਦਰਾ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋ ਤਾਂ ਉਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਨੋਵਿਗਿਆਨਕ ਦਾਅ-ਪੇਚ ਖੇਡਣੇ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ।” ==ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦਾ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਛੋਟੀ ਧੋਤੀ ਪਾਉਣ ਦਾ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ==ਵੈਸੇ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂਆਤੀ ਤਸਵੀਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੂਟ-ਬੂਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੇਖ ਸਕਦੇ ਹੋ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਅਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਹ ਗੁਜਰਾਤ ਦੇ ਕਾਠੀਆਵਾੜੀ ਪਹਿਰਾਵੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਆਏ ਸਨ।ਸਵਾਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਦੀ ਪਛਾਣ ਬਣ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਅੱਧੀ ਧੋਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਚਾਦਰ ਕਦੋਂ ਅਤੇ ਕਿਵੇਂ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿੱਚ ਆਈ ਜੋ ਦੇਸ਼-ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਤੀਕ ਬਣ ਗਈ। ਗੱਲ 1921 ਦੀ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਤਾਮਿਲਨਾਡੂ ਦੇ ਮਦੁਰਈ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਨ। ਉਦੋਂ ਤੱਕ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਫ਼ੈਸਲਾ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕੇ ਸਨ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਸਵਦੇਸ਼ੀ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਹੀ ਪਾਉਣਗੇ।ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ੀ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਸਾੜਨ ਦਾ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਸੱਦਾ ਇੱਕ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਦਾ ਰੂਪ ਧਾਰਨ ਕਰ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਸੀ। ਤਾਮਿਲਨਾਡੂ ਵਿੱਚ ਇੱਕ ਰੇਲ ਯਾਤਰਾ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹ ਆਮ ਰੇਲ ਮੁਸਾਫ਼ਰਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਸਨ। ਇਸ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਕਿ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਕੋਲ ਪੈਸੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਨ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਪੁਰਾਣੇ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਸਾੜ ਕੇ ਖਾਦੀ ਦੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਖ਼ਰੀਦ ਸਕਦੇ।ਆਪਣੇ ਰੇਲ ਸਫ਼ਰ ਬਾਰੇ ਗਾਂਧੀ ਲਿਖਦੇ ਹਨ, “ਮੈਂ ਰੇਲ ਦੀ ਭੀੜ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੇਖਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਸਵਦੇਸ਼ੀ ਮੂਵਮੈਂਟ ਨਾਲ ਕੋਈ ਲੈਣ-ਦੇਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ੀ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਪਾਏ ਹੋਏ ਸਨ। ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਤਾਂ ਕਈਆਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲਈ ਮਹਿੰਗਾ ਖਾਦੀ ਕੱਪੜਾ ਖਰੀਦਣਾ ਸੰਭਵ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਮੈਂ ਟੋਪੀ, ਪੂਰੀ ਧੋਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਕਮੀਜ਼ ਪਾਈ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ।”ਗਾਂਧੀ ਲਿਖਦੇ ਹਨ, “ਉਦੋਂ ਮੈਂ ਸੋਚਿਆ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਜਵਾਬ ਦੇ ਸਕਦਾ ਹਾਂ। ਸਿਵਾਇ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਕਿ ਸ਼ਾਲੀਨਤਾ ਦੇ ਘੇਰੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਮੈਂ ਆਪਣੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਉੱਪਰ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਕੱਪੜੇ ਤਿਆਗ ਦੇਵਾਂ। ਅਤੇ ਖ਼ੁਦ ਨੂੰ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ ਲੈ ਜਾਵਾਂ। ਅਗਲੇ ਹੀ ਦਿਨ ਮੁਦਰਈ ਦੀ ਬੈਠਕ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਉੱਪਰ ਅਮਲ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ।”"},{"question":"வினா: ஈராக் நாட்டின் தலைநகரம் எது?","answer":"விடை:ஈராக் நாட்டின் தலைநகரம் பாக்தாக்.பகுதாது (பக்தாத்) என்பது ஈராக் நாட்டின் தலைநகரமாகும். இப்பெயர், பாரசீக மொழிச் சொல்லான, பக்-தாத் அல்லது பக்-தா-து என்பதின் அடியாகப் பிறந்தது. இதன் பொருள் இறைவனின் பூங்கா என்பதாகும். இது தென்மேற்கு ஆசியாவில் தெஹ்ரானுக்கு அடுத்த இரண்டாவது பெரிய நகரமாகும். அரபு உலகத்திலும் எகிப்திலுள்ள கெய்ரோவுக்கு அடுத்த இரண்டாவது பெரிய நகரம் இதுவாகும். 2003 ஆம் ஆண்டில் எடுக்கப்பட்ட கணக்கெடுப்பின் படி 5,772,000 மக்கள்தொகையைக் கொண்டு ஈராக்கின் மிகப்பெரிய நகரமாகவும் இந்நகரம் விளங்குகிறது. டைகிரிஸ் நதிக்கரையில் அமைந்துள்ள இந்த நகரம் 33°20′N 44°26′E ஒரு காலத்தில் முஸ்லிம்களின் பண்பாட்டு மையமாக விளங்கியது.உயர் இடைக்காலங்களில்(Middle Age), பாக்தாத் நகரம் 1,200,000-3,000,000 மக்கள் தொகை கொண்ட உலகின் மிகப்பெரிய நகரமாகக் கருதப்பட்டது. 1258 ஆம் ஆண்டில் மங்கோலிய சாம்ராஜ்யத்தினின் பிடியில் சிக்கி இந்த நகரம் அழிக்கப்பட்டது, இதன் விளைவாக பல நூற்றாண்டுகளாக அடிக்கடி கொள்ளை நோய்கள்(plagues) மற்றும் பல தொடர்ச்சியான பேரரசுகள் காரணமாகவும் இந்நகரம் பலவீனப்படுத்தப்பட்டது. 1938 ல் ஒரு சுயாதீனமான நாடாக ஈராக் அங்கீகாரம் பெற்றபின், பாக்தாத் படிப்படியாக அதன் முந்தைய முக்கியத்துவமான அரபு கலாச்சாரத்தின் முக்கிய மையமாக மீண்டும் உயிர்பெற்றது.அண்மை காலத்தில், இந்த நகரம் அடிக்கடி கடுமையான உள்கட்டமைப்பு சேதத்தை எதிர்கொண்டது. இது 2003 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஈராக்கின் படையெடுப்பு மற்றும் டிசம்பர் 2011 வரை நீடித்த ஈராக் போரினால் ஏற்பட்ட விளைவுகள் ஆகும். சமீபத்திய ஆண்டுகளில், இந்நகரம் அடிக்கடி கிளர்ச்சி தாக்குதலுக்கும் ஆளாகியுள்ளது.2012 ஆம் ஆண்டில், பாக்தாத் நகரம் உலகில் வாழும் குறைந்த விருந்தோம்பல் இடங்களில் ஒன்றாக பட்டியலிடப்பட்டது. மெர்சர் தரவரிசையில் 221 பெரிய நகரங்களில் மோசமான நகரம் என இந்நகரம் மதிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"Mạc Đĩnh Chi có một vợ ngoại quốc. Bà vợ đó là người xứ nào?","answer":"Mạc Đĩnh Chi có vợ người Cao LySau khi so tài đề quạt ở nước Nguyên, sứ thần Cao Ly (Triều Tiên bây giờ) tuy bị thua nhưng rất cảm phục tài năng của Mạc Đĩnh Chi. Hai người đã kết thân và trở thành đôi bạn tri kỷ. Khi sứ thần Cao Ly về nước, ông đã mời Mạc Đĩnh Chi sang thăm Cao Ly 4 tháng. Lần đó, sứ thần Cao Ly đã làm mối cho Mạc Đĩnh Chi với người cháu gái để làm thiếp. Người vợ Cao Ly theo Mạc Đĩnh Chi đi sứ. Hai người có với nhau ba người con, hai trai và một gái.Người vợ sau đó trở về quê hương, chịu thương chịu khó nuôi nấng dạy bảo, dựng vợ gả chồng cho các con. Sau đó, bà từ biệt con cháu, đi vào chùa ở. Hai người con trai của Mạc Đĩnh Chi sau này trở thành bậc kỳ tài của xứ Cao Ly.Về việc này, gia phả tộc Mạc có viết: \\"Trên đường về nước, nhận lời mời của sứ thần Cao Ly, Mạc Đĩnh Chi có ghé Bình Nhưỡng. Quý trọng một tài năng và nhân cách, sứ thần Cao Ly gả cháu gái yêu của ngài cho sứ thần Đại Việt làm vợ thiếp. Vì nặng tình người và mến cảnh đất nước Đại Hàn, Mạc Đĩnh Chi đã lưu lại Triều Tiên sinh hạ một dòng con bên đó. Mạc Đĩnh Chi lưu luyến giã biệt vợ con một mình lên đường trở về cố quốc\\".Theo bài viết Người Triều Tiên đi bán sâm là hậu duệ của Mạc Đĩnh Chi đăng trên An Nam tạp chí số 4 năm 1926, ông Lê Khắc Hòe cho biết có một người Triều Tiên xưng là hậu duệ của Mạc Đĩnh Chi qua Việt Nam để tìm kiếm dòng họ. Sau này, tác giả Vũ Hiệp sưu tập và đăng trên tạp chí Nghiên cứu Sử số 2, 1996 tại Sài Gòn."},{"question":"Dark Olive ne renk?","answer":"Altın-yeşil bir ton."},{"question":"ඔන්චිල්ලා වාරම් කවියක් කියන්න ","answer":"අට දෙන අට කොණ වාඩි වෙය ල්ලාසිට ගෙන දෙන්නෙක් පොලු පාග ල්ලාවවුලන් ලෙස කැරකෙන ඔන්චි ල්ලාඅපිත් පදිමු දැන් රන් ඔන්චි ල්ලා"},{"question":"ธาตุ F มีชื่อเรียกในภาษาไทยว่าธาตุใด","answer":"ธาตุฟลูออรีน"},{"question":"HALISTA AMA KHATARKA DAAWADA CILAANKA AMA XINIGA LOO ISTICMAALO EE DALWANDI AMA MAHLABIYAD.","answer":"Maanta waxaan ka hadlaynaa arrin kaloo bulshadu aad u isticmaasho halisna ku ah caafimaadkeeda, waana daawooyinka cillaanka lagu daro oo soomaalidu qaar u taqaano \\"Dalwandi\\" iyo \\"mahlabiyad\\" afka qalaadne daawooyinkaas waxay ka siman yihiin kiimikada loo yaqaano \\"Paraphenylenediamine\\" loona soo gaabiyo \\"PPD\\".Waxaa daawadaan cillaanka loogu darsadaa si ay midabka dhakhso u soo saarto,cillaankane uga dhigto mid tiq ah.Daawadaan waxaa badanaa lagu soo daraa madoobeysada la marsado, waxaa kaloo lagu daraa khadka daabacadda dharka iyo dunta laga sameeyo taayarrada gawaarida.Daawadaan kiimikada ah waxay leedahay halis caafimaadka u daran, waana muhiim in qofkasta oo isticmaalo ogaado, marmarka qaar halisteeda waa loo dhiman karaa.Dhibaatada ugu horeyso ee laga dhaxli karo waa xasaasiyadda ama allejiga oo gaarsiisan heerka loo yaqaano \\"Anaphlactic shock\\" oo ah mid qofka dili karto, xasaasiyadaas oo laga dareemo meelaha cillaanka la mariyay sida maqaarka, tinta, garka iyo sunniyaha, haddii sunniyaha la marsado cillaan leh daawo oo qofka xasaasiyad ku qaado in uu ku indho beelo iyadoo keento laba xaaladooda oo loo yaqaano \\"keratitis\\" iyo \\"Neuritis\\".Haddii aad daawadaan xasaasiyad horey ugu dareentay oo mar kale isticmaashid waa halis in aad u dhimato ayaa dhici karto oo neefsashada kugu dhegto ama cadaadiska dhiigaaga uu hoos u dhaco ama coma aad gasho.Xasaasiyada ugu horeyso waa qofka oo dareemo in maqaarka midabkiisu isbadalay, cuncun ama jirka oo biyo gashado oo bacoolo yeesho, marmarka qaar dubka ayaa ka kici karo maqaarka oo qofka wuu dhiigbixi karaa ama suntaa dhiiga u sii gudbi karto oo qofka caafimaadkiisa halis ayuu gali karaa.Dhibaatada kale ee la dareemo waa in daawada oo la joogteeyo keento in dareemaha lugaha ama faraha ay dhaawac gaarsiiso taasoo loo dareemo kabuubyo ahaan, xaaladaan oo loo yaqaano \\"Toxic Neuropathy\\", waa xaalad uusan qofka ku baraarugin marka hore.Dhibaatada kale ee keento daawada cillaanka \\"PPD\\" waxaa ka mid ah kansarrada qaar oo ay soo bandhigtay hay'adda daawooyinka mareykanka ee FDA, kuwaas oo kala ah, kansarka dhiigga, kansarka qanjirrada, kansarka maqaarka, kanasarka naasaha iyo kansarka kaadiheysta.Cilmibaaris lagu sameeyay xanuunka howlgabka kilyaha oo la arkay inuu ku badanayo dadka ka shaqeeyo saaluunnada iyo meelaha la isku qurxiyo ayaa waxaa la sheegay in lala xiriirnayo sababta ay kilyaha u beeleen daawadaan PPD oo ku badan waxyaabaha ay isticmaalaan.Halista kiimikadaan waa mid mar hore la ogaaday oo joogto looga digo, wadamo dhowr ah sida jarmalka, Sweden iyo faransiiska waa ka mamnuuc in lagu gado waxyaabo jirka lagu qurxiyo in lagu daro daawadaan.Jarmalka wuxuu mamnuucay sanadkii 1900-kii.Faransiisku wuxuu mamnuucay sanadkii 1909-kii.Sweden waxay mamnuucday sanadkii 1964-tii."},{"question":"විටමින් E ඌනතා ලක්ෂණ නම් කරන්න.","answer":"විටමින් E ඌනතා ලක්ෂණ පහත දැක්වේ.1)      පරිණත නොවූ දරු උපත්2)      රතු රුධිරාණු බිදී යාම වේගවත් වීම3)      සෛල විභාජනයේ දුර්වලතා4)      ප්‍රජනනය හා සම්බන්ධ ගැටලු"},{"question":"Nhiều người quan tâm đến bất động sản phát mãi bởi cho rằng giá rẻ hơn thị trường, nhưng thực tế đây chưa chắc là \\"món hời\\", theo chuyên gia.Tôi xem được nhiều thông tin về các ngân hàng phát mãi bất động sản như nhà đất, chung cư. Giá rao bán tôi thấy khá hấp dẫn vì thấp hơn so với thị trường. Nhưng do không có nhiều kinh nghiệm, tôi băn khoăn có nên mua những căn nhà được ngân hàng phát mãi không? Giao dịch tài sản này cần lưu ý gì?Mong chuyên gia và các độc giả cho tư vấn.","answer":"Bất động sản phát mãi được hiểu là tài sản thế chấp vay vốn của cá nhân, tổ chức nhưng không đủ năng lực trả nợ các khoản vay. Nếu chủ sở hữu không thanh toán nợ đúng hạn, ngân hàng sẽ tịch thu và thanh lý tài sản đảm bảo để thu hồi nợ.Nhiều người quan tâm đến bất động sản phát mãi của ngân hàng vì một số ưu điểm. Thứ nhất là giấy tờ pháp lý đã được thẩm định kỹ càng, sẵn sàng chuyển nhượng cho người mua, ví dụ như căn hộ phải có sổ hồng. Điều này sẽ giúp người mua hạn chế những rủi ro về pháp lý khi mua bất động sản. Thứ hai, ngân hàng thường cung cấp người mua các gói vay tài chính để thúc đẩy quá trình phát mãi tài sản.Một lý do quan trọng nữa đến từ tâm lý của nhiều người mua là giá bất động sản phát mãi rẻ hơn hơn thị trường. Tuy nhiên bạn cần lưu ý không phải trường hợp nào cũng có \\"giá hời\\". Lý do là nhiều bất động sản đã được định giá cao hơn thực tế khi ngân hàng duyệt khoản vay, đặc biệt trong giai đoạn thị trường phát triển cao trào.Ví dụ vào năm 2021, một căn nhà được ngân hàng định giá 10 tỷ đồng, khoản vay 70% là 7 tỷ đồng. Tuy nhiên hiện nay, khi thị trường đi xuống, giá sụt giảm còn 8 tỷ đồng, 70% giá trị căn nhà chỉ còn 5,6 tỷ đồng. Nếu bạn xuống tiền, giá trị căn nhà này vẫn được tính theo định giá năm 2021. Chưa kể, giá bất động sản phát mãi thường bao gồm cả dư nợ gốc cộng với lãi khoản vay và tiền phạt của ngân hàng. Bởi vậy, người mua nên thoát khỏi tâm lý đây là \\"món hời\\", có giá rẻ hơn thị trường.Bất động sản phát mãi cũng tiềm ẩn một số rủi ro. Việc mua nhà đất phát mãi liên quan đến ba bên gồm ngân hàng, chủ sở hữu và người mua. Nếu người mua ít kinh nghiệm trong mua bán bất động sản, quá trình hoàn tất giao dịch sẽ tốn nhiều thời gian hơn. Trong trường hợp chủ sở hữu chưa hoàn tất nghĩa vụ hay không hợp tác bàn giao, bạn sẽ phải chờ cơ quan có thẩm quyền tham gia cưỡng chế. Bạn còn phải chịu thêm một số khoản chi phí phát sinh như thuế chuyển nhượng hoặc các phí tồn đọng liên quan.Do đó, người mua bất động sản phát mãi của ngân hàng cần lưu ý một số vấn đề sau:Thứ nhất, bạn nên định giá lại bất động sản, đồng thời so sánh với mặt bằng thị trường hiện tại để xác định giá phát mãi của ngân hàng có thực sự hấp dẫn. Nếu không có nhiều kinh nghiệm, bạn nên thuê đơn vị tư vấn để có thể định giá tài sản chính xác.Thứ hai, người mua cần yêu cầu ngân hàng cung cấp thông tin và hồ sơ pháp lý của tài sản để nắm được lý do bị phát mãi, tránh trường hợp có tranh chấp với bên thứ ba hay bất động sản nằm trong diện quy hoạch.Thứ ba, bạn cần nằm rõ thủ tục định giá và quy trình phát mãi để tránh những rủi ro sau khi mua. Một lưu ý là khi mua thông qua đấu giá, người mua sẽ phải trả thêm một số khoản phí phát sinh. Việc thanh toán này cần phải thực hiện theo ba bên tại ngân hàng thay vì thanh toán trực tiếp cho chủ sở hữu cũ"},{"question":"मकालु क्षेत्रको कुन पदयात्रा गन्तव्यले संसारको पाँचौं-अग्लो हिमाल मकालुको दृश्यको साथ पुरानो उजाडस्थानको अनुभव प्रदान गर्दछ?","answer":"मकालु क्षेत्रको मकालु आधार शिविर पदयात्राले विश्वको पाँचौं-अग्लो हिमाल मकालुको मनमोहक दृश्यहरूको साथ एक पुरानो उजाडस्थानको अनुभव प्रदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"ජීවත්ව සිටින ලාබාලතම එක්සත් ජනපද හිටපු ජනාධිපතිවරයා කවුද, සහ 2023 ඔක්තෝබර් 12 වන විට ඔවුන්ගේ වර්තමාන වයස කීයද?","answer":"2023 ඔක්තෝම්බර් 12 වන විට, ජීවත්ව සිටින ලාබාලතම එක්සත් ජනපද හිටපු ජනාධිපති බරක් ඔබාමා වන අතර ඔහු වයස අවුරුදු 62 කි."},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:Nu def ko muy mbugal, mu nekk luy waar ñi teew ak ñay ñëwi ca seen ginnaaw te di waaraateb way-gëm ña.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Nu def ko mu'y mbugal, mu nekk lu'y waar ñi teew ak ña'y ñëwi ca séen ginnaaw te di waaraateb waygëm ña."},{"question":"Ọwọ ba Fulani mẹta nibi ti wọn ti n da awọn eeyan lọna niluu Tede","answer":"Ọwọ awọn ẹṣọ fijilante ti ba awọn afurasi ọdaran Fulani mẹta kan, Yakubu Mohammed, ẹni ogun ọdun, Saleh Magu, ọmọ ọdun mẹtadinlogun ati Ibrahim Legi, ẹni ọdun mẹtalelogun. Ọna to lọ lati ilu Tede si Ọjẹ-Owode, nijọba ibilẹ Atisbo, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, ni wọn ti mu wọn.Gẹgẹ ba a ṣe gbọ, wọn ni niṣe lawọn afurasi mẹtẹẹta yii n fibọn ati ada halẹ mọ awọn arinrin-ajo atawọn agbẹ to n gba ọna naa kọja lọ soko wọn, wọn si n ja wọn lole dukia wọn.L’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, tọwọ palaba wọn segi, itosi abule Ayefẹlẹ ni wọn lawọn janduku naa duro si, ti wọn si n ba iṣẹ laabi wọn lọ.Ọgbẹni Ademọla Ọlaworẹ, to jẹ ọga agba awọn fijilante agbegbe naa ṣalaye fakọroyin wa pe o ti to ọsẹ mẹta sẹyin tawọn ti gbọ oriṣiiriṣii iroyin buruku nipa iwa ọdaran tawọn amookunṣika ẹda naa n hu lagbegbe ọhun, ṣugbọn bawọn ṣe n dọdẹ wọn ni wọn sa kiri lati ibikan si omi-in.Ọlawọọre ni oju ọna kan to lọ si adugbo Ayefẹlẹ lawọn Fulani ọdaran yii fẹẹ fi ṣe ibuba wọn, wọn ti n mura lati kọ Gaa kan sibẹ kọwọ too tẹ wọn.O ni igba kẹta ree tawọn n gba adugbo naa kọja, tawọn n wa wọn kiri, laimọ pe ori igi ni wọn sa pamọ si.Lọjọ ti wọn mu wọn yii, Ọlawọọre ni awọn ko gba ọna ti gbogbo eeyan maa n gba, ki wọn ma baa fura, lojiji si lawọn yọ si wọn, bi wọn ṣe ri awọn ni wọn bẹrẹ si i yinbọn, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ibọn naa ko le jiṣẹ ti wọn ran an.Ẹyin naa ni wọn gba awọn ohun ija oloro ti wọn gbe dani, lara rẹ ni ibọn, ida oloju meji, ada, ati ọpọ oogun abẹnugọngọ. Wọn lawọn Fulani yii jẹwọ pe ipinlẹ Katsina lawọn ti wa, ati pe loootọ lawọn n da awọn eeyan lọna lagbegbe naa.Ọlawọre ni gbara tawọn ba ti pari iwadii lawọn yoo fa wọn le awọn ọlọpaa teṣan Tede lọwọ, awọn si nigbagbọ p’awọn ọlọpaa yoo fẹsẹ ofin to ọrọ naa bo ṣe yẹ.Ọlawọọre waa gba awọn araalu nimọran lati yẹra fun irin alẹ ati aajin lasiko yii, nitori awọn apamọlẹkun-jaye wọnyi."},{"question":"السؤال:  شنو هي السورة الملقبه بعروس القرآن؟","answer":"الإجابة: الرحمن"},{"question":"பூனையின் ஆயுட்காலம்?","answer":"12 வருடங்கள்."},{"question":" இந்தியாவின் பிரதமர் யார் ?","answer":"இந்தியப் பிரதமர் அல்லது இந்தியத் தலைமை அமைச்சர் என்பவர் இந்திய அரசின் செயலாக்கத் தலைவர் ஆவார். இவர் இந்தியக் குடியரசுத் தலைவரின் தலைமை ஆலோசகரும் மத்திய அமைச்சரவையின் தலைவரும் ஆவார். இந்தியாவில் பிரதமர் பதவி என்பது மிக உயர்ந்த, அதிக அதிகாரங்கள் உள்ள பதவியாகும். இந்திய பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மக்களவை உறுப்பினர்களால் இந்தியப் பிரதமர் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்படுவார். இந்தியாவின் முதல் பிரதமர் ஜவஹர்லால் நேரு ஆவார், தற்போதைய பிரதமராக நரேந்திர மோதி பதவியில் உள்ளார்.பிரதமர் பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மக்களவை அல்லது மாநிலங்களவையின் உறுப்பினராக இருத்தல் வேண்டும். இல்லையென்றால் ஆறு மாதத்திற்குள் மக்களவைமேலவையின் உறுப்பினராக தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட வேண்டும். ஒரு பிரதமரின் பதவிக்காலம் ஐந்து ஆண்டுகள் ஆகும்.பிரதமர், இந்தியக் குடியரசுத் தலைவரால் நியமிக்கப்படுகிறார். பாராளுமன்றத்தின் மக்களவையின் பெரும்பான்மை உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட கட்சியின் தலைவரை மட்டுமே குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ஆட்சி அமைக்க அழைப்பார். எந்தக் கட்சிக்கும் பெரும்பான்மை பலம் இல்லையென்றால் கூட்டணிக்கட்சித் தலைவரையோ அல்லது அதிக மக்களவை உறுப்பினர்களைக் கொண்ட ஒரு கட்சியின் தலைவரையோ அழைப்பார்."},{"question":"ලහත් තිඹයි, තිඹත් ලහයි යන ගැමි වහරේ නිධාන කතාව සහ තේරුම කුමක්ද?","answer":"හතර කෝරලයෙ අය තිඹ කියන්නේ සේරු 3 ට ලාහ කියන්නේ සේරු 4ට සේරුව කියන්නේ හුන්ඩු 4 ට"},{"question":"రాజా బహద్దూర్ వెంకట రామారెడ్డి స్థాపించిన విద్యావ్యవస్థలను వివరించండి?","answer":"వెంకట రామారెడ్డి అందరి మన్ననలను పొందిన వ్యక్తి. బహుభాషావేత్త. తన జీవితాన్ని -ప్రజాసేవకే అంకితం చేసిన వ్యక్తి. ఆయనకు విద్యపట్ల శ్రద్ధగలవారు. పలు విద్యాసంస్థలను స్థాపించి ప్రజాసేవ చేశారు.1. బాలికల ఉన్నత పాఠశాల :మొత్తం హైదరాబాదు రాష్ట్రంలో మన బాలికలకు మాతృభాషా బోధనకు ప్రభుత్వ ఉన్నత పాఠశాల లేకపోవటం దురదృష్టకరమని రెడ్డిగారు భావించారు. ఉన్నత పాఠశాలల్లో కూడా ఉర్దూ, ఆంగ్ల మాధ్యమ బోధన జరుగుతుంది. కావున హైదరాబాదులో ఒక మాతృభాషా పాఠశాలను బాలికల కోసం నిర్మించాలని తలచి స్త్రీ విద్యా ప్రోత్సాహకులు మాడపాటి హనుమంతరావుగారిని కలిసి బాలికల పాఠశాలను నిర్మించారు. ఇది బొంబాయిలో ‘కార్వే’ మహాశయులు స్థాపించిన మహిళావిద్యాపీఠంతో జత చేశారు. దీనికి అధ్యక్షులుగా రామారెడ్డి ఉన్నారు.2. పరోపకారిణీ బాలికా పాఠశాల :హైదరాబాద్ రామారెడ్డిగారు స్థాపించిన మరొక పాఠశాల పరోపకారిణీ బాలికా పాఠశాల. ఇది ప్రైమరీ తరగతి వరకు ఉన్నది. దీనికి అధ్యక్షులుగా రామారెడ్డి న్నారు.3. ఎక్సెల్ సియర్ మిడిల్ పాఠశాల:ఈ పాఠశాలను 1945లో స్థాపించారు. దీని పాలక వర్గ అధ్యక్షులు రామారెడ్డిగారే! దీనిలో తెలుగు బాలురకే ప్రవేశముంది. ఆంగ్ల, ఉర్దూ మాధ్యమాలు లేకపోవటంతో అంతగా విద్యార్థులు ఆసక్తి చూపలేదు.4. బాలికా పాఠశాల (గొల్లబిడ్కి) :హైదరాబాదు గొల్లఖిడ్కిలో ఒక ఆంధ్రబాలికా పాఠశాలను ప్రజాసేవకులు కొందరు స్థాపించారు. దీని బాధ్యతను కూడా రెడ్డిగారే స్వీకరించారు.5. పరోపకారిణీ బాలికా పాఠశాల :సికిందరాబాదు నగరంలో కీ॥శే॥ సీతమ్మగారు ఆ కాలంలో ఉండేవారు. ఆమె తన జీవితాన్ని ధారపోసి ఒక మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాలను స్థాపించారు. ఆ పాఠశాల అభివృద్ధికి రెడ్డిగారు సహాయ పడ్డారు.6. ఆంధ్రవిద్యాలయం :హైదరాబాదు నగరంలో తెలుగు పిల్లలకు మాతృభాష ద్వారా చదువు చెప్పుటకు ఒక్క మాధ్యమిక పాఠశాల కూడా లేదు. 1931లో దేవరకొండ సభలో ఈ విషయం ప్రస్తావనకు వచ్చింది. రాజాబహద్దూర్ వెంకట రామరెడ్డిగారు ఆ సభకు అధ్యక్షత వహించారు. ఎలాగైనా ఒక పాఠశాలను నిర్మించాలని తీర్మానం చేశారు. అది చివరకు సెప్టెంబరు1, 1944కు కానీ సానుకూలం కాలేదు. ఆ తరువాత అది 1947 నాటికి రెడ్డిగారి చలవతో ఉ న్నత పాఠశాలగా ఎదిగింది.ఇలా రాజాబహద్దూర్ రామారెడ్డిగారు విద్యపట్ల మిక్కిలి ఆసక్తిని కనపరచి, తెలుగు మాధ్యమంలో బాలికలు చదువు కోవటానికి పాఠశాలలను స్థాపించటానికి ప్రత్యక్షంగా పరోక్షంగా కారకులయ్యారు."},{"question":"Nêu nguyên nhân, diễn biến, kết quả của mỗi phát minh trong bài Những phát minh tình cờ và bất ngờ Ngữ văn lớp 6.","answer":"Nguyên nhân, diễn biến, kết quả của mỗi phát minh:- Đất nặn:+ Nguyên nhân: Người dân có xu hướng sử dụng ga dẫn đến loại bột đất sét đặc biệt có công dụng loại bỏ các vết đen do bồ hóng không còn được bán chạy, công ti có nguy cơ thua lỗ nghiêm trọng.+ Diễn biến: Vích-cơ nhớ lại bài học ngày xưa chị dạy về việc sử dụng những chất bột nhão để mô phỏng độ dẻo của đất sét.+ Kết quả: Năm 1957, ông biến thiết kế của mình thành một loại đồ chơi trẻ em với nhiều màu sắc, đem lại lợi nhuận cao hàng triệu đô la Mỹ.- Kem que:+ Nguyên nhân: Ép-pơ-xơn vô tình dùng một chiếc que trộn bột soda khô và nước lại với nhau trong một chiếc cốc để nghịch, sau đó, bỏ quên chúng.+ Diễn biến: Hôm sau, Ép-pơ-xơn phát hiện ra một “que kẹo băng” ở đó và khoe các bạn. Vì được làm từ soda nên khi nếm sẽ có hiện tượng nổ li ti.+ Kết quả: Năm 1923, Ép-pơ-xơn đã kí bằng sáng chế cho thiết kế của mình, đánh dấu ra đời kem que – sản phẩm bán chạy nhất mùa hè.- Lát khoai tây chiên+ Nguyên nhân: Crăm khi ấy đang cố phục vụ món khoai tây Pháp do một khách hàng đặt vào mùa hè.+ Diễn biến: Khách hàng liên tục trả món và yêu cầu phải thái lát mỏng hơn và giòn hơn. + Kết quả: Crăm đã mất bình tĩnh, cắt lát khoai mỏng hơn rồi chiên chúng sao cho khô cứng nhất có thể. Chúng trở nên phổ biến.- Giấy nhớ:+ Nguyên nhân: Xin-vơ tạo ra một chất dính tạm trong phòng thí nghiệm nhưng không biết sử dụng nó vào việc gì.+ Diễn biến: Chất dính có thể dính một vật có trọng lượng nhỏ, dính lên bề mặt mà không làm hư hại gì và rất bền, có thể dùng dán lại nhiều lần.+ Kết quả: Khi đồng nghiệp của ông đang bực tức vì không thế tìm cách gì dán một số tờ giấy lên cuốn sách của mình và từ đó ý tưởng ra đời."},{"question":"ਵਾਸ਼ਿੰਗਟਨ, 5 ਮਾਰਚਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਵਿਚ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੇ ਰਾਜਦੂਤ ਅਸਦ ਮਜੀਦ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਪੁਲਵਾਮਾ ਹਮਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਪਾਕਿ ਨੂੰ ਨਿਸ਼ਾਨੇ ’ਤੇ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਭਾਰਤ ‘ਖ਼ੁਦ ਹੀ ਅਦਾਲਤ, ਜੱਜ ਤੇ ਫਾਹੇ ਟੰਗਣ’ ਵਾਲਾ ਬਣ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਕਿ ‘ਸੰਗਠਿਤ ਪੱਧਰ ਉੱਤੇ’ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿਚ ਕੋਈ ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀ ਜਥੇਬੰਦੀ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਰਾਜਦੂਤ ਨੇ ਨਾਲ ਹੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਾਕਿ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਐੱਫ-16 ਜਹਾਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਮੰਗੀ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਇਲਮ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ। ਜ਼ਿਕਰਯੋਗ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਹਵਾਈ ਫ਼ੌਜ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਖ਼ਾਸ ਕਿਸਮ ਦੀ ਮਿਜ਼ਾਈਲ ਪਾਕਿ ਹਮਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸਬੂਤ ਵੱਜੋਂ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤੀ ਸੀ ਤੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਐੱਫ-16 ਵਿਚ ਹੀ ਵਰਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ। ਜਦਕਿ ਪਾਕਿ ਨੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਜਹਾਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਤੋਂ ਪੱਲਾ ਝਾੜਿਆ ਸੀ। ਅਮਰੀਕੀ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ ਵਿਭਾਗ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਨੇਮਾਂ ਦਾ ਉਲੰਘਣ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਐੱਫ-16 ਵਰਤਣ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਾਕਿ ਤੋਂ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਮੰਗ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਖ਼ਾਨ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵਿਚ ਵੜ ਕੇ ਹਵਾਈ ਹਮਲਿਆਂ ਰਾਹੀਂ 300 ਅਤਿਵਾਦੀ ਮਾਰਨ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਨੇ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਹੀ ਸਿਖ਼ਰਾਂ ’ਤੇ ਪੁੱਜੇ ਟਕਰਾਅ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਹਵਾ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਰਾਜਦੂਤ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਮੰਚ ਉੱਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿਚ ਵੀ ਹੁਣ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾਅਵਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਖਾਰਜ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ। ਅਮਰੀਕੀ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਚਲਾਏ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਥਿੰਕ ਟੈਂਕ ਯੂਐੱਸ ਇੰਸਟੀਚਿਊਟ ਆਫ਼ ਪੀਸ ਅੱਗੇ ਪੇਸ਼ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਾਇਲਟ ਨੂੰ ਰਿਲੀਜ਼ ਕੀਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਹੁਣ ਐਲਓਸੀ ’ਤੇ ਤਣਾਅਪੂਰਨ ਮਾਹੌਲ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਪਾਕਿ ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਇਮਰਾਨ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਸੱਦੇ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਦੁਹਰਾਇਆ।                                                     ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿਰੁੱਧ ਐਫ-16 ਜਹਾਜ਼ਾਂ ਦੀ ਵਰਤੋਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਦੂਤਾਵਾਸ ਨੂੰ ਕੀ ਪਤਾ ਹੈ?                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    ","answer":"ਦਿੱਤੀ ਗਈ ਖਬਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਜਦੂਤ ਨੂੰ ਅਮਰੀਕਾ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਮੰਗੀ ਗਈ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਜਾਣਕਾਰੀ ਬਾਰੇ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"පහත  නාම පදයට අදාළ ස්ත්‍රී ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද?නළුවා ","answer":"නිළිය "},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:విపిన బంధుర వృక్షవాటికఉపనిషన్మధు వొలికె నిచ్చటవిపుల తత్త్వము విస్తరించినవిమల తల మిదె తమ్ముడా !","answer":"తమ్ముడా ! ఈ దేశంలో దట్టమైన చెట్లతో కూడిన, విస్తారమైన అరణ్యాలు ఉన్నాయి. మధురమైన ఉపనిషత్తులు ఇక్కడే పుట్టాయి. ఇది వివరాలతో కూడిన తత్త్వబోధన విస్తరించిన పవిత్రభూమి.ఉపనిషత్తులు : వేదాల అంత్యభాగాలు. (వీటినల్ల బ్రహ్మజ్ఞానం కలుగుతుంది.)1) ఛాందోగ్యము,2) ఈశా వాస్యము,3) కఠోపనిషత్తు,4) కేనోపనిషత్తు మొ||వి."},{"question":"相撲で、体勢が崩れ、すでに立て直すことができない状態のことを何というでしょう？","answer":"死に体です。"},{"question":"Vraag: Wie maakte het schilderij Het Joodse Bruidje? A. Rembrandt, B. Vermeer, C. Van Gogh. D. Rubens","answer":"Antwoord: A. Rembrandt"},{"question":"ஒற்றை ஒலிம்பிக்கில் அதிக ஒலிம்பிக் பதக்கம் வென்ற நாடு எது?","answer":"விடை: அமெரிக்கா"},{"question":"Göz tansiyonu ne gibi belirtiler olur?","answer":"Göz tansiyonu nasıl anlaşılır? Başlangıçta göz tansiyonu belirti vermez ancak rutin muayenede göz tansiyonu olup olmadığı anlaşılır. İlerleyen durumlarda göz ağrısı, göz kızarıklığı, ani görme sorunları, renkli halkalar görmek, bazı durumlarda mide bulantısı ve istifra ile de belirti verebilir."},{"question":"පහත නාම පදයට අදාළ පුරුෂ ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද? දුව ","answer":"පුතා"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì?  Nguồn: https://arttimes.vn/video/to-hop-vu-khi-34ho-bay34-chuyen-diet-phi-co-tam-thap-cua-han-quoc-c13a...Nguồn: https://arttimes.vn/video/to-hop-vu-khi-34ho-bay34-chuyen-diet-phi-co-tam-thap-cua-han-quoc-c13a8434.html ","answer":"Tổ hợp vũ khí \\"hổ bay\\" chuyên diệt phi cơ tầm thấp của Hàn Quốc"},{"question":"અવિનાશ વ્યાસ ની \\"એક પાટણ શહેરની\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"એક પાટણ શહેરની નાર પદમણી,આંખ નચાવતી ડાબી ને જમણી,સૂરત જાણે ચંદા પૂનમની, બીચ બજારે જાય..ભાતીગળ ચૂંદલડી લહેરાય,ઝાંઝરીયું ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક થાય..એક વાગડ દેશનો બંકો જુવાનીયો,રંગ જાણે એનો લાલ ફાગણીયો,કંઠે ગરજતો જાણે શ્રાવણિયો, સાવજડો વર્તાય,નજર્યુંમાં આવી એવો નજરાય,દલડું ધબક ધબક ધબક ધબક ધબક ધબક થાય..રંગમાં નખરો, ઢંગમાં નખરો,રૂપ એવું અંગ અંગમાં નખરો;પાતળી કેડને ભાર જોબનનો જીરવ્યો ના જીરવાય,ભાતીગળ ચૂંદલડી લહેરાય,ઝાંઝરીયું ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક ઝમક થાય..બંકડી મૂછો અરે બંકડી પાઘડી,રંગ કસુંબલ ભરી આંખલડી,હાલક ડોલક ડુંગરે ચડે પડ છો ના પરખાય,નજર્યુંમાં આવી એવો નજરાય,દલડું ધબક ધબક ધબક ધબક ધબક ધબક થાય.."},{"question":" Inona no vanim-potoana manaraka ny fahavaratra araka ny filaharan’ny fizaran-taona?","answer":" Ny fararano no vanim-potoana manaraka ny fahavaratra araka ny filaharan'ny fizaran-taona."},{"question":"Gịnị bụ okpukpe ọdịnala ndị Igbo?","answer":"Okpukpe ọdịnala nke ndị Igbo bụ nke a na-akpọ Odinani, nke gụnyere ikwere chi dị iche iche na mmụọ ndị nna ochie."},{"question":"बहुतेक कोळसा साठा भारतात कुठे आढळून येतो?(A) ओडिशा(B) छत्तीसगड(C) झारखंड(D) पं. बंगाल=> ","answer":"(C) झारखंड"},{"question":" சமீபத்தில் இஸ்ரோ பிஎஸ்எல்வி-சி29 மூலம் ஆறு செயற்கைக் கோள்களை விண்ணில் செலுத்திய நாடு?","answer":"இந்தியாவின் துருவ செயற்கைக்கோள் ஏவுதல் வாகனம், அதன் முப்பத்தி இரண்டாவது விமானத்தில் (பிஎஸ்எல்வி-சி29), பூமத்திய ரேகைக்கு 15 டிகிரி சாய்ந்த 550 கிமீ வட்ட சுற்றுப்பாதையில் சிங்கப்பூரின் ஆறு செயற்கைக்கோள்களை ஏவியது.  பிஎஸ்எல்வி-சி29 ஸ்ரீஹரிகோட்டாவில் உள்ள சதீஷ் தவான் விண்வெளி மையத்தில் (எஸ்டிஎஸ்சி) முதல் ஏவுதளத்தில் இருந்து ஏவப்பட்டது. இது 'கோர்-அலோன்' கட்டமைப்பில் (திடமான ஸ்ட்ராப்-ஆன் மோட்டார்களைப் பயன்படுத்தாமல்) பிஎஸ்எல்வியின் பதினொன்றாவது விமானமாகும்."},{"question":"متى أسس ارماني علامته التجارية الخاصة ” جورجو ارماني ”؟","answer":"أسس جورجو أرماني علامته التجارية الخاصة به في عام 1975."},{"question":"اكمل الفقرة التالية:وهذا أمر طبيعي؛ فالسماء -التي تحيط بالأرض نهارًا بسطوع شمسها وليلا بلمعان نجومها- تجعل الإنسان يتساءل عن","answer":"ماهيتها وأسرارها، فكيف أُغطِش ليلُها وأُخرِج ضُحاها، وكيف يبزغ قمرها ويتحرك فينتقل من طور إلى آخر منذ لحظة ميلاده، مرورا بكونه بدرًا يملأ السماء نورًا في ظُلمة الليالي، وانتهاءً بخفوت نوره فيتبدّد اضمحلالا ثم يتجدّد استهلالا.. وهكذا دواليْكَ!!"},{"question":"සිංහල අක්ෂර වින්‍යාසය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන ජාතිය වන සිංහල ජනයාගේ මව් බස සිංහල වෙයි. අද වන විට ණඞ 20 කට අධික සිංහල සහ මිලියනඤ 3කට අධික සිංහල නොවන ජනගහනයක් සිංහල භාෂාව භාවිත කරති. සිංහල‍ ඉන්දු-යුරෝපීය භාෂාවල උප ගණයක් වන ඉන්දු-ආර්ය භාෂා ගණයට අයිති වන අතර මාල දිවයින භාවිත කරන දිවෙහි භාෂාව සිංහල බසේ ළඟම සහෝදරිය වෙයි. ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ නිල භාෂාවයි .ප්‍රාග් ඓතිහාසික යුගයේ පටන් පැවති හෙළබස ඈත අතීතයේ ඉන්දියානු භාෂා හා යටත් විජිත සමයේ බටහිර භාෂා සමග සම්මිශ්‍රණයෙන් වත්මන් සිංහල භාෂාව බිහිවී ඇත. සිංහල භාෂාවේ ස්වර 18 කි. ඉන්‍දියානු භාෂා සමග සසඳන විට සිංහල අක්‍ෂර වින්‍යාසයේ විශේෂ ලක්‍ෂණ කිහිපයක් දැකිය හැක. ඒවා නම් 'ඇ', 'ඈ' ස්වර යෙදීම, ශුද්ධ සිංහල භාෂාව සඳහා මහාප්‍රාණ අකුරු අවශ්‍ය නොවීම ආදී ලෙස දැකිය හැක. දකුණු ඉන්දියානු භාෂා වල මෙන් න, ණ, ල, ළ යන අක්‍ෂර භාවිතය සිංහල බසෙහිද ඇත. මෙම අක්‍ෂර භාවිතය නිසා සමහර වචන වල අරුත වෙනස් විය හැක."},{"question":"ulimi wa mpunga mu dziko la Malawi","answer":"Dziko la Malawi lili ndi malo okwana mahekitala 600,000 omwe angagwiritsidwe ntchito polima mpunga. Derali likadagwiritsidwa ntchito mokwanira, dziko likhoza kutulutsa matani oposa 2,000,000 a mpunga pachaka. Pakali pano, kuchuluka kwa mpunga ndi matani 150,000 pachaka, zomwe zikutanthauza kuti 7.5 peresenti yokha ya zomwe zingathe kupanga."},{"question":"සඳ යන වචනයෙන් ආරම්භ වන සිංහල සින්දු පහක් නම් කරන්න.","answer":"සඳ යන වචනයෙන් ආරම්භ වන සිංහල සින්දු පහක් පහත පරිදි දැක්විය හැකි ය.- සඳ තරු නිහඬයි - පණ්ඩිත් අමරදේව- සඳ රේණු ගලන - තීක්ෂණ අනුරාධ- සඳ ලතා පායනා - කීර්ති පැස්කුවෙල්- සඳ ලේඛා - රූකාන්ත ගුණතිලක හා චන්ද්‍රලේඛා පෙරේරා- සඳවතියේ - රිද්ම වීරවර්ධන "},{"question":"Markasta waxeynu iska jecelnahay?","answer":"Markasta waxaynu iska jecelnahay innaynu helno wax kasta oo aynnu u niyoono, weliba si deg deg ah. Laakiin taa baddelkeeda waxa jira qorshayaal uu il Ilaahay innoo sameeyey, kuwaas oo kasii wanaagsan kana sii qiimo badan adiga kuwaaga yar yar ee ku qancin kara. Sidaa aawadeed haddii qorshe aad niyad iyo dadaal badan gelisay kuu suurto geli waayo, naftaada haku cannaanan innay tahay mida ugu nasiibka xun adduunka, ee waxaad ogaataa innuu soo socdo qorshihii Eebbe oo ka qiimo badan midkaas aad weyday insha allah. Noloshu mar kasta oo ay innagu adkaato waxaynu ku mashquulnaa dhibaatada iyo culayskeeda, laakiin taa baddelkeeda haddii aynnu ku mashquuli lahayn xal u helida dhibaatada ina haysata, waxa iman lahayd innaanay dhibaatadaasi innagaga badateen muddada aynnu xalka helayno uun. Sidaa aawadeed illaahay la kaasho dhibaatadaada oo isaga bari, adiguna baadi-goob u gal innaad xal u hesho dhibaatada ku haysata. Ogow xalka ugu wanaagsani waa ka Rabbi kula rabo, ee maaha midkaad adigu rabto."},{"question":"Manana teny mikorontana ianao: \\"kasitra\\" Alamino io teny io. ","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"sitraka\\". "},{"question":"inona avy no karazana fifamangiana?","answer":"ireto avy no karazana fifamangiana: ny fifamangiana amin'ny fifaliana, ny fifamangiana amin'ny fahoriana, ny fifamangiana amin'ny fiainana andavanandro"},{"question":"Inoa avy ireo sakafo tsara hoanin'ny mpiasa birao ?","answer":"Ny vitamine A no anisan’ny sakafo atao loha laharana ho an’ireo mpiasa birao mampiasa solosaina. Izany dia mba hiarovana ny fahasalaman’ny maso. Efa voaporofo ara-tsiansa tokoa fa ny fihinanana sakafo be vitamine A dia mampatanjaka ny maso ka mahatonga azy tsy ho mora simban’ny solosaina. Anisan’ireo sakafo ahitana vitamina A ny karaoty, voankazo sy legioma miloko mavo, ny atin-kena, ny voatabia… Mba hisorohana ny aretin-damosina kosa dia ilaina ny mihinana sakafo manankarena antioxydant sy ny manankarena omega 3, toy ny tongolo gasy, ny legioma, ny tamenak’atody, ny trondro matavy…"},{"question":"為什麼在睡覺時會做夢","answer":"　　　　夜深了，人們都進入甜蜜的夢鄉，有的在夢中露出微笑，有的在夢中咿咿呀呀低語。人為什麼在睡覺時會做夢呢？這要問我們每個人的大腦了。我們每個人的大腦里有著許許多多的腦細胞，這些腦細胞有的管我們說話，有的管我們睡覺，有的管我們走路等等，我們不管做什麼事都要經過大腦。晚上睡覺時，有的腦細胞和我們人一樣也休息了，可是，有的腦細胞卻沒有休息，所以，我們在白天想的事或看到的事就會在睡覺時重現在腦中，這就是夢。　　俗話說“夢是心中想”，就是這么回事。做夢是因為有的腦細胞沒有休息的緣故。"},{"question":"Ọkan ninu awọn tina jo l’Abẹokuta lọjọ Iṣẹgun ti ku o","answer":"Ọsibitu ‘Federal Medical Center’(FMC), l’Abẹokuta, ti fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ọkan ninu awọn tina jo nibi ijamba to ṣẹlẹ ni Kutọ l’Abẹokuta, lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii ti dagbere faye.Agbẹnusọ ọsibitu yii, Ọgbẹni Ṣẹgun Orisajo, lo sọ eyi di mimọ ninu atẹjade to fi sita laaarọ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọjọ kọkanlelogun, oṣu kin-in-ni, ọdun 2021 yii.O ṣalaye pe ọkunrin ni ẹni ọdun mejilelogoji to doloogbe naa. Orisajo ṣalaye pe ina jo ọkunrin naa pupọ, ida mẹrindinlọgọrun-un (96%) lo pe apa ibi ti ina ti jo o.O tẹsiwaju pe nigba ti wọn gbe e de pẹlu awọn meji mi-in ti ina yii jo, awọn n fa omi ti oogun wa ninu rẹ si wọn lara gẹgẹ bi ọna itọju kan ni. Nigba ti ọkunrin naa ni iṣoro ati tọ, awọn bẹrẹ eto lati ṣe itọju ti wọn n pe ni ‘Dialisis’ fun un, ṣugbọn aarọ Ọjọbọ yii lo ku ki wọn too ṣeto itọju naa fun un rara.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, ọjọ Iṣẹgun, ọjọ kọkandinlogun, oṣu kin-in-ni yii, ni ina sọ lagbegbe banki GTB, ni Kutọ, l’Abẹokuta, lasiko ti tanka epo kan padanu ijanu ẹ nigba to fẹẹ sọkalẹ lori afara Kutọ.Eeyan mẹta lo ku loju-ẹsẹ nibẹ, mọto ati ọkada jona, awọn mi-in si fara pa, wọn gbe wọn lọ si FMC, ọkan ninu awọn to fara pa lo dagbere faye yii."},{"question":"E okuldan nakil verilir mi?","answer":"Kesin kayıt işleminden önce aday kaydı iptal edilebilir. Aday öğrenciler daha sonra kesin kayıt yapılmalıdır. Kesin kayıt işleminden sonra öğrenci kaydı silinemez, başka okula nakil verilebilir."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Faedah-Faedah Program Motivasi kepada Diri Pelajar.","answer":"Mutakhir ini, sama ada kita sedar atau tidak lantaran terlalu dihidangkan dengan kerancakan pembangunan negara yang semakin gah di persada dunia. Namun disebalik itu, kita acapkali tersentak oleh pelbagai permasalahan sosial yang dicetuskan oleh rakyat kita sendiri. Kes-kes seperti pergaulan bebas, lumba haram dan sebagainya telah memberikan imej buruk kepada masyarakat kita kerana pelakunya terdiri daripada generasi muda yang merupakan pelajar-pelajar di sekolah. Pelbagai punca dan faktor permasalahan ini berlaku namun pihak sekolah lazimnya menganjurkan program motivasi kepada pelajar di sekolah bagi memupuk sikap madani dalam diri mereka. Penganjuran program ini memakan perbelanjaan wang yang banyak dan mengambil masa dan tenaga daripada para guru bagi memastikan anak-anak murid mereka mendapat manfaat daripada penyertaan mereka. Persoalan yang timbul adalah apakah faedah-faedah program motivasi kepada diri pelajar?Faedah yang paling mustahak dalam penganjuran program atau kem motivasi adalah ia membuka mata dan minda pelajar tentang kepentingan motivasi diri. Mungkin ibu dan bapa atau ahli keluarga di rumah terlepas pandang akan perkara ini tetapi pihak sekolah yang merupakan institusi pendidikan perdana seharusnya mendidik tentang pentingnya motivasi diri. Hal ini demikian kerana ia bukan sahaja penting semasa pelajar di sekolah tetapi ia adalah santapan rohani untuk sepanjang kehidupan kita. Kebanyakan di antara pelajar yang tidak mempunyai pencapaian yang baik dalam bidang akademik mahupun kokurikulum didapati kurang mendapat motivasi diri. Sekiranya mereka didedahkan dan sedar betapa mustahak untuk mempunyai motivasi diri yang utuh dalam menempuhi apa jua perkara pasti masyarakat yang inteligensia dan cakna dapat dilahirkan. Pelajar masa kini seharusnya sudah mengetahui minat dan masa hadapan yang diinginkan agar ibu bapa dapat membantu dalam merancang perjalanan yang menepati kehendak dan kemampuan pelajar. Intihannya, jika pelajar mempunyai kemahuan dan disertakan dengan motivasi, anda pasti dapat mencapai cita-cita tersebut walau apa jua rintangan yang datang. Persis peribahasa Melayu, belakang parang pun kalau diasah nescaya tajam.Faedah lain yang akan diperoleh pelajar apabila menyertai program motivasi adalah membentuk disiplin diri. Pelajar akan didedahkan tips-tips atau cara untuk belajar dengan lebih mudah oleh perunding atau pakar motivasi yang terlatih. Perkongsian ini adalah kritikal kerana pelajar tidak tahu-menahu cara pembelajaran yang efektif kerana latar belakang dan kemampuan mereka adalah berbeza. Maka, fasilitator yang bertanggungjawab dalam program motivasi pelajar seharusnya memberikan solusi atau pendekatan kepada pelajar untuk menelaah atau mengulang kaji pelajaran dengan lebih baik. Ibarat jauhari mengenal manikam. Sebagai contoh, teknik penulisan nota ringkas, penggunaan kad-kad untuk menguatkan hafalan dan cara mengenal pasti corak soalan yang bakal dikeluarkan dalam peperiksaan peringkat sekolah mahupun awam. Kesannya, pelajar akan bertambah rajin dan tercelik hati bahawa setiap di antara mereka mampu mencapai kejayaan dari segi akademik ataupun aktiviti di luar bilik darjah. Berbekalkan motivasi yang kuat, pelajar akan menjadi seorang yang tidak mengenal erti putus asa bak kata pepatah Melayu, alah bisa tegal biasa.Pada masa yang sama, semangat kepimpinan dapat dipupuk dalam kalangan pelajar jika mereka menyertai program motivasi diri. Nilai kepimpinan diri seharusnya dimiliki oleh setiap individu menjelang kedewasaan kerana semakin kita membesar, semakin banyak tanggungjawab dan amanah yang akan dipikul dan perlu dilunaskan dengan baik. Dengan adanya kepimpinan diri yang tinggi pelajar akan mengutamakan perkara yang mustahak berbanding perkara remeh dan yang tidak mendatangkan manfaat kepada diri mereka. Selain itu, penyertaan dalam kem-kem motivasi akan mendedahkan diri pelajar untuk menjadi seorang ketua. Hal ini kerana peserta akan dibahagikan kepada kumpulan-kumpulan kecil secara rawak dan peluang untuk mengetuai kumpulan masing-masing wajar diambil supaya pelajar tahu bagaimana untuk menjadi seorang pemimpin. Secara tidak langsung, pelajar akan menjadi seorang yang lebih baik berbanding ahli kumpulan masing-masing supaya menjadi contoh tauladan kepadda semua. Izharnya, penyertaan pelajar dalam kem motivasi dapat mencungkil potensi serta bakat pelajar dalam kepimpinan kerana manfaatnya kelak adalah berbaloi. Ibarat peribahasa Melayu, kalau tidak dipecahkan ruyung, manakan dapat sagunya.Di samping itu, pelajar juga dapat memperbaiki kemahiran komunikasi apabila menyertai program motivasi anjuran sekolah mahupun swasta. Tahukah anda bahawa kemahiran komunikasi adalah sangat penting khususnya apabila pelajar akan memasuki alam pekerjaan. Umum sedia maklum, manusia mempunyai pelbagai ragam dan sekiranya kita ingin menjadi seorang yang professional kita harus menguasai kemahiran komunikasi yang baik. Selalunya program motivasi akan menjalankan aktiviti-aktiviti yang memerlukan penglibatan aktif daripada semua peserta. Maka, pelajar perlu meningkatkan keyakinan diri untuk menyumbang tenaga dan idea bagi menjayakan kumpulan dalam aktiviti yang dijalankan. Setelah meningkatkan tahap keyakinan, pelajar juga akan didedahkan untuk menyampaikan persembahan atau bercakap dihadapan khalayak ramai. Dengan bimbingan dan dorongan daripada fasilitator para pelajar pasti dapat memecahakn tembok yang sebelum ini menjadi penghalang kepada mereka dan tampil dengan sifat dan sikap yang lebih positif. Natijahnya, penyertaan rogram motivasi yang menjalankan pelbagai aktiviti dapat memperbaiki kemahiran komunikasi dalam kalangan pelajar kerana yang elok itu budi, yang indah itu bahasa.Sebagai konklusi, penganjuran program atau kem motivasi adalah medan terbaik untuk pelajar membentuk ketrampilan diri yang lebih unggul dan cemerlang. Pelajar seharusnya bersikap terbuka dan gemar untuk menyertai inisiatif-inisiatif yang direncana oleh pihak sekolah dalam membantu pelajar menjadi seorang manusia yang lebih baik. Guru-guru, ibu dan bapa serta perunding motivasi pula seharusnya sentiasa menggunakan pendekatan yang lebih menarik dan sesuai dengan persekitaran pelajar dalam menganjurkan program motivasi supaya dapat menarik minat mereka. Persis kata peribahasa, melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Sesungguhnya jika usaha ini diperkasa dan dilaksana dengan efisien, generasi muda kita akan bebas dari dibelenggu masalah sosial serta melonjak kemampuan masyarakat tempatan untuk menjadi komuniti madani. Semoga iltizam dalam membawa diri, masyarakat dan juga negara kita untuk berdiri sama tinggi dan duduk sama rendah dengan negara lain dapat dihasilkan dan memebri manfaat kepada kesejahteraan hidup rakyat sejagat."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bawa nasib'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud menjauhkan diri daripada kaum keluarga dan sahabat untuk mencari kehidupan sendiri."},{"question":"l, m бул натуралдык сандар:l жуп m так сандары үчүн l*m=36 болсо, l+m канча болушу мүмкүн ?","answer":"l+m = 13"},{"question":" على أي بحر كاينة مدينة بيروت ؟","answer":"  البحرالأبيض المتوسط"},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?ආකර්ෂණය ","answer":"විකර්ෂණය"},{"question":"Бул жомоктун уландысын жазып берчи: Анда кайырчы кан: — \\"Мен койдун жүрөгүн гана жечү элем. Бир кой сойсоң, бир койдун жүрөгүнө мен тойбойм, этин жебейм\\",- дейт.","answer":"Бул жомоктун уландысы мындай болушу мүмкүн: Анда жигит, эшикке жүгүрүп чыгып, энесине: — \\"Эне, кайырчы жүрөк гана жейм дейт. Бир койдун жүрөгүнө тойбойм дейт. Кайырчыга беш коюбузду тең союп, жүрөгүн берели, кайырчы бечара тойсун, этин өзүбүз жеп, же сатарбыз\\",-  дегенде энеси макул болот."},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:થાકવાનું ન મારે નામ, રાત દિવસ હું ચાલતી રહેતી જ્યારે પૂછો ત્યારે સમય બતાવતી, આગળ વધવાનો સંદેશો હું જાતી.","answer":"ઘડિયાળ"},{"question":"भारतीय मुद्रेचे नाव “रूपया” सर्वात पहिले कोणत्या शासकाने ठेवले ?","answer":"भारतीय मुद्रेचे नाव “रूपया” सर्वात पहिले शेरशहा सुरी शासकाने ठेवले."},{"question":"ما هو مقياس الإشعاع. بحثت عن السؤال ووجدت هذا النص:هو جهاز يستخدم لقياس شدة الإشعاع الكهرومغناطيسي مثل الضوء. هناك مكاشيف مختلفة حسب المجال الكهرومغناطيسي مثل مجال الأشعة تحت الحمراء التي تقيس شدة الإشعاع في ذلك المجال؛ كما توجد أيضاً مكاشيف تقيس شدة الإشعاع في مجال الأشعة فوق البنفسجية وفي مجال الموجات الميكروية. هل تستطيع استخراج جواب السؤال من النص؟ اذكر الإجابة","answer":"جهاز يستخدم لقياس شدة الإشعاع الكهرومغناطيسي مثل الضوء."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo dingana tena ilaina amin'ny fametrahana ny demokrasia marin-toerana?","answer":"Anisan’ny dingana tena ilaina amin’ny fametrahana ny demokrasia marin-toerana : ny fametrahana ny lalàm-panorenana mifanaraka amin'ny firenena iray, ny fifidianana mangarahara , ny fitsarana amin'ny rariny ary ny fiarovana ny zo fototra."},{"question":"Apakah gasing? ","answer":"Gasing merupakan sejenis permainan yang boleh berputar pada paksinya, sambil mengimbang pada satu titik. Gasing merupakan permainan tradisional orang-orang Melayu sejak dahulu lagi. Biasanya dimainkan selepas musim menuai. Permainan gasing dipertandingkan antara kampung. Pemenang dikira berdasarkan tempoh masa gasing mampu berputar.Istilah \\"gasing\\" gunaan masyarakat Semenanjung Melayu, Sumatera dan Kepulauan Riau turunan kata akar Proto-Austronesia *gasiŋ. "},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianao manao hoe : ATROVAOmeo ary teny marina .","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"avotra \\" ."},{"question":"Daga cikin waɗannan bukukuwa a wanne ne ake ɗauri?A) kalankuwaB) buɗar dawaC) Sallar ganiD) Sallar idi","answer":"A) kalankuwa"},{"question":"Hiện tại em đang bị cận loạn khá nặng, cụ thể là mắt trái cận 11 diop và loạn 1.25 diop, mắt phải cận 8 và loạn 1, độ dày giác mạc 500 Mm. Trước đây em có đi khám và được bác sĩ tư vấn là không thể mổ được bằng phương pháp lasik do cận loạn nặng. Vậy cho em hỏi liệu mắt em cận nặng như vậy có thể mổ bằng phương pháp smile được không?","answer":"Với mắt bên trái, bạn có thể phẫu thuật được bằng phương pháp Smile. Còn với mắt phải, phương pháp Smile cũng có thể thực hiện được nhưng sau phẫu thuật, sẽ tồn dư hơn 1 độ cận. Vì thế Femto-Lasik sẽ là lựa chọn tối ưu cho mắt phải của bạn. Tuy nhiên bạn nên đến bệnh viện để được bác sĩ phẫu thuật kiểm tra lại chính xác tình trạng mắt, để có tư vấn phù hợp nhất."},{"question":"Tsumo inotevera inorevei?Bofu kuti huya tirwe hunge rakatsika pfuti.","answer":"Ukawona munhu achitanga  kudenha nezvakawoma anenge aine zvaakatemba."},{"question":"මේවර කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණයක් දෙන්න. ","answer":"මේවර කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණයක් පහත දී ඇත.\\"මුං වතු කන්දේ මුං නෙලනා දා  වල ගියෙදෝ මගෙ මේවරයානෑනෝ නුඹ පල් නුඹෙ දරුවන් පල්  මා දුටුවේ නැත මේ වරයා\\""},{"question":"Maputo moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Maputo moy péeyu réwum Mozambique"},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਆਪੁਨੀ ਭਗਤਿ ਨਿਬਾਹਿ ॥ਠਾਕੁਰ ਆਇਓ ਆਹਿ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਪਦਾਰਥੁ ਹੋਇ ਸਕਾਰਥੁ ਹਿਰਦੈ ਚਰਨ ਬਸਾਹਿ ॥੧॥ਏਹ ਮੁਕਤਾ ਏਹ ਜੁਗਤਾ ਰਾਖਹੁ ਸੰਤ ਸੰਗਾਹਿ ॥੨॥ਨਾਮੁ ਧਿਆਵਉ ਸਹਜਿ ਸਮਾਵਉ ਨਾਨਕ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਨ ਗਾਹਿ ॥੩॥੬॥੧੪੬॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 407 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਾਲਕ! ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂਘ ਕਰ ਕੇ (ਤੇਰੀ ਸਰਨ) ਆਇਆ ਹਾਂ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀ ਭਗਤੀ ਸਦਾ ਦੇਈ ਰੱਖ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਾਲਕ! ਆਪਣੇ ਚਰਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਹਿਰਦੇ ਵਿਚ ਵਸਾਈ ਰੱਖ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣਾ ਕੀਮਤੀ ਨਾਮ ਦੇਈ ਰੱਖ, ਤਾਕਿ ਮੇਰਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਸਫਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਮਾਲਕ! ਮੈਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੰਤਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਖੀ ਰੱਖ, ਇਹੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਮੁਕਤੀ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਇਹੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਾਸਤੇ ਜੀਵਨ-ਚੱਜ ਹੈ ।੨।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! (ਆਖ—) ਹੇ ਹਰੀ! (ਮੇਹਰ ਕਰ) ਤੇਰੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਚੁੱਭੀ ਲਾ ਕੇ ਮੈਂ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਸਿਮਰਦਾ ਰਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਰਹਾਂ ।੩।੬।੧੪੬।\\""},{"question":"「とりあえず」と「いまのところ」は同じですか。","answer":"例えば、「飲み物は足りていますか」という質問に対して「とりあえず足りています」「今のところ足りています」確かにどちらでも同じような意味になります。どちらも使える場合と、どちらかしか使えない場合があります。「何か質問がありますか」に対して「とりあえず大丈夫です」でも「今のところ大丈夫です」でもいいでしょう。しかし、「とりあえず」はもともと「とるものもとりあえず」、つまり急いでいるニュアンスがあります。ですから「田舎の父が倒れたという知らせがあって、詳細はわからないがとりあえず東京駅に向かった」というとき、「いまのところ」はおかしいです。"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இன்றைய போராட்டமே சாதியைக் காப்பாற்றுவது என்பதும், சாதியை ஒழிப்பது என்பதும்தான்."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Erwin Rommel. ","answer":"Bhí Erwin Johannes Eugen Rommel (rugadh 15 Samhain 1891 agus d'éag 14 Deireadh Fómhair 1944) ina cheannasaí ar an arm Gearmánach i rith an Dara Cogadh Domhanda.Thóg sé páirt in san Chéad Chogadh Domhanda. "},{"question":"كمل الفقرة:وأما عن العلاقات مع دول منظمة التعاون الإسلامي، فقال بولات إن حجم الصادرات التركية ارتفع من 4.7 مليارات دولار عام 2002 إلى 65 مليارا العام الماضي.","answer":"وأكد وزير التجارة أن تركيا وضعت إستراتيجية جديدة لزيادة حجم التجارة بما يتماشى مع تكثيف العلاقات الثنائية مع العالم الإسلامي، بما في ذلك دول الخليج."},{"question":"Jawab teka teki yang lawak ini: Orang beli benda ini untuk makan, tetapi benda ini tidak dimakan.","answer":"Jawapan: Pinggan dan sudu."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kuih beko nyor yang merupakan kuih-muih tradisional Melayu? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 2 cawan kelapa parut, 1 cawan tepung pulut, 2 sudu makan gula (boleh tambah mengikut kemanisan)1 cubit garam, Air untuk menguliCara-cara:1. Gaul semua bahan hingga sebati. Pastikan adunan tidak terlalu pekat atau cair.2. Masukkan ke dalam bekas.3. Bakar selama 30 minit menggunakan api atas bawah pada suhu 180°C.4. Sedia untuk dihidang."},{"question":"টাইম ট্রাভেলের সাথে সম্পর্কিত টুইন প্যারাডক্সের বর্ণনা দাও।","answer":"কাল দীর্ঘায়নের একটি মজার ফলাফল বা পরিণতি হলো টুইন প্যারাডক্স বা যমজ কূটাভাস। ২০ বছর বয়সী দুই যমজ ভাই সাদিক ও ইকবালকে নিয়ে একটি নিয়ন্ত্রিত পরীক্ষণ বিবেচনা করা যাক। সাদিক ভ্রমণবিলাসী সে পৃথিবী থেকে ৩০ আলোক বর্ষ দূরে একটি গ্রহে যেতে পৃথিবী থেকে রওনা হলো। তার মহাশূন্য যান প্রায় আলোর সমান দ্রুতিতে যেতে সক্ষম। গ্রহে পৌছার পর সাদিকের মন বাড়ির জন্য আনচান করতে লাগল। তাই সে একই দ্রুতিতে (আলোর কাছাকাছি দ্রুতিতে) পৃথিবীতে ফিরে এলো । পৃথিবীতে ফিরে সে দেখে অবাক হলো যে, পৃথিবীর অনেক কিছুই পরিবর্তিত হয়ে গেছে। সাদিকের যমজ ভাই ইকবালের বয়স প্রায় ৮০ বছর। আর সাদিকের বয়স তার চেয়ে কম হয়েছে প্রায় ১০ বছর। স্বাভাবিকভাবেই প্রশ্ন জাগতে পারে কোন যমজ ভাই (সাদিক না ইকবাল) একে অপরের তুলনায় আলোর কাছাকাছি দ্রুতিতে ভ্রমণ করেছে, সুতরাং কার বয়স বাড়েনি। এখানেই রয়েছে কূটাভাস। ইকবালের প্রসঙ্গ কাঠামোর সাপেক্ষে ইকবাল নিশ্চল কিন্তু সাদিক অত্যন্ত বেশি বেগ নিয়ে ভ্রমণ করেছে। সাদিকের মতে, যদিও ইকবাল পৃথিবীতে সাদিকের সাপেক্ষে দূরে চলে যাচ্ছে এবং পরে ফিরে আসছে। এটাই হলো অসঙ্গতি যে আমাদের উপরিউক্ত ভবিষ্যদ্বাণী বা ধারণায় কোনো যমজ ভাই প্রকৃতপক্ষে বেশি বয়স্ক।"},{"question":"Yaraanta Iodine.","answer":"Calaamadaha ugu waa weyn waa (qanjirkathyroidka oo balaarta), indhaha oo soo baxa (koru soo taagma), hypothyroidism (Daal, culeyskaqofka oo kordha, tabar darri iyo iskuyaacsanaanmaskaxeed) and hyperthyroidism (miisaanlumin, wadna garraacid aad ah, iyo dhibaatooyinla xiriira rabitaanka cuntada). IDD (iskudhexyaacsanaanta ka timaadda la’aanta iodine)xilliga uurka waxay sababtaa cillinimo (dib udhac ba’an oo ku yimaada maskaxda,hagaasnimo ku timaada koritaanka jirka, madax ballaarnaan iyo dhagoolnimo) ilmaha dhashay ilmaha dhashay."},{"question":" Inona no firenena sadnany Eoropa no any Azia?","answer":"Torkia no firenena izay samy any Eoropa sy Azia. Ny ampahany amin'i Torkia dia any Eoropa ary ny ampahany hafa any Azia."},{"question":"የመደመር መጽሐፍ ጸሐፊ ማነው?","answer":"ጠቅላይ ሚኒስትር ዐቢይ አሕመድ"},{"question":"வினா:சந்திரிகையின் கதை நூலின் ஆசிரியர் ……………….அ) பாரதியார்ஆ) பாரதிதாசன்இ) தமிழண்ணல்ஈ) கு.பா.ரா.","answer":"விடை:அ) பாரதியார்"},{"question":"waa maxay Suuqgeyn?","answer":"Suuqgeyntu waa hab loo maro ka iibinta alaab ama adeeg la doonayo in laga iibiyo macmiil"},{"question":"శ్రీరాముని ముద్రికను చూసి సీత హనుమతో ఏమన్నది ?","answer":"శ్రీరాముని ముద్రికను హనుమ చూపగా, అతనితో సీతాదేవి ఇలా పలికెను. నా భర్త అయిన శ్రీరాముని సమాచారమును నీ వలన తెలుసుకొన్నాను. కానీ నీ నిజరూపమును చూడకుండా నిన్ను నమ్మి నా శిరోరత్నమును నీకివ్వను అని హనుమతో సంశయముగా పలికినది. అప్పుడు హనుమ ఆకాశమును అంటునట్లుగా తన నిజ స్వరూపమును సీతాదేవి ఎదుట ప్రదర్శించెను."},{"question":" “అనుచున్ జేవురు మీఱు కన్నుగవతో, నాస్పందదోష్ణంబుతో, ఘనహుంకారముతో, నటద్ర్భుకుటితో గర్జిల్లు నా ఫోన్ సలేశుని” ఈ వాక్యంలో అలంకారాన్ని గుర్తించండి.A) ఉపమB) ఉత్ప్రేక్షC) స్వభావోక్తిD) వృత్త్యనుప్రాస","answer":"C) స్వభావోక్తి"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي كانت معجزته إحياء الموتى؟","answer":"الإجابة:  نبي الله عيسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"పుంప్వాదేశ సంధి గురించి వివరించి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"పుంప్వాదేశ సంధి :కర్మ ధారయములందలి ‘ము’ వర్ణమునకు పుంపులగు.ఉదా :సరసము + వచనము – సరసపువచనము – సరసంపువచనమవిరసము + మాట – విరసపుమాట , విరసంపుమాట"},{"question":"Неологизмдер дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Неологизмдер (нео... жаны гр. logos – сөз) – коомдук турмуштагы ар кандай зарылчылыктан улам пайда болгон жаңы сөздөр. Алар жалпы тилдик жана автордук (жеке стилдик) деп бөлүнөт. Жалпы тилдик Н. жаңы чыккан затты же көрүнүштү атоо зарылчылыгына байланыштуу пайда болот (мисалы,мониторинг, инновация, cайт жана башка) да, тилде толук өздөштүрүлгөн соң неологизм болуудан калат. Автордук неологизм көбүнчө стилдик максатта чыгарылып, контексттен сырткары дээрлик колдонулбайт жанаанча кеңири тарала албайт. Мисалы:Интроверсия, кайдан келдиң?Аморалдуу ойлор мененМизантропия тамчылапНигилисттик жолдор мененЦинизмиң камчылапАнан келдиң, \\"Абсурд!\\" дедиңБаарын жокко чыгарыпИшеним да, Кудай дагыКалды артта кызарыпБаткан күндөй кызарыпАзыр издейм ошолордуГармонияны, убайдыУнутулган, жолдо калганбалким өлгөн КудайдыИздейм аны тоодон, таштаниздейм суудан, абаданиздейм ушу табигаттанизи сууган адамдан.издейм толо измдерденэкзистенция, аскетизмдаосизм, суфизмжашооизм, өмүризмизм изм изм измбу баарына жетмек кайдаболуп турса меланхолия азырынча меланхолия..."},{"question":"السؤال: لأيّ نبيٍّ من الأنبياء انشقّ البحر؟","answer":"      الجواب: نبيّ الله موسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"Sheeg cuduradda ugu caansan ee la is qaadsiiyo?","answer":"Waxaa kamid ah cuduradda ugu caansan ee la is qaadsiiyo:b) Kuwa hawadaa isuku mariyo, sida Hargabka, Burukiitada, Iyo Tiibishada.t) Kuwa galmada lagu kala qaado, sida Isfiilitada, Jabtada, iyo Aydhiska (AIDS).j) Kuwa lagu kala qaado cuntada iyo biyaha wasakheysan, sida Daacuunka iyo Tiifowga.x) Kuwa cayayaanka u Kala gudbiyo, sida Duumada ay soo gudbiso Kaneecada."},{"question":"Вопрос: объясни образование слова семья","answer":"Семья,  \\"семь\\" - значит 7, \\"я\\" - означает me, I с английского"},{"question":"Viết một vài ví dụ sử dụng tác phẩm Truyện Kiều của Nguyễn Du để thể hiện cách nói khi CÁC NHÂN VẬT VĂN HỌC VIỆT NAM HÓA \\"NGÔN TÌNH\\"","answer":"- Thúy Kiều nói với Thúy Vân: “Cô bé của tôi, chúc em một đời bình an vui vẻ.”- Kim Trọng nói với Thuý Vân: “Sau này em sẽ hiểu, ở nơi nào đó trên thế giới này có Kiều xuất hiện, thì những người khác chỉ là tạm bợ. Anh không muốn tạm bợ.”- Thúy Kiều nói với Kim Trọng: “Gặp anh là điều bất ngờ tuyệt vời nhất. Yêu anh là ước nguyện cả đời không hối tiếc. Vứt bỏ anh là điều dũng cảm nhất!”"},{"question":"شنو هو أبرد جسم فالمجموعة الشمسية ؟","answer":"قمر كوكب نبتون (ترايتون)"},{"question":"aiza avy no toerana azo iompiana trondro?","answer":"ireto avy no azo iompiana trondro: ny farihy, ny dobo, ny tanimbary"},{"question":"No contexto da computação, explique o significado de Realidade Virtual (VR) e Realidade Aumentada (AR).","answer":"Realidade Virtual (VR) é uma tecnologia que cria um ambiente digital imersivo, permitindo que os usuários interajam com esse ambiente como se estivessem realmente lá. Já a Realidade Aumentada (AR) combina elementos do mundo real com elementos virtuais, sobrepondo informações digitais ao ambiente físico, melhorando assim a experiência do usuário."},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、このトピックに関する記事を書きなさい： 日本のロケット「H2A」　月を調べる探査機を宇宙に運んだ","answer":"日本のJAXAは7日の朝、ロケットの「H2A」を打ち上げました。H2Aは、月を調べる探査機「SLIM」を高さ約620kmまで運んで、軌道に入れました。宇宙を調べる人工衛星「XRISM」も軌道に入れて、打ち上げは成功しました。JAXAは今年3月、新しいロケット「H3」の打ち上げに失敗しました。このため、H2Aが成功するかどうか、多くの人が注目していました。H2Aが運んだSLIMは、3か月か4か月あとに月を回る軌道に入って、来年1月か2月ごろ月に下りることを計画しています。日本の探査機はまだ月に下りたことがありません。SLIMが調べるデータは、アメリカの「アルテミス計画」で人が月に行って調べることにも役に立てる予定です。"},{"question":"Ban xaaliss lañuy jëfëndiko reewum Itaali?","answer":"Euro "},{"question":"Sókótó","answer":"Sokoto je ilu pataki kan ni ariwa iwo oorun Naijiria, nitosi idapomora Odo Sokoto ati Odo Rima. Ni Odun 2006, olugbe ti o wa ni be ju 427,760. Sokoto ni oluilu Ipinle Sokoto, o si je oluilu awon ipinle ti o wa ni ariwa iwo oorun Naijiria tele.Oruko Sokoto (oruko atijo re ni Sakkwato) ni ipilese Larubawa, je sooq ti o tunmo si oja ni Yoruba. Atun mo si Sakkwato, Birnin Shaihu da Bello tabi \\"Sokoto, Oluilu Shaihu ati Bello\\" Bello Umar Maikaset.Ibujoko Kalifu Sokoto teleri, esin musulumi ni o bori ni ilu naa ti o si je ibujoko pataki ti won ti n ko eko Islam. Sultanu ti o je oludari Kalifu ni adari elesin awon Musulumi Naijiria.Sokoto ni oju ojo ologbele-ogbele (Isori oju ojo Köppen BSh). O wa ni apa Sahel to gbe, Savana oniyanrin ati oke die si yiika. Pelu iwon igbona tabi otutu odoodun to saba ma n je 28.3°C (82.9°F), Sokoto je ikan lara awon ilu to gbona julo ni Naijiria, sibesibe iwon igbona tabi otutu ni osan saba ma n je 40°C (104.0°F) fun pupo igba lodun, gbigbe re kii je ki ooru poju. Osu keji titi de Osu kerin ni o ma n gbona julo, ti gbigbona re le ju 40°C lo. Iwon igbona tabi otutu ti o ga julo ni 45°C. Igba ojo beere lati Osu kefa titi de Osu kewa, nigbati ojo ma n ro lojoojumo. Ojo naa kii saba ma n pe, oyato si bi ojo ti ma n ro ni awon agbegbe ti ojo ti man ro daradara. Lati opin Osu kewa de Osu keji, ni 'igba otutu', ategun oye ti o n fe eruku Sahara ma n bo oju ojo. Eruku yii ma n bo oorun, o si ma n di iwon igbona tabi otutu ku lopolopo.Anfani ti agbegbe naa ni lati gbin irugbin ni ibi isan omi odo Sokoto-Rima, ti o ni ile olora. Awon irugbin ti won ma n gbin ni Sokoto ni jero, oka baba, ewa to fere poju, leyin re ni agbado, iresi, yamati/eeku, awon irugbin oka ati ewebe miran ni alubosa, tomati, ata, igba/ikan, letusi, ati kabeeji. Yato si jero, Sokoto ni o n pese alubosa julo ni Naijiria. Ni ti eweko, Sokoto bosi agbegbe Savana. Eyi jẹ ilẹ-koriko ti ko ni eṣinṣin tse-tse, o dara fun ogbin awọn irugbin ọkà ati osin ẹran. Òjò máa ń pe bẹ̀rẹ̀ ó sì ma n tete dawoduro pẹ̀lú ìwọ̀n idaji òjò odoodun láàárín 500mm ati 1,300mm. Awọn igba meji pataki lo wa ni Sokoto, igba otutu ati ogbele. Ogbele ma n bẹrẹ lati Oṣu Kẹwa titi di Oṣu Kẹrin ni awọn apa kan o si le di Osu Karun tabi Osu Kefa ni apa miiran. Igba otutu ni apa keji bẹrẹ ni Osu Karun titi di Oṣu Kẹsan tabi Oṣu Kẹwa ni opo ibi ni ipinle naa. Oye, gbigbẹ, otutu, ati afẹfẹ eruku ni iriri ipinle naa laarin Oṣu Kọkanla ati Osu keji. Ooru ma n po ni ipinlẹ naa ni Oṣu Kẹta ati Oṣu Kẹrin. Ṣugbọn oju ojo ni ipinle naa ma tutu ni owurọ o si ma n gbona ni awọn ọsan, yato si igba oye lile. Petele ti o wopo ni ile Hausa, apa ariwa Naijiria ni o poju ni ipinle naa. Ilẹ fadama ti o tobi pupo ti awọn ọna Odo Sokoto-Rima wa ni pẹtẹlẹ ti o si pese ilẹ olora ti o dara fun ogbin ọpọlọpọ irugbin ni ipinle naa. Awọn oke ati oke-nla wa kaakiri ipinlẹ naa.Shehu Usmanu Dan Fodiyo ti lo Sokoto ni ibere osu kewaa odun 1804 gege bi ibi ipade pelu Galadima, Yunfa's Vizier. Lẹyin naa, Muhammad Bello lo o gẹgẹbi ibi ikọlu Dufua ni ibere ọdun 1806. Bovil daba pe won ti mo agbegbe naa si Sokoto lati ibẹrẹ awon ọdun kẹtadinlogun. Ni iwoye itan, Sokoto ni a da sile bi agọ ologun ni ọdun 1809, nigbati Shehu Usmanu wa ni Sifawa. Lẹhinna o di olu-ilu kalifu lẹhin iku Shehu.Ni awọn ọdun 1820, Sokoto wa ni ipo giga rẹ ti aisiki ni ibamu pẹlu ipo giga ti awọn agbara 'awọn alaṣẹ' ni aarin kalifu, ti o n gba isakole lododun lati ọdọ gbogbo awọn fiifu ṣaaju ki agbara won to dinku. Oluwakiri Hugh Clapperton (1827) ni iwunilori pupọ nipasẹ aisiki yii ati awọn ipa rẹ lori ilu naa.Clapperton ṣe akiyesi pataki bi agbegbe Sokoto se sunmora won: awọn odo, dipo iṣowo jijinna, ni ọrọ-aje ilu naa. Ṣugbọn iṣowo Sokoto ko da bii ti tele mo, nitori ipo idamu ti orilẹ-ede ti o sunmo wa.Ni akoko ti oluwakiri Heinrich Barth de ni 1853, die eniyan lo n gbe Sokoto o si ti bajẹ pupọ. Barth ni 1857 ṣe iṣiro awọn olugbe ni 20,000-22,000, ṣugbọn ọja naa si n se daadaa, ati agbegbe eyin odi ti o dara ju Sokoto funrararẹ.Bovil ṣapejuwe ni deede Sokoto gẹgẹbi ipo ti o lagbara, pẹlu awọn apata giga lati ila-oorun si ariwa-iwọ-oorun ati afonifoji kekere kan ni iwọ-oorun ati guusu iwọ-oorun ti o daabobo lodi si awọn ikọlu alagbara aimotele. Ilu naa jẹ gaba lori ilẹ pẹtẹlẹ ti o gbooro nibiti awọn odo meji, Rima ati Sokoto pade, ti o jẹ ipade ọna lati Gobir ni ariwa, Kebbi ni guusu ati Burmi Zamfara ni ila-oorun.Ni ibẹrẹ orundun kọkandinlogun, ilu naa (Sokoto) ti pin si awọn eka. Irú àwọn eka bẹ́ẹ̀ ni ẹ̀ka Magajin Gari, ẹ̀ka Waziri, ẹ̀ka Sarkin Musulumi, ẹ̀ka Sarkin Adar, ẹ̀ka Magajin Rafi, àti eka Sarkin Zamfara. Ni akoko yii awọn wọọdu naa jẹ kekere ti wọn si fi odi yi wọn ka, pelu eyiti o wa ninu mọṣalaṣi Sultan Bello ati Shehu, Aafin Sultan ati awọn ile miiran ati agbo ile Shehu.Ni ọdun 1818, won fe odi naa si iwọn ti o ni awọn ẹnu-ọna ti o wọle ati jade lati odi Birni. Iru ibode ni Kofar-Kade, Kofar-Kware, Kofar-Rini, Kofar-Dundaye, Kofar-Taramniya, Kofar-Aliyu Jedo, ati Kofar-Marke.Agbegbe Sokoto ti o wa lọwọlọwọ jẹ ile ti ọpọlọpọ awọn ijọba ti ìwọ̀ oòrùn Sudan ṣaaju ikonileru. Awọn yii ni ijọba Gobir ati Kebbi pẹlu kalifu olokiki agbaye ti olu-ilu ti ẹmi ati ti iṣelu jẹ olu-ilu ipinlẹ naa.Lẹ́yìn ìṣẹ́gun kalifu látọwọ́ àwọn Gẹ̀ẹ́sì lọ́dún 1903, oríṣiríṣi ẹ̀yà ara rẹ̀ ni wọ́n fi ṣe àdáṣe tí wọ́n sì darapọ̀ mọ́ ìjọba Àríwá Nàìjíríà. Ẹkùn àríwá tipa bẹ́ẹ̀ jẹ́ apá kan kalifu Sokoto àti ijoba Kanem-Bornu. Eyi tẹsiwaju titi di Oṣu Kini ọdun 1967 nigbati a ṣẹda awọn ipinlẹ lati rọpo awọn ijọba agbegbe nipasẹ Ajagun Yakubu Gowon. Sokoto di olu-ilu ipinlẹ àríwá ìwọ̀ oòrùn ti a ṣẹda ni ọdun 1967. Ni ọdun 1976 lẹyin idasile ipinlẹ Niger kuro ni ipinlẹ àríwá ìwọ̀ oòrùn, ipinlẹ Sokoto farahan pẹlu olu ile rẹ. Sibẹsibẹ ni Sokoto, ipinle Kebbi ati Zamfara ni won yo kuro ni Sokoto, ni 1991 ati 1996 lẹsẹsẹ.Ilu Sokoto ti jẹ olu-ilu fun ọpọlọpọ awọn ijọba lati igba idasile rẹ nipasẹ Kalifu Muhammad Bello ni ọdun 1809.Ipinle Sokoto ni iye eniyan bii 3.7 milionu ti o da lori ikaniyan ọdun 2006 ti ẹya meji ti o jẹ Fulani ati Hausa . Ilu Sokoto, olu ilu ipinle Sokoto, ni iye eniyan ti o to 2.5 milionu. Yatọ si Fulani ati Hausa, eya kekere Zabarmawa ati Tuareg wa ni awọn aala ti ijọba ibilẹ. Gbogbo awọn ẹgbẹ wọnyi n sọ Hausa gẹgẹbi ede ti o wọpọ. Fulfulde ni awọn Fulani n sọ.Awon Hausa ni ipinle naa je Gobirawa, Zamfarawa, Kabawa, Adarawa ati Arawa. Awọn Fulani ni apa keji jẹ ti awọn ẹgbẹ pataki meji; ilu Fulani (Hausa: Fulanin Gida; Fula: Fulbe Wuro) àti awon awọn alarinkiri. Awọn akoko ni Torankawa, awọn idile ti Shehu Usmanu Danfodiyo, Sullubawa ati Zoramawa. Awon Torankawa jẹ kilasi aristocratic lati ọdun 1804.Ni aṣa, ipinle na jẹ isokan. Awọn eniyan ti ipinle na jẹ Musulumi, ati pe ẹsin Islam n fun wọn ni eto ti iwa ati ihuwasi. Ilana imura wọn tun jẹ ti orisun Islam. Awọn ayẹyẹ pataki meji ti o jẹ, Eid-el-Fitri ati Eid-el-Kabir ni won ma n se ni ipinle na ni odoodun. Ayeye akoko duro fun opin awe Ramadan, nigba ti ikeji wa fun pipa àgbo ni iranti ise Anabi Ibrahim (Abraham).Ijakadi ibilẹ (Kokawa) ati ese (Dambe) ni ere idaraya meji ti Hausa n gbadun nigba ti Fulani ati Sullubawa ma n daraya pẹlu Sharo ati Doro lẹsẹsẹ. Awọn alejo ti o ṣe pataki si ipinlẹ naa ni won ma n pe si ibi ayeyedurbar nla tabi kekere, ayeye ti o wa fun iwode ẹṣin ti a ṣe lọṣọ daradara ati awọn ibakasiẹ ti awọn ọkunrin ti o wo aso ogun ibile ati aso asa maa n gun.O ju ọgọrin ninu ọgọrun (80%) awọn olugbe ilu Sokoto ti o n ṣe iru iṣẹ-ogbin kan tabi omiran. Wọ́n ń pese irúgbìn bii jéró, okababa, àgbàdo, ìrẹsì, anoman, ege, ẹ̀pà, àti ẹ̀wà fún oúnjẹ, wọ́n sì ń pese àlìkámà, òwú, àti ẹfọ̀ jáde fún owó. Iṣẹ́ ọnà abẹ́lẹ̀ bíi alágbẹ̀dẹ, aso híhun, pipa aso laro, gbígbẹ́ ona àti iṣẹ́ áwọ̀ tún kó ipa pàtàkì nínú ètò ọrọ̀ ajé àwọn ará Sokoto; nitori eyi, awọn agbegbe oriṣiriṣi bii Makera, Marina, Takalmawa ati Majema di pataki. Sokoto tun jẹ ọkan ninu awọn agbegbe ti o n pese ẹja ni orilẹ-ede. Nitori naa, opolopo eniyan lẹba agbada odo ma n peja pẹlu.Bakanna ni Sokoto ni awọn ohun elo adayeba ati erupẹ. Awon ile ise ogbin ti o n lo owu, epa, oka, goomu, agbado, iresi, ireke, alikama, ege, goomu Arab ati taba bi awọn ohun elo ise ni won le dasilẹ ni agbegbe naa. Ogbin aladanla ni won tun le ṣe ni ipinlẹ na nipa lilo omi irigeson lati Daamu Goronyo, Lugu, Kalmalo, Wammakko ati adagun Kwakwazo laarin awọn miiran.Awọn ohun alumọni bii kaolini, gipisum, okuta-efun, lateraiti, awọn ọlọ pupa, fosifeti mejeeji ofeefee ati alawọ ewe, amọ iboji, iyanrin ati bẹbẹ lọ, wa ni awọn iwọn iṣowo. Awọn ile-iṣẹ ti o nlo awọn ohun elo ise wọnyi le ti fi idi mulẹ ni ipinlẹ naa.Àìsí esinsin tse-tse lórí ilẹ̀ pápá oko tí ó ṣí sílẹ̀ ní èrè fun àwọn ẹranko igbó àti ẹran agbéléjẹ̀. Sokoto wa ni ipo keji ni ipese ẹran-ọsin ni iye ẹranko ti orilẹ-ede ti o ju miliọnu mẹjọ lọ.Wiwa awọn agbara eto-aje wọnyi n pese awọn anfani idoko-owo to dara, ni pataki ni awọn ile-iṣẹ ogbin gẹgẹbi bii ọlọ iyẹfun, ṣiṣe awọn tomati, isọdọtun suga, awọn aṣọ, goomu, soradi, ẹja agolo, ati bẹbẹ lọ.Sokoto ko ni eto irinna gbogbo eniyan. Gbigbe laarin ilu naa (nigbati kii ṣe nipasẹ ẹsẹ) ni nipasẹ okada eyiti o ṣiṣẹ bi takisi eniyan kan ati nigbamiran awọn kẹkẹ ẹlẹsẹ mẹta ma n gbe eniyan lati ibi kan si ekeji; eyi ngbanilaaye fun gbigbe eniyan diẹ sii ju ọkan lọ ni akoko kan (sibẹ ni idiyele olowo poku bi awọn okada). Awọn ọkọ akero ati awọn takisi kii ṣe loorekoore ati pe wọn lo fun gbigbe laarin awọn ilu.Papa ọkọ ofurufu agbaye pẹlu asopọ deede si Abuja, Kano ati Eko wa ni kilomita mewa guusu si Sokoto.Ni Oṣu Kẹjọ ọdun 2008, won se adehun fun kikọ awọn iṣẹ simenti ni Sokoto.Didi ilu nla ni Ìtàn tó ti pẹ́ gan-an ní ilẹ̀ Hausa. Eto naa bẹrẹ nigbati awọn agbegbe ilana kan ti ilẹ Hausa ni idagbasoke lati Kauyuka si Birane. Sibẹsibẹ ọkan ninu awọn abajade pataki ti jihadi ni iyara ti iṣẹlẹ yii kii ṣe ni ilẹ Hausa nikan ṣugbọn ni gbogbo awọn agbegbe ti iṣakoso kalifu. Awọn ilu tuntun dide ati ilu Birane to ti pe wọ inu akoko idagbasoke ti a ko ri tẹlẹ, diẹ ninu won bi awọn agbegbe tuntun ti awọn iṣẹ iṣowo, awọn miiran bi awọn olu-ilu Emirati ati aarin gungun iṣakoso ati iṣowo.Ọkan ninu awọn ẹya olaju ninu itan kalifu Sokoto bẹrẹ pẹlu idasile ilu Sokoto (olu-ilu kalifu). Ki jihadi to sele, agbegbe laarin Ijọba Gobir ati Kebbi ni agbegbe ti a n pe ni “ilẹ awon arinkiri”. Sugbon pelu aseyori jihad ti Shehu Usmau dan Fodiyo (1804–1808) dari ati isegun ti awon jihadi lori awon olori ile Hausa, ilu Sokoto (olori ile ijoba kalifu) ni Muhammad Bello ko. Pẹlupẹlu, gẹgẹbi Abdul-Razaq Shehu ṣe akiyesi ninu iwe rẹ Sakkwato Birnin Shehu ), won ti ya aworan ilu Sokoto lori iwe nipasẹ Muhammad Bello paapaa ṣaaju ki won to kọ ọ. Bello, ọmọ Sheikh, wa ninu awọn ogagun baba rẹ ati awọn adari ogun. O ja ogun ti o lera julo ti o si gun julo, o si je ayaworan kalifu Sokoto Birnin Shehu.Ilu Sokoto gẹgẹ bi a ti ya aworan re nipasẹ ayaworan Muhammad Bello ni gbogbo awọn ẹya ara ti ilu ode oni pẹlu awọn ọna, awọn afara, ọja, ganuwa (awọn ibi agbara kaakiri ilu) ati pẹlu awọn ile-iṣẹ iṣakoso ati iṣowo. Lara awọn ile-iṣẹ iṣakoso ti Muhammad Bello ṣe ni Kanwuri, Binanchi, Galadanci, Alkalanci, Dogarawa ati bẹbẹ lọ. Sibesibe, yato si ọja aarin ti a mọ si Yardole, awọn agbegbe iṣowo miiran ti a ṣe nipasẹ Muhammad Bello ni Makera, Madinka, Marina, Siriddawa, Takalmawa, Runji ati Jirgawa. Ni afikun, ninu awọn ohun miiran ko si ilu ni boya ṣaaju jihadi tabi orundun kokandinlogun ile Hausa ti o le di ilu nla laisi odi ti o munadoko (ganuwa). Eyi ni a kọ pẹlu ọpọlọpọ awọn ibi agbara bi Kofar Aliyu Jedo, Kofar Dundaye, Kofar Marke, Kofar Rini, Kofar Kware, ati Kofar Taramniya, ati pe idagbasoke pataki yii fa ọpọlọpọ eniyan lati lọ kuro ni agbegbe wọn si ilu Sokoto fun iwalaaye.Lati akiyesi ti o wa loke lori bi kalifu Muhammad Bello ṣe ya aworan ilu Sokoto, a o ri pe Sokoto jẹri sii awọn aṣikiri ti o ni ifẹ si awọn iṣẹ alagbẹdẹ, ise awo, ohun elo amọ ati bẹbẹ lọ. Fun apẹẹrẹ, diẹ ninu awọn eniyan wọnyi ṣe iṣowo ti alagbẹdẹ tabi ni iṣowo miiran ti o jọmọ bi Makera Assada. Awon eniyan kan wa ti won maa n rin irin ajo lo si orisiirisii ilu Naijiria ati awon orile-ede to wa nitosi lati ra awon ohun elo irin to baje bii oko to yonu, oko ayokele, oko nla, oko ofurufu ati beebee, paipu irin, ati tanki epo ki won le tu won ka, ti won si n ta won fun ẹnikẹni ti o fẹ lati loo tabi yi wọn pada si ọja miiran."},{"question":"मुझे इस श्रेणी में एक प्रश्न और उत्तर दीजिए: भूगोल","answer":"कौनसे कांटीनेंट में शहर नहीं हैं? अंटार्टिका "},{"question":"Mene ne Bayanau?","answer":"Bayanau kalmomi ne da ke yin ƙarin bayani game da aikatau. Wannan bayani da suke yi shi ya ke fito da aikin a fili. Sukan faɗi gurin da aka yi aikin, lokacin da aka yi aiki ko kuma yadda aka yi, ake yi ko za a yi aiki."},{"question":"Dapọ Abiọdun kilọ fawọn to n da rogbodiyan silẹ ni Yewa","answer":"Latari rogbodiyan to mu ẹmi lọ to n waye lawọn àgbegbe Yewa, nipinlẹ Ogun, lasiko yii, Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun ti kilọ fawọn to wa nidii iṣẹlẹ naa. O ni ijọba oun ko ni i faaye gba palapala bẹẹ. Ẹni tọwọ ba si ba nidii ẹ yoo jẹ buruku iya.Ọjọbọ, ọjọ kọkanla, oṣu keji yii, ni gomina kilọ bẹẹ, ninu atẹjade kan lati ọfiisi Akọwe iroyin ẹ, Ọgbẹni Kunle Ṣomọrin.Ṣe lọjọ naa ni iroyin jade pe awọn Fulani paayan ni Owode-Ketu, pe wọn tun daamu awọn eeyan Igan -Alade, Eegua ati Igbogila.Yatọ si ikilọ yii, ikọ alaabo ti i ṣe ọlọpaa, fijilante, otelemuye atawọn ẹṣọ mi-in nijọba làwọn ti da sawọn agbegbe ti rogbodiyan ti n ṣẹlẹ, awọn agbegbe bíi Ariwa Yewa, Ìmẹ̀kọ-Afọn ati Guusu Yewa.Wahala naa pọ lawọn agbegbe yii to bẹẹ ti wọn ti ileewe ati ọpọlọpọ ibi pa. Eyi lo fa a ti Gomina fi ni ki iwadii bẹ̀rẹ̀ kia lori awọn to lọwọ si ikọlu to mu ẹmi lọ naa, wọn ni ijọba yoo gbe ẹni tọwọ ba tẹ pe o lọ́wọ́ si wahala naa lọ si kootu kíá ni.“Gbogbo ohun to ba gba la maa fun un lati mu alaafia duro nipinlẹ Ogun, koda bo gba ifiyajẹni gidi, a o ni i woju ẹnikẹni ka too lo o lati mu ifọkanbalẹ wa nipinlẹ yii”Bẹẹ ni apa kan atẹjade naa wi."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fambara ho an'ny malagasy?","answer":"Ny fambara izay dia zava-mitranga tsapan' ny olona (hita maso na ren' ny sofina sns) ka manampy azy hahalala mialoha ny zavatra hitranga amin' ny hoavy akaiky na lavitra. Mety ho zava-tsoa no hitranga nefa matetika dia zava-dratsy no ahenoana ny teny hoe fambara, toy ny hoe fambara loza. Tsy voatery ho ny razana ihany no mandefa fambara fa mety ho i Zanahary na ny fanahy hafa rehetra."},{"question":"E-imza en kolay nereden alınır?","answer":"e-İmza Başvuru İşlemlerie-İmza işlemlerinizi gerçekleştirebilmek için size en yakın PTT Müdürlüğümüze https://pttkep.gov.tr/basvuru-merkezleri-2/ adresinden “Merkez”leri filtreleyerek ulaşabilirsiniz."},{"question":"Этнонимика бул…","answer":"Этнонимика (этнонимия) – этникалык глобализация же чакан элдердин, уруулардын, уруулук топтордун чоң элдердин арасына сиңип кетүү коркунучу, кооптонуу жараткандыктан, бул тармакка тарыхчылар менен экологдор кызыгууда."},{"question":"أجب على السؤال التالي : ماهي رائداة الشركة الأوروبية للصناعات الجوية في عام 2009 ؟","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة هي إيرباص."},{"question":"Tọ́pẹ́ Tedela","answer":"Temitope Christopher Tedela tí gbogbo ènìyàn mọ̀ sí Tọ́pẹ́ Tedela jẹ́ òṣèré orí-ìtàgé àti olùgbéré-jáde ọmọ orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà.Wọ́n bí Tọ́pẹ́ gẹ́gẹ́ bí àkọ́bí àwọn òbí rẹ̀ sí ìlú Èkó. Àwọn òbí rẹ̀ jẹ́ ọmọ bíbí Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkìtì. Ó lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ girama ti Model College, tí ó wà ní ìlú Mẹran ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó. Ó kẹ́kọ̀ọ́ gboyè akọ́kọ́ nínú ìmọ̀ Mass Communication ní ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ fásitì Ìpínlẹ̀ Èkó.Ó ti gba ọ̀pọ̀ amì-ẹ̀yẹ fún àeọn iṣẹ́ takun takun tí ó ń gbé ṣe ní inú agbo àwọn òṣèré Nollyeood. Lára awọn amì-ẹ̀yẹ yí ni: Africa Magic Viewers Choice Award, Nigeria Entertainment Award, Best of Nollywood Award àti Nollywood Movies Award. Wọ́n i wo àwọn eré ọlọ́kan-ò-jọkan tí Tades ti gbé jáde ní àwọn sinimá káàkiri ní ilẹ̀ Adúláwọ̀ ati ní òkè òkun bíi Cannes Film Festival, Toronto International Film Festival àti BFI London Film Festival. Lára àwọn iṣẹ́ rẹ̀ tí ó ti gbé jáde ni: The Lost Okoroshi (2019), What Lies Within (2017), Slow Country (2017), Ojukokoro (2017), Suru L'ere (2016), Out of Luck (2015), A Soldier's Story (2015) àti A Mile from Home tí ó jẹ́ eré tí ó ti fi gba amì-ẹ̀yẹ oríṣiríṣi.Nígbà tí ó kẹ́kọ́ nílé ẹ̀kọ́ fásitì lọ́wọ́, Tọ́pẹ́ kópa lààmì-laaka nínú eré àtìgbà-dégbà onípele tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Edge of Paradise. Ó jáwọ́ nínú ìkópa nínú eré fúngbà díẹ̀ láti lè fojú sínẹ̀kọ́ rẹ̀ , lẹ́yìn tí ó sì kàwé já, ó ṣiṣẹ́ fúgbà díẹ̀ ní ilé iṣẹ́ rédíò ti UNILAG FM. Tọ́pẹ́ fìgbà kan rí ṣe olóòtú ètò lórí ìkanì NTA. Ó ti kópa nínú àwọn eré oríṣiríṣi. Ó kópa nínú eré, A Mile from Home. Ní ọdún 2015, Tọ́pẹ́ tún kópa nínú eré A Soldier's Story àti eré Out of Luck. Ipa rẹ̀ tí ó kó nínú eré Suru Le're ní ọdún 2016, gẹ́gẹ́ ẹ̀dá ìtàn Kyle Steven-Adedoyin jẹ́ kí awọn ènìyàn ó fẹ́ láti máa wo eré tí ó bá ti kópa. Tọ́pè kópa nínú eré apanilẹ́rín kan tí wọ́n pè Ojúkòkòrò àti Slow Country ní ọdún 2017. Ó tún di gbajú-gbajà olùgbéré-jáde pẹ̀lú eré tìrẹ ty ó gbé jáde tí ó pe àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ní What Lies Within. Ní ọdún 2018, kópa nínú eré ọ̀daràn kan tí akọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Knock Out Blessing. Ó tú kópa bí ẹ̀dá-ìtàn Dr. Dauda nínú eré The Lost of Okoroshi He alEall-shades-of-amazing-in-whumanizer-toni-kan/</ref> Tedela tún kópa nínú eré tí àkọ́lé rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ The Ghost and the House of Truth.Ní ọdún 2016, wọ́n fi Tọ́pẹ́ Tedela ṣe aṣojú fún ilé-iṣẹ́ Global Rights, ilé-iṣẹ́ tí ó ń rí sí ẹ̀tọ́ ọmọnìyàn láti lè jẹ́ kí ó lè ṣe ìpolongo tako ìwà ìfipábánolòpọ̀ awọn ọmọ obìnrin ní orílẹ̀-èdè Nàìjíríà."},{"question":"भारतीय संस्कृतीचे गाढे अभ्यासक जर्मन पंडित कोण होते ?","answer":"भारतीय संस्कृतीचे गाढे अभ्यासक जर्मन पंडित मॅक्स मुलर होते."},{"question":"ما عاصمة روسيا ؟","answer":"موسكو"},{"question":"வினா : உடலில் இரத்தம் பாயாத பகுதி எது ?","answer":"விடை : கருவிழி,"},{"question":"Антонимдер деген эмне?","answer":"Бири-бирине карама-каршы маанидеги сөздөрдү антонимдердейбиз.М и с а л ы: жакшы – жаман, чоң – кичине, оор – жеңил"},{"question":"Văn bản thuật lại một sự kiện theo mối quan hệ nguyên nhân – kết quả thường bao gồm những phần nào?","answer":"Văn bản thuật lại một sự kiện theo mối quan hệ nguyên nhân – kết quả thường bao gồm ba thông tin chính: nguyên nhân – diễn biến – kết quả, nhằm trả lời ba câu hỏi lớn: Vì sao lại xảy ra sự việc ấy?, Sự việc ấy diễn ra thế nào?, Kết quả ra sao?."},{"question":"Oración 1: Oaklyn está ubicada en el 1er distrito electoral y es parte del 6to distrito legislativo estatal de Nueva Jersey.Oración 2: Oaklyn se ubica en el 6to Distrito del Congreso y forma parte del 1er Distrito Legislativo de Nueva Jersey.Pregunta : ¿la oración 1 parafrasea la oración 2?. ","answer":"No, expresan lo mismo. "},{"question":"তথ্য প্রযুক্তিনির্ভর বিশ্বই বিশ্বগ্রাম— মন্তব্যটি ব্যাখ্যা কর।","answer":"তথ্য প্রযুক্তিই প্রকৃতপক্ষে বিশ্বগ্রামের ধারণার মূল ভিত্তি। বিশ্বগ্রাম এমন একটি পরিবেশ, যেখানে পৃথিবীর সকল মানুষ একটি একক সমাজের ন্যায় বসবাস করে এবং ইলেকট্রনিক মিডিয়া ও তথ্য প্রযুক্তি ব্যবহারের মাধ্যমে একে অপরকে সেবা প্রদান করে। তথ্য ও যোগাযোগ প্রযুক্তির বিস্তৃত ব্যবহার তথা তথ্য আদান-প্রদানের জন্য ইনফরমেশন সুপার হাইওয়ের সাথে সংযোগ ছাড়া বিশ্বগ্রামের ধারণা অসম্ভব। তথ্য প্রযুক্তির বিস্ময়কর উৎকর্ষতার কারণে সমগ্র বিশ্ব এক বিনিসুতার বাঁধনে পরস্পরের থেকে ভৌগোলিকভাবে দূরে থেকেও একটি একক সমাজের বাসিন্দা হয়ে ওঠাই প্রমাণ করে তথ্য প্রযুক্তিই প্রকৃতপক্ষে বিশ্বগ্রামের ধারণার মূল ভিত্তি।"},{"question":"रासायनिक ईन्जिनियरिङ् मा रिएक्टर को भूमिका चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"रासायनिक ईन्जिनियरिङ्मा रिएक्टरहरू पोतहरू हुन् जहाँ रासायनिक प्रतिक्रियाहरू हुन्छन्। तिनीहरू कच्चा माललाई इच्छित उत्पादनहरूमा कुशलतापूर्वक रूपान्तरण गर्न महत्त्वपूर्ण छन्। रिएक्टरको डिजाइन र प्रकार, जस्तै ब्याच वा निरन्तर प्रवाह, विशिष्ट प्रतिक्रिया गतिविज्ञान र प्रक्रिया आवश्यकताहरूमा निर्भर गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Lista ug lima ka tawo na mao pinaka daghan ug silver medals sa Olympics.","answer":"Kini ang lima ka tawo na naay pinaka daghan silver medals sa Olympics:1. Larisa Latynina - 5 medals2. Nikolai Andrianov - 5 medals3. Edoardo Mangiarotti - 5 medals4. Ireen Wust - 5 medals5. Isabell Werth - 5 medals"},{"question":"Fan mooy gëblag réewum Afghanistan ?","answer":"Gëblag réewum Afghanistan mu ngi tuddu Kaboul."},{"question":"Omeo ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny teny hoe \\"Faly\\".","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny hoe faly dia :  Ravo."},{"question":"மட்டைப் பந்து விளையாட்டில் இரண்டு முறை 20/20 உலக கோப்பையை வென்ற முதல் அணி எது?","answer":"இருமுறை டி20 உலகக் கோப்பையை வென்ற முதல் அணி என்ற பெருமையை வெஸ்ட் இண்டீஸ் பெற்றது. இந்தியாவில் 2016 டி20 உலகக் கோப்பையை கரீபியன் அணி வென்றது. அவர்கள் இங்கிலாந்தை தோற்கடித்தனர்."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn ji alakooso kansu l’Ekiti","answer":"Awọn agbebọn ti ji alakooso fun eto ọgbin nijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ekiti, Ebenezer Busuyi, lẹyin ọsẹ kan ti wọn ji Ọbadu tilu Ilẹmẹṣọ, Ọba David Oyewumi.Lalẹ Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, niṣẹlẹ naa waye loju ọna Ilawẹ-Ekiti si Ẹrijiyan-Ekiti, lasiko ti ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu All Progresives Congress (APC) naa n lọ pẹlu mọto ẹ.A gbọ pe lẹyin ti wọn ji i gbe tan lawọn eeyan too mọ nigba ti wọn deede ri mọto ẹ lẹgbẹẹ titi, to si han gbangba pe wọn ti wọ ọ wọ inu igbo.Nigba to n fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ, Alukoro ọlọpaa Ekiti, ASP Sunday Abutu, sọ pe awọn ọlọpaa Rapid Response Squad, ikọ Amọtẹkun, atawọn ọdẹ ti n ṣiṣẹ takuntakun ninu gbogbo igbo to wa lagbegbe naa.O ni aago mẹfa irọle niṣẹlẹ naa waye, ko si sẹni to mọ ibi ti wọn gbe oloṣelu naa lọ.O waa ni ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ko ni i gba kawọn ajinigbe sọ Ekiti di ibugbe wọn, bẹẹ lo gba awọn eeyan niyanju lati maa ṣọra ni gbogbo igba."},{"question":"Zer da teknologia 5G, eta nola eragiten du komunikazioen abiadura?","answer":"Teknologia 5G da hainbat komunikazio teknologia konbinatzen dituen sare berria. Komunikazioen abiadura eragiteko, 5G teknologiak erakusten du nola datuak abiadura handiagoz bidali daitezkeen, latentzia gutxituz."},{"question":"Bada misalin Mahaɗi mai Haɗe ibara da Ibara.","answer":"1. Gidan Bala da gidan Sani2. Naman akuya ko naman Saniya.3. Hawa mota ko hawa Jaki. "},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Gny nahalava moko gn'akanga .....................  \\" ","answer":"\\"  Gny nahalava moko gn'akanga dra gny mitao \\" "},{"question":"චිංචිකරු හෝ  මිංච්කරු යැයි කියා  හෝ  වචනයක් තිබේ ද ? එය රැකියාවක් ලෙස තමා  දක්වා  තිබෙන්නේ. එහි අදහස කුමක් ද ?","answer":"වරායන් ආශ්‍රිතව හෝ පාවෙන යාත්‍රා  ආදියේ හෝ  ගොඩ බිම් ආශ්‍රිතව බඩුබාහිරාදිය බෑම පැටවීම සඳහා  යොදාගන්නා  දොඹකර වර්ගයේ යන්ත්‍රයක් ක්‍රියාකාරවන්නා  වින්චිකරු(Winchman,winch operator )එය වෘත්තිය කි.සමහර දුම්රිය ස්ථානවල අදත් දැකිය හැක."},{"question":"Kan moy njiitou reew u Gambi?","answer":"Adama Barrow "},{"question":"Yan réew ñooy làkk wolof ?!","answer":"Senegaal , Móritani ak Gàmbi."},{"question":"కింది వాక్యాలు ఏ అర్థాన్ని సూచించే వాక్యాలో రాయండి.దయచేసి సెలవు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"ప్రార్థనాద్యర్థక వాక్యం."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mahatakatra\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mahatakatra\\" dia \\"Mahatratra\\"."},{"question":"ايش معنى الجملة التالية \\"شغم شغمه قات\\" بالفصحى.","answer":"يشغم: ياخذ ملئ كفيه من شيء ما . مثال (شغم شغمه قات) اخذ ملئ يده قاتا."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది ప్రశ్నలకు జవాబులు రాయండి.ఒకవేళ మీ శరీరంలో ఎముకలు, కీళ్ళు లేనట్లయితే ఏమి జరుగుతుందో ఊహించి రాయండి.","answer":"మన శరీరంలో ఎముకలు, కీళ్ళు లేకపోతేమన శరీరానికి ప్రత్యేకమైన ఆకారం ఉండదు.కదలికలు మరియు చలనము సాధ్యంకాదు.ఒక్కమాటలో చెప్పాలంటే మనం ఆకారం లేకుండా గుండ్రని బంతిలా ఉంటాము."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mandi darah'? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berlumuran darah. Contoh ayat: Perajurit itu mandi darah kerana cedera terkena tembakan musuh."},{"question":"ジャニーズ事務所のタレントで、キムタクといえば木村拓哉ですが、マツジュンといえば嵐に所属する誰のことでしょう？","answer":"松本潤です。"},{"question":"السؤال: من الفائز في بطولة رولان غاروس لعام ٢٠٠٧ للرجال؟","answer":"الإجابة: فاز رافاييل نادال أمام روجر فيدرير "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai berseru di padang pasir\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud seruan yang tidak diendahkan orang"},{"question":"සිංහල භාෂාව ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ප්‍රධාන රාජ්‍ය භාෂාවක් වන එරට බහුතර සිංහල ජාතිකයින්ගේ මව් භාෂාව සිංහල භාෂාව වේ. අද වන විට මිලියන 20 කට අධික සිංහල සහ මිලියන 3කට අධික සිංහල නොවන ජනගහනයක් සිංහල භාෂාව භාවිත කරති. සිංහල‍ භාෂාව ඉන්දු-යුරෝපීය භාෂාවල උප ගණයක් වන ඉන්දු-ආර්ය භාෂා ගණයට අයිති වන අතර මාල දිවයින භාවිත කරන දිවෙහි භාෂාව සිංහල බසට බොහෝ දුරට සමාන භාෂාවකි.ප්‍රාග් ඓතිහාසික යුගයේ පටන් පැවති හෙළබස ඈත අතීතයේ ඉන්දියානු භාෂා හා යටත් විජිත සමයේ බටහිර භාෂා සමග සම්මිශ්‍රණයෙන් නූතන සිංහල භාෂාව බිහි වී ඇත.සිංහල යනු මධ්‍යම ඉන්දු-ආර්ය (එළු) \\"සිහල\\" යන වචනයට අනුරූප සංස්කෘත පදය වේ. මෙය \\"සිංහ\\" යන සංස්කෘත වචනයේ ව්‍යුත්පන්නයක් වේ. \\"භගවත පුරාණයෙ\\" හි සිංහලය, දිවයිනේ සංස්කෘත නාමය ලෙස සඳහන් කර ඇත. මෙම නම සමහර අවස්ථාවලදී \\"සිංහයන්ගේ වාසස්ථානය\\" ලෙසද අර්ථ දක්වා ඇත. මෙය අතීතයේ සිංහයන් බහුල වශයෙන් සිටින්නට ඇතැයි යන විශ්වාසය මත යෙදුනක් යැයි පැවසේ.සිංහල භාෂාව උප භාෂා ලෙස බෙදීමක් විශාල වශයෙන් දක්නට නොමැත. නමුත් ප්‍රදේශීය වශයෙන් කතා විලාශය හා ආවේනික වූ වචන හා යෙදුම් වල වෙනස්කම් දැකිය හැකිය. රජරට (උතුරු මැද පළාත), රුහුණ (දකුණු පළාත), ඌව (ඌව පළාත) මෙසේ වෙනස්කම් දැකිය හැකි පළාත් කිහිපයකි. නමුත් මෙම විශේෂිත යෙදුම් හා කතා විලාශ අනෙකුත් සිංහලයන්ට බොහෝ විට පහසුවෙන් තේරුම්ගත හැක."},{"question":"अन्नपूर्ण क्षेत्रको वातावरण र संस्कृतिमा पर्यटनले पारेको प्रभावको चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"अन्नपूर्ण क्षेत्रमा पर्यटनले आर्थिक अवसरहरू ल्याएको छ तर दिगो व्यवस्थापन आवश्यक वातावरणीय र सांस्कृतिक चुनौतीहरू पनि छन्।"},{"question":"Cabdi raxmaan daakhil .","answer":"9) Cabdi raxmaan Bin Mucaawiya Bin Haashim Bin Cabdi malik ( Cabdi raxmaan daakhil ), wuxuu ka mid ahaa dadkii reer Banii ummaya ee ka haray xasuuqii ay u gaysteen cabbaasiyiintu markay xukunka kala wareegeen Banii ummaya, cabdi raxmaan daakhil wuxuu usoo cararay  magaalada Qayrawaan ee ka tirsan wadanka Tuunis, markuu imaanayay magaalada Qayrawaan wuxuu jirey 19 sano, wuxuuna arkay in ay ka jirto wadamada lays ku yiraahdo (North Africa), kacdoon lagaga soo horjeedo nin markaas ka talinaayay oo la yiraahdo ( Cabdi Raxmaan Xabiib) wuxuuna ahaa nin cadaawad weyn u haya Banii ummaya, Cabddi Raxaman Daakhil  wuxuu isku dayay inuu ka faa'iidayso kacdoonkan looga soo horjeedo ninkan ka talinayaa meesha,  wuxuuna arkay inay Andalus tahay meesha ugu haboon ee uu ku xaqiijin karo himiladiisa uu hiigsanaayo oo ah inuu yagleelo marlabaad dawlad ay u talinayaan  banii ummaya , si haddaba ay ugu suurtagasho hir gilinta himmaladiisa wuxuu ku talaabsaday inuu sameeyo qodobadan soo socda :- 1- Wuxuu u diray wadanka Andalus nin ay safarka rafiiq ku wada ahaayeen oo la yiraahdo Badar, muhiimmadiisuna ay noqonayso inuu u soo sahmiyo xaalada Andalus soona ogaado  dadka samaynta weyn ku leh bulshada ku dhaqan Andalus iyo waliba inuu soo xog ogaado  dadka fikradahooda iyo waxay aaminsanyihiin . 2- Wuxuu toos ula xiriiray  isagoo u sharxaaya yoolka uu hiigsanaayo,  qof kasta oo jeclaa dawladii banii ummaya ee ku nool gudaha wadanka Andalus. 3- Wuxuu xiriir dhaw lasameeyay qabiilooyinka la yiraahdo Barbarka isagoo u sheegaya yoolka uu hiigsanaayo oo ah inuu dhiso dawlad Banii ummaya u taliyaan, wuxuuna ogaaday inay aad u jeclaayeen xukunkii Banii ummaya, haddana ay diyaar u yihiiin inay garab istaagaan si uu usoo celiyo xukunkaas. 4- Wuxuu la xiriiray dhamaan wixii ka haray Banii ummaya isagoo ku war gelinaya inuu Andalus ka asaasaayo xukunkii Banii ummaya, markaas ayay iskaga yimaadeen daafaha adduunka dhan. Markii uu hubsaday Cabdi raxmaan Daakhil in ayay diyaar u tahay inuu galo wadanka Andalus, ayuu isku diyaariyay safarkii uu ku gelilahaa Andalus, isagoo aan ciidan iyo askartoona wadan ayuu galay waxaana soo dhaw weeyay rafiiqiisii sahan ka u ahaa ( Badar), wuxuu tagay magaalada  Qurduba, markaas Andalus  waxaa ka talinaayay in la yiraahdo Yusuf Cabdiraxmaan Fihri oo xoogag badan kasoo hor jeedaan, wuxuu ku talagalay inuu ururiyo dhamaan dadkii ka soo horjeeday xukunka yusuf isla markaasna jeclaa xukunkii Banii ummaya ee cabbaasiyintu rideen, diyaar garow weyn kadib waxaa dagaal iskaga horyimi, laba ciidan oo ay kala hogaaminayaan Cabdi raxmaan Daakhil iyo Yusuf Cabdi raxmaan Fihri, dagaal dheer kadib waxaa guushu raacday  Cabdi arxmaan Daakhil, maalintaas wixii ka danbeeyay xukunkii Andalus wuxuu gacantiisa ku soo wareegay Cabdi Raxmaan Daakhil halkaasna wuxuu ku asaasay dawlad aad u xoog badan oo ay ka taliyaan Bani ummaya. Cabdi raxmaan daakhil wuxuu ahaa nin aqoon badan, deeqsi ah, dhaqan wanaag lagu yaqaan, gabayaa ah, hogaan fiican. Wuxu lahaa laba naanaysood oo kala ah :- 1-  Cabdiraxmaan Daakhil (Cabdiraxmaankii soo galay) 2-  Saqru Quraysh (Gorgorkii reer quraysh) Mid kastoo ka mid ah labadaas naanaysood sabab ayay ugu baxeen, hadaan soo qaadano sababtii ay ugu baxday naanaysta cabdi raxmaan daakhil waxay ahayd, isagoo keligiisa ayuu yimi oo soo galay  wadanka Andalus markaas ayuu ka yagleelay dawlad aad u xoog badan, saas ayaana loogu bixiyay cabdi raxmaankii soogalay, naanaysta kale ee ah Saqru Quraysh ( Gorgor), waxaa u bixiyay amiirkii la oran jirey Abuu jacfar almansuur, isagoo maalin  fadhiya Magaalada Baqdaad ayuu weydiiyay ragii la fadhiyay su'aashan, mataqaaniin gorgorka qureysheed ? markaas ayay ku dheheen waa adiga, wuxuu yiri may ani maahi, niman badan ayay sheegeen mid kasta wuxuu ku dhahaayay maahan ninkaasi, markaas ayuu u sheegay oo yiri :- waa Cabdiraxmaan  bin mucaawiya bin cabdi malik, wadan uusan waligiis tagin ayuu intuu tagay ka asaasay dawlad xoog badan."},{"question":"ጨረቃ በምድር ዙሪያ ለመጓዝ ስንት የምድር ቀናት ያህል ይወስዳል? መልስህን ከዚህ ውስጥ ምረጥ፦ (ሀ) 1 ቀን (ለ) 27 ቀናት (ሐ) 180 ቀናት (መ) 365 ቀናት","answer":"(ለ) 27 ቀናት"},{"question":"Leia Dongue","answer":"Leia Tânia do Bastião Dongue, tit ọpọ̀ èniyàn mọ̀ si Tanucha, ti a bi ni ojo, kerinlelogun osu kaarun odun 1991 ni Maputo, Mozambique, jẹ oṣere bọọlu inu agbọn Mozambique kan. O jẹ ọdun 185 cm (6'07\\") ati ki o dun bi kekere siwaju .Ni May 2013, o ti wole nipasẹ Primeiro de Agosto .Tanucha ni a dibo MVP ni Ajumọṣe bọọlu inu agbọn Awọn Obirin 2014 Angola ati ni 2014 ati 2015 FIBA Africa Clubs Champions Cup."},{"question":"Cột cờ Lũng Cú nằm trên đỉnh Lũng Cú. Đỉnh Lũng Cú  còn có tên gọi là đỉnh núi gì?A. Núi Rồng (Long Sơn)B. Núi ChúaC. Núi thiêng","answer":"A. Núi Rồng (Long Sơn)Cột cờ Lũng Cú là cột cờ quốc gia nằm ở đỉnh Lũng Cú hay còn gọi là đỉnh núi Rồng (Long Sơn) có độ cao khoảng 1.470 m so với mực nước biển, thuộc xã Lũng Cú, huyện Đồng Văn, tỉnh Hà Giang. Cột cờ đặt ở nơi Đài vọng cảnh cực Bắc Việt Nam, cách cực Bắc khoảng 3,3 km theo đường thẳng, cách huyện lỵ Đồng Văn 24 km, thành phố Hà Giang 154 km.Cột cờ được xây dựng theo mô hình cột cờ Hà Nội, nhưng kích thước nhỏ hơn. Về kiến trúc, cột cờ được thiết kế theo hình bát giác, chân gắn 8 tấm phù điêu đá xanh minh họa cho các giai đoạn thời kỳ lịch sử của đất nước và các phong tục tập quán của nhân dân tỉnh Hà Giang, phía trên gắn 8 mặt trống đồng."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Bila satu dipanggil pokok, bila banyak dipanggil apa?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah hutan. "},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la réewum Grenade nekk ?","answer":"Réewum Grenade mu ngi nekk ci kembaaru Amerique."},{"question":"Berikan saya jawapan untuk soalan teka-teki ini: Pembiayaan sekolah yang percuma.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah biasiswa"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Eslováquia?","answer":"0,848."},{"question":"Awọn alagbara to ju temi lọ lo wa nidii iṣẹlẹ to ṣẹlẹ ni Lẹkki-Sanwo-Olu","answer":"Gomina ipinle Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu ti sọ pe awọn agbara kan to ju toun lọ lo wa nidii iṣẹlẹ aburu to ṣẹlẹ ni Lẹkki lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii, nibi ti awọn ọlọpaa ti dana ibọn fun awọn oluwọde ti wọn duro soju kan naa, ti mọkandinlaaadọta si ku ninu wọn, ti ọpọ ninu wọn fara pa.Gomina ni, ‘‘Aṣaalẹ ọjọ Iṣẹgun yii jẹ aṣaalẹ to lagbara ju ninu itan ilẹ wa, nigba ti awọn alagbara ti agbara wa ko ka, ti agbara wọn ju tiwa lọ waa fi itan buruku balẹ fun wa. Ṣugbọn a ṣetan lati koju rẹ, a oo si jade kuro ninu iṣoro naa gẹgẹ bii akọni ju bi a ṣe wa bayii lọ.‘‘Mo ṣẹṣẹ pari abẹwo kaakiri awọn ileewosan ti wọn gbe awọn to fara gba ninu ijamba naa lọ ni.‘‘Awọn mẹwaa lo wa nileewosan ijọba, mọkanla wa ni ileewosan Reddington, awọn mẹrin ti ipalara wọn ko pọ pupọ wa ni Vedic, nigba ti awọn meji mi-in wa nibi ti wọn ti n gba itọju pajawiri, iyẹn ẹka to jẹ pe ọwọ Ọlọrun nikan ni ẹmi wọn wa.‘‘Awọn mẹta ni wọn ti da silẹ lọsibitu pe ki wọn maa lọ sile. A maa tẹsiwaju lati maa ṣamojuto awọn to wa nileewosan yii lati ri i pe wọn gba itọju to peye.‘‘Gẹgẹ bii gomina, mo mọ pe gbogbo ẹbi ọrọ yii, ori mi lo wa, ṣugbon mo maa ṣiṣẹ pẹlu ijọba apapọ lati ri i pe a ridii okodoro ọrọ naa, ki a si ri i pe eto aabo to dara fẹsẹ mulẹ lati daabo bo ẹmi ati dukia awọn araalu.’’"},{"question":"මොනා ලීසා චිත්‍රය සිතුවම් කළේ කවුද?","answer":"මොනා ලීසා චිත්‍රය සිතුවම් කළේ ඉතාලි ජාතික චිත්‍ර ශිල්පියෙකු වූ ලියනාඩෝ ඩාවින්සි විසිනි."},{"question":"ব্যাংক ঋণের সুবিধাসমূহ বর্ণনা করো।","answer":"আধুনিক জটিল ও প্রতিযোগিতামূলক কারবারি বিশ্বে ব্যাংক ঋণের গুরুত্ব ও ব্যবহার অত্যধিক। কেননা এ জাতীয় ঋণ গ্রহণের ফলে বেশ কিছু সুবিধা ভোগ করা যায়। নিম্নে এ সম্পর্কে আলোচনা করা হলো:১. ক্ষুদ্র প্রতিষ্ঠানের ক্ষেত্রে একমাত্র উৎস: সাধারণত ক্ষুদ্র প্রতিষ্ঠানের আর্থিক সচ্ছলতা ও বাজারে সুনাম না থাকায় তারা দীর্ঘমেয়াদি ঋণ গ্রহণ করতে পারে না। ফলে বাধ্য হয়েই তাদের স্বল্পমেয়াদি ঋণের উপর নির্ভর করতে হয়।২. কম খরচ: এ ধরনের ঋণের ব্যয় দীর্ঘমেয়াদি ও মধ্যমমেয়াদি ঋণের তুলনায় কম। ফলে ব্যবসায়ীরা কম খরচ বলে এ ধরনের ঋণগ্রহণ করতে আগ্রহ প্রকাশ করে।৩. কর বাঁচানো: স্বল্পমেয়াদি ঋণের উপর ধার্যকৃত কর, কর-বাদ যোগ্য ব্যয়। এর ফলে নীট মুনাফার পরিমাণ কম বলে কম কর ধার্য হয় এবং প্রদান করতে হয়। ফলে ব্যাংক ঋণ গ্রহীতার করের পরিমাণ কমিয়ে থাকে।8. সহজলভ্যতা: এ ধরনের ঋণ গ্রহণ করতে ঋণ গ্রহীতাকে কম আনুষ্ঠানিকতা পালন করতে হয়। তাছাড়া এ ধরনের ঋণ প্রদানে বেশি কড়াকড়ি করা হয় না বলে তা ক্ষুদ্র, মাঝারি ও বৃহদায়তন ব্যবসায়ের জন্য সহজলভ্য হয়ে থাকে।৫. নমনীয়তা: এ ধরনের ঋণ বেশ নমনীয়। ফলে এ ধরনের ঋণের পরিমাণ ও পরিশোধ কাল ঋণগ্রহীতা সহজেই বাড়াতে ও কমাতে পারে।"},{"question":"Terno e tenor são anagramas?","answer":"Sim, as letras podem ser rearranjadas para criar a outra palavra."},{"question":"வினா:பிடிகருணை குழம்பு செய்வது எப்படி?","answer":"விடை:தேவையானவை: பிடிகருணை - 200 கிராம், சின்ன வெங்காயம் - 10, பூண்டு - 10 பல், தக்காளி - 2, புளி - எலுமிச்சை அளவு,  மஞ்சள்தூள் - அரை டீஸ்பூன், குழம்பு மிளகாய்த்தூள் - 3 டீஸ்பூன், வடகம், வெல்லம் - சிறி தளவு, கறிவேப்பிலை - ஒரு ஆர்க்கு, நல்லெண்ணெய், உப்பு - தேவையான அளவு.30 வகை கிராமிய சமையல்செய்முறை: பிடிகருணையை மண் போக கழுவி, வேக வைத்து, தோலு ரித்து, வட்டம் வட்டமாக நறுக்கவும். சின்ன வெங்காயம், பூண்டு, தக்காளியை பொடியாக நறுக்கவும். புளியை நன்கு கரைத்து வடிகட்டிக் கொள்ளவும். அதில் உப்பு, மஞ்சள்தூள், மிளகாய்த்தூள் சேர்த்துக் கொள்ளவும்.மண் சட்டி அல்லது அடி கனமான வாணலியை அடுப்பில் வைத்து சூடேற்றி நல்லெண்ணெய் விட்டு, காய்ந்ததும் வடகம் தாளித்து, சின்ன வெங்காயம், பூண்டு, கறிவேப்பிலை, தக்காளி சேர்த்து நன்கு வதக்கி... துண்டுகளாக்கிய பிடிகருணையை சேர்த்து மேலும் வதக்கவும். பிறகு, புளிக்கரைசலை விட்டு நன்கு கொதிக்க விடவும். குழம்பு சற்று கெட்டியானதும் வெல்லத்தூள் சேர்த்து இறக்கவும்.சூடான சாதத்தில் நல்லெண்ணெய் விட்டு இந்த குழம்பை ஊற்றிச் சாப் பிட... சுவை அள்ளும்!"},{"question":"Bakit sinasabi na may siyam na buhay ang mga pusa?","answer":"Hindi totoong may siyam na buhay ang mga pusa dahil maari silang madisgrasya at magkasakit katulad ng iba pang hayop. Gayunpaman, sinasabi ito dahil likas na maliksing gumalaw ang mga pusa upang maiwasan ang disgrasya. Maari ring nagsimula ang kasabihang ito dahil sa mga paniniwala, katulad nang sa mitolohiyang Ehipto, na sagrado at maswerte ang mga pusa."},{"question":"Quantas pessoas a Peste Negra matou?","answer":"Acredita-se que entre 75 milhões e 200 milhões de pessoas tenham sido mortas pela Peste Negra. Esse número é aproximado devido à falta de registros precisos da época e à dificuldade em calcular o impacto total em uma população dispersa e em constante mudança."},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?අනුමාන ","answer":"ප්‍රත්‍යක්ෂ"},{"question":"Hevero ity hafatra manaraka ity: “Ny olona amin'ity vondrona ara-poko ity dia henatry ny fiarahamonina avokoa.” Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay bitsika?","answer":"Eny, mirakitra teny feno fankahalana amin'ny foko iray ilay hafatra."},{"question":"கேள்வி: அதிகப்படியான மீன்பிடித்தல் கடல் சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்புகளையும் உலகளாவிய மீன் வளங்களையும் எவ்வாறு பாதிக்கிறது?","answer":"பதில்: அதிகப்படியான மீன்பிடித்தல் மீன்களின் எண்ணிக்கையை குறைக்கிறது, உணவு வலைகளை சீர்குலைக்கிறது மற்றும் கடல் சுற்றுச்சூழல் அமைப்புகளை சேதப்படுத்துகிறது. மீன்பிடித்தலை நம்பியுள்ள சமூகங்களின் உணவுப் பாதுகாப்பையும் அச்சுறுத்துகிறது. நிலையான மீன்பிடி நடைமுறைகள் மற்றும் கடல் இருப்புக்களை நிறுவுதல் ஆகியவை அதிகப்படியான மீன்பிடித்தலின் விளைவுகளைத் தணிக்க முக்கியமானவை."},{"question":"Тамак жөнүндө макал билесизби?","answer":"Тамак болбой дымак болбойт."},{"question":"\\"අඹ යාලුවෝ\\"පොත ලිව්වෙ කවුරුන්ද?","answer":"ටී.බී ඉලංගරත්න"},{"question":"கேள்வி: இந்தியாவில் கயிறு தயாரிக்கும் தொழிலில் முக்கியத்துவம் பெறும் மாநிலம்?கீழ் காணப்படும் நான்கு பதிலில் இருந்து சரியான பதிலை தேர்ந்து எடுக்கவும்:அ) கேரளாஆ) மேற்கு வங்காளம்இ) தமிழ்நாடுஈ) மகாராஷ்டிரா","answer":"சரியான பதில்: அ) கேரளா.விளக்கம்: கயிறு தொழில் அதிக தொழிலாளர்களை கொண்டதும் ஏற்றுமதி செய்யத்தக்கதும், பாரம்பரியமிக்கதுமான  விவசாயம் சார்ந்த குடிசைத் தொழிலாகும். தேங்காய் நார் சார்ந்த தொழிலின் மூலமாக கிராமப்புறங்களில் உள்ளவர்களுக்கு குறிப்பாக பெண்களுக்கு அதிக வேலை வாய்ப்பு கிடைக்கப் பெற்று வருகிறது. கயிறு தொழிலில் கேரளா மாநிலத்திற்கு அடுத்தப்படியாக தமிழகம் உள்ளது. ஆனாலும் பழுப்பு நிற நார் உற்பத்தியில் நாட்டிலேயே  தமிழகம் முதன் இடத்தில் உள்ளது."},{"question":"Which British action actor played the part of Lee Christmas alongside Sylvester Stallone in the film The Expendables?","answer":" Jason Statham"},{"question":"प्रश्न :भविष्यत्‌ कालका अपूर्ण तथा पूर्ण पक्षको प्रयोग गरीआफ्नो भविष्यको योजनाबारे लेख्नुहोस्‌ ।","answer":"उत्तर : म भविष्यमा असल शिक्षक बनेको हुने छु । म उच्च शिक्षाअध्ययनका लागि त्रिभुवन विश्व | विद्यालयमा भर्ना भएको हुने छु ।म धेरै मिहिनेत गरी पढ्दै हुने छु । राम्रो प्रतिशत ल्याएर ।स्नातकोत्तर तह उत्तीर्ण गरेको हुने छु । शिक्षक सेवा आयोगकोतयारी गर्दै हुने छु । आयोगको परीक्षा दिँदै हुने छु । मैले परीक्षामाराम्रोसँग लेखेको हुने छु । आयोगको परीक्षामा नाम निकालेको हुनेछु । दुर्गम गाउँमा शिक्षाको ज्योति छर्दै हुने छु । म असल एवंकर्तव्यनिष्ठ शिक्षक बनेको हुने छु ।"},{"question":"வினா:  பாரதியாரின் பாடல்களை முதன் முதலில் மக்களுக்கு அறிகுகம் செய்தவர்.","answer":"விடை: பரலி சு. நெல்லையப்பர் "},{"question":"السؤال: من من أمهات المؤمنين كانت زوجة زيد بن حارثة فطلقها، فأنزل الله تعالى يخاطب رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم {فَلَمَّا قَضَى زَيْدٌ مِنْهَا وَطَرًا زَوَّجْنَاكَهَا} [الأحزاب: 37]، فتزوجها رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: زينب بنت جحش"},{"question":"Iza no filoham-pirenena voalohany tany Afrika Atsimo? 1. Cyril Ramaphosa2. Jacob Zuma3. Nelson Mandela","answer":"Safidy 3 - Nelson Mandela no filoham-pirenena voalohany tany Afrika Atsimo."},{"question":"میتھی صحت کے لیے کتنی مفید ہے؟","answer":"قصوری میتھی کا استعمال تقریباً ہر میں عام ہے، اکثر گھروں میں مختلف قسم کے کھانوں میں اسے استعمال ہوتے ہوئے بھی دیکھا ہوگا، مگر کیا آپ جانتے ہیں کہ اگر آپ قصوری میتھی کے فوائد جان جائیں تو اسے سونے کے دام بھی خریدنے پر تیار ہو جائیں گے۔صوری میتھی میں فائبر کی اتنی مقدار موجود ہے جس کی ہمارے جسم کو لازمی ضرورت ہوتی ہے ، یہ جسم کے لئے فیول کا کام کرتی ہے، نظام ہاضمہ کو بہتر بنا کر جسم کے سارے مسائل کو کنٹرول کرلیتی ہے۔میتھی کے پتوں سے شوگر اور بلڈ پریشر پر باآسانی قابو پایا جاسکتا ہے میتھی کے پتے ٹائپ 1 اور ٹائپ 2 ذیابیطس دونوں میں بہت فائدہ مند ہیں میتھی جسم میں انسولین کی مقدار بڑھاتی ہے جو ذیابیطس کے مریضوں کے لیے بہت ضروری ہے۔ میتھی کے پتوں میں فائبر کے ساتھ اینٹی آکسیڈنٹ خصوصیات بھی ہوتی ہیں جو ہاضمہ کو بہتر کرتی ہیں جن لوگوں کو پیٹ کے مسائل درپیش ہوتے ہیں وہ اپنی خوراک میں میتھی کا ساگ ضرور شامل کریں۔اس کے علاوہ ایک مٹھی میتھی کے پتے اور ایک مٹھی پودینہ لے کر ایک گلاس پانی کے ساتھ بلینڈ کرلیں اور دن میں ایک گلاس کھانے سے پہلے پی لیں۔ اس سے امراض قلب اور بلڈ پریشر کے مریضوں کو بہت فائدہ ہوگا۔"},{"question":"Nitori wahala awọ ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun, ijọba ranṣẹ pe Olukẹrẹ ati Ogoga l’ Ekiti","answer":"Lori ipaniyan to n waye lemọlemọ niluu Ikẹrẹ-Ekiti, ijọba ipinlẹ naa ti Ekiti ranṣẹ pe awọn ọba alaye mejeeji to wa niluu naa, Ọba Adejimi Adu ati Olukẹrẹ,  Oloye Ganiyu Ọbasọyin, lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọṣẹ yii.Ijọba sọ pe ki awọn ori-ade mejeeji waa ṣalaye nipa ipaniyan to ṣẹlẹ l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee,  ati eyi to ṣẹlẹ ni nnkan bii oṣu kan sẹyin niluu naa.Ninu lẹta pajawiri kan ti Oludamọran lori eto iroyin igbakeji gomina ipinlẹ naa, Ọgbẹni Ọdunayọ Ogunmọla, fi sita lorukọ Oloye Bisi Ẹgbẹyẹmi lo ti sọ pe awọn ọba mejeeji to wa niluu naa gbọdọ gba alaafia laaye niluu naa.Wọn fi kun un pe awọn ọba naa ko gbọdọ ba awọn araalu fa wahala kankan ti yoo mu ipaniyan tabi rogbodiyan dani niluu ọhun.Bakan naa ni wọn tun fa awọn ọba mejeeji leti pe wọn ko gbọdọ ṣe ipade kankan tabi ipejọpọ kankan niluu titi digba ti rogbodiyan naa yoo fi rọlẹ.Igbakeji gomina ni ijọba yoo fi imu awọn ọba ati oloye ilu naa danrin ti wahala mi-in ba tun ṣẹlẹ, tabi ti ija miiran ba tun bẹ silẹ laarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun .Bi ẹ ko ba gbagbe, Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii ni awọn ọdọ meji gba ọrun lọ lojiji ninu ija awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun. Bakan naa ni awọn ọdọ  mẹfa ku lojiji ninu oṣu to kọja yii.Ijọba ipinlẹ naa ṣekilọ pataki fawọn olori ati awọn olugbe ilu naa pe ki wọn sọwọ pọ pẹlu ijọba ati awọn agbofinro, ki wọn si maa fi ọrọ awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ti wọn ba kẹẹfin niluu naa to ijọba leti."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人工智能在网络安全中的应用有哪些？","answer":"答案：人工智能在网络安全中的应用包括入侵检测、恶意代码识别、行为分析等方面。"},{"question":"Kung ang 7 ay nagiging 13 at ang 11 ay naging 21, ano ang magiging 16?","answer":"31. Ang pattern ay dodoblehin nag numero at babawasan ng isa. 16 x 2 = 32 - 1 ay 31."},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Cuál es la canción más corta del álbum de Bob Dylan Blonde on Blonde?. ","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es identificar la canción más corta del álbum de Bob Dylan Blonde on Blonde. "},{"question":"文章からキーワードを選び、その解釈を述べなさい。 夏休みになって、川で遊ぶ人が増えています。川の事故で亡くなる人もいます。店などでは、安全に遊ぶためにどんな「ライフジャケット」を選んだらいいかという相談が多くなっています。専門家によると、ライフジャケットは水に落ちたときに膨らむ種類もあります。しかし川で遊ぶためには、ライフジャケットに最初から浮く材料が入っている種類を選びます。そして、十分に体が浮くことができるか、説明をよく読んでください。水の中で簡単に脱げないようになっているかも大事です。買うときに、ベルトなどをしっかり体につけて、引っ張っても動かないか確認してください。子どもは大人より脱げやすいので、足の間につけるベルトがあるライフジャケットを選ぶことも必要です。","answer":"この文章に含まれるキーワードとその解釈は以下です。- 膨らむ: 1）中から盛り上がって、大きくなる。ふくれて大きくなる。- 種類: 1）共通する形や性質によって分けたもの。- 浮く: 1）水の上にある。沈んでいたものが、水の上に出る。うかぶ。2）地面から離れて、空中にある。3）表面に現れる。4）心がはずむ。5）お金や時間の余りが出る。6）しっかりとくっついていない。7）相手にされなくなる。- 材料: 1）物を作るもとになるもの。多くは、元の形や性質が残っている場合にいう。2）研究・表現などのもとになるもの。- 脱げ: 1）身に着けたものが、自然にはなれて落ちる。2）脱ぐことができる。- ベルト: 1）洋服に使う帯。バンド。2）乗り物で、体を固定させるもの。3）機械で、動力を伝えるために、二つの車にかけわたす帯のようなもの。4）帯のように続く所。- つけ: 1）物が、はなれないようにする。2）しるしを残す。3）書きこむ。しるす。4）加える。5）そっとあとについて行く。6）ものごとを収める。7）注意を向ける。8）値段を決める。9）そばに付きそわせる。10）…し慣れている。- 引っ張っ: 1）強く引き寄せる。2）たるまないように、ぴんと張る。3）無理に連れて行く。4）仲間にさそいこむ。5）長くのばす。- 確認: 1）十分に確かめること。"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Basil McCrea. ","answer":"Is Comhalta den Tionól Reachtach de chuid Pháirtí Aontachtach Uladh é Basil McCrea, a sheasann i dtoghcheantar Ghleann an Lagáin, i gContae Aontroma.Rugadh é ar an 13 Samhain 1959 i mbaile Dhún na nGall agus fuair sé a chuid oideachais in Acadamh Ríoga Bhéal Feirste agus in Ollscoil Bhirmingham. Sa bhliain 2010, chuaigh sé san iomaíocht in aghaidh Tom Elliott le ceannaireacht an pháirtí a bhaint amach, ach níor éirigh leis.Is é an tuairim choitianta, sna meáin chumarsáide ach go háirithe, ná go mbaineann Basil McCrea le eite chlé an pháirtí.D'fhreastail Basil McCrea ar sheoladh an fheachtais Líofa 2015 i Meán Fómhair na bliana 2011 agus dúirt ag an ócáid go raibh sé ag iarraidh tuiscint níos fearr ar ról na bProtastúnach a stair na Gaeilge a chur chun cinn. Cé nach bhfuil sé de rún aige féin páirt a ghlacadh sa tionscnamh, chuir sé fáilte roimhe is ghuigh gach rath air."},{"question":"路易斯安那州紅河的起點和終點在哪裡？","answer":"在德克薩斯的邊境地區。"},{"question":"Нептун планетасындагы шамалдын ылдамдыгы канча?","answer":"Нептундагы шамалдын ылдамдыгы - 2100 км/с"},{"question":"Fibromiyalji ağrısı neye benzer?","answer":"Fibromiyaljide ağrı özellikle sırt, boyun gibi bölgelerde yoğunlaşabilir. Fibromiyalji ağrısı birkaç ay devam eden zonklayıcı, sızlayıcı tarzda bir ağrı olabilir. Katılık: Fibromiyalji hastalarında uzun süre aynı pozisyonda kaldıktan sonra tutulma, katılık gibi durumlar ortaya çıkabilir."},{"question":"من هي الصحابية التي كانت لقبت قبل إسلامها أكالة الكبود ولماذا ؟\\t","answer":"هند بنت عتبة، التي أكلت كبد الصحابي حمزة بن عبد المطلب"},{"question":"Over wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis praat de volgende tekst: Thomas-Robert Bugeaud is een Franse maarschalk. Hij speelt een belangrijke rol in de Franse verovering van Algerije in de 19e eeuw. Hij voert er moeizame vredesbesprekingen met de plaatselijke bevolking.","answer":"De Franse verovering van Algerije"},{"question":"नेपालमा \\"भगवती जात्रा\\" पर्वको सांस्कृतिक महत्वबारे चर्चा गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"भगवती जात्रा देवी भगवतीको सम्मान गर्न र उहाँको आशीर्वाद लिनको लागि जुलुस र अनुष्ठानका साथ मनाइन्छ।"},{"question":"හේනේ පැල් රකිනවා.මෙය නිවැරදි ද?","answer":"හේනක පැලට ගොස් රකින්නේ හේනේ ඇති බෝග වගාව මිස පැල නොවේ...!! නමුත් පොදු ව්‍යවහාරය \\" පැල් රකිනවා \\" යන්නයි....!!!"},{"question":"Wọn ti fun Ṣoworẹ atawọn ẹgbẹ ẹ ni beeli ogun miliọnu","answer":"Ifa ajafẹtọ-ọmọniyan nni, Ọmọyele Ṣoworẹ, ti fọ’re bayii, ileejọ ti fun un ni beeli to beere fun, miliọnu lọna ogun naira lo maa fi duro lati le maa tile waa jẹjọ.Owurọ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, nile-ẹjọ Majisreeti kan niluu Abuja fọwọ si ẹbẹ oludasilẹ ati alakooso ileeṣẹ iroyin ori atẹ ayelujara, Sahara Reporters, to ti kọkọ wa lahaamọ awọn agbofinro, kile-ejọ too fi i ṣọwọ sẹwọn lọsẹ to kọja.Yatọ si miliọnu ogun naira beeli ti wọn bu fun un yii, o tun gbọdọ wa oniduuro meji ni iye owo kan naa, ti wọn si ni dukia to jọju bii ile tabi ilẹ l’Abuja, bẹẹ ni ko gbọdọ ṣere kọja origun mẹrin ilu Abuja, titi ti ẹjọ to n jẹ lọwọ yoo fi pari, aijẹ bẹẹ, awọn agbofinro yoo tun un gbe.Bakan naa ni wọn fun awọn ẹlẹgbẹ ẹ mẹrin, Juwọn Sanyaolu, Damilare Adenọla, Peter Williams ati Emmanuel Bulus ni beeli, miliọnu kan naira niye owo ti ọkọọkan wọn maa fi duro, wọn si gbọdọ wa oniduuro kọọkan ni iye owo kan naa.Tẹ o ba gbagbe, alẹ aisun ọdun tuntun, lọjọ kọkanlelọgbọn, oṣu kejila, ọdun 2020 to kọja yii, lawọn agbofinro mu Ṣoworẹ atawọn ẹgbẹ ẹ niluu Abuja, nibi ti wọn ti lawọn n ṣe iwọde alaafia kan.Ẹyin naa ni wọn foju wọn bale-ẹjọ, lara ẹsun tijọba ka si wọn lẹsẹ ni igbimọ-pọ lati dalu ru, apejọ ti ko bofin mu ati riru awọn araalu soke lati dẹyẹ sijọba. Latigba naa nile-ẹjọ ti paṣẹ ki wọn wa lọgba ẹwọn Wuse, l’Abuja."},{"question":"ما المقصود بالثرى في المثل الذي يقال(بعد الثريا عن الثرى)؟","answer":"-الأرض"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: തിരുവിതാംകൂർ സംസ്ഥാനത്തെ ആദ്യത്തെ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് ദിവാനായി നിയമിതനായത് ആരാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"തിരുവിതാംകൂർ സംസ്ഥാനത്തെ ആദ്യത്തെ ഇംഗ്ലീഷ് ദിവാനായി പി.രാജഗോപാലാചാരി നിയമിതനായി."},{"question":"ما هو مرادف كلمة جاء؟في مثال : جاء الرجل من مكان بعيد.","answer":"مرادف كلمة جاء : أقبل.يقتل أقيل الرجل أي جاء"},{"question":"అనాథలను ఆదుకొన్న మీ మామయ్యను అభినందిస్తూ లేఖ వ్రాయండి.","answer":"నెల్లూరు,x x x x x.పూజ్యులైన చిన్న మామయ్యకు నమస్కరించి,మీ మేనకోడలు పద్మ వ్రాయు లేఖ.ఇక్కడంతా క్షేమం. అక్కడ మీరంతా క్షేమమని తలచెదను.మొన్న తుపాను మీ ప్రాంతంలో చాలా భీభత్సం సృష్టించిందని టీ.వీ. లో చూశాను. పేపర్లో చదివాను. చాలా కంగారు పడ్డాము. మా అమ్మా నాన్నా మిమ్మల్ని చూసి వచ్చేక నాకొక సంగతి చెప్పారు.ఒక కుటుంబంలో తుపానుకు ఇల్లు కూలి అందరూ మరణించారనీ, ముగ్గురు చిన్నపిల్లలు మిగిలారనీ, ఆ పిల్లలను మీరు పెంచుతున్నారనీ మా అమ్మ చెప్పింది. అంతేకాకుండా చాలామందికి ఆహారం, బట్టలు అందించారని కూడా చెప్పారు. మీ పరోపకార బుద్ధికి నాకు చాలా ఆనందం కల్గింది.నా స్నేహితులకు మీ మంచి మనసు గురించి చెప్పాను. వాళ్ళంతా చాలా ఆనందించారు. మీ మేనకోడలిని అయినందుకు చాలా గర్వపడ్డాను. కేవలం మాటలు కాకుండా, చేతలతో మంచి చేసే మీకు చేతులెత్తి నమస్కరిస్తున్నాను, అభినందిస్తున్నాను. అత్తయ్యకు నా నమస్కారాలు.ఇట్లు,మీ మేనకోడలు,వి. పద్మ.చిరునామా :ఎస్. నరసింహారావుగారు,తెలుగు ఉపాధ్యాయులు,బాలికోన్నత పాఠశాల,నరసరావుపేట, గుంటూరు జిల్లా."},{"question":"Tori bi wọn ṣe n ji awọn akẹkọọ gbe, ẹgbẹ olukọ lawọn maa ti ileewe pa","answer":"Pẹlu bi iṣẹlẹ jiji awọn ọmọleewe ati olukọ gbe lapa Oke-Ọya orileede yii ṣe di lemọlemọ, ẹgbẹ awọn olukọ Naijiria (Nigeria Union of Teachers), ati ẹgbẹ awọn akẹkọọ (National Association of Nigerian Students), ti sọ pe awọn maa tilẹkun awọn ileewe pa jake-jado orileede yii ni. Ki i ṣe apa ariwa nikan o, tori ko si aabo to peye fawọn olukọ ati akẹkọọ kaakiri mọ bayii.Oru mọju ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii, lawọn agbebọn kan tun lọọ ji awọn ọmọọlewe akẹkọọ-binrin bii ọọdunrun (300) ko nigba ti wọn ṣi n sun lọwọ, ti wọn si ṣe bẹẹ ko wọn wọgbo lọ.Nigba to n ba akọroyin wa sọrọ lori aago nipa iṣẹlẹ yii, Dokita Mike Ene, to jẹ akọ̀wé apapọ ẹgbẹ awọn olukọ nílẹ̀ wa, sọ pe o ti han gbangba bayii pe niṣe lawọn kan fẹ diidi fawọ aago itẹsiwaju eto-ẹkọ lorileede yii sẹyin, tabi ki wọn tiẹ doju ẹ de paapaa.“Awọn iṣẹlẹ ijinigbe to n waye lọtun-un losi maa mu kawọn eeyan kaaarẹ ọkan nipa eto ẹkọ, o si maa le awọn kan sa nileewe, wọn aa di alaabọ ẹkọ, wọn o ni i fẹ lati tẹsiwaju mọ. Awọn to ba si n tiraka lọ naa, inu ibẹrubojo ni wọn maa wa. Bawo leeyan ṣe le kawe kiwee naa wọri nibi to ti n wo fẹtofẹto pẹlu ipaya boya awọn ajinigbe le waa ya bo wọn?“A ti ri i pe awọn ileewe to jẹ kidaa ọkunrin tabi obinrin ni wọn yan laayo lati maa ṣe akọlu si bayii, lati mu kawọn majeṣin wọnyẹn ni irẹwẹsi ọkan nipa ẹkọ wọn, wahala tawọn akẹkọọ ti wọn ji ni Kagara la ṣi n ba yi lọwọ ti eleyii fi tun ṣẹlẹ. Bọrọ ṣe ri yii, ko sigba ta o ni ti awọn ileewe pa patapata, tori ko si aabo fawọn akẹkọọ ati olukọ.A ti ni kijọba ṣe fẹnsi sawọn ileewe ijọba gbogbo ki eto aabo ati aago idagiri si wa ni sẹpẹ, ṣugbọn wọn o ti i ṣe bẹẹ. A maa ṣepade lori ọrọ yii,” bẹẹ ni akọwe apapọ ẹgbẹ naa wi.Ọgbẹni Ọlawale Samuẹl to jẹ oluṣekokaari ni Guusu/Iwọ-Oorun ẹgbẹ awọn akẹkọọ, NANS, ni tiẹ sọ pe saka lo daju bayii pe ijọba ti kuna patapata lati pese aabo fun ẹmi ati dukia awa ọmọ orileede yii.“Awa akẹkọọ o nigbẹkẹle kan mọ ninu ijọba yii, ijọba naa ko sapa to, wọn o si ṣe ohun to yẹ lati dawọ eto aabo to dẹnu kọlẹ yii duro. Awọn olori ẹgbẹ awọn akẹkọọ, NANS maa ṣepade pajawiri lori ọrọ yii, a maa bẹrẹ iwọde kaakiri awọn ileewe, a si maa ri i pe a tilẹkun awọn ileewe pa, tori a o le jẹ kijọba sọ ẹmi awọn ewe ati ọdọ di nnkan iṣere lasan bii eyi.”"},{"question":"এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি ধারাবাহিকতা লিখুন :এ পতাকাটি আরব উপদ্বীপের বিলুপ্ত হাশেমী হেজাজ রাজতন্ত্রের পতাকা এবং আরব সমাজতান্ত্রিক বা'আস পার্টির পতাকার অনুরূপ (তবে এরা ২:৩ অনুপাতের পতাকা ব্যবহার করে; আর ফিলিস্তিন ১:২ অনুপাতের পতাকা ব্যবহার করে)। ইরাক ও জর্ডান যে স্বল্পস্থায়ী আরব ফেডারেশন গঠন করেছিল তার পতাকাও অনেকটা একই রকম (তবে এতে ব্যবহৃত লাল ত্রিভুজটি সমবাহু ত্রিভুজ ছিল)। এছাড়া, উত্তর সাহারা ও জর্ডানের জাতীয় পতাকার সাথেও ফিলিস্তিনী পতাকাটির বেশ মিল রয়েছে। এর কারণ হলো: এই সবগুলো পতাকার নকশাই উসমানীয় সাম্রাজ্যের বিরুদ্ধে","answer":"আরব বিদ্রোহে ব্যবহৃত পতাকার নকশার অনুকরণে তৈরি করা হয়েছে।"},{"question":"ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ \\"අගුන්ග් කන්දේ\\" ඓතිහාසික පිපිරීම් ඒවායේ බලපෑම මත පදනම්ව වර්ග කරන්න.","answer":"ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ අගුන්ග් කන්දේ ඓතිහාසික පිපිරීම් ඒවායේ බලපෑම මත පදනම්ව පහත පරිදි වර්ග කළ හැක.1. 1843 පුපුරා යාම: මෙම පිපිරීම සාපේක්ෂව කුඩා වූ අතර, අළු, වැලි සහ ගල් විමෝචනය වීම මගින් සංලක්ෂිත විය. භූමිකම්පා  වැනි ගිනිකඳු ක්‍රියාකාරකම්වල ආරම්භක සලකුණු හැර, සැලකිය යුතු බලපෑමක් වාර්තා වී නොමැත.2. 1963-64 පිපිරීම: මෙය ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ විශාලතම හා විනාශකාරී පිපිරීම් වලින් එකකි. එය ඝෝෂාකාරී පිපිරීම්, ලාවා ගලායාම සහ දැවැන්ත පයිරොක්ලැස්ටික් ප්රවාහයන් සම්බන්ධ වූ අතර, ඇස්තමේන්තුගත පුද්ගලයන් 1,100-1,500 ක් මිය ගියහ. පිපිරීමෙන් පසු අධික වර්ෂාපතනය හේතුවෙන් ඇති වූ සීතල ලාහාර් හේතුවෙන් අතිරේක පුද්ගලයින් 200 ක් මිය ගියහ. මැයි මාසයේ දෙවන පිපිරුම තවත් මාරාන්තික වීමට හේතු වූ අතර කුඩා පිපිරීම් වසරකට ආසන්න කාලයක් පැවතුනි. මෙම පිපිරීම උෂ්ණත්වය මත ගෝලීය බලපෑම් ඇති කළ අතර USAT Liberty එක්සත් ජනපද ප්‍රවාහන නෞකාව විස්ථාපනය විය.3. 2017-2019 පිපිරීම්: මෙම කාල සීමාව සැලකිය යුතු භූ කම්පන ක්‍රියාකාරකම් සහ පිපිරීම් වලින් සලකුණු වූ අතර, පුද්ගලයන් 122,500 ක් පමණ ඉවත් කිරීමට හේතු විය. පිපිරුම්වලට පිපිරුම් සහ මැග්මැටික් ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ඇතුළත් වූ අතර අළු වලාකුළු මීටර් 9,144ක් උසට ළඟා වන අතර ගුවන් ගමනාගමනයට බලපායි. මෙම පිපිරීම් හේතුවෙන් බොහෝ පුද්ගලයන් තාවකාලික සරණාගතයන් ලෙස නවාතැන් ගැනීමටත්, Ngurah Rai ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් තොටුපළ වසා දැමීමටත්, ජාත්‍යන්තර ගුවන් ගමන් අඩාල වීමටත් හේතු විය. 2018 සහ 2019 හි ක්‍රියාකාරකම් ගුවන් ගමනාගමනයට බාධා කළ අතර අවට ප්‍රජාවන්ට බලපෑවේය. හැක."},{"question":"கேள்வி: மின்னணுக் கழிவுகள் மற்றும் அதன் சுற்றுச் சூழல் பாதிப்பை நாம் எவ்வாறு தீர்க்கலாம்?","answer":"பதில்: மின்-கழிவுகளை நிர்வகித்தல் என்பது சுற்றுச்சூழலில் நச்சுப் பொருட்கள் வெளியிடுவதைத் தடுக்க மின்னணு சாதனங்களின் பொறுப்பான அகற்றல் மற்றும் மறுசுழற்சி ஆகியவற்றை உள்ளடக்கியது. மின்-கழிவு மறுசுழற்சி திட்டங்களை செயல்படுத்துதல், நிலையான வடிவமைப்பு மூலம் மின்னணு கழிவுகளை குறைத்தல் மற்றும் மின்னணு தயாரிப்பு ஆயுட்காலம் நீட்டிப்பை மேம்படுத்துதல் ஆகியவை முக்கிய உத்திகள்."},{"question":" වනයේ රජු ලෙස හඳුන්වනු ලබන්නේ කුමන සත්වයාද?","answer":"සිංහයා  බොහෝ  විට හඳුන්වනු ලබන්නේ \\"වනාන්තරයේ රජු\\" ලෙසිනි. මෙම මාතෘකාව බොහෝ දුරට සංකේතාත්මක වන අතර සිංහයාගේ තේජාන්විත පෙනුම සහ ශක්තිය, ධෛර්යය සහ නායකත්වය වැනි සංජානනීය ලක්ෂණ මත පදනම් වේ. සිංහයන් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් කැලෑවල වාසය නොකරන බව සිත්ගන්නා  කරුණකි. ඒවා  බහුලව දක්නට ලැබෙන්නේ අප්‍රිකාවේ තණබිම්, සැවානා සහ විවෘත වනාන්තරවල සහ ඉන්දියාවේ ගිර් වනාන්තරයේ ය."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Trước khi bước vào trận thư hùng tối nay, CLB Hà Nội (17 điểm) đang dẫn đầu bảng, hơn 1 điểm so với đội xếp ngay phía sau là SLNA. Nói cách khác, một kết quả hòa cũng vẫn giúp CLB Hà Nội giữ vị trí đỉnh bảng. Trên lý thuyết, khi chơi trên sân Hàng Đẫy, SLNA cũng không dám vội đẩy cao đội hình, mà cố gắng chơi chắc chắn bên phần sân nhà, chờ cơ hội từ những đường phản công với khả năng càn lướt của bộ đôi ngoại binh Oseni - Olaha. Vấn đề của CLB Hà Nội là cần phát huy tối đa khả năng kiểm soát bóng, chờ đối thủ sốt ruột và khi đó những khoảng trống sẽ mở ra. Diễn biến trên sân cho thấy CLB Hà Nội đã nhập cuộc đầy chủ động nhưng bất ngờ lại tới từ phút thứ 4. Trong một tình huống được hưởng phạt góc bên cánh trái, Phan Văn Đức chuyền vào vòng cấm cho Olaha bật cao đánh đầu hiểm hóc mở tỷ số. Bàn thắng đầy bất ngờ của Olaha dường như đã khiến những tính toán của CLB Hà Nội không đi đúng hướng. Và khi không có HLV trưởng người Hàn Quốc Chun Jae-ho trên băng ghế huấn luyện vì bị nhiễm Covid-19, CLB Hà Nội đã tỏ ra nóng vội trong những tình huống lên bóng. Đội trưởng Văn Quyết vẫn thể hiện được độ điềm tĩnh và kinh nghiệm trong những pha điều tiết bóng nhưng các đồng đội của anh trên hàng công như Siladi, Tuấn Hải, Xuân Tú thì không có được điều đó. Trong khoảng 9 phút thừ 21 đến 29, Văn Quyết đã 3 lần đưa ra những đường kiến tạo rất tốt nhưng hoặc Xuân Tú đá vọt xà trong tư thế đối mặt thủ môn Văn Hoàng trong vòng cấm; hoặc Tuấn Hải xử lý bước 1 không tốt, để lỡ mất cơ hội có thể dứt điểm. Tình huống còn lại phút 29, Văn Hậu đánh đầu vọt xà cận thành từ đường chuyền bên cánh phải của Văn Quyết. Trong 45 phút đầu tiên, ngoại binh Siladi thi đấu khá mờ nhạt. Pha bóng đá chú ý duy nhất của Siladi là nỗ lực cá nhân đi bóng, dứt điểm ngay sát vòng cấm phút 42 thì lại bị hậu vệ SLNA đã chơi lăn xả chặn bóng, cứu thua cho đội khách. Bên kia chiến tuyến, sau khi có bàn dẫn trước, SLNA càng có điều kiện thể hiện rõ lối chơi phòng ngự-phản công và một cú sút nhanh đầy bất ngờ ở cự ly khoảng 30m của Oseni giữa hiệp 1 đã khiến thủ môn Tấn Trường giật mình không thể bắt dính bóng. Sau giờ nghỉ, ban huấn luyện CLB Hà Nội đã đưa ngoại binh người Croatia Tonci Mujan vào sân thế chỗ Xuân Tú để tăng cường sức mạnh tấn công. Và khi Tonci Mujan chưa kịp phát huy khả năng thì ngoại binh Olaha bên phía SLNA đã làm \\"giúp\\". Trong một pha bóng rất vô hại ở giữa sân phút 49, trước khi bật cao tranh bóng, bàn tay của Olaha lại đưa ra có chủ ý trúng mặt Đậu Văn Toàn (số 8 - CLB Hà Nội) ngay ở góc quan sát thuận lợi của trọng tài chính Nguyễn Mạnh Hải. Và trọng tài đã lập tức rút thẻ đỏ truất quyền thi đấu của chân sút chủ lực bên phía SLNA. Một quyết định mà các cầu thủ và rất đông CĐV SLNA có mặt trên sân Hàng Đẫy có thể cho là nặng tay nhưng Olaha có lẽ chỉ biết tự trách mình. \\"Vận đen Olaha\\" chưa qua, SLNA lại phải nhận thêm một \\"đòn\\" choáng váng phút 51. Từ pha tạt bóng \\"khó chịu\\" bên cánh trái của Văn Hậu, Thái Bá Sang (số 86-SLNA) trong nỗ lực cản phá đã để bóng chạm tay trong vòng cấm và đội khách đã phải nhận phạt đền. Từ chấm 11m, Siladi đã đánh bại thủ môn Văn Hoàng, gỡ hòa 1-1 cho CLB Hà Nội. Chơi thiếu người nhưng trong khoảng thời gian sau đó, SLNA mới là đội tạo ra nhiều cơ hội khiến các CĐV Hà Nội \\"thót tim\\". Phút 60, Phan Văn Đức solo, dứt điểm táo bạo ngoài vòng cấm khiến thủ môn Tấn Trường phải bay người cứu thua. Ngay trong tình huống phạt góc sau đó, SLNA lại tạo ra một cơ hội nguy hiểm khi Xuân Mạnh đánh đầu làm thủ môn Tấn Trường bó tay nhưng trung vệ Thành Chung đã đọc tình huống cực hay, bọc lót cứu thua ngay trên vạch vôi. Khi sóng gió đã qua, điều gì phải đến cũng đã đến ở phút 76. Đúng 1 phút sau khi Văn Quyết dứt điểm đưa bóng trúng cột dọc hỏng ăn, CLB Hà Nội đã có pha phối hợp rất hiện đại. Thành Chung bật cao đánh đầu chuyền bóng cho Tonci để ngoại binh này \\"làm tường\\" ngược lại cho chính Thành Chung sút bóng nâng tỷ số lên 2-1. Khoảng thời gian 15 phút cuối trận, SLNA lực bất tòng tâm trong việc tìm cách tiếp cận khung thành thủ môn Tấn Trường, chấp nhận trắng tay rời sân Hàng Đẫy. Với cuộc lội ngược dòng thành công thắng chung cuộc 2-1, CLB Hà Nội (20 điểm) đã củng cố chắc ngôi đầu bảng, hơn nhóm 3 đội xếp sau 4 điểm gồm SLNA, HAGL, SHB.Đà Nẵng.","answer":"Kết quả vòng 10 V.League 2022: Thẻ đỏ, phạt đền khiến SLNA trắng tay trước CLB Hà Nội"},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية: وحسب تقرير \\"الجفاف بالأرقام\\" الصادر عن اتفاقية الأمم المتحدة لمكافحة التصحر عام 2022، فإن تكلفة تلف المحاصيل والعواقب الاقتصادية الأخرى للجفاف يمكن أن تكون أعلى 5 مرات مما هي عليه اليوم، إذا وصل","answer":"الاحترار العالمي إلى 3 درجات مئوية بحلول عام 2100 كما هو متوقع."},{"question":"スペインの闘牛で、マタドールがウシを誘うのに使う、棒に巻いた赤い布を何というでしょう？","answer":"ムレタ"},{"question":"మాటతీరు అంటే ఏమిటో వివరించండి.","answer":"మాటతీరు అంటే మనం మాట్లాడే విధానం. ఎప్పుడూ సున్నితంగా, మృదువుగా, చిరునవ్వుతో మాట్లాడే వారిని ఎక్కువమంది ఇష్టపడతారు. వారికి ఎక్కువ స్నేహితు లుంటారు. ఎప్పుడూ చిరాకు పడుతూ, పరుషంగా మాట్లాడే వారితో ఎవరూ కలవరు వారితో దూరంగా ఉంటారు. మానవ సంబంధాలన్నీ మనం మాట్లాడే విధానం పైనే ఆధారపడి ఉంటాయి.సుదీర్ఘకాలంగా మనిషి సంఘజీవిగా మనుగడ సాగించటం వెనుక గల అనేక అంశాలలో మాటతీరు చాలా బలమైన అంశం. ప్రతి భాషకూ కొన్ని ప్రత్యేక లక్షణాలుంటాయి. నుడికారాలు. జాతీయాలు, సామెతలు వంటివి ఆయా భాషల అస్తిత్వాన్ని ప్రతిష్ఠిస్తాయి. ఇవి భాషా సౌందర్యాన్ని ఇనుమడింప చేస్తాయి. ఈ విషయంలో మన మాతృభాష తెలుగు ఇతర భారతీయ భాషల కంటే ఇంకా కొంత విశిష్టంగా ఉంటుంది.సమాచారాలను చేరవేయ నికి మానవ సంబంధాలను మెరుగుపరుచుకోవటానికి భాషలో మనం అనేక పదాలను అలవోకగా ప్రయోగిస్తూ వుంటాం. అవి మన వ్యవహారంలో కలిసిపోయి వుంటాయి. ఈ పదాలు మన సామాజిక – సాంస్కృతిక, చారిత్రక, ఆర్థిక అంశాలతో ముడిపడి వుంటాయి. వీటిని ప్రయోగిస్తూ మాట్లాడు తున్నపుడు మన మాటతీరు ఎటువంటిదో తెలుస్తుంది."},{"question":"Qual é o signo do zodíaco associado a pessoas nascidas entre 23 de julho e 22 de agosto?","answer":"O signo do zodíaco associado a pessoas nascidas entre 23 de julho e 22 de agosto é Leão."},{"question":"السؤال: من آخر امرأة تزوجها رسول الله صلى الله عليه وسلم؟","answer":"الإجابة: ميمونة بنت الحارث"},{"question":"Dhaqanka Soomalida?","answer":"Dhaqanka Soomalida?Sheekooyinka Wiilwaal oo ay soomaalidu isu weriyaan waxaa kamid ah mar ayodayaal beeshiisa ah inta u yimaadeen isaga oo hurda ay ka xishoodeen inaykiciyaan, markii ay xaaskii Wiilwaal ka codsadeen inay u kiciso, inta dul istaagtayayay haraati ku kicisey. Xushmadda ay dumarku ku lahaayeen dhaqanka reerguuraaga soomaaliyeed, waxay ahayd mid muuqata xilli walba oo ay beeluhu kusugnaayeen. Arrintaasina waxaa laga garan karaa sida Raage Ugaas looga xaalmariyey xaaskiisii mar uu gabey wax uga sheegay. Raage, gabaygaas wuxuu kutilmaamayay falal uu quursadey oo uu gabadha ku arkey. Raage wuxuu yiri :-“Naa soow Xaliimaay Xadiyo xaalna kama raacdid,Naa soow dabkuba waa xurmee xaabo lama saaro,Naa soow ardaagaan xunka ah waana lama xaaqo,Naa soow xalid laguma dayo xeeradiyo dhiisha,Allahayoow xaraaraa anfaci xaleyto la´ isiiyey…”Aflagaaddada uu gabaygaas gaystey ayaa Raage waxaa lagu xukumay inuu gabadha siiyo kala bar magteedii oo dhan 50 halaad. Waxaa kale oo jirtey sheeko dhacdey mar Saahid Qamaan gabar uu jeclaa oo Mullaaxo la oran jiray uu nin xoolo badan leh ka qaaday. Qoyskii Saahid ayaa waxay u dooreen gabadhii qoyskooda ugu qurux badnayd si uu u illaawo Mullaaxo. Habeenkii markii gabadhii loo guri geeyay ayay gabadhii waxay istiri si uu ninku u illaawo gabadhuu jeclaa bal wax kasta oo uu uga samri karo u samee. Waxay ku dadaashay inay wax kasta oo uu jeclaysan karo horgeyso. Hufnaan sariireed, haybad dhago nugayl, haasaawe dabacsan, hooh gacanqabow, iyo heeh walaale waxaan ahayn kuma holliso. Gaarinnimo, gacalnimo,bilic gaammurtay, iyo xaal gobeed ayay gundhig uga dhigtay jeceylkeeda aangaamurin. Habeenkii danbe ayay iyada oo isleh ninku gabadhii hore ha illaawomaskaxdiisana kasaar, ayay waxay usoo dhigtay haruub si wanaagsan loo culayoo caano xoor lihi afkaa ka hayaan, waxayna soo raacisay luqmad ama oodkacay haweeney jari taqaan si wanaagsan ugu soo farayaraysatay, laguna soodaray neef yar oo xilli gu'ah jooga subaggiis, markaas ayay ku tiri, \\" Baashe balisku day xoogaagaan luqmadda ah, raallina ka noqo intaad caanaha lisiddoodasugaysay \\".  Dabadeed, inta dacalka maradeeda kusii jiidday ayay ku tiri, iskanadaa hammiga iyo walaaca aad la foorartid. Odaygii Saahid ahaa, afka ma saarinwixii cunto lasoo hordhigay. Markii ay tiri, \\" Saahid walaale maxaad cunnada uqaadan waydey, miyaad xanuunsan tahay?\\" Saahid wuxuu ku taamaygabaygaan, ay tixihiisa ka mid ahaayeen:-“…Haruub laban ah caanaha hoyaad halab karuurkeeda,Hilibka cusub haydaari iyo sogob la hoogaanshay,Habka fudud halkaan yeel ku oran hagar la'aantaada,Habkaad igu baayici kabahaad howda kaga yeerin,Haween baad tahee adiga oon hadin kobtaan joogo,Waa habbi la'aan dhuunigaad hoo ileedahaye,Hindisaha Mullaaxaa qalbigu haabo leeyahaye,Haasaawahaan qaybsannaa magac habeenkiiye,Adoon i hubsan soortaad halligi haysku hanaq goyne,Haraggayga uun baad arkiye kuuma soo hoyane”.Gabaygu wuu dheeraa laakiin gabadhii waxay la gam'i waydey habeenkaasereyga ah “Hindisaha Mullaaxaa qalbigu haabo leeyahaye, Haraggayga uun baadarkiye kuuma soo hoyane”. Waxay ogaatay in Saahid xabbad ku dhuftay, maxaayeelay waxay u qaadan waydey jacaylkii ay islahayd bal abuur oo wiilku yuusunku baabi'in jacaylkii laga qaaday, waxay kaloo istiri ninku waa qoyskaa oo ficilo ayaa ku khasabtay inay u hoyato, waxayse la kulantay dhacdadaas foosha xuniyo inuu ku caayo cunto siintii iyo raaligelintii ay ku wanaajinaysay. Habeenkaasayay goor madoow ka guuraysay, tolkii markay maqleenna sida gabadha loogalay, waxaa Saahid lagu xukumay oo laga qaaday magteedii illeen wuu dilaye."},{"question":"请介绍下支付宝","answer":"支付宝是中国最大的第三方移动和在线支付平台，由阿里巴巴集团于2004年在中国杭州创立，最初是作为阿里巴巴集团旗下淘宝网的在线支付服务平台。支付宝提供了一种快速、方便、安全的支付方式，用户可以使用支付宝进行在线购物、转账、缴费、投资等各种交易。同时，支付宝也为商家提供了一种收款的方式，可以帮助商家提高交易效率，降低运营成本。除了基础的支付功能，支付宝还推出了一系列的金融服务，如余额宝、蚂蚁花呗、蚂蚁借呗等，为用户提供了便捷的理财和信贷服务。支付宝的安全性得到了广泛认可，它采用了多重加密技术和实名制认证，有效防止了欺诈和盗窃行为。随着移动互联网的发展，支付宝已经成为中国人生活中不可或缺的一部分，无论是在线上还是线下，支付宝都在各种场景中发挥着重要的作用。"},{"question":"misy firy ny karazana sekoly ary inona avy izy ireo?","answer":"misy karazany telo ny sekoly: ny sekolim-panjakana, ny sekolim-pinoana, ary ny sekoly tsy miankina"},{"question":"ਸਾਲ 2010 ’ਚ ਆਈ ‘ਹਾਊਸਫੁੱਲ’ ਦੀ ਸਫ਼ਲਤਾ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਸਾਜਿਦ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਉਸ ਦਾ ਸੀਕੁਅਲ ‘ਹਾਊਸਫੁੱਲ-2’ ਲੈ ਕੇ ਆਏ ਹਨ ਪਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਸੀਅਤ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਕਿਰਦਾਰ ਨਵੇਂ ਹਨ। ਕਹਾਣੀ ਵੀ ਨਵੀਂ ਹੈ। ਦੋਵਾਂ ਫ਼ਿਲਮਾਂ ’ਚ ਸਮਾਨਤਾ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਇੱਕ ‘ਹਾਊਸ’ ਭਾਵ ਘਰ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਹੀ ਵਾਪਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਪਹਿਲੀ ਵਾਰ ਸਾਜਿਦ ਖ਼ਾਨ ਨੇ ਹਿੰਦੀ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਦੇ ਤਿੰਨ ਮਹਾਂਰਥੀਆਂ ਰਿਸ਼ੀ ਕਪੂਰ, ਰਣਧੀਰ ਕਪੂਰ ਅਤੇ ਮਿਥੁਨ ਚੱਕਰਵਰਤੀ ਨੂੰ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਬਣਾਇਆ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੇ ਨਾਲ ਆਸਿਨ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਐਂਟਰੀ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਸਾਜਿਦ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਬਚਪਨ ਤੋਂ ਮਿਥੁਨ ਦੇ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ੰਸਕ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਤੇ ਉਸ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਹਰ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇਖੀ ਹੈ। ਬਚਪਨ ’ਚ ਮੈਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਨਕਲ ਕਰਿਆ ਕਰਦਾ ਸੀ। ਸਾਜਿਦ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਪਰਿਵਾਰਕ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਬਣਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਨਿਰਦੇਸ਼ਕ ਦੇ ਰੂਪ ’ਚ ‘ਬ੍ਰਾਂਡ’ ਬਣ ਚੁੱਕਿਆ ਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਬਦਲਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ।ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ‘ਹਾਊਸਫੁੱਲ -2’ ਇੱਕ ਦਰਜਨ ਡਰਟੀ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਕਾਰਨਾਮਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਦਾਸਤਾਨ ਹੈ। ਇਹ ਕਹਾਣੀ ਚਾਰ ਪਿਤਾ, ਚਾਰ ਧੀਆਂ ਤੇ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਚਾਰ ਜਵਾਈਆਂ ਦੁਆਲੇ ਘੁੰਮਦੀ ਹੈ। ਹਰੇਕ ਪਿਤਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਧੀ ਦਾ ਵਿਆਹ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਅਮੀਰ ਇਨਸਾਨ ਨਾਲ ਹੋਵੇ ਤੇ ਹਰ ਧੀ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਇਹੀ ਇੱਛਾ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਚਾਰੇ ਜਵਾਈ ਇਹੀ ਦਿਖਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਅਮੀਰ ਜਵਾਈ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਸਭ ਕਾਰਨ ਹਾਸਰਸ ਘਟਨਾਵਾਂ ਵਾਪਰਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਮਜ਼ੇਦਾਰ ਗੱਲ ਇਹ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਇੱਕ-ਦੂਜੇ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਨਾ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਇੱਕ ਘਰ ’ਚ ਇੱਕ ਛੱਤ ਹੇਠ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ ਇੱਕ-ਦੂਜੇ ਨੂੰ ਮਾਤ ਦੇਣ ਬਾਰੇ ਸੋਚਦੇ ਹਨ।‘ਹਾਊਸਫੁੱਲ-2’ ਦੀ ਇੱਕ ਖ਼ਾਸੀਅਤ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਮਿਤਾਭ ਬੱਚਨ ਤੇ ਵਿਨੋਦ ਖੰਨਾ ਦੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਅਕਸ਼ੈ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਤੇ ਜਾੱਨ ਅਬਰਾਹਿਮ ਦੇ ਆਪਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੜਨ ਦੇ ਦ੍ਰਿਸ਼ ਹਨ। ਇਸ ਵੱਡੇ ਬਜਟ ਦੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਦੇ ਨਿਰਮਾਤਾ ਸਾਜਿਦ ਨਾਡਿਆਡਵਾਲਾ ਦਾ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਵੱਡੇ ਪੱਧਰ ਦੀ ਵੱਡੇ ਬਜਟ ਵਾਲੀ ਤੇ ਐਨੇ ਕਲਾਕਾਰਾਂ ਵਾਲੀ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਅੱਜ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਮਾਨੇ ’ਚ ਬਣਾਉਣਾ ਸੌਖਾ ਨਹੀਂ।ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ’ਚ ਰਿਸ਼ੀ ਕਪੂਰ, ਰਣਧੀਰ ਕਪੂਰ, ਮਿਥੁਨ ਚੱਕਰਵਰਤੀ, ਰਣਜੀਤ, ਬੋਮਨ ਈਰਾਨੀ, ਅਕਸ਼ੈ ਕੁਮਾਰ, ਜਾੱਨ ਅਬਰਾਹਿਮ, ਰਿਤੇਸ਼ ਦੇਸ਼ਮੁੱਖ, ਸ਼੍ਰੇਆਸ ਤਲਪੜੇ, ਆਸਿਨ, ਜੈਕਲਿਨ ਫਰਨਾਂਡੇਜ਼, ਸ਼ਹਿਜਾਨ ਪਦਮਸੀ, ਜਾਨੀ ਲੀਵਰ, ਚੰਕੀ ਪਾਂਡੇ, ਵਿਰੇਂਦਰ ਸਕਸੈਨਾ ਆਦਿ ਕਲਾਕਾਰ ਕੰਮ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।ਇਹ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਸਿਨੇਮਾ ਘਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਸ਼ਿੰਗਾਰ ਬਣ ਚੁੱਕੀ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਨਾਲ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਇਸ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ ਨੂੰ  ਦਰਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਚੰਗਾ ਹੁਲਾਰਾ ਮਿਲ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ।ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਨਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ  ‘ਹਾਊਸਫੁੱਲ-2’ ਕਿਸ ਪ੍ਰਕਾਰ ਦੀ ਹੈ?","answer":"ਉੱਤਰਃ ਫ਼ਿਲਮ  ‘ਹਾਊਸਫੁੱਲ-2’  ਕਾਮੇਡੀ ਨਾਲ ਭਰਪੂਰ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"මෙම සිංහල කතන්දරයට සුදුසු මාතෘකාවක් දෙන්න. ඔන්න ඉන්දියාවේ ගමක පියෙක් හා පුතෙක් තමන්ගේ බූරුවාද සමඟ ගමනක් යාමට පිටත් වුණා. මේ දෙදෙනා ටික දුරක් ඉදිරියට යන විට, බූරුවකු පිට නැගී, ගමනක් යන මිනිසකු ඔවුන් ට මුණ ගැසුණා.\\"මේ තාත්තයි පුතයි මොන මෝඩයෝ දෙන්නෙක්ද ? බූරුවා පිට උඩ යන්නේ නැතුව මොන එහෙකටද බුරුවෙක් එක්ක යන්නේ.\\" යැයි මේ මිනිසා ඔච්ච්ච්මට කියාගෙන ගියා. ඉතින් මේ ගැන කල්පනා කල තාත්තා, තම පුතාව බූරුවා පිට උඩට නංවා ගමන යාමට පිටත් වුණා. ඉතින් ඔහොම තව ටික දුරක් මේ දෙදෙනා ගමන් කළා. යන අතරමගදී තවත් මිනිසුන් පිරිසක් මොවුන්ට මුණ ගැසුණා. එම පිරිස මේ දෙදෙනා දෙස බලා \\"අනේ මෙහෙමත් කම්මැලි ළමයෙක්. වැඩිහිටියන්ට ගරු කරන්න දන්නෙ නෑ. තාත්තා බූරුවා දක්කන් යනවා.ළමයා හොඳට බූරුවගෙ පිට උඩ යනවා\\" කියා සිනා සෙමින් කතා වෙන්නට වුණා. තාත්තා ටික දුරක් ගොස් පුතා ව බූරුවා පිටින් බස්වා, ඔහු බූරුවා ගේ පිට උඩ නැග ගමන් ගන්නට වුණා. මෙහෙම තවත් ටික දුරක් ගමන් කළා. නැවතත් මේ දෙදෙනාට පාරේ ගමන් ගන්නා පිරිසක් හමු වුණා. \\"අනේ අද කාලේ ඉන්න තාත්තලා ගේ හැටි. තමන්ගේ ළමයා පයින් යනවා.තාත්තා හොඳහැටි බූරුවගෙ පිට උඩ යනවා. ළමයින්ට ආදරේ නැති මිනිස්සු\\" කියා බනිමින් එම පිරිස ද යන්න ගියා. මේ කතාව ඇසූ පියා දරුවාද බූරුවාගේ පිට උඩ නංවාගෙන තවත් දුර ගමන් කරන්න වුණා. තව දුර යනකොට ආයෙමත් තවත් පුද්ගලයෙක් මුණගැසුණා. \\"මෙහෙමත් මිනිස්සු.!! අර අහිංසක බූරුවාගේ පිටේ තාත්තයි පුතයි දෙන්නම යන අපූරුව. මේ බූරුව ට මොනතරම් අමාරු ඇද්ද ? හිතක් පපුවක් නෑ.\\" කියා කියමින් යන්න ගියා. අන්තිමේදී, මේ තාත්තයි පුතයි දෙන්නා ට බූරුවා කරපිට තියාගෙන යන්න සිදු වුණා.මගදී හම්බෙන හැමෝම මේ දෙන්නට හිනා වුණා. හැමෝම කියන කියන විදිහට ඉන්න ගියාම තමයි මෙවැනි වැඩ සිදු වෙන්නේ. ","answer":"පියා, පුතා සහ බූරුවාගේ ගමන"},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Những chiếc siêu xe, xe siêu sang hàng chục tỷ đồng luôn là niềm ao ước của nhiều người. Tuy nhiên, việc sở hữu một chiếc xe như vậy không chỉ là mua về và sử dụng mà còn liên quan đến hàng loạt các vấn đề khác đủ để khiến chủ nhân từ cảm thấy \\"sướng run người\\" mỗi khi cầm lái trở nên lo âu. Hạ tầng, mật độ giao thông Tuy hạ tầng giao thông có thể nói là không còn khó khăn để những chiếc siêu xe gầm thấp di chuyển như hồi mới được đưa về Việt Nam. Tuy nhiên, vẫn còn đó nhiều khó khăn để những chiếc xe này có thể đi thoải mái. Chất lượng đường không tốt mang đến cảm giác không thoải mái khi sử dụng xe, đồng thời khiến các chi tiết cơ khí, điện tử ở hệ thống treo hoạt động nhiều hơn. Mặt khác, mật độ giao thông đông đúc tại các thành phố lớn (nơi tập trung hầu hết xe đắt tiền tại nước ta) cũng là một vấn đề mà các chủ xe phải bận tâm. Điều này khiến chủ sở hữu trở nên e dè mỗi khi xuống phố do lo ngại va quẹt. Chất lượng nhiên liệu Tại Việt Nam, loại nhiên liệu cao cấp nhất hiện tại là xăng RON 97, một loại nhiên liệu phù hợp với những chiếc siêu xe, xe sang đắt tiền. Tuy nhiên, loại nhiên liệu này vẫn chưa được phổ biến và đa số vẫn phải dùng xăng RON 95. Với những chủ nhân kỹ tính, RON 95 vẫn chưa phù hợp và có thể sẽ gây hư hỏng về sau cho xe của họ. Để khắc phục, những người này thường sử dụng phụ gia tăng octane cho xăng. Cơ sở bảo dưỡng Siêu xe, xe sang đắt tiền tại Việt Nam đa phần được được về bởi các đơn vị nhập khẩu tư nhân chứ không phải là các đơn vị phân phối ủy quyền và thậm chí là có mặt trước khi đại lý được mở tại Việt Nam. Điều này khiến cho các chủ xe phải sử dụng dịch vụ bảo dưỡng, bảo trì tại các gara bên ngoài thay vì gửi chiếc xe cho những chuyên gia được đào tạo bởi hãng. Mặc dù các hãng xe sang, siêu xe phổ biến đã đều có","answer":"mặt tại nước ta, phần nhiều chủ xe vẫn sử dụng các dịch vụ đến từ gara bên ngoài. Sở dĩ có tình trạng này là do các gara ngoài đã quá quen với chủ nhân xe, giá cả hợp lý hơn so với chi phí mà chủ nhân phải bỏ ra khi vào hãng. Bên cạnh đó, những chiếc xe mua không chính hãng phải buộc mua thêm gói dịch vụ mới có thể được các chuyên gia chính hãng chăm sóc. Bảo hiểm Cuối cùng, là những chiếc xe trị giá ngang những căn biệt thự, biệt phủ nhưng những chiếc xe này thường ít khi nào được mua bảo hiểm. Vấn đề đến từ việc giá bảo hiểm hai chiều cho chúng khá \\"chát\\", khoảng 1,5% giá trị xe khiến những gói bảo hiểm mỗi năm có thể lên đến hàng trăm triệu đồng. Đồng thời, khi xảy ra sự cố, các công ty bảo hiểm thường giải quyết chậm chạp cũng là lý do khiến các chủ xe không muốn mua bảo hiểm. Mặt khác, những chiếc siêu xe đắt tiền thường chỉ được cho xuống phố vài lần mỗi tháng, từ đó cũng giảm thiểu khả năng xảy ra sự cố của chúng trong một năm./. https://vov.vn/o-to-xe-may/o-to/so-huu-sieu-xe-chuc-ty-tuong-suong-ma-khong-he-suong-post960078.vov Trang Thông tin điện tử Docbao.vn Công ty Cổ phần Quang Minh Việt Nam Giấy phép thiết lập Trang thông tin điện tử tổng hợp trên Internet số 2372/GP-STTTT cấp ngày 29/8/2014. SĐT: 024. 666.40816 Địa chỉ: P604, Tầng 6, Tòa nhà Golden Field, Khu đô thị mới Mỹ Đình 1, phường Cầu Diễn, quận Nam Từ Liêm, Hà Nội Chịu trách nhiệm nội dung: Điều Thị Bích; ĐT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn Đọc báo trực tuyến hiện tại chỉ sử dụng tên miền duy nhất là docbao.vn; độc giả lưu ý tránh nhầm lẫn. Chính sách bảo mật RSS"},{"question":"ભારતીય સ્વતંત્રતા ચળવળ વિષે માહિતી આપો.","answer":"ભારતીય સ્વતંત્રતા ચળવળ એ ભારતમાં બ્રિટીશ શાસનનો અંત લાવવાના અંતિમ ઉદ્દેશ સાથે ચલાવવામાં આવેલી ઐતિહાસિક લડતની ઘટનાઓની શ્રેણી હતી. આ ચળવળ ૧૮૫૭ થી ૧૯૪૭ સુધી ચાલી હતી. ભારતીય સ્વતંત્રતા માટેની પહેલી રાષ્ટ્રવાદી ક્રાંતિકારી ચળવળ બંગાળમાં શરૂ થઈ.  ત્યાર બાદ અગ્રણી મવાળ નેતાઓ સાથે નવી રચાયેલી ભારતીય રાષ્ટ્રીય કોંગ્રેસ થકી ભારતીય સનદી સેવાની (સિવિલ સર્વિસ) પરીક્ષાઓ આપવાના મૂળભૂત અધિકારની અને દેશવાસી માટે વધુ અધિકારોની (મુખ્યત્વે આર્થિક) માંગણી કરતી ચળવળો દ્વારા સ્વતંત્રતાની ચળવળના મૂળ વધુ ઊંડા ઉતર્યા. ૨૦ મી સદીના પ્રારંભિક કાળમાં લાલ બાલ પાલ (ત્રિનેતા) , અરબિંદો ઘોષ અને વી.ઓ. ચિદમ્બરમ પિલ્લાઈ જેવા નેતાઓના માર્ગદર્શન હેઠળ આ ચળાવળે વ્યાપક રાજકીય સ્વરૂપ ધારણ કર્યું અને તે સ્વરાજ્યની માંગણી તરફ વળી. ૧૯૨૦ ના દાયકાથી સ્વરાજ્યની લડતના છેલ્લા તબક્કામાં કોંગ્રેસે મહાત્મા ગાંધીના અહિંસા, સવિનય કાનૂન ભંગ અને અન્ય એવા ઘણા અન્ય અભિયાનો અપનાવ્યા હતા. સુભાષચંદ્ર બોઝ, ભગતસિંહ, ભગત સિંહ, સૂર્ય સેન જેવા રાષ્ટ્રવાદી ક્રંતિકારીઓએ સ્વ-શાસન મેળવવા માટે સશસ્ત્ર ક્રાંતિનો ઉપદેશ આપ્યો હતો. રવીન્દ્રનાથ ટાગોર, સુબ્રમણ્યા ભારતી, બંકિમચંદ્ર ચટ્ટોપાધ્યાય અને કાઝી નઝરૂલ ઈસ્લામ જેવા કવિઓ અને લેખકો રાજકીય જાગૃતિ માટેના સાધન તરીકે સાહિત્ય, કાવ્ય અને ભાષણનો ઉપયોગ કરતા હતા. સરોજિની નાયડુ, પ્રીતીલતા વાડ્ડેદર, બેગમ રોકેયા જેવી નારીવાદી નેતાઓએ ભારતીય મહિલાઓની મુક્તિ અને રાષ્ટ્રીય રાજકારણમાં તેમની ભાગીદારીને પ્રોત્સાહન આપ્યું. બી.આર. આંબેડકરે વધુ સ્વરાજ્યની ચળવળમાં ભારતીય સમાજના વંચિત વર્ગના મુદ્દાને વણી લીધો.  બીજા વિશ્વયુદ્ધના દરમ્યાન જાપાનની મદદથી સુભાષચંદ્ર બોઝની આગેવાની હેઠળની ભારતની રાષ્ટ્રીય સૈન્યની ચળવળ અને કોંગ્રેસની આગેવાની હેઠળના ભારત છોડો આંદોલન એ આ ચળવળનો ચરમકાળ હતો. "},{"question":"Mi ake nufi da \\"light\\" da Hausa? \\t\\t","answer":"Tana nufin \\"wuta\\"\\t\\t\\t\\t"},{"question":"यदि राष्ट्रपति का पद खाली हो, तो उसे कितनी अवधि के अन्दर भरना आवश्यक होता है ?","answer":"राष्ट्रपति का पद यदि ख़ाली हो, तो उसे ६ महीने में भरना आवश्यक होता है।"},{"question":"Kedu mgbe emere steeti Adamawa?","answer":"E mere ya na 27 Ọgọọst 1991"},{"question":"Kí ni àpẹẹrẹ ọ̀rọ̀ tí a fi àfòmọ́ ìbéèrè ṣẹ̀dá?","answer":"Àpẹẹrẹ kan ni 'Awakọ̀'."},{"question":"મને મનીષ વઘાસિયા એક પ્રેરક વક્તા વિશે કહો.","answer":"મનીષ વઘાસિયા એક જીવન કોચ અને પ્રેરક વક્તા છે જે વ્યક્તિગત પરિવર્તન પર ધ્યાન કેન્દ્રિત કરવા માટે જાણીતા છે. તે 'માનસ લાઈફ કોચ' સંસ્થાના સ્થાપક છે, જે વ્યક્તિગત વિકાસ અને સ્વ-શોધ પર કોચિંગ પ્રોગ્રામ્સ, વર્કશોપ અને સેમિનાર ઓફર કરે છે."},{"question":"Inona no tena loharanon'ny entona mampidi-doza avy amin'ny fiara?1-karbônina (CO)2-gazy karbonika (CO2)3-Metana (CH4)","answer":"Valiny: 2Ny gazy karbonika (CO2) dia zava-doza ho an'ny fomba fiainan'ny olombelona."},{"question":"Sidee ayaa loo maareyn karaa walwalka oo maxaan sameyn karaa anigu?","answer":"Waxa caadi ah in la rabo in la baxsado marka uu walwalku kuu yimaado. In waxa xun la iska dhowro ayaa ah mid biniaadamku sameeyo. Laakiin walwalku iskama tago kalliya iyadoo la iska ilaalinaayo uun, waxa dhacda taas mid liddi ku ah. Hab wanaagsan oo la iskaga ilaaliyo walwalku waa iyadoo la ogolaado kaas, xaalada laga helo oo aan la isku deyin inaan laga baxsan. Haddii aad awoodi karto ayaa inta badan walwalku dhakhso iskaga tagaa, iyadoo marka danbe ay ka sii dhib yaraan karto in la maareeyo.Waxa caawisa in qof lagala hadlo sida aad dareemeyso. In laga hadalo ayaa inta badan ay talaabada ugu horeysa ee lagaga roonaanaayo. Waxaad sidoo kale ka baran kartaa wax badan oo ku saabsan walwalka adigoo akhriya waxyaalaja ku sabsan walwalka iyo sida loo daaweyn karo.Istareeska iyo walwalkaayaa inta badan wada socda. Haddii aad isku daydo inaad cunto, seexato oo aad sameyso waxyaalaha aad jeceshahay, ayuu sii badanayaa iska caabinta aad yeelaneyso istareeska iyo walwalka. Qeyb kale oo muhiim ah waa in maya la odhan karro oo la xadeeyo waxyaala aah awoodi karo."},{"question":"2015 டிசம்பரில் அமெரிக்காவிலிருந்து எந்த விண்வெளி நிறுவனம் ராக்கெட்டை பூமிக்கு கொண்டு வந்தது?","answer":"நாசா எனப்படுவது ஐக்கிய அமெரிக்காவின் விண்வெளி ஆய்வு அமைப்பாகும். இது அமெரிக்காவின் விண்வெளி ஆய்வு மற்றும் வானூர்தியியல், விண்ணூர்தியியல் ஆராயச்சிகளின் கட்டுப்பாட்டு மற்றும் நிர்வாக அமைப்பாகும். இது 1958 ஜூலை 29 அன்று தேசிய வானூர்தியியல் மற்றும் விண்வெளிச் சட்டத்தின் கீழ் நிறுவப்பட்டது. இது இதற்கு முன் வானூர்தியியல் ஆராயச்சிகளுக்காக இருந்த, தேசிய வானூர்தியியல் ஆலோசனை செயற்குழுவைக் ( நாகா) கலைத்து அதன் வடிவில் நிறுவப்பட்டது. இதன் ஆண்டு வரவு செலவு, 2012 இல் 17.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள் ஆகும்.துறை மேலோட்டம்:அமைப்பு: ஜூலை 29,1958 ; 64 ஆண்டுகள் முன்னர்முன்பிருந்த அமைப்பு: நாசா (1915–1958)ஆட,சி எல்லை: அமெரிக்க அரசுதலைமையகம்: வாஷிங்டன்,டி.சி.பணியாட்கள்: 18,800 பேர்ஆண்டு நிதி :17.8 பில்லியன் அமெரிக்க டாலர்கள்அமைப்பு தலைமைகள்: சார்லஸ் போல்டன், நிர்வாகி. லோரீ கார்வெர், துணை நிர்வாகிவலைத்தளம்: nasa govபிப்ரவரி 2006- லிருந்து விண்வெளி ஆய்வு, அறிவியல் ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் வானூர்தியியல் ஆராய்சிகளில் எதிர்காலத்துக்கான முன்னோடியாக இருத்தல் என்பது நாசாவின் தாரக மந்திரமாகவுள்ளது. செப்டம்பர் 14, 2011 அன்று, புதிய விண்வெளி ஏவுத் தொகுதியின் வடிவமைப்பைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்துள்ளதாக அறிவித்துள்ளது. இதன் மூலம் அமெரிக்க விண்வெளி வீர்ர்கள் விண்வெளியில் இதுவரை செல்லவியலாத தொலைவுகளுக்கெல்லாம் செல்லவியலும் எனவும், எதிர்காலத்தில் மனிதர் செல்லும் விண்வெளி ஆய்வுகளுக்குப் புதுபெரும் தொடக்கமாக இருக்குமெனவும் நாசா அறிவித்துள்ளது.அக்டோபர் 1 1958 அன்று செயல்படத் தொடங்கிய இவ்வமைப்பு, அன்றிலிருந்து அமெரிக்காவின் விண்வெளி ஆய்வுகளைச் செய்து வருகறது. குறிப்பாக அப்பல்லோ திட்டம், விண்ணாய்வகம் எனும் விண்வெளி நிலையம், விண்ணோடத் திட்டங்களைச் செயல்படுத்தியுள்ளது. தற்போது அனைத்துலக விண்வெளி நிலையத்துக்கு பலவிதங்களில் ஆதரவளித்து வருகிறது. ஓரியான் பல்நோக்க குழு வாகனம் மற்றும் வணிகரீதியிலான குழு மேம்பாடு போன்ற திட்டங்களை முன்னெடுத்துச் செய்து வருகிறது. மேலும் ஆளற்ற விண்பயண ஏவுதல்கள் அனைத்தையும் இதுவே கண்காணிக்கிறது.புவி அவதானிப்புத் தொகுதி மூலம் புவியை மேலும் புரிந்து கொள்ளுதல், அறிவியல் திட்ட இயக்குநரகத்தின் பரிதியியற்பியல் ஆராய்ச்சித் திட்டத்தின் கீழ் பரிதியியற்பியல் ஆய்வுகளை மேற்கொள்ளுதல், சூரியக் குடும்பத்திலுள்ள ஒவ்வொரு உறுப்புக்களைப் பற்றியும் ஆளற்ற விண்ணுலவிகள் அனுப்பி ஆராய்ந்தறிதல், பெரு வெடிப்புக் கோட்பாடு போன்ற வானியற்பியல் கோட்பாடுகளை ஆராய்வது போன்ற பணிகளை நாசா செய்து வருகிறது. மேலும் இவ்வமைப்பு கண்டறியும் தரவுத்தொகுப்புகளைப் பலநாடுகளின் அமைப்புகளோடும் பங்கீடும் செய்கிறது. விண்வெளித் திட்டங்கள் தவிர இராணுவ விண்வெளி ஆய்வுகளையும் இவ்வமைப்பு மேற்கொள்ளுகிறது.இந்த நாசா விண்வெளி ஆராய்சிக்குரிய நிதி ஒதுக்கீட்டை அமெரிக் அரசே அளித்து வருகிறது.நாசாவின் பிரதிநிதியாக தலைமை விஞ்ஞானி பிரதிபலிப்பார்.நாசாவின் நிதிநிலை அறிக்கையில் தேவையான ஆலோசனைகள் வழங்குதல், மூலோபாய இலக்குகளை நிர்ணயித்தல், நாசாவின் நடப்புத்திட்டங்களின் உள்ளடக்கத்தை நெறிப்படுத்துதல் போன்ற செயல்பாடுகளுக்காகவே தலைமை விஞ்ஞானி என்ற நிலை நாசாவில் உருவாக்கப்பட்டது. மூலோபாய முயற்சிகள் மற்றும் கள் மையங்களில் நாசாவின் பிரதிநிதியாக தலைமை விஞ்ஞானி நெருக்கமாகப் பணிபுரிவார். இவைமட்டுமின்றி ஆலோசனைக்குழு, வெளிப்புற சமூகத் தொடர்பு ஆகியவற்றிலும் இவர் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிப்பார். முகமையின் அறிவியல் நோக்கங்கள் மற்றும் பிற கூட்டாட்சி நிறுவனங்களின் சாதனைகள், தொழிற்சாலை, கல்வி, ஏனைய அரசாங்க நிறுவனங்கள், சர்வதேச சமூகம் மற்றும் பொதுமக்கள் ஆகியோருக்கு நாசாவின் பிரதிநிதியாக தலைமை விஞ்ஞானி பிரதிபலிப்பார்."},{"question":"¿De qué está hecha la seda artificial?","answer":"A diferencia de la seda natural, que se fabrica a partir de los capullos de los gusanos de seda, la seda artificial se produce tratando químicamente e hilando fibras naturales como pulpa de madera, bambú o algodón. El tejido resultante es muy similar a la seda en cuanto a aspecto y tacto, pero a un coste mucho menor. La seda artificial es también más versátil que la seda real y puede teñirse en una amplia gama de colores. También es más transpirable y absorbente que la seda auténtica. Sin embargo, es más propensa a arrugarse y encogerse, y puede no durar tanto como la seda auténtica."},{"question":"கேள்வி:சங்க இலக்கிய வரலாறு  குறித்து கட்டுரை வரைக:","answer":"பதில்:       மொழிகளில் மிகவும் பழமையானது என போற்றப்படும் தமிழ் மொழியானது பல்லாயிரம் வருட கால இலக்கண, இலக்கியங்களை கொண்ட அமைந்ததாகவே காணப்படுகின்றது.  தமிழ் மொழியினுடைய இலக்கிய வரலாறு என்பது மிகவும் நீண்ட காலத்துக்குரியதாகவே காணப்படுகின்றது. இதில் முதன்மையான இலக்கிய வரலாற்றுக் காலமாகவே இந்த சங்க காலம் திகழ்கின்றது.குறிப்பு சட்டகம்:முன்னுரைசங்ககால புலவர்கள்சங்ககால இலக்கியங்கள்சங்க இலக்கியங்கள் கூறும் அறக்கருத்துக்கள்சங்க கால இலக்கியங்களில் தென்படும் தமிழர் வாழ்வியல்முடிவுரைமுன்னுரை:       எம்முடைய தாய்மொழியான தமிழில் தோன்றிய இலக்கியங்களில் மிகவும் பழமையானவையும் சிறப்புக்கள் நிறைந்தவையாகவும் காணப்படுபவை சங்க காலத்தில் தோன்றிய இலக்கியங்கள் ஆகும். இந்த சங்க காலம் மூன்று வகையான காலப்பகுதிகளாக காணப்படுகின்றது. இக்காலப் பகுதியில் அகத்தினை புறத்தினை சார்ந்த பதினெண் மேல் கணக்கு நூல்கள் எழுந்தன இவை காலத்தால் அழியாச் சிறப்புடைவையாக திகழ்கின்றன.சங்க கால புலவர்கள்:       சங்ககால இலக்கியங்கள் யாவும் புகழ்பெற்ற புலவர்களினாலே இயற்றப்பட்டுள்ளன. அக்காலப் புலவர்கள் சங்ககால மன்னர்களினால் ஆதரிக்கப்பட்டு வந்தவர்களாவர். இவ்வாறாக சங்க காலதில் சிறந்த இலக்கியங்களை இயற்றிய புலவர்களுள் ஒளவையார், பரணர், கணியன் பூங்குன்றன், நக்கீரர், கபிலர் போன்றோரை குறிப்பிடலாம்.சங்க காலத்து இலக்கியங்கள்:சங்க காலத்தில் எழுந்த இலக்கியங்ளை எட்டுத்தொகை, பத்துப்பாட்டு என வகைப்படுத்தி உள்ளனர். மேலும் பொருள் அடிப்படையில் சங்க கால இலக்கியங்கள் அகத்திணை புறத்திணை சார்ந்த இலக்கியங்கள் என வேறுபடுத்தப்படுகின்றன. இங்கு அகம் எனப்படுவது பொதுவாக காதல் பற்றிய செய்திகளை குறிப்பிடுவதாகும். புறம் எனப்படுவது கொடை, வீரம் போன்றவற்றினை எடுத்துக்காட்டுவதாகவும் காணப்படுகின்றது.சங்ககால இலக்கியங்கள் கூறும் அறக்கருத்துக்கள்:சங்க காலம் என்பது பொதுவாகவே அகம், புறம் சார் இலக்கியங்களின் தோற்ற காலமாகும்.அதாவது இங்கு புறம் எனப்படுவது மன்னர்களுடைய போர்ஒழுக்கம் பற்றியாகும். மன்னர்கள் எதிர் நாட்டின் மீது படையெடுத்து அந்நாட்டை கைப்பற்றவும் செய்தனர். இதனால் அங்கு நிறைய உயிர்ச்சேதங்கள், பொருட்சேதங்கள் இடம்பெறுகின்றன.  இவ்வாறான செயல்களில் இருந்து மக்களை மீட்டி நல்வழிப்படுத்தும் வகையிலேயே புலவர்கள் அறக்கருத்துக்கள் நிறைந்த இலக்கியங்களையும் செய்யுள்களையும் எழுத ஆரம்பித்தனர்.  அந்த வகையில் “யாதும் மூரே யாவரும் கேளிர்…..” என்ற புகழ்பெற்ற பாடல் வரிகளின் ஊடாக மனிதனுக்கு தேவையான அறங்கள் அனைத்தையும் போதித்துள்ளமையை காண முடியும்.சங்ககால இலக்கியங்களில் தென்படும் தமிழர் வாழ்வியல்:தமிழர்களுக்கு என வாழ்வியல், வரலாறு, இலக்கியம் என்பன காணப்படுகின்றது என்பதனை உலக அரங்களவில் எடுத்து காட்டியுள்ளது என்றால் அது சங்க இலக்கியங்கள் தான் என்பதில் மிகை இல்லை. பண்டைத் தமிழர்களது போர், வீரம், கொடை, காதல் போன்றவற்றை மிகவும் அழகான முறையில் எடுத்துக்காட்டுவனவாக இந்த சங்க காலத்து இலக்கியங்கள் காணப்படுகின்றன. மேலும் அறத்தோடு இணைந்த தமிழர்களின் வாழ்வியலை எடுத்துக்காட்டுகின்றன. அதாவது பிறருக்கு தானம் செய்ய வேண்டும், உறவினர்களுக்கு உதவி செய்ய வேண்டும், ஏமாற்ற கூடாது போன்றவற்றினைக் குறிப்பிடலாம்.முடிவுரை:சங்க காலம் பற்றியும் சங்ககாலத்து புலவர்களின் கவிநயம் மற்றும் ஆற்றல் பற்றியும் எமக்கு எடுத்துச் சொல்வதாகவே இந்த சங்க காலத்தில் இலக்கியங்கள் அமையப் பெறுகின்றன. எம்முடைய முன்னோர்களது வாழ்வியலை தற்காலத்தில் வாழக்கூடிய இளம் சமூகத்தினரும் கற்று அறிந்து கொள்வதற்கான ஓர் அடிப்படையாகவே இந்த சங்க காலத்து இலக்கியங்கள் காணப்படுகின்றன என்பது குறிப்பிடத்தக்க விடயமாகும்."},{"question":"\\"වසන්තයේ මල් සුපිපුණ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ","answer":"වසන්තයේ මල් සුපිපුණසුන්දරතාවය ඉහිරුණහද මඬලට කවුදෝ ආවාහද දුක ගාවා කවුදෝ ආවාමල්පෙති සිඹ සිනා රැගෙනමල සිඳ බිඳ යන්ට ගියාහද දුක ගාවා කවුදෝ ආවාහස අංගනාවන්සේසඳ දිය මැද කිමිදීකිරි සිහිනෙක මා රඳවාකොහිදෝ බැඳුනේනීල කැලුම් ගලා හැලෙනඉඳුනිල් මිණි දෑස වසාමගෙ දෝතට නෑවිත් නුඹකොහිදෝ බැඳුනේහිරු මැලවුණ හැන්දෑවේ අඳුරට ගුලි වීමධු බඳුනට හාදු දිදී හිඳිනා යාමේනෙතු කඳුලින් බොඳ කළ ඒඅතීතයේ හීන පැලටමා කැඳවා යන්නට නුඹඇයිදෝ ආවේඉමාන් පෙරේරාතිළිණ රුවන් මලලසේකරරංජිත් සුධර්මන් "},{"question":"Sheeg xilligii uu Madaxweynaha ahaa C/qaasim Salaad Xasan?","answer":" Wuxuu ahaa intii  u dhaxeysay 27/08/2000 – 14/10/2004."},{"question":"Ngizw' imvunge yeminyezane,Izwakal' ezinkwazini zoMhlathuze,Iqongel' ezintabeni zoNgoye,Ingikhumbuz' amaqhawe namaqhawekaziAdl' umhlanganiso kwaNgqondebanzi,Evath' iminyezane yobuhlakaniAhlahl' indlela yakwaLwaziEhanjwa ngokuzinikela zikhuthali.Ngizw' imvunge yeminyezane,Izwakal' osebeni loMngeni,Naphakath' ezizibeni zoMngeniOkubhukud' amaqhawe namaqhawekazi,Evunul' izidlodlo zenhlonipho,Avunul' ezegwalagwala zekhethelo,Kwahlokom' umhlaba ngenhlokomo,Kwenanel' imvelo ngemvunge.Ngizw' imvunge yeminyezane,Ngavul' izindlebe zakhongozelaUnqambothi lobuzwilili baphakade,Ngaqanul' amaqaphelo ngasingaIzimangaliso zemikhiqizo yakwaNgqondebanzi:Zihlinzek' ubuntu nobunye,Zahlinzek' ubuqotho nesineke,Zahlinzek' inhlonipho nenkuthalo.1. Chaza ngokukhethwa kwala magama alandelayo asenkondlweni ukuthiawuthinta kanjani umoya wenkondlo. Umhlanganiso, Iminyezane. ","answer":"Umoya wokutusa. Uma sebenqobile (umhlanganiso) bafunda bagogodabagqoka amajazi emfundo(iminyezane). "},{"question":"Tính các biểu thức sau một cách hợp lí:a) (– 16) . (– 7) . 5; b) 11. (– 12) + 11. (– 18);c) 87. (– 19) – 37 . (– 19); d) 41 . 81 .(– 451). 0.","answer":"a) (– 16) . (– 7) . 5 = [(– 16) . 5] . (– 7)          (tính chất giao hoán và kết hợp)= [– (16 . 5)] . (– 7) = (– 80) . (– 7)= 80 . 7 = 560. b) 11 . (– 12) + 11 . (– 18) = 11 . [(– 12) + (– 18)]     (tính chất phân phối của phép nhân đối với phép cộng)= 11 . [– (12 + 18)] = 11 . (– 30) = – (11 . 30) = – 330.  c) 87 . (– 19) – 37 . (– 19) = (– 19) . (87 – 37)          (tính chất phân phối của phép nhân đối với phép trừ)= (– 19) . 50 = – (19 . 50) = – 950. d) 41 . 81 . (– 451) . 0 = 0.         (tính chất phép nhân một số với 0) Hoặc chúng ta có thể làm lần lượt từng bước như sau: 41 . 81 . (– 451) . 0 = 41 . 81 . [(– 451) . 0]     (tính chất kết hợp)= 41 . 81 . 0           (tính chất phép nhân một số với 0)= 41 . (81 . 0)         (tính chất kết hợp)= 41 . 0 = 0.           (tính chất phép nhân một số với 0)"},{"question":"Motorlu Taşıtlar Vergisi hangi bankalar alıyor?","answer":"Motorlu Taşıtlar Vergisi ödemenizi Halkbank Mobil, İnternet Şubesi, Halkbank Dialog ve ATM'lerimizden hızlı ve zaman kaybetmeden hesabınızdan veya kredi kartınızdan kolayca gerçekleştirebilirsiniz."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air diminum rasa duri, nasi dimakan rasa sekam\\"?","answer":"Dikatakan bkn orang yang dalam kesusahan (dukacita) sehingga tidak sedap makan dan minum"},{"question":"قم بالإجابة على السؤال ما هي كلمة استراحة في اللغة السويدية ؟ من النص التالي: رغم ان الكلمة تعني في حد ذاتها \\"أخذ استراحة من العمل\\" ففي الغالب يشدد ذلك على استخدام كلمة fikapaus (وقفه الفيكه أو fikarast (\\"استراحة الفيكه\\") مع وقفه الفيكه واستراحة الفيكه على التوالي كالمرادفات القريبة..","answer":"حسناً بإستخدام النص السابق الإجابة هي fikarast."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - På seniornivå slog Talbot igenom när han blev bronsmedaljör sin specialdistans 200 meter vid EM 2012","answer":"i Helsingfors, besegrad endast av den nederländska duon Martina och van Luijk. Samma år sprang han tredjesträckan i det brittiska korta stafettlaget som växlade bort sig i försöken i Londonolympiaden. I EM 2014 i Zürich nådde Talbot semifinal på 200 meter och löpte sistasträckan i det brittiska guldlaget på 4 x 100 meter. I Samväldesspelen 2014 i Glasgow blev Talbot sjua i 200 metersfinalen och därmed bäste europé. I stafetten var Talbot slutman för det engelska laget som slutade tvåa bakom Jamaica. På slutsträckan fick Talbot ge sig för Usain Bolt men höll Trinidads Richard Thompson bakom sig."},{"question":"\\"Ny tabataba tsy tapaka amin'ny fananganana akaikin'ny tranoko dia mahatonga ahy ho adala, ka tsy azo atao ny mifantoka.\\" inona ny fihetseham-pon' io fanambarana io ?","answer":"Ny andian-teny dia miteraka fahasosorana sy fahasarotana vokatry ny tabataba fananganana mitohy, mitarika fihetseham-po ratsy noho ny fiantraikany manelingelina ny fahafahan'ny mpandahateny mifantoka."},{"question":"දී ඇති සංඛ්‍යාවකට සමාන වන පූර්ණ සංඛ්‍යා මාලාවක සියලුම යුගල සොයා ගන්නේ කෙසේද?","answer":"def find_pairs(lst, sum_value):    pairs = [(x, y) for x in lst for y in lst if x + y == sum_value]    return pairsnumbers = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]print(find_pairs(numbers, 5))  # Output: [(1, 4), (2, 3), (3, 2), (4, 1)]"},{"question":"Toonta faaidada laga helo maxey tahay?","answer":"TOONTA WA DAAWO LAHUBO MISANA INBADAN O NAGA MID AH MOOGYIHIINToonta inta ugu badan badan waxa loo isticmaala in lagu udgooneeyo dhadhana loogu yeelo cuntooyin aad u farabadan. dhinaca kale toontu waxay leedahay faa’idooyin caafimaad oo cajaa’ib ah.Toontu waxay inta ugu badan ka kooban tahay maado loo yaqaano Allicin taasi oo la dagaalanta bacteriyada, virus-ka, funguska iyo sidoo kalena jidhka sunta ka saarta.Toonta waxay kaloo ka mid tahay geedo daaweedyada ay cilmibaarayaashu isku waafaqeen waxtarkeeda caafimaadkeeda.Maqaalkan waxaan kuugu sheegi doonaa 8 faa’ido oo toontu u leedahay caafimaadka. 1. WAXAY HORMARISAA CFMDKA WADNAHA:Toontu waxay si aad ah ugu fiican tahay caafimaadka wadnaha, waxay caawimaad ka geysataa inay horumariso wareegga dhiigga waxay hoos u dhigtaa kalastaroolka, waxaanay ka hortagtaa cudurrada wadnaha ku dhaca, sidoo kale waxay ka hortagtaa in halbowlayaasha wadnaha ee dhiigga haba ay cidhiidhi noqdaan taasi oo ah waxa ugu badan ee sababa wadne istaagga.2. WAXAY KANTOROOSHA DHIIGKARKA:Cilmi Baadhis ayaa waxay caddeysay in toontu ay hoos u dhigto dhiig karka, dadka dhiig karka qabaa waa inay maalin walba cunaan jab yar oo toon qeydhiin ah iyagoo calooshoodu madhan tahay.3. WAXAY SARRE UQAADA DIFAACA JIRKA:Toonta waxaa aad ugu badan fiitamiinada ay ka mid yihiin Fiitamiin C, B6 iyo macdanaha sillium iyo magnesium kuwaasi oo si aad ah sare ugu qaada difaaca jidhka.4.WAXAY DAWEYSA QUFACA IYO HERGEBKA:Toontu waxay si weyn u daweysaa qufaca iyo durayga sidoo kale waxay sidoo kale waxay faa’iido weyn u leedahay daweynta xiiqda (asthma) iyo burukiitada.5. WAXAY LADAGAALANTA ELERJIGA:Toonta Waxaa ku jira maadooyin la dagaalama fayraaska iyo inflamation-ka kuwaasoo jidhka ka caawiya inuu la dagaalamo noocyada kala duwan ee elerjiga ama xasaasiyadda.6. WAXAY DAWEYSAA ILKO XANUUNKA:Toontu waxay sidoo kale aad hoos ugu dhigtaa ilko xanuunka maadaama ay ku jiraan maadooyin la dagaalama bakteeriyada. Si iligga ku xanuunaya si dhakhso ah xanuunka uga joojiso burburi jab yar oo toon ah islamarkaana dul dhig iligga ku xanuunaya.7.WAXAY CAWISAA DHEFSHIIDKA:Toontu nidaamisaa shaqada caloosha si ay sare ugu qaado dheefshiidka iyo burburinta cuntada toontu waxay sidoo kale beerka ku caawisaa inuu jidhka kasii daayo sunta, iyadoo sidoo kalena beerka ka ilaalisa inay waxyeello soo gaadho.8. WAXAY KAHORTAGTA KANSARKA:Toontu waxay caawimo ka geysataa ka hortagga kansarka siiba kansarka ku dhaca hab-dhiska dheefshiidka iyo sambabada. Dadka taariikh ahaan qoysaskooda uu kansarku ku lugleeyahay waxaa lagula taliyaa inay si joogto u cunaan toonta si ay hoos u dhigaan khatarta ay ugu jiraan noocyo badan oo kansar ah. ALLAHA INNAGA HAYO DHAMMAANTEEN."},{"question":"නාමිකත්වය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"නාමිකත්වය යනු මිනිසුන්ට ජීවත් වීමට ස්ථිර ස්ථානයක් නොමැති ජීවන රටාවකි. ඒ වෙනුවට ඔවුන් ආහාර සහ තණබිම් සොයමින් යම් ප්‍රදේශයක් වටා ගමන් කරයි. සංක්‍රමණික වීමේ සිට එක තැනක රැඳී සිටීමේ වෙනස මුල් ශිෂ්ටාචාරවලට හේතු විය."},{"question":"uAYa uyambhambhazela","answer":"Aya is beating his chest."},{"question":"Bana herhangi bir şairden bir şiir yaz.","answer":"Sana gitme demeyeceğim.Üşüyorsun ceketimi al.Günün en güzel saatleri bunlar.Yanımda kal.Sana gitme demeyeceğim.Gene de sen bilirsin.Yalanlar istiyorsan yalanlar söyleyeyim,İncinirsin.Sana gitme demeyeceğim,Ama gitme, Lavinia.Adını gizleyeceğimSen de bilme, Lavinia.Özdemir Asaf - Lavinia"},{"question":"Inona ny anaran'ny \\" Idlewild Airport \\" amin'izao ? ","answer":"Niova ho \\" John F. Kennedy International Airport \\" ny Idlewild Airport amin'izao. "},{"question":"பாரதியார் சத்ரபதி சிவாஜியைப்பற்றி பாடிய பாடலை எழுதுக.","answer":"ஜயஜய பவானி! ஜயஜய பாரதம்!ஜயஜய மாதா! ஜயஜய துர்க்கா!வந்தே மாதரம்! வந்தே மாதரம்!சேனைத் தலைவர்காள்! சிறந்த மந்திரிகாள்!யானைத் தலைவரும் அருந்திறல் வீரர்காள்!அதிரத மனர்காள்! துரகத் ததிபர்காள்எதிரிகள் துணுக்குற இடித்திடு பதாதிகாள்!வேலெறி படைகாள்! சூலெறி மறவர்காள்!கால னுருக்க்கொளும் கணைதுரந் திடுவீர்.மற்றுமா யிரவிதம் பற்றலர் தம்மைச்செற்றிடுந் திறனுடைத் தீரரத் தினங்காள்!யாவிரும் வாழிய! யாவிரும் வாழிய!தேவிநுந் தமக்கெலாம் திருவருள் புரிக!மாற்றலர் தம்புலை நாற்றமே யறியாஆற்றல்கொண் டிருந்ததில் வரும்புகழ் நாடு!வேதநூல் பழிக்கும் வெளித்திசை மிலேச்சர்பாதமும் பொறுப்பளோ பாரத தேவி?வீரரும் அவரிசை விரித்திடு புலவரும்பாரெலாம் பெரும்புகழ் பரப்பிய நாடு!தர்மமே உருவமாத் தழைத்த பே ரரசரும்நிர்மல முனிவரும் நிறந்த நன் னாடு!வீரரைப் பெறாத மேன்மைநீர் மங்கையைஊரவர் மலடியென் றுரைத்திடு நாடு!பாரதப் பூமி பழம்பெரும் பூமி;நீரதன் புதல்வர், இந் நினைவகற் றாதீர்!பாரத நாடு பார்க்கெலாம் திலகம்;நீரதன் புதல்வர், இந் நினைவகற் றாதீர்!வானக முட்டும் இமயமால் வரையும்ஏனைய திசைகளில் இருந்திரைக் கடலும்காத்திடு நாடு! கங்கையும் சிந்துவும்தூத்திரை யமுனையும் சுனைகளும் புனல்களும்இன்னரும் பொழில்களும் இணையிலா வளங்களும்உன்னத மலைகளும் ஒளிர்தரு நாடு!பைந்நிறப் பழனம் பசியிலா தளிக்கமைந்நிற முகில்கள் வழங்கும் பொன்னாடு!தேவர்கள் வாழ்விடம், திறலுயர் முனிவர்ஆவலோ டடையும் அரும்புகழ் நாடு!ஊனமொன்றறியா ஞானமெய் பூமி,வானவர் விழையும் மாட்சியார் தேயம்!பாரத நாட்டிசை பகரயான் வல்லனோ?நீரதன் புதல்வர் நினைவகற் றாதீர்!தாய்த்திரு நாட்டைத் தறுகண் மிலேச்சர்பேய்த்தகை கொண்டோ ர் பெருமையும் வன்மையும்ஞானமும் அறியா நவைபுரி பகைவர்வானகம் அடக்க வந்திடும் அரக்கர் போல்இந்நாள் படை கொணர்ந்து இன்னல்செய் கின்றார்!ஆலயம் அழித்தலும் அருமறை பழித்தலும்பாலரை விருத்தரைப் பசுக்களை ஒழித்தலும்மாதர்கற் பழித்தலும் மறைவர் வேள்விக்குஏதமே சூழ்வதும் இயற்றிநிற் கின்றார்!சாத்திரத் தொகுதங்யைத் தாழ்த்துவைக் கங்ன்றார்கோத்தங்ர மங்கையர் குலங்கெடுக் கின்றார்எண்ணில துணைவர்காள்! எமக்கிவர் செயுந்துயர்கண்ணியம் மறுத்தனர, ஆண்மையுங் கடிந்தனர்,பொருளினைச் சிதைத்தனர், மருளினை விதைத்தனர்திண்மையை யழித்துப் பெண்மையிங் களித்தனர்,பாரதப் பெரும்பெயர் பழிப்பெய ராக்கினர்,சூரர்தம் மக்களைத் தொழும்பராய்ப் புரிந்தனர்,வீரியம் அழிந்து மேன்மையும் ஒழிந்து நம்ஆரியர் புலையருக் கடிமைக ளாயினர்.மற்றிதைப் பொறுத்து வாழ்வதோ வாழ்க்கைவெற்றிகொள் புலையர்தாள் வீழ்ந்துகொல் வாழ்வீர்?மொக்குகள்தான் தோன்றி முடிவது போலமக்களாய்ப் பிறந்தோர் மடிவது திண்ணம்.தாய்த்திரு நாட்டைத் தகர்த்திடு மிலேச்சரைமாய்த்திட விரும்பான் வாழ்வுமோர் வாழ்வுகொல்?மானமென் றிலாது மாற்றலர் தொழும்பாய்ஈனமுற் றிருக்க எவன்கொலோ விரும்புவன்?தாய்பிறன் கைப்படச் சகிப்பவ னாகிநாயென வாழ்வோன் நமரில்இங் குளனோ?பிச்சைவாழ் வுகந்து பிறருடைய யாட்சியில்அச்சமுற் றிருப்போன் ஆரிய னல்லன்,புன்புலால் யாழ்க்கையைப் போற்றியே தாய்நாட்டுஅன்பிலா திருப்போன் ஆரிய னல்லன்.மாட்சிதீர் மிலேச்சர் மனப்படி யாளும்ஆட்சியி லடங்குவோன் ஆரிய னல்லன்.ஆரியத் தன்மை அற்றிடுஞ் சிறியர்யாரிவண் உளரவர் யாண்டேனும் ஒழிக!படைமுகத்து இறந்து பதம்பெற விரும்பாக்கடைபடு மாக்களென் கண்முனில் லாதீர்!சோதரர் தம்மைத் துரோகிகள் அழிப்பமாதரர் நலத்தின் மகிழ்பவன் மகிழ்க,நாடெலாம் பிறர்வசம் நண்ணுதல் நினையான்வீடுசென் றொளிக்க விரும்புவோன் விரும்புக!தேசமே நலிவொடு தேய்ந்திட மக்களின்பாசமே பெரிதெனப் பார்ப்பவன் செல்க!நாட்டுளார் பசியினால் நலிந்திடத் தன்வயிறுஊட்டுதல் பெரங்தென உண்ணுவோன் செல்க!ஆணுருக் கொண்ட பெண்களும் அலிகளும்வீணில்இங் கிருந்தெனை வெறுத்திடல் விரும்பேன்.ஆரியர் இருமின்! ஆண்கள்இங்கு இருமின்!வீரியம் மிகுந்த மேன்மையோர் இருமின்!மானமே பெரிதென மதிப்பவர் இருமின்!ஈனமே பொறாத இயல்பினர் இருமின்!தாய்நாட் டன்புறு தனையர் இங்கு இருமின்!மாய்நாட் பெருமையின் மாய்பவர் இருமின்!புலையர்தம் தொழும்பைப் பொறுக்கிலார் இருமின்!கலையறு மிலேச்சரைக் கடிபவர் இருமின்!ஊரவர் துயரில்நெஞ் சுருகுவீர் இருமின்!சோர நெஞ்சங்லாத் தூயவர் இருமின்!தேவிதாள் பணியுந் தீரர் இங்கு இருமின்!பாவியர் குருதியைப் பருகுவார் இருமின்!உடலினைப் போற்றா உத்தமர் இருமின்!கடல்மடுப் பினும்மனம் கலங்கலர் உதவுமின்!வம்மினோ துணைவீர்? மருட்சிகொள் ளாதீர்!நம்மினோ ராற்றலை நாழிகைப் பொழுதெனும்புல்லிய மாற்றலர் பொறுக்கவல் லார்கொல்?மெல்லிய திருவடி வீறுடைத் தேவியின்இன்னருள் நமக்கோர் இருந்துணை யாகும்பன்னரும் புகழுடைப் பார்த்தனும் கண்ணனும்வீமனும் துரோணனும் வீட்டுமன் றானும்ராமனும் வேறுள இருந்திறல் வீரரும்நற்றுணை புரிவர்; வானக, நாடுறும்!வெற்றியே யன்றி வேறெதும் பெறுகிலேம்!பற்றறு முனிவரும் ஆசிகள் பகர்வர்செற்றினி மிழேச்சரைத் தீர்த்திட வம்மீன்!ஈட்டியாற் சிரங்களை வீட்டிட எழுமின்!நீட்டிய வேல்களை நேரிருந்து எறிமின்!வாளுடை முனையினும் வயந்திகழ் சூலினும்,ஆளுடைக் கால்க ளடியினுந் தேர்களின்உருளையி னிடையினும் மாற்றலர் தலைகள்உருளையிற் கண்டுநெஞ் சுவப்புற வம்மின்!நம்இதம், பெருவளம் நலிந்திட விரும்பும்(வன்மியை) வேரறத் தொலைத்தபின் னன்றோஆணெனப் பெறுவோம், அன்றிநாம் இறப்பினும்வானுறு தேவர் மணியுல கடைவோம்,வாழ்வமேற் பாரத வான்புகழ்த் தேவியைத்தாழ்வினின் றுயர்த்திய தடம்புகழ் பெறுவோம்!போரெனில் இதுபோர், புண்ணியத் திருப்போர்!பாரினில் இதுபோற் பார்த்திடற் கெளிதோ?ஆட்டினைக் கொன்று வேள்விகள் இயற்றிவீட்டினைப் பெறுவான் விரும்புவார் சிலரேநெஞ்சகக் குருதியை நிலத்திடை வடித்துவஞ்சக மழிக்கும் மாமகம் புரிவம்யாம்வேள்வியில்இதுபோல் வேள்வியொன் றில்லை!தவத்தினில் இதுபோல் தவம்பிறி தில்லை!முன்னையோர் பார்த்தன் முனைத்திசை நின்றுதன்னெதிர் நின்ற தளத்தினை நோக்கிடமாதுலர் சோதரர் மைத்துனர் தாதையர்காதலின் நண்பர் கலைதரு குரவரென்றுஇன்னவர் இருத்தல்கண்டு, இதயம்நொந் தோனாய்த்தன்னருந் தெய்விகச் சாரதி முன்னர்ஐயனே! இவர்மீ தம்பையோ தொடுப்பேன்?வையகத் தரசும் வானக ஆட்சியும்போயினும் இவர்தமைப் போரினில் வீழ்த்தேன்.மெய்யினில் நடுக்கம் மேவுகின் றதுவால,fகையினில் வில்லும் கழன்றுவீழ் கின்றது.வாயுலர் கின்றது; மனம் பதைக்கின்றது,ஓய்வுறுங் கால்கள, உலைந்தது சிரமமும்,வெற்றியை விரும்பேன், மேன்மையை விரும்பேன்சுற்றமிங் கறுத்துச் சுகம்பெறல் விரும்பேன்,எனையிவர் கொல்லினும் இவரையான் தீண்டேன்,சினையறுத் திட்டபின் செய்வதோ ஆட்சி?எனப்பல கூறியவ் விந்திரன் புதல்வன்கனப்படை வில்லைக் களத்தினில் எறிந்துசோர்வோடு வீழ்ந்தனன், சுருதியின் முடிவாய்த்தேர்வயின் நின்றநம் தெய்விகப் பெருமான்வில்லெறிந் திருந்த வீரனை நோக்கிபுல்லிய அறிவொடு புலம்புகின் றனையால்அறத்தினைப் பிரிந்த சுயோதனா தியரைச்செறுத்தினி மாய்ப்பது தீமையென் கின்றாய்,உண்மையை அறியாய் உறவையே கருதிப்பெண்மைகொண் டேதோ பிதற்றிநிற் கின்றாய்வஞ்சகர், தீயர், மனிதரை வருத்துவோர்,நெஞ்சகத் தருக்குடை நீசர்கள்; இன்னோர்தம்மொடு பிறந்த சகோதரராயினும்வெம்மையோ டொறுத்தல் வீரர்தஞ் செயலாம்.ஆரிய நீதிநீ அறிகிலை போலும்!பூரியர் போல்மனம் புழுங்குற லாயினைஅரும்புகழ் தேய்ப்பதும் அனாரியத் தகைத்தும்பெரும்பதத் தடையுமாம் பெண்மையெங் கெய்தினை?பேடிமை யகற்று! நின் பெருமையை மறந்திடேல்!ஈடிலாப் புகழினாய்! எழுகவோ எழுக! என்றுமெய்ஞ் ஞானம்நம் இறையவர் கூறக்குன்றெனும் வயிரக் கொற்றவான் புயத்தோன்அறமே பெரிதென அறிந்திடு மனத்தனாய்மறமே உருவுடை மாற்றலர் தம்மைச்சுற்றமும் நோக்கான் தோழமை மதியான்பற்றலர் தமையெலாம் பார்க்கிரை யாக்கினன்.விசயனன் றிருந்த வியன்புகழ் நாட்டில்இசையுநற் றவத்தால் இன்றுவாழ்ந் திருக்கும்ஆரிய வீரர்காள்! அவருடை மாற்றலர்,தேரில்இந் நாட்டினர், செறிவுடை உறவினர்,நம்மையின் றெதிர்க்கும் நயனிலாப் புல்லோர்,செம்மைதீர் மிலேச்சர், தேசமும் பிறிதாம்பிறப்பினில் அன்னியர், பேச்சினில் அன்னியர்சிறப்புடை யாரியச் சீர்மையை அறியார்."},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية:ويحتوي الشاي الأسود والأخضر والماتشا وأولونغ على الكافيين، وهو منبه يجب الحد منه أثناء الحمل. وعلى الرغم من أنها آمنة بشكل عام، فإن النساء قد يستفدن من التقليل من تناولهن اليومي لأنواع الشاي،","answer":"التي تحتوي على الكافيين أثناء الحمل، بحيث لا يتجاوز المأخوذ اليومي 200 مليغرام."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta :¿Dónde estudió la universidad David Schwimmer?","answer":"La respuesta es en la universidad del Noroeste. "},{"question":"لدي هذا السؤال أين يوجد دماغ الإنسان ؟ ، أجب عليه بطريقة مبسطة.","answer":"حسناً. الإجابة هي في جمجمته."},{"question":"为以下的原文给译文：苻坚召见（高泰），悦之，问以为治之本。对曰：“治本在得人，得入在审举，审举在核真，未有官得其人而国家不治者也。”坚曰：“可谓辞简而理博矣。”","answer":"符坚召见高泰，很喜欢他，向他请教治国的根本办法。高泰回答说：“治国的根本办法在于得人才，得人才在于慎重推荐，慎重推荐在于考察这人的真实情况。每个官位得到合适人选，国家却治理得不好的情况，是不会有的。”苻坚（听后）说：“说的真是言词简略而道理深广啊。”"},{"question":"Cé hé Richard Brinsley Sheridan/ ","answer":"Drámadóir as Baile Átha Cliath ab ea Richard Brinsley Sheridan (a rugadh ar 30 Deireadh Fómhair 1751 -a d'éag 7 Iúil 1816), agus úinéir na hamharclainne Drury Lane i Londain ó 1776 go dtí 1811.Ba den fhíorfhuil éː a athair, Tomáis, aisteoir, agus a sheanathair, an Dr Thomas Sheridan (1687–1738), múinteoir cáiliúil agus cara mór Swift. Fuir sé post san amharclann Drury Lane, áit a raibh Bleá Cliathach eile - an teanór Michael Kelly ag obiar.Is léir freisin gurbh fhear mór grinn é Sheridan. Oíche ar fhág Michael Kelly a theach faoi Sheridan agus beirt cairde leis, d'ól siad cúig bhuidéal póirt, dhá bhuidéal fíona Maidéarach agus buidéal branda, agus bhí Sheridan chomh tinn sin ina dhiaidh nach bhféadadh sé éirí go dtí a seacht a chlog tráthnóna an lae dár gcionn."},{"question":"வினா : இந்தியாவில் முதன் முதலாக வானொலி ஒலிபரப்பு துவங்கப்பட்ட ஆண்டு..............","answer":"விடை: 1927"},{"question":"Inşaatta en çok hangi çimento kullanılır?","answer":"Bununla beraber, en yaygın kullanılan çimentolar genellikle OPC ve PPC'dir. OPC yani açılımı sıradan Portland çimentosu olan bu çimento türü tüm genel beton yapılar için uygun olan ve en yaygın şekilde kullanılan çimento türüdür."},{"question":"ما هو الفيتامين المسئول عن تقوية نظر الإنسان ؟","answer":"الإجابة : فيتامين أ."},{"question":"Àwọn àdúgbò ìlú Iléṣà","answer":"1. Àdúgbo: Ìkótì Ìtumò: Ìbí yìí ni àwon omo ogun Ìjèsà gbà lé àwon òtá won ni ìgbà ogun ni èyí, èka ède ló fà á tí ó fi jé Ìkótì.2. Àdúgbo: Bíládù Ìtumò: Orúko owá ketàlá tó jè ni Ilésà ni Bíládù Arère, ìrántí rè ni won fi so àdúgbò yìí ni orúko rè. Nìgbà tí ò ti dé orí oyè, ó wá gbajúmò débi pé fí àwon èèyàn ba n lo si àdúgbò yen, dígbò ki won so pe àwon n lo si ògbón wón á ni àwon n lo sí ilé Bíládù bí wón se so ó àdúgbò yìí di Bíládù nìyí3. Àdúgbo: Ota pèté Ìtumò: ibi tí àwon jagunjagun Ìjèsà pelu àwon omo Ogun Èkìtì ti pàdé ní ìgbà Ogun ni àdúgbò yìí torí pé ota ìbón pò ni ilè ibi yìí léyìn Ogun yìí ni won se so o ní ota pèté.4. Àdúgbo: Omi Asorò Ìtumò: Omi kan wà ni àdúgbò yìí tí won ń pè ni asorò tori omi yìí ni won se so àdúgbò yìí ni omi-asorò.5. Àdúgbo: Orinkùnràn Ìtumò: Àwon ènìyàn gbà pé igbó tí ó wà ni àdúgbò yìí ni ìgbà àtijó ni àwon abàmì lópòlópò eni tó sì mú ki won gbà pé òràn ni yóò ri, Orìn-ken-òràn (èdè Ìjèsà) O rìn kan òràn.6. Àdúgbo: Ìdí àyàn Ìtumò: Igi ààyàn kan wà ní agbègbè yìí tele èyí ló fàá tí won fi so àdúgbò yìí ní ìdí àyàn.7. Àdúgbo: Ita-Balogun Ìtumò: Àdúgbò yìí ni ilé Obalógun Ilesa wà ní àkókò ti won so orúko àdúgbò yìí (Ìta-Obalogun).8. Àdúgbo: Mùrókò Ìtumò: Ibi yìí kojá ibi tí ìrókò kan wà díè, èyí ló fà á ti won fi so pe o-mu-iroko (èdè Ìjèsà) ìtumò-mu-iroko nip é ó kojá ìrókò mùrókò.9. Àdúgbo: Isarè Ìtumò: Ibi tí àwon Haúsá ń gbé tí won sí ti n ta ojà, àlejò ni arè ní èdè Ìjèsà10. Àdúgbo: Ìdásà Ìtumò: Àwon tí won ón dá ara won sà sí ònà kan ni ìtumò ìdásà, àwon kan kúrò ni àárín ìgboro, wón sì lo da àdúgbò yìí sílè ni won ba so o ni Ìdásà.11. Àdúgbo: Òkè-Padre Ìtumò: (Páàdì) Ibi yìí ni àwon Òyìnbó ìjo Rátólíkì tí a gbà pé won mu ìgbàgbó wá ń gbé nígbà yen ni òkè-Páàdì.12. Àdúgbo: Arágan Ìtumò: Eni tí ó kókó dá àdúgbò yìí sílè bínú kúrò láàrin àwon ènìyàn lo dá dúró síbè ni, èyí ni awon ènìyàn fì so ibè ní arágan torí pé, wón gbà pé ìwà eni tí ó kókó dé àdúgbò yìí kò jot i ènìyàn tó kù lò fàá to fi wá dá àdúgbò tirè sílè.13. Àdúgbo: Bámúso Ìtumò: Òtè ló gbé àwon tó kókó de adugbo yìí dé ibè torí pé wón ń gbèrò láti yan olóyè láàrin ara won, Owá gbó èyí ló bá lé won kúrò ni ibi tí won ti wá télè.14. Àdúgbo: Ìlórò Ìtumò: Àwon tí ó kókó dé adúgbò yìí jè ólòwó pàápàá àwon tí ó kókó jáde to se awo ni èyìn odi tí won fi wá n kólé sí ilé.15. Àdúgbo: Òkè èsó Ìtumò: àdúgbò yìí ni won ti máa n ta aso àwon oyinbo nigba tí àwon kòráà kókó gbé aso títà dé Ilesa, ìdí niyi ti won fi n pè é ni Òkè-eso.16. Àdúgbo: Ìsònà Ìtumò: Ibi tí àwon tó ma n se isé onà pò jù sí láyé àtijó, ìtàn so fún wa pé ibè ni won ti máa n hun òpá àse àti ìlèkè owá, tí àwon ìyàwó rè àti àwon olóyè.17. Àdúgbo: Ìgandò Ìtumò: Ìgi ìgandò kan náà ló wà ní àdúgbò yìí láyé àtijó.18. Àdúgbo: Òkè-Ayò Ìtumò: Àwon désìn kinyó ló so àdúgbò yìí ni òkè ayò nígb\`atí won kó ilé ìjósìn ati ibi ìsojí àti lé isun won síbè.19. Àdúgbo: Omo-Ofe (Omife) Ìtumò: Ìtàn so pé àdúgbò yìí àwon omo ogun ti níláti gbéra lati sigun lo sibi ti won ti fé jagun. Béè náà ni won sì gbódò wá jábò ti won si pin enìati erú tí wón kó bò lójú ogun.20. Àdúgbo: Ìlájé Ìtumò: ìbi tí ará ìgboro ti má a ń wá pàdé àwon ará oko láti ra ojà lówó won èyí ló fà á tí wón fi so àdúgbò yìí ní Ìlájé.21. Àdúgbo: Òkè Ìrò Ìtumò: Orúko igi kan tó wà ládùgbóò yìí télè ni wón fi so àdúgbò yìí22. Àdúgbo: Odò Ìrò Ìtumò: Ibi tí ó bó sí aopá ìsàlè ní adúgbò òkè ìrò ni odò ìrò23. Àdúgbo: Ìjòfì Ìtumò: ibí yìí ni wón ti máa n aso ofì nígbà tí ó kókó dé Ilésà.24. Àdúgbo: Ìkòyí Ìtumò: Àdúgbò yìí jè ìbi titun tí òpòlopò àwon tí ó fi jáde nílùú tipé tipé ń gbé òpòlopò won lo ti Èkó wá kólé síle, ojú tì wòn fi wo ìkòyí Estate l’Ekoo ni won fi mu àdúgbò náà.25. Àdúgbo: Enú Odi Ìtumò: Ibí yìí ni ìlú parí si látijó sùgbón ìlú ti fe séyìn si i ju ibí yìí lo26. Àdúgbo: Adétí Ìtumò: Ibi tí àwon Ìbòkun dúró dí nígbà tí ogún parí ti won wá láti dúpé lówó Owá ti o ràn wón lówó láti segun òtá wòn (A-de-eti-owá) À dé tòsí ilé Owá Adètí Owá.27. Àdúgbo: Ìjòkà Ìtumò: Àwon ará Òwò ló so adúgbò yìí lórúko yìí, àgbàdo ni won máa n tà níbè télè bóyá àgbàdo tí won máa n dàpè ní okà ló fa orúko yìí.28. Àdúgbo: Ìmàdín Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà àtijó àwon ìyá àgbà má a n se àdín níbí yìí (Ùmàdín)29. Àdúgbo: Temìdire Ìmàdín Ìtumò: àdúgbò titun tó jáde lara Ìmàdín nìyí30. Àdúgbo: Omo Olúpè Ìtumò: Òríkì èèyàn tí ó kókó kólé sí àdúgbò yìí ni won fi pe ibí yìí.31. Àdúgbo: Òkèsà Ìtumò: Ìkòkò ni àwonìjèsà máa ń dà á pè ní ìsà. Àdúgbò yìí sì ni wón ti máa ń ná oyà ìkòkò saájú kí ilésà tó di ilé-ìsà.32. Àdúgbo: Ìsòkùn Ìtumò: Ìsò okùn ló di ìsokùn yìí, ibè ni àwon àgbè àti elému ti máa ń wá okùn láti fid i erù tàbí òpe-emu won ní ìgbà láéláé.33. Àdúgbo: Ìdí Ose Ìtumò: Igi osè ńlá kan ló wà ní ìbí yìí ni ìgbà láéláé tí àwon ènìyàn máa ń dúró ta ojà mí abé rè.34. Àdúgbo: Ìdí Ògún Ìtumò: Ìbí yìí ni wón ti máa ń bo ògún owá ní ìgbà àtijó, wón sì máa ń pa ajá ògún sí ibé yìí títí di oní.35. Àdúgbo: Ìta Akogun Ìtumò: Ibí yìí ni àwon ológun máa ń dúró sí de àwon òtá ní ìgbà láéláé, ìdí nìyí tí wón fi ń pè é ní ìta akogun.36. Àdúgbo: Adétí Ìtumò: Àgékúrín fún “A dé etí owá” mí èyí, ibè ni àwon ará ìbòkun dúró sé nígbà tí ogun parí tí wón fé wá dúpé lówó owá-omo-Ajíbógun tó ràn wón lówó láti ségun àwon Ìlàré.37. Àdúgbo: Ìbàlá Ìtumò: Òrúko akoni kan tó wá láti ìbòkun sùgbón tó wolè láàrin ìlésà àti ìbòkun nígbà tí ó gbó pé ogun ti pa ìyàwó àti omo òun mi ìbòkun.38. Àdúgbo: Erégúrìn Ìtumò: Orí egúrù ló di Erégúrù, ìlè tó le ló wà ní ibí yìí télè àwon omodé sì máa ń seré níbè.39. Àdúgbo: Ìsònà Ìtumò: Ibi tí àwon tó má a ń se isé onà pò jù sí láyé àtijó ìtàn so fún wa pé ibè ni wón ti máa ń hun òpá ńlèkè owá, tí àwon Olóyè rè àti ti àwon ìyàwó rè.40. Àdúgbo: Araromi Ìtumò: Orúko ìgbàlódé ní èyí, Arágan ni orúko àdúgbò yìí télè wón sèsè yíi padà sé Aráròmí ni41. Àdúgbo: Ìtinsin Ìtumò: Ìgi Isis ńlá kan ló wà ní ibí yìí télè tí àwon ènìyàn máa ń ta ayò ní idi rè èyí ló di ìtà-isin lónìí (Ìhnsin).42. Àdúgbo: Bólórundúrò Ìtumò: Orúko tuntun ni orúko àdúgbò yìí nítorí pé àwon tó kókó dé ibè kò tètè kólé kan ara won, wón gbà pé àwon bá olórun dúrò.43. Àdúgbo: Ìgbàyè Ìtumò: Ní ìgbà ogun, Ibí yìí ni àwon Ológun ìjèsà gbà láti sá àsálà fún èmí won. “Ibi tí a gbà tí a fi yè”ni àpèjá rè.44. Àdúgbo: Eréjà Ìtumò: Orí ojà ni wón gé kúrú sí Eréjà, ibí yìí ló jé bíi oríta fún gbogbo àwon ìlú kékèèké ibè sì ni wón ti máa ń pàdé láti ta ojà won.45. Àdúgbo: Ìkòyí Ìtumò: Àdúgbò tuntun ni èyí, àwon tó sì fún un ní orúko yìí yá a lò láti ìlú Èkó ni.46. Àdúgbo: Omi-Oko Ìtumò: Àdúgbò tí omi tí àwon ènìyàn máa ń pon ní ayé àtijó, omo yìí wà ní ìtòsí ibi tí wón máa ń dá oko sí, èyí ni wón fi máa ń pè é ní omi-oko.47. Àdúgbo: Enu-Odi Ìtumò: Ibí yìí ni ilésà dé ní àkókò yìí, èyí ló fà á tí wón fi ń pe ibí yìí ní Enu-Odi.48. Àdúgbo: Ìróyè Ìtumò: Ìróyè yìí kò jìnà sí ìgbàyè, ibè ni àwon tó sá fún èmí won ní ìgbà ogun ti kókó dúró.49. Àdúgbo: Ìlórò Ìtumò: Àwon tí ó kókó dó àdúgbò yìí jé olówó, pàápàá wón jé òkan lára àwon tó kókó jáde lo sòwò ní òkè oya tí wón wá ń kólé sílé.50. Àdúgbo: Òlómilágbàlá Ìtumò: Àdúgbò yìí kò jìnà sí omi kan tí àwon ènìyàn máa ń mu, èyí ló jé kí àwon ènìyàn máa pe àwon tó ń gbé àdúgbò yìí ní òlómilágbàlá.51. Àdúgbo: Ògbón Àgbède Ìtumò: Àgbède kan wà ní àdúgbò yìí ní àkókò tí wón fún un ní orúko yìí, omo Èfòn alààyè ni àgbède yìí.52. Àdúgbo: Òkè-jìgbà Ìtumò: Òrúko Babaláwo kan ni Jìgbà, àdúgbò yìí ló sì máa ń gbé tí ó ti ń se isé owo rè. ìdí nìyí tí wón fi ń pe àdúgbò náà ní òkè-jìgbà.53. Àdúgbo: Òkè-omi-irú Ìtumò: Òmi kan wà ní ibí yìí tí wón ti máa ń fo irú ní ayé àtijó, ìgbà tí àwon ènìyàn téèrè sin í kólé omi irú.54. Àdúgbo: Omi-Aládìe Ìtumò: Oko kan wà ní ibí yìí ní ìgbà àtijó tí wón ti máa ń sin adie (poultry) omi kan sì wà ní ìtòsí oko yìí, èyí ló mú kí won máa pe omi yìí ní omi aládìe èyí tó di o’ruko àdúgbò náà lónìí.55. Àdúgbo: Olórunsògo Ìtumò: Àdúgbò yìí ti wà láti ìgbà láéláé sùgbón àwon ènìyàn kò tètè wá ko ilé sí ibè, nígbà tí ó sì yá ààrin ìgbà díè ni àwon ènìyàn kó òpòlopò ilé sí ibè, èyí ló mú kí won pè é ní Olórunsògo.56. Àdúgbo: Ìjámo Ìtumò: Ibí yìí ni àwon àgbè tó bá ń bò láti oko ti máa ń já imò òpe láti di erù won ibè ló di Ìjámò nígbà tí ilé bèrè si ní de ibè.57. Àdúgbo: Ògúdù Ìtumò: Orúko akíkanjú kan ni ìgbà ogun ògèdèǹgbé ni èyí, ní ìrántí rè ni wón se so àdúgbò yìí ní ògúdù.58. Àdúgbo: Ìfòfín Ìtumò: Òmi kan wà ní àdúgbò yìí télè tí àwon ènìyàn ti máa ń do nǹkan, torí omi yìí ni wón se so àdúgbò yìí ní Ìfofín.59. Àdúgbo: Omi-Eran Ìtumò: Ibi tí àwon alápatà ti máa ń pa eran won fún títà ni wón so di omi-eran.60. Àdúgbo: Imàdín Ìtumò: Ibi tí àwon ìyá àgbà ti máa ń se àdín ní ìgbà àtijó ni wón ń pè ní Umàdín ní èka èdè ìjèsà, èyí ló sì di Imàdín lónìí."},{"question":"Jox ma been waxi wolof.","answer":"Nopp pejj la, waaye kenn du ca wékk gafaka."},{"question":"人体具有解毒作用的内脏是","answer":"人体具有解毒作用的内脏是"},{"question":"ம. சிங்காரவேலர் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"புலியும் பசுவும் ஒரு துறையில் நீர் அருந்தினாலும் அருந்தும். ஆனால், முதலாளியும் தொழிலாளியும் சரிசமத்துவமாக தங்கள் தேசப் பொருள்களை, காந்தியாரின் சுயராஜ்ஜியத்தில் அனுபவிப்பார்கள்எ ன்பது பகற்கனவே."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'gajah sama gajah berjuang, pelanduk mati di tengah-tengah'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud jika pemimpin (kuasa besar) bergaduh (berperang), rakyat (negara kecil) juga yang susah. Contoh ayat: Pemimpin-pemimpin harus mengetepikan kepentingan peribadi masing-masing kerana jikalau mereka bersengketa, orang-orang bawahan juga yang akan menderita, seperti kata pepatah gajah sama gajah berjuang, pelanduk mati di tengah-tengah."},{"question":"ඉන්දු-යුරෝපීය භාෂා නම් කරන්න.","answer":"ඉන්දු-යුරෝපීය භාෂා යනු අයිස්ලන්තයේ සිට දකුණු ආසියාව දක්වා ව්‍යවහාර වන පොදු සම්භවයක් සහිත භාෂා පවුලකි. මෙම භාෂා පවුල ලෝක සමස්ත මානව වර්ගයා අතරින් 50% කට අධික සංඛ්‍යාවකගේ මාතෘ (හෝ පිතෘ) භාෂා නියෝජනය කරයි. මෙහි උප පවුල් හා ඊට අයත් භාෂා මෙසේ ය. 1. ඇල්බේනියානු - ඇල්බේනියානු භාෂාව2. ආමේනියානු - ආමේනියානු භාෂාව3. බෝල්ටෝ-ස්ලැවික්3.1. බෝල්ටික් - ලැට්වියානු භාෂාව, ලිතුවේනියානු භාෂාව3.2 ස්ලැවික් - පෝලන්ත භාෂාව (පෝලිශ්), චෙක් භාෂාව, ස්ලෝවැක් භාෂාව, බොස්නියානු භාෂාව, සර්බියානු භාෂාව, ක්‍රොඒෂියානු භාෂාව, බල්ගේරියානු භාෂාව, මැසිඩෝනියානු භාෂාව, බෙලරුසියානු භාෂාව, යුක්‍රේනියානු භාෂාව, රුසියානු භාෂාව4. කෙල්ටික් භාෂා - අයිරිෂ් භාෂාව, ස්කොටිෂ් ගේලික්, කෝනිෂ් භාෂාව, වෙල්ශ් භාෂාව5. ඉතාලික භාෂා - ලතින්5.1 රෝමාන්තික භාෂා (ලතින් භාෂාවෙන් සම්භවය වී ඊට වෙනස් ලක්ෂණවලින් සමන්විත) - රොමේනියානු භාෂාව, ප්‍රංශ භාෂාව, පෘතුගීසි භාෂාව, ස්පාඤ්ඤ භාෂාව, ඉතාලි භාෂාව, සිසිලි භාෂාව, සාර්ඩිනියන් භාෂාව6. ජර්මානුක භාෂා - අයිස්ලන්ත භාෂාව, ඩේනිෂ් භාෂාව, ස්විඩිෂ් භාෂාව, යිඩිෂ් භාෂාව, ලන්දේසි භාෂාව, ඇෆ්‍රිකාන්ස් භාෂාව, සම්මත ජර්මන් භාෂාව, ඉංග්‍රීසි භාෂාව, ස්කොට්ස් භාෂාව7. හෙලෙනික් භාෂා - ට්සකෝනියානු භාෂාව, ග්‍රීක භාෂාව8. ඉන්දු- ඉරානීය භාෂා -8.1 නුරිස්තානු භාෂා - කම්කටා-වාරි භාෂාව, අස්කුනු භාෂාව8.2 ඉන්දු-ආර්ය භාෂා - සංස්කෘත භාෂාව, පාලි භාෂාව, හින්දුස්තානි භාෂාව (හින්දි,උර්දු), පංජාබි භාෂාව, සින්දි භාෂාව, කෂ්මීරි භාෂාව, ගුජරාටි භාෂාව, රාජස්තානි භාෂාව, රොමානි භාෂාව, ඇසෑමි භාෂාව, බෙංගාලි භාෂාව, ඔරියා භාෂාව, කොන්කානි භාෂාව, මරාති භාෂාව, නේපාලි භාෂාව, සිංහල භාෂාව, දිවෙහි භාෂාව8.3 ඉරානීය භාෂා - ඔසේටියානු භාෂාව, පශ්ටෝ භාෂාව, පර්සියානු භාෂාව, ටජික් භාෂාව, බලෝචි භාෂාව, කුර්දිෂ් භාෂාව"},{"question":"ايش معنى الجملة التالية \\"هذه الاكله شحيفه\\" بالفصحى.","answer":"شحفه: شهيه ( هذه الاكله شحيفه) هذه الاكله شهيه."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Jakie są typowe polskie potrawy wigilijne?","answer":"Typowe potrawy wigilijne to barszcz z uszkami, zupa grzybowa, kapusta z grochem, pierogi z kapustą i grzybami, karp smażony, kutia. Kutia to potrawa wschodnich regionów Polski, przygotowywana z gotowanej pszenicy, którą wcześniej obtłukiwano w stępach, z dodatkiem miodu i maku. Zarówno mak, jak i miód to produkty zajmujące specjalne miejsce w wigilijnym menu. Mak znany ze swej mocy usypiania mógł być pomocny w drodze w zaświaty lub być poczęstunkiem dla tych, którzy stamtąd przychodzą na ziemię. Miód to produkt od pszczół, powszechnie w kulturze uważanych za święte, był darem ofiarnym dla dusz zmarłych. Wigilia nie mogła się też obyć bez suszonych grzybów. Ich znaczenie wynikało z faktu, że rosły w lasach czyli przestrzeni nieoswojonej przez ludzi, a więc należały bardziej do przestrzeni zaświatów i dlatego miały niezwykłą moc. Ryba na wiejski stół trafiła dość późno, wcześniej „królowała” na dworach."},{"question":"Tamin' ny oviana no nanjakan'i Radama II  teto Madagasikara ? ","answer":"1861-1863 no nanjakan'i Radama II teto Madagasikara "},{"question":"ඇමරිකාවේ ජන්ද විද්‍යාල ගණන","answer":"538"},{"question":"إذا أحد قلك كفو إيش ترد؟","answer":"كفوك الطيب"},{"question":"கேள்வி :இந்தியாவில் இருந்து முதல் உலக அழகி யார்?","answer":"விடை: ரீட்டா ஃபரியாகேள்வி :ரீட்டா ஃபரியா - வாழ்க்கை வரலாறு: இந்தியாவின் முதல் பெண் உலக அழகிரீட்டா ஃபரியா பவல், ஆகஸ்ட் 23, 1943 இல் பிறந்தார், அவரது அழகுப் போட்டிகள் மற்றும் மருத்துவத்தில் அவரது அற்புதமான வெற்றிக்காக கொண்டாடப்பட்ட ஒரு குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நபர். 1966 ஆம் ஆண்டில், உலக அழகி பட்டத்தை வென்ற முதல் இந்தியர் மற்றும் முதல் மருத்துவர் என்ற வரலாற்றைப் படைத்தார். இது தடைகளைத் தகர்த்தது மட்டுமல்லாமல், உலகளவில் பெண்களுக்கு ஒரு உத்வேகமான அளவுகோலையும் நிறுவியது.ஆரம்பகால வாழ்க்கை மற்றும் சவால்கள்பிறந்த தேதி: ஆகஸ்ட் 23, 1943பிறந்த இடம்: மும்பை, இந்தியாரீட்டா ஃபரியா மும்பையில் ஒரு நடுத்தர வர்க்க கோவா கத்தோலிக்க குடும்பத்தில் பிறந்தார். அவளுடைய பெற்றோர், ஜான் மற்றும் அன்டோனெட், கடின உழைப்பு மற்றும் உறுதிப்பாடு ஆகியவற்றின் மதிப்புகளை அவளுக்குள் விதைத்தனர். தனது உயரத்திற்காக கிண்டல் செய்யப்படுவது போன்ற சவால்களை எதிர்கொண்ட போதிலும், ரீட்டா தனது உயரமான மற்றும் ஒல்லியான சட்டகத்தை விளையாட்டில், குறிப்பாக ஹாக்கியில் சிறந்து விளங்க பயன்படுத்தினார், அங்கு அவர் தனது ஹாட்ரிக் நடிப்பிற்காக அங்கீகாரம் பெற்றார்.மற்ற முக்கியமான கட்டுரைகள்இந்தியாவில் முதல் பெண்கள் உலகிலேயே முதல்இந்தியாவின் முதல் பெண் விமானி, இந்தியாவின் முதல் பெண் ரயில் ஓட்டுனர்மாடலிங் தொழில்மிஸ் பம்பாய் கிரீடத்தை வென்றபோது ரீட்டாவின் உலக அழகி கிரீடத்திற்கான பயணம் தொடங்கியது. அவரது வெற்றி 1966 இல் ஈவ்ஸ் வீக்லி மிஸ் இந்தியா போட்டியில் அவர் பங்கேற்பதற்கு வழி வகுத்தது, அங்கு அவர் வெற்றியாளராக உருவெடுத்தார். இந்த வெற்றி, 1966 ஆம் ஆண்டு உலக அழகி போட்டியில் இந்தியாவைப் பிரதிநிதித்துவப்படுத்தி, சர்வதேச அரங்கில் அவரைத் தூண்டியது.உலக அழகி 1966மிஸ் வேர்ல்ட் 1966 போட்டியின் போது, ரீட்டா ஃபரியா, 'பெஸ்ட் இன் நீச்சலுடை' மற்றும் 'பெஸ்ட் இன் ஈவினிங்வேர்' ஆகிய துணை தலைப்புகளை வென்றதன் மூலம் முத்திரை பதித்தார். அவரது கருணை, புத்திசாலித்தனம் மற்றும் கண்கவர் அழகு ஆகியவை நடுவர்கள் மற்றும் பார்வையாளர்களிடையே நீடித்த தாக்கத்தை ஏற்படுத்தியது. ஒரு வரலாற்று தருணத்தில், ரீட்டா ஃபரியா உலக அழகியாக முடிசூட்டப்பட்டார், இந்த மதிப்புமிக்க பட்டத்தை வென்ற முதல் இந்தியர் என்ற பெருமையைப் பெற்றார்.  நட்சத்திரம் மற்றும் மருத்துவம் இடையே ஒரு தேர்வுஉலக அழகி என்ற வெற்றிகரமான ஆட்சிக்குப் பிறகு, ரீட்டா ஃபரியா ஒரு முக்கியமான முடிவை எதிர்கொண்டார். மாடலிங் மற்றும் படங்களில் நடிப்பதற்கு ஏராளமான லாபகரமான வாய்ப்புகளைப் பெற்றார், ஆனால் அவர் வேறு பாதையைத் தேர்ந்தெடுத்தார். பொழுதுபோக்கில் ஒரு கவர்ச்சியான வாழ்க்கையைத் தொடர்வதற்குப் பதிலாக, அவர் மருத்துவத்தின் மீதான தனது ஆர்வத்திற்கு உறுதியளித்தார். ரீட்டா கிராண்ட் மருத்துவக் கல்லூரியில் சேர்ந்தார் & சர் ஜே.ஜே. மருத்துவமனைகள் குழு, அங்கு அவர் தனது எம்.பி.பி.எஸ். பட்டம்.மருத்துவத் துறையில் சிறந்து விளங்குவதைத் தொடர்ந்து, இங்கிலாந்தின் லண்டனில் உள்ள கிங்ஸ் கல்லூரி மருத்துவமனையில் ரீட்டா படிப்பைத் தொடர்ந்தார். அவரது கல்விக்கான அவரது அர்ப்பணிப்பு அசைக்க முடியாதது மற்றும் 1971 இல், அவர் தனது வழிகாட்டியான டாக்டர். டேவிட் பவலை, உட்சுரப்பியல் நிபுணரை மணந்தார். இந்த ஜோடி பின்னர் அயர்லாந்தின் டப்ளினுக்கு குடிபெயர்ந்தது, அங்கு ரீட்டா தனது மருத்துவப் பயிற்சியைத் தொடங்கினார், மிஸ் வேர்ல்ட் கிரீடத்தை வெல்வதற்கான அவரது அர்ப்பணிப்பு எவ்வளவு வலிமையானது என்பதை நிரூபித்தார்.மரபு மற்றும் பங்களிப்புகள்ரீட்டாவின் குறிப்பிடத்தக்க பயணத்தில் 1998 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஃபெமினா மிஸ் இந்தியா போட்டியில் நடுவராக பணியாற்றியது மற்றும் பல சந்தர்ப்பங்களில் மிஸ் வேர்ல்ட் போட்டியில் நடுவராக திரும்பியதும் அடங்கும். மிஸ் வேர்ல்ட் 1976 நடுவர் குழுவில், டெமிஸ் ரூசோஸுடன் இணைந்து, சிண்டி பிரேக்ஸ்பியரின் உலக அழகி பட்டத்தை வென்றார்."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన భావం వచ్చేలాగా పద్యం రాయండి:నా శబ్దం యొక్క ప్రతాపాన్ని వినండి. నా పేరు ప్రజాకోటి. ఒక్క కోటి కాదండి. కోటానుకోట్ల ప్రాణులకు మాటలనే బలాన్నిచ్చి నైపుణ్యాన్ని కలిగిస్తాను.","answer":"వినుడీ నా శబ్దధాటినా పేరు ప్రజాకోటిఒక్క కోటి కాదండోకోటికోట్ల ప్రాణులకుమాట బలంతో ఆశాపాటవమును కలిగిస్తా"},{"question":"క్రింది పేరా చదివి, ఇచ్చిన వాక్యాలు సరైనవో కాదో (✓ ) (✗) గుర్తుల ద్వారా గుర్తించండి.అందరికీ ఆధారమైన చెట్లు నేడు కను మరుగై పోతున్నాయి. ఊళ్లను, పట్టణాలను భవనాలతో నింపుతున్నారు. చెట్లు పెంచాలన్న ధ్యాస లేకుండా పోతోంది. జనాలు తాము మొక్కలు నాటి పెంచాలన్న ఆలోచనను మరిచి, ఏళ్ల తరబడిగా విస్తరించిన వటవృక్షాలను కూడా నేల కూలుస్తున్నారు. దీనంతటికీ మనిషి అత్యాశే ప్రధాన కారణం. స్వార్థంతో ముందు చూపు లేకుండా ప్రకృతినంతా అంతరింప జేస్తూ, అభివృద్ధి పేరుతో ఆకాశ హర్మ్యాలు నిర్మిస్తున్నాడు. అలాగే రోడ్లను ఆనుకుని ఉన్న వ్యవసాయ భూములను ప్లాట్లుగా చేసి విక్ర యిస్తున్నాడు. కొన్నాళ్లకు వ్యవసాయ భూమి కొరవడి మనిషి ‘అన్నమో రామచంద్రా’ అని అరిచి చావక తప్పని పరిస్థితిని చేజేతులా సృష్టించుకుంటున్నాడు.ప్రశ్నలు – జవాబులు :1. అందరికీ ఆధారమైనవి చెట్లు. (  )2. చెట్లను పెంచాలన్న ధ్యాస అందరిలో పెరిగి పోయింది. (  )3. మనిషి అత్యాశ లేకుండా జీవిస్తున్నాడు. (  )4. వ్యవసాయ భూములు ప్లాట్లుగా మారుతున్నాయి. (  )5. అన్నం దొరకని పరిస్థితి రాబోతుంది. (  )","answer":"ప్రశ్నలు – జవాబులు :1. అందరికీ ఆధారమైనవి చెట్లు. (  )జవాబు:(✓ )2. చెట్లను పెంచాలన్న ధ్యాస అందరిలో పెరిగి పోయింది. (  )జవాబు:(✗)3. మనిషి అత్యాశ లేకుండా జీవిస్తున్నాడు. (  )జవాబు:(✗)4. వ్యవసాయ భూములు ప్లాట్లుగా మారుతున్నాయి. (  )జవాబు:(✓ )5. అన్నం దొరకని పరిస్థితి రాబోతుంది. (  )జవాబు:(✓ )"},{"question":"Pasakykite didžiausią salą pasaulyje?","answer":"Grenlandijos bendras plotas yra 2,16 milijono kvadratinių kilometrų, kurį didžiąją sausumos masę visiškai užima ledas."},{"question":"ග්‍රීක කඳුකරයේ, විශේෂයෙන් සරත් සෘතුවේ සහ ශීත ඍතුවේ දී කෙනෙකුට භුක්ති විඳිය හැකි විනෝදාත්මක ක්‍රියාකාරකම් මොනවාද?","answer":"ග්‍රීක කඳුකරයට පැමිණෙන අමුත්තන්ට ශීත ඍතුවේ දී උසම කඳු බෑවුම්වල හිම මත ලිස්සා යාම ඇතුළු ක්‍රියාකාරකම් රාශියක් භුක්ති විඳිය හැකිය. මීට අමතරව, කඳු නැගීම, කඳු නැගීම, මවුන්ටන් බයිසිකල් පැදීම, අශ්වයින් පැදීම සහ තවත් බොහෝ දේ සඳහා අවස්ථා තිබේ. ඇල්පයින් සමාජ ශාලා උද්යෝගිමත් අය සඳහා කඳුකරයේ ක්රියාකාරකම් සංවිධානය කරයි."},{"question":"O que é uma \\"função anônima\\" em Go?","answer":"Uma função anônima é uma função sem nome que pode ser definida e usada diretamente em expressões ou atribuída a variáveis."},{"question":"Naa ka'y gipanagot nga problema karon? Unsa ang imong mga buhaton?","answer":"Usa ka labing daku nga challenge karon mao ang pagdumala sa mga isyu sa trabaho, ug akong gipaningkamutan nga makakita og solusyon pinaagi sa komprehensibo nga pag-alam sa sitwasyon."},{"question":"Туулган күнгө карата куттуктоо жазып бере аласыңбы  ?","answer":"Сизге күлкү жана бактылуулукка толгон улуу күндү каалайм. Туулган кунуңуз менен куттуктайм!"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana : « Mbola injany tsaroako mangorintsina any ami’ny tenako rehetra any, mivaivay any anaty rako any ny akon’ny fitiavana nanjary antom-pahavelomako ankehitriny. Lasa anefa ianao, tsy hiverina intsony. »","answer":"Maneho alahelo io fanambarana io. Nandao ny tany ilay olon-tiany."},{"question":"Pergunta: Qual foi o maior projeto de obras públicas na história dos EUA? Resposta:","answer":"Big Dig"},{"question":"සත්ත්‍ව කිරි යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"තම පැටවුන් වෙනුවෙන් ක්‍ෂීරපායී ස්ථන ග්‍රන්ථීවලින් නිපදවෙන සුදු පාට දියරය සත්ත්‍ව කිරි වේ."},{"question":"Inona no dikan'ny teny hoe \\"plante\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy?","answer":"Ny dikan'ny teny hoe \\"plante\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy dia \\"zava-maniry\\"."},{"question":"Where do you live?","answer":"Currently, I live in Somalia and I want to know the location of the job."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny diso tsipelina ao anatin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Ny fitantanana ny ala mahartra dia manampy amin'ny fiarovna ny zavamannaina sy ny ady amin'ny fiovana.\\"","answer":"Ity ilay fanambarana miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy \\"Ny fitantanana ny ala maharitra dia manampy amin'ny fiarovana ny zavamananaina sy ny ady amin'ny fiovana\\""},{"question":"Thời gian vừa rồi tôi thấy nhiều thông tin rao bán giảm giá đất ở Sóc Sơn, Ba Vì nên cũng hỏi một số môi giới. Tôi được một người giới thiệu một khu đất tầm nhìn hồ ở Sóc Sơn có diện tích đất 3.000 m2. Giá hai năm trước khoảng 5,5 triệu đồng mỗi m2, giảm còn 5 triệu đồng một m2.Môi giới cho biết đây là khu vực chủ yếu đất lâm nghiệp chưa có sổ đỏ, mua bán công chứng vi bằng. Những giao dịch quanh khu vực này vẫn được thực hiện như thế. Nhiều nhà đầu tư sau khi mua đất đã xây khu nghỉ dưỡng hay homestay, chờ chuyển đổi mục đích sử dụng đất.Mong chuyên gia tư vấn xây nhà trên đất rừng có rủi ro ra sao? Nhà đầu tư cần lưu ý những gì nếu giao dịch những khu đất như trên?","answer":"Biệt thự, homestay là công trình nhà ở riêng lẻ của các hộ gia đình, cá nhân. Theo Luật Nhà ở, pháp luật cấm hành vi xây dựng nhà ở trên các loại đất mà không phải đất ở. Do đó, việc xây dựng các công trình nhà ở trên đất rừng, tùy từng trường hợp và hành vi cụ thể, có thể vi phạm rất nhiều quy định khác nhau như Luật Xây dựng, Luật Đất đai hay quy định pháp luật về lĩnh vực lâm nghiệp.Cụ thể, hành vi xây dựng nhà ở trên đất rừng phòng hộ có thể bị xử phạt hành chính từ 3 đến 250 triệu đồng vì chuyển mục đích khi chưa có sự chấp thuận của cơ quan có thẩm quyền, theo Nghị định 91/2019. Bên cạnh đó, người vi phạm sẽ phải khôi phục lại tình trạng ban đầu của đất và nộp lại số lợi bất hợp pháp có được. Ngoài ra, xây dựng nhà trên đất lâm nghiệp sẽ không được cơ quan có thẩm quyền cấp giấy phép xây dựng.Có thể thấy, việc xây dựng nhà trên đất rừng luôn tiềm ẩn hàng loạt rủi ro. Trong đó, việc xử phạt vi phạm hành chính giới hạn trong hai năm, kể từ thời điểm kết thúc vi phạm thì biện pháp khắc phục hậu quả không bị giới hạn thời gian. Điều này có nghĩa là bạn xây nhà trên đất rừng, bất cứ khi nào mà cơ quan có thẩm quyền phát hiện đều có quyền yêu cầu tháo dỡ, khôi phục tình trạng ban đầu của đất và nộp lại số lợi bất hợp pháp (gồm việc thu lợi từ kinh doanh homestay).Thực tế, việc xử lý với công trình vi phạm trật tự xây dựng tại Sóc Sơn và một số địa phương tại Hà Nội gặp nhiều khó khăn thời gian qua, góp phần tạo tâm lý nhờn luật của một số người. Cộng thêm với tâm lý đầu tư, xây dựng để chờ chuyển đổi mục đích sử dụng đất dẫn đến tình trạng vi phạm pháp luật về đất đai, xây dựng ở khu vực này khá phổ biến."},{"question":"എന്താണ് ലാർജ് ഹാഡ്രോൺ കൊളൈഡർ?","answer":"ലാർജ് ഹാഡ്രോൺ കൊളൈഡർ ലോകത്തിലെ ഏറ്റവും വലുതും ശക്തവുമായ കണികാ ആക്സിലറേറ്ററാണ്, ഇത് സ്വിറ്റ്സർലൻഡിലെ ജനീവയ്ക്ക് സമീപമുള്ള യൂറോപ്യൻ ഓർഗനൈസേഷൻ ഫോർ ന്യൂക്ലിയർ റിസർച്ച്-ൽ സ്ഥിതി ചെയ്യുന്നു. ഇത് ഉപആറ്റോമിക് കണങ്ങളെ പ്രകാശത്തിന്റെ വേഗതയിൽ ത്വരിതപ്പെടുത്തുന്നു, കണികാ ഭൗതികത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാന വശങ്ങളും ദ്രവ്യത്തിന്റെ ഘടനയും പര്യവേക്ഷണം ചെയ്യുന്നതിനുള്ള പരീക്ഷണങ്ങൾ സുഗമമാക്കുന്നു. ഹിഗ്സ് ബോസോണിനെ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നതിൽ എൽഎച്ച്സി ഒരു പ്രധാന പങ്ക് വഹിച്ചു, പ്രപഞ്ചത്തിന്റെ അടിസ്ഥാന കണങ്ങളെയും ശക്തികളെയും കുറിച്ചുള്ള നമ്മുടെ ഗ്രാഹ്യത്തിന് കാര്യമായ സംഭാവന നൽകി."},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Buléen di yëdoonte; buléen di jëwante.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Buléen di yëdoonte; buléen di jëwante.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Buléen: AUXdi: AUXyëdoonte: VERB;: PUNCTbuléen: AUXdi: AUXjëwante: VERB.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Dorcas ṣọlá Fapson","answer":"Dorcas ṣọlá Fapson jẹ́ òṣèrébìnrin àti atọ́kùn tí ó gbajúmọ̀ fún ipa tó kó nínú ètò kan tí wọ́n pè ní ṣúgà lórí ìkànnì MTV's. Àdàkọ:Circular reference as ‘Sophie’. Lọ́dún 2020, ó padà sí ètò ṣúgà náà lórí ìkànnì MTV láti sọ̀rọ̀ lórí àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn kòrónà pẹ̀lú àwọn òṣèré tí wọ́n ń ṣiṣẹ́ pọ̀ káàkiri ilẹ̀ adúláwọ̀ ÁfíríkàWọ́n bí Fapson nilui London ní nǹkan bí ọdún 1990s. Ìyá rẹ̀ kú nígbà tó wà lọ́mọ ọdún mẹ́rìnlá. Ó kàwé gboyè nínú ìmọ̀ ìṣe ọ̀daràn (Criminology) lórílẹ̀ èdè England. Ó tẹ̀ síwájú nínú ẹ̀kọ́ rẹ̀, ó sìn kàwé gboyè nínú ìmọ̀ tíátà ní New York.Ó kópa nínú ètò ṣúga abala kẹta ní ìkànnì MTV.[1] as ‘Sophie’ and she was the presenter of \\"The Juice\\" an interview series for NdaniTV.Ó wà nínú ètò ṣúgà ní ìkànnì MTV tí ó ó tún fi padà di akọ́ṣẹ́mọṣẹ́ ìṣègùn tí wọ́n pè ní \\"Sophie\\" nínú ètò mìíràn tí wón pè ní MTV Shuga Alone Together níbi tí wọ́n ti ń sọ̀rọ̀ nípa àjàkálẹ̀ àrùn kòrónà lọ́dún 2020. The series was written by Túndé Aládéṣe and broadcast for several nights - its backers include the United Nations. Àwọn ètò wọ̀nyí wà ní Nàìjíríà, South Africa, Kenya àti Côte d'Ivoire, tí ìtàn náà ń tẹ̀ síwájú lórí ìtàkùn ayélujára who include Mohau Cele, Lerato Walaza, Sthandiwe Kgoroge, Uzoamaka Aniunoh, Mamarumo Marokane and Jemima Osunde."},{"question":"Wafika ekhaya wangawuvala umlomo ngendlela uMaNdlovu amtshele ngayo.Baqala ukuba bethuke manje, kwakufanele ukuba basuke ngaso leso sikhathi bayeeMnambithi nabo bayofuna lapho becabanga ukuthi bakhona oyise nonina.Bahamba ubusuku bonke indodakazi yabo ingafuni ngisho ukubakhulumisa.EThekwini uMjwayeli nomkakhe baya kulo muzi lapho uyise wayejwayele ukuyakhona. Bathi bengena nje esangweni, indoda yavulela inja kwakhalwaubumayemaye inja enkulu ibasukela, wayikhuza. Bacela ukukhuluma nayo, yathiabangene.Baba ukungena nje endlini yababuza: 'Nginganisiza ngani?'Kwaphendula uMchunu: 'Besicela ukubuza ukuthi ubaba evalelisa kinina akashongoyini ukuthi uyaphi?''Uthe uya eMnambithi. Nikushiso yini lokho?''Abafowethu ababatholanga esiteshini, bafike sebehlile esitimeleni.''Kanti ubaba wenu ngempela uMchunu naningamnakile nje. UMchunu ubehambangezinto ezinganakekelwe zonke izinsuku ukhona makoti?' 1. Uyavumelana yini nombono wokuthi ukubekezela kuyasiza? Sekelaimpendulo yakho ngokubhekisa kuManyoba.","answer":"Ngiyavumelana ngoba ...• Ziningi izinkinga abhekana nazo esakhula, esesebenza nalaphoesenomndeni. Akalilahli nokho ithemba. • Nalapho esegugile eselahlwa yizingane zakhe ulokhu ebambeleleethembeni njalo nje futhi ugcina ephumeleleNOMAAngivumelani ngoba ...• Wabekezela esebenza kanzima efundisa izingane zakhe ngobaekholelwa ukuthi ziyoba usizo kuye uma esephelelwe ngamandlaokuzisebenzela. • Ukubekezela kwakhe akubanga nomphumela othokozisayo ngoba impiloyakhe yaze yashintsha emva kokuba ewine ilotho, okuyintoengahlanganise lutho nokubekezela kwakhe. "},{"question":"नेपालमा कागजी नोट कहिले देखि सुरु भयो ?","answer":"नेपालमा कागजी नोट बि.स. २००२ असोज ०१ देखि सुरु भयको थियो।"},{"question":"Qual a resposta correta para a pergunta a seguir: Qual é o rio mais longo do Brasil?","answer":"A resposta correta é Rio Amazonas"},{"question":"පහත වචනයට අදාළ විරුද්ධ පද කුමක්ද?අබියස","answer":"පිටුපස"},{"question":"Португалияда ден-соолуктун жана гүлдөп өнүгүүнүн символу деп эмне айтылат?","answer":"Жүзүм сабагы - Португалияда ден-соолуктун жана гүлдөп өнүгүүнүн символу"},{"question":"Qual é o processo pelo qual as plantas perdem água na forma de vapor através de pequenos poros em suas folhas?","answer":"Esse processo é chamado de transpiração. A transpiração é uma parte importante do ciclo da água nas plantas, e ocorre maioritariamente através das suas folhas."},{"question":"¿Cuál es la capital de Nariño Colombia?","answer":"La capital de Nariño Colombia es Pasto"},{"question":"Мүнүшкөр бул...","answer":"Илгери-илгери он жети жашар мүнүшкөр бир байдын үйүнө келип консо бир бүркүт турат. Эртең менен бай байбичеси экөө желеге бээ байлайлы деп кетишет. Бала бүркүткө карап:-Кайран асыл, билген кишинин колуна тийбей, билбес кишинин колуна тийипсиң,-деп сүйлөнөт.Анын сөзүн угуп калган бир бала байга барып:-Үйдөгү конок бала бүркүттү \\"кайран асыл, билген кишинин колуна тийбей, билбес кишинин колуна тийип калыпсың\\"-деп жатат,-дейт.Балага келип бай:Бүркүттү таптап бергин,-дейт.Бүркүттү таптоону билбеймин,-дейт бала.Балам, ушул бүркүттү таптап берсең, кызымды сага беремин,-дейт бай.Ошондо бала макул болуп:-Эки жыл туу калган бээ тап, бир боз үй тиктирип коюңуз, ал үйдүн ичинде эч нерсе болбосун, ага бүркүттү коёмун жана бээни союп этин киргиземин,-дейт. Бай эки жыл туу калган бээни алып келет жана бир үйдү тиктирип даярдайт, үйдүн ичине эч нерсе койдурбайт.Бала бээни сойдурат, аны бүтүн үйгө киргиздирет. Бүркүттү да кийирип байлабай бош коет. Ал чыгып кетпей турган кылып үйдү жылчыгы жок бекитет. Ошентип бүркүттү камап коет да, кээде гана суу берип коюп жүрөт. Бүркүт бээнин этин жеп бүтүп, семизинен басалбай калат. Бала: \\"Басалбай калган бүркүт таптоого оңой болот\\" деп, таптай баштайт. Бир ай таптагандан кийин аны түлкүгө салуу үчүн алып чыгат. Бир топ киши менен бала кыдырып жүрсө, бир кара түлкү чыга качат да, бүркүттү көрө салып тиктеп туруп калат, ал жөн түлкү эмес калтар экен. Бала бүркүттүн томогосун башынан алат да, бирок бүркүттө калтарга салбай томогосун кайра кийгизип коет. Бала менен бирге жүргөн кишилер: \\"Бүркүттү эмне салбайт?\\" деп таң калышат.Бала бүркүттү томогосун дагы башынан шыпырып алып, бүркүттү салбай томогосун кайра кийгизип коет. Баланын жолдоштору \\"бул бала бүркүтүн эмне салбайт, калтарды бизге ыраа көрбөй турат го\\" дешип наалышат.Бала томогону алып бүркүттү шилтейт. Бүркүт калтарга карабай асманга кетет. Калтар болсо алдыңкы эки бутун көтөрүп асманды тиктеп калат. Бүркүт өтө бийик көтөрүлүп, карааны көзгө көрүнбөй үлбүлдөп калган кезде шукшурулуп тик сайылып келип калтарды башынан мыкчый кармап көккө көтөрүлдү да, жерге таштап жиберди. Калтарды алышкандан кийин жолдоштору:Эки жолу бүркүттүн томогосун алдың, бирок салбадың, үчүнчү жолу гана салдың, мунун себеби кандай?-деп баладан сурашат.Биринчи жолу асыл менен асыл кантип беттешет деп бүркүттү калтарга салууга колум барбады. Экинчи жолу асылды асыл кантип кыят деп салууга колум барбады, үчүнчүсүндө тобокел деп чымырканып туруп бүркүтүмдү кое бердим, бүркүттүн асманга бийик чыкканынын себеби, ал канчалык бийик көтөрүлсө, ошончолук тиктей берип түлкүнүн көзүнө жаш толот, качырып келе жаткан бүркүттү көрбөй калат. Акчекир деген бүркүт ушул,-деди бала.Эл: \\"Чынында байдын кызы балага ылайык экен\\" дешип, баланы үйлөндүрүп-жайландырып коюшкан экен."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Togo?","answer":"Lomé é a capital do Togo e a maior cidade do país. A cidade e localiza-se na costa do Golfo da Guiné. Para além de ser a capital administrativa do país, é também a mais importante cidade do Togo. Lomé foi fundada no século XVIII pelos jejes e tornou-se capital no século seguinte."},{"question":"අතැඹුල උපසර්ගවලට අයත් වන්නෙ නැහැ නේ ද?","answer":"නෑ ....අත යනු උපසර්ගයක් නොවේ අත+ඇඹුලඅත්+අ+ඇඹුලඅත්+[අ]ඇඹුලඅතැඹුලපූර්ව ස්වර ලෝප සන්ධි "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'makan bunga'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengambil keuntungan daripada wang yang dipinjamkan. Contoh ayat: Ceti itu makan bunga dengan mengenakan kadar faedah 20% daripada jumlah wang yang dipinjam."},{"question":"Lớp 6A có 6 tổ học sinh. Để tổ chức liên hoan cho lớp, cô Ngân đã mua 42 chiếc bánh ngọt và 45 quả quýt.Cô Ngân có thể chia đều số bánh ngọt cho 6 tổ được không?Cô Ngân có thể chia đều số quả quýt cho 6 tổ được không?","answer":"Để biết cô Ngân có chia đều số bánh ngọt và số quả quýt cho 6 tổ hay không thì ta thực hiện phép chia.Ta có: 42 : 6 = 7 ; 45 : 6 = 7 (dư 3).Khi đó ta nói 42 chia hết cho 6 và 45 không chia hết cho 6 (qua bài học dưới này ta sẽ tìm hiểu kĩ hơn)Vậy cô Ngân có thể chia đều số bánh ngọt cho 6 tổ và không thể chia đều số quả quýt cho 6 tổ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berakit-rakit ke hulu, berenang-renang ke tepian; bersakit-sakit dahulu, bersenang-senang kemudian\\"? Berilah contoh ayat untuknya. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud untuk mendapat kesenangan, biar bersusah payah dahulu. Jikalau mahu menjadi orang yang berjaya, kamu mesti tabah menghadapi segala cabaran dan rintangan seperti kata pepatah berakit-rakit ke hulu, berenang-renang ke tepian; bersakit-sakit dahulu, bersenang-senang kemudian."},{"question":"Ibo ipinlẹ Edo ti wọn ti ka, Ọbasẹki lo wọle nibẹ o","answer":"Ninu ibo gomina ti wọn di ni ipinlẹ Ẹdo lanaa ode yii, awọn esi lati ijọba ibilẹ ti wọn ti ka ni akayanju bayii, Gomina Godwin Ọbasẹki lo wọle julọ. Ijọba ibilẹ mẹtala ni esi wọn ti jade, ninu awọn mẹtala naa, Ọbasẹki to n dije lorukọ ẹgbẹ APC ti mu mọkanla, nigba ti ẹni to n ba a du ipo naa, Pasitọ Ize-Iyamu ti mu meji pere. Lapapọ, o ti le ni ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọta ibo ti Ọbaseki fi ju Ize Iyamu lọ. Lati ipinlẹ marun-un lo ku t iwon tin reti esi idibo bayii, lẹyin naa ni ajọ INEC to n ṣeto idibo na ayo si kede ẹni to ba bori pata ninu wọn.Bi wọn ti to esi idibo naa tẹ le ara wọn ree, ati awọn ijoba ibilẹ wọn:Esan WestAPC 7,189PDP 17,434Oredo LGAAPC 18,365PDP 43,4983. Etsako West LGAAPC 26,140PDP 17,9594. Ovia North EastAPC 9,907PDP 16,9875. Esan South EastAPC 9,237PDP 10,5656. Owan WestAPC 11,193PDP 11,485Owan EastAPC 19,295PDP 14,7628. Egor LGAAPC 10,202PDP 27,6219. UhunmwondeAPC 5,972PDP 10,02210. Ikpoba-Okha LGAAPC – 18,218PDP – 41,03011. Esan Central LGAPC 6,719PDP 10,6941 Esan North East LGAPC – 6,556PDP – 13, 57913. Igueben LGAPDP – 7,870APC – 5,199"},{"question":"Kedu mgbe agbara ụlo Igwe Oliver Nnaji ","answer":"A gbara ụlọ Igwe Oliver Nnaji nke Ogwu Aniocha Anambra steeti ọkụ n'abalị iri na isii nke ọnwa Nọvemba  nke afọ 2021."},{"question":"“东风压倒西风”这句话是什么意思呢？","answer":"这句话原指封建大家庭里对立的两方,一方压倒另一方；现比喻革命力量对于反动势力占压倒的优势。"},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay fipoahana volkano malaza any Indonezia izay nisy vokany ara-toetr'andro tamin'ny 1815?","answer":" Ny anaran'ilay fipoahana volkano malaza any Indonezia izay nisy fiantraikany ara-toetr'izao tontolo izao tamin'ny 1815 dia ny fipoahan'ny Tendrombohitra Tambora."},{"question":"O dono de um restaurante situado às margens de uma rodovia percebeu que, ao colocar uma placa de propaganda de seu restaurante ao longo da rodovia, as vendas aumentaram. Pesquisou junto aos seus clientes e concluiu que a probabilidade de um motorista perceber uma placa de anúncio é 1/2 . Com isso, após autorização do órgão competente, decidiu instalar novas placas com anúncios de seu restaurante ao longo dessa rodovia, de maneira que a probabilidade de um motorista perceber pelo menos uma das placas instaladas fosse superior a 99/100. A quantidade mínima de novas placas de propaganda a serem instaladas é?a) 99.b) 51.c) 50.d) 6.e) 1.","answer":"d) 6."},{"question":"Umhlaba ungumhlaba ngokuhlabaUwuhloniphe uwukhonze uyakuhloniphaUbazonda kabi abazazi ukuhlakanipha.Lunye kuwo uhamboImpinda ayikho.Sinye kuwo isikhathiSifushane aseneleUbupigogo nobusakabuli buyaqedwaBushazwe yizangqotho nemishazo yomhlabaOmahlalothini abantengenyekayo ntengentengeBawe bhu bahuhuluze okwamahoboshaAbaqhwaklazela phezul' onontandakubukwaBaphenduk’izinqibi kugayingane imilomoOsemuva limshwibe shwi limbeke phambiliNgentobeko yobuphansi okwentuthaneUbe phansi nangenzolo ezothile yobuntu.1. Fingqa kafushane okushiwo yimbongi","answer":"Imbongi ithi ukuziqhenya nokuziphakamisa/ukuzithwalakomuntu kugcina kuphelile. Imbongi ithi ukuzikhukhumeza kwenza umuntu agcineejezisiwe ukuze afunde isifundo sokuthi kubalulekileukuzehlisa. Abaziphakamisayo bayathotshiswa bazithole sebebhuquzaphansi."},{"question":"Tunjukkan saya cara-cara menyediakan Bak Kut Teh yang halal dengan daging lembu dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan A: Herba bak kut teh-Dang shenTong DSum (Codonopdidi root)-You zhuYok cook (Solomon seal’s rhizome)-Black dates-GojiWolf Berries-Chuan Xiong (Rhizoma ligustici)-Shu di huang/Lo sok tei (Rehmannia)-Star anise, clove, fennel seeds, peppercornBahan B: Daging lembu, 1 labu bawang putih yang tidak perlu dikupas dan diketuk. halia, cendawan shitake, sos tiram, kicap cair, sedikit kicap pekat, perasaCara memasak:1. Kesemua bahan-bahan dimasukkan sekali ke dalam periuk.2. Masak dengan api perlahan selama 1 jam lebih atau lagi bagus guna pressure cooker.3. Guna pressure cooker tak perlu masak lama. Set je bahagian daging, dalam 30 minit daging sudah empuk dan bahan-bahan herba tadi pun dah meresap ke seluruh daging.4. Sup siap dan boleh dimakan."},{"question":"සිංහල ආප්තෝපදේශයක් එහි උපදෙසද සමග දෙන්න.","answer":"අලි විකුණා ලාභ ගන්න බැරි වූදේ තම්පලා විකිණීමෙන් ලබාගත නොහැකලැබුණු ලොකුම අවස්ථාවෙන් ප්‍රයෝජන නොගෙන වෙනත් සුළු සුළු දේවල් කිරීමෙන් පලක් නැත"},{"question":"Iza no tena anaran'ilay mpanao sarimihetsika mampihomehy Roy Chubby Brown ? ","answer":"I Royston Vasey no tena anaran'ilay mpanao sarimihetsika mampihomehy mitondra ny solon'anarana Roy Chubby Brown. "},{"question":"Idayari yami: impelasontoA uSenzoEkugcineni, usuku ebengilufisa seluze lwafika. NguMgqibelo namuhla futhi usuku lwami lokuzalwanjengoba ngineminyaka eyishumi nesithupha. Angilicelanga ikhekhe elibhakwe ekhaya kulokhukodwa abazali bami bangithengele yonke into engibacele yona – angikholwa! Ngiyacabanga ukuthiudadewethu nomfowethu bese bekhathele yimi ngibaxoxela ngokuthi ngifisa lube njani lolu suku.Sekuphele amasonto amaningi ngilungiselela futhi ngicabanga ngalolu suku. Angikholwa ukuthiangilalanga ngicabanga ubumnandi esizoba nabo mina nabangane bami. Bonke abangane bamibangitshelile ukuthi bazofika ekhaya lami ngehora lokuqala. Ngiyathemba ukuthi abangane bamibangithengele izipho ezinhle. Ubani ngempela ongazithandi izipho.B uZandleLolu suku belulude kodwa futhi lube mnandi kakhulu. Abangane bami bangijabulise kakhulungokuzongihalalisela emva kokuphumelela emncintiswaneni wokugijima obungempelasontoedlule. Khona ngangingakholwa nami ukuthi yimi lo osekwazi ukugijima ibanga elide kangaka.Bengingakulindele ukuthi abangane bami bangihalalisele ngokungithelenga izinto eziningi kangaka.Noma ngingeyena umuntu othanda izipho kakhulu kodwa ngiyazi ukuthi uma uthola izipho lokhokukhombisa ukuthi abantu bakukhonzile. Mina kungenze ngaba namahloni kodwa ngabona futhiukuthi abangane bami bangithanda kangakanani. Angazi ukuthi yini engiyenzile ukuba ngifanelweukwenzelwa into enhle kangaka. Ngithole izinto eziningi kakhulu futhi ebengihlale ngifisa ukubanazo kodwa ebengingakabi nawo amandla okuzithengela zona. Ukuba nabangane abafana nalabakungikhumbuza izimfundiso zikamama wami zokuthi kubalulekile ukukhetha abangane abajabulanawe futhi bakweseke.C uMattAbantu abaningi bajwayele ukusho ukuthi abezwani nezingane zakubo. Bayaxabana njalo futhiabalekelelani. Lokhu kubi ngempela. Ngiyawuthanda umndeni wami. Senza izinto ezahlukene.Kwesinye isikhathi udadewethu uthanda ukulalela umculo ekamelweni lakhe kanti mina nomfowethusidlala ibhola. Sivame ukudlala umdlalo wamakhadi noma umdlalo webhodi ngempelasonto futhisiyahleka siphinde sikhale kwezinye izikhathi. Ngithemba ukuthi izingane zami ziyofana nathi. Nomasingefani, siyezwana kakhulu, futhi asithandi ukuxabana. Siyadumala uma oyeda wethu engaphilile.Nginesiqiniseko ukuthi ubaba nomama bayaziqhenya ngathi.D uKhethiweLolu bekuwusuku oluhle kimi. Ubaba wami ungisizile ukuthi sithenge yonke into engiyidingayoukubhaka ikhekhe futhi umama ungithembisile ukuthi uzongisiza uma esebuyile emsebenzini.Yisona sipho engizosipha umngane wami uSamantha. Ukubhaka kuyiyona ndlela engiziphumuzangayo nokuthatha ikhefu emsebenzini wami wesikole. Uthisha wami uthi kumele senze nezinyeizinto ngaphandle komsebenzi wesikole. Ukubhaka kungisize ukuba ngifunde ukuthi ezinye izintokumele zilindwe. Kumele ulandele iresiphi, ukuhlanganisa izithako, ulinde likhukhumale, ukulilindaliphole bese ulihlobisa bese uzwa ubumnandi. Ngiyazi umngane wami uzojabula ngoMsombulukouma esebona ngifika nekhekhe esikoleni.1.  owazimangaza ngokuphumelela kwakhe?","answer":"B"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa sidda looga hortagi karo  kansarka ku dhaca mindhicirrada?","answer":"Hadii aad ku jirto  ama aad nolol maalmeedkaagu ku salaysanyahay qodobada dadka halista ugu jirah aan ku xusnay waxaad u  baahantahay in 2—6 bilood inta udhaxaysa hal mar inaad fiirisid mindhiradaada. Sidaad u nooshahay waxay ka hortagi kartaah  darajada xanuunku uu kugu dhici karoh  tusaale ahaan hadii aad isticmaasho cuntooyin isku dheeli tiran  subaxa canjeero ,duhurka khudaar habeenka cuntooyinka galka leh  waxay kaa fogaynaysaa ama aad kaga hortagaysaa darajada xanuunku uu kuugu dhici karoh.Jimicsigu waxa uu ka qayb-qaatah in caafimaadka mindhicirka weyn uu noqdo mid caafimaadkiisu uu aad u sareeyoh  ,biyo cabista badan iyo dhaqdhaqaaqa muruqyada ka sareeya mindhicirada waxa ay kor uqaadan in qashin badan laga saaro mindhicirada lagana hortago calool istaag.Miisaankaga ku ilaali  miisaan caafimaad qab ah 75kg.SIDEE LOO BAADHAA XANUUNKA. Tuunbo ku xidhantahay kamerad ayaa lagu dhaadhiciniyah qofka.Dhiig ayaa baadhitaan lagu samaynayah.DAAWAYN.Daawaynta ugu muhiimsan waa in laga jaraa mindhicirka halka uu kaga dhacay xanuunka kansarka.Daawooyinka kale dhakhaatiirta ayaa ka tashanaysa si xaaladiisa loogu lifaaqo.Hadii aad  halis ugu jirto xanuunkan hagaaji oo ka hortag xanuunka.Hadii aad calaamadaha  isku aragtay la xidhiidh sida ugu dhakhsiyaha badan  dhakhtar."},{"question":"ಒಗಟನ್ನು ಬಿಡಿಸಿ: ಊಟಕ್ಕೆ ಕುಳಿತವರು ಹನ್ನೆರಡು ಜನರು, ಬಡಿಸುವವರು ಇಬ್ಬರು, ಒಬ್ಬನು ಒಬ್ಬರಿಗೆ ಬಡಿಸುವಸ್ಟರಲ್ಲಿ ಇನ್ನೊಬ್ಬನು ಹನ್ನೆರಡು ಜನಕ್ಕೂ ಬಡಿಸಿರುತ್ತಾನೆ","answer":"ಗಡಿಯಾರ"},{"question":"मराठ्यांचा सर्वश्रेष्ठ सेनापती कोण होता ?","answer":"मराठ्यांचा सर्वश्रेष्ठ सेनापती बाजीराव पेशवा होता ."},{"question":"在加拿大，當發生交通意外時，什麼情況下一定要報警？","answer":"損失超過2000 或有人受傷或死亡"},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana :  “Mankahala legioma maitso izy ireo.” sy \\"Tsy tian'izy ireo mihitsy ny legioma maitso.\\"Mifanindran-teny ve ireo ?","answer":"Eny, miresaka momban'ny tsy fitiavana legioma maintso ireo."},{"question":"Kí ni orúkọ gómínà àkọ́kọ́ ní ìpínlẹ̀ Delta?","answer":"Felix Ibru ni."},{"question":"અહીં એક \\"સૌથી મોટું ઈનામ\\" બાળવાર્તા ના શરૂઆતના ફકરા લખેલા છે:\\"એક વરુ હતું. એક દિવસ તે શિકાર કરીને ખાતું હતું ત્યારે ઉતાવળમાં તેના ગળામાં નાનું હાડકું ફસાઈ ગયું. એણે હાડકાને બહાર કાઢવા ઘણી મહેનત કરી પણ હાડકું બહાર નીકળ્યું નહિ.તેને થયું કે જો આ હાડકું નહિ નીકળે તો હું ભૂખ અને તરસથી મરી જઈશ! તે જંગલનાં બધાં પ્રાણીને કહેવા લાગ્યું, ‘મારા ગળામાંથી હાડકું કાઢી આપો ને?’ પણ બધાં પ્રાણીઓએ એને કહ્યું કે ના, અમે નહિ કાઢી આપીએ.વરુને ગળામાં ખૂબ જ દુઃખવા લાગ્યું. તે બરાડા પાડતું નદી કિનારે આવી પહોંચ્યું. ત્યાં એક બગલો ઊભો હતો.\\"આ વાર્તા ને પુરી કરો.","answer":"વરુએ બગલાને કહ્યું,‘બગલાભાઈ, મારા ગળામાં ફસાયેલ હાડકું કાઢી આપો, હું તમને મોટું ઈનામ આપીશ.’વરુ પોતાનું મોં ખલ્લું રાખીને બેઠો હતો. બગલાભાઈએ ઈનામની લાલચે વરુના મોંમા તેની ચાંચ નાખી ખૂબ મહેનત કરીને વરુના ગળામાંથી હાડકું બહાર કાઢ્યું. વરુને રાહત થઈ.બગલો કહે, ‘વરુભાઈ, મને મારું ઈનામ આપી દો.’વરુ ઘૂરક્યો, ‘અલ્યા બગલા! તું ઈનામથી વાત ભૂલી જા. મારા મોંમાંથી કોઈ બચ્યું છે ખરું? તારી ડોક મારા મોમાં હતી તોય હું તને મારીને ખાઈ ન ગયો એટલે તારે મારો આભાર માનવો જોઈએ. તું બચી ગયો છે, આથી વધુ સારું ઈનામ હું તને બીજું શું આપું, બોલ?’બગલો શું બોલે? મોં વકાસીને બેસી રહ્યો. લુચ્ચું વરુ ત્યાંથી હસતું હસતું જતું રહ્યું."},{"question":"Jox ma péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Ñent (4) i néew la'ñ yóbbu fa cùuruur u Dàlal Jàmm bu Géejawaay ginnaaw ñaxtu yi àm ci réew mi.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Ñent (4) i néew la'ñ yóbbu fa cùuruur u Dàlal Jàmm bu Géejawaay ginnaaw ñaxtu yi àm ci réew mi.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Ñent: NUM(: PUNCT4: NUM): PUNCTi: ADPnéew: NOUNla: AUX'ñ: PRONyóbbu: VERBfa: ADVcùuruur: NOUNu: ADPDàlal: NOUNJàmm: NOUNbu: PRONGéejawaay: PROPNginnaaw: ADPñaxtu: NOUNyi: PRONàm: ADJci: ADPréew: NOUNmi: DET.: PUNCT"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الملقب بروح الله؟","answer":"الإجابة: عيسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"Enunciado 1: Imagica y Robot Communications fundaron Imagica Robot Holdings Inc. el 1 de abril de 2004 e Imagica se volvió parte de esta compañía.Enunciado 2: El 1 de abril de 2004, Imagica y Robot Communications coestablecieron Imagica Robot Holdings Inc., e Imagica se volvió parte de esta compañía.Pregunta: ¿El Enunciado 1 expresa el mismo significado al Enunciado 2? Responde Sí o No a la pregunta.","answer":"Sí, el Enunciado 1 tiene el mismo significado al Enunciado 2."},{"question":"දාර්ශනික දේවධර්මය යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"දාර්ශනික දේවධර්මය, දේවධර්මයේ ශාඛාවක් වන අතර දිව්‍යය සත්‍යයන් පිළිබඳ පැහැදිලි අවබෝධයක් ලබා ගැනීම සඳහා දාර්ශනික ක්‍රම උපයෝගී කර ගනියි. සත්‍යය කරා ලඟා වීමට මිනිසා දරන උත්සහයට දේවධර්මය හා දර්ශනය යන දෙකම සම්බන්ධ විය යුතුද, නැතහොත් දිව්‍යමය එළිදරව්ව තනිවම පැවතිය හැකිද යන්න පිළිබඳ විවාද පවතී. දේවධර්මවාදී සංකල්පවලට දාර්ශනික ක්‍රමය කෙතරම් පුළුල් ලෙස යොදා ගත යුතුද යන්න පිළිබඳව රටවල් පුරා විවිධ න්‍යායන් තිබේ. සමහරු පවසන්නේ එම කරුණු දෙක එකිනෙක සමඟ කිසිම සම්බන්ධයක් නැති බවයි. දිව්‍යමය එළිදරව්ව මිනිසා නිවැරදිව වටහා ගැනීමට නම් දර්ශනය හා තර්කය අවශ්‍යය බව තවත් සමහරු පවසති. තවත් සමහරු දර්ශනවාදය ප්‍රයෝජණවත් මෙවලමක් වන නමුත් එය සම්පූර්ණයෙන් රඳා නොපවතින බව පවසමින් මධ්‍යස්ථ ප්‍රවේශයක් ගනිති. දාර්ශණික දේවධර්මය යනු නිවැරදි ආකාරයකින් හෝ වැරදි ආකාරයකින් භාවිතා කළ හැකි මෙවලමකි. එය චේතනාව හා ප්‍රමුඛතාවය පිළිබඳ ප්‍රශ්ණයකි: මිනිසා විසින් සාදනලද ඉදිකිරීම් මනා විශ්වාසය තබා දෙවියන්ගේ මාර්ග සහ සිතුවිලි තේරුම් ගැනීමට අප උත්සහ කරන්නේ නම්, අප බලාපොරොත්තු සුන්වනු ඇත. මිනිසා බාබෙල් කුළුණේ සිට දෙවියන්වහන්සේ වෙත ළඟා වීමට ඇති හැකියාව ඔප්පු කිරීමට උත්සහ කරයි. නමුත් ප්‍රේමයෙන් සහ දෙවියන් වහන්සේව හඳුනාගැනීමේ ආශාවෙන් පෙළඹී ඇත්නම්, අපි අපගේ මනස වඩාත් හොඳින් භාවිතා කරමු."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"belum tuarang panjang, buah sengkuang sebesar betis\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud khabar angin yang dilebih-lebihkan."},{"question":"Qeex koox? ","answer":"Koox waa dad badan oo meel iskugu imaaday."},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் முக்கடல் சங்கமிக்கும் இடம்  எது?","answer":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் முக்கடல் சங்கமிக்கும் இடம்  கன்னியாகுமாரி. கன்னியாகுமரி மாவட்டம் தமிழ்நாட்டின் முப்பத்தி எட்டு மாவட்டங்களில் ஒன்றாகும். இந்தியாவின் தென்கோடியில் அமைந்துள்ள இம்மாவட்டத்தின் தலைநகரம் நாகர்கோவில் ஆகும். இந்த மாவட்டம் 1,672 ச.கி.மீ. பரப்பளவைக் கொண்டுள்ளது. இம்மாவட்டத்தில் தமிழ் மற்றும் மலையாள மொழிகள் பேசப்படுகின்றன."},{"question":"* ما عدد أجنحة البرغوث؟","answer":"لا يوجد أجنحة بل يمشي قفزاً."},{"question":"\\"Nahazo fanomezana tsy fantatra anarana teo am-baravarako aho nandritra ny fialantsasatra:\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha?A. Fihetseham-po avy amin'ny mpankafy miafina ilay fanomezana.B. Fifangaroana fanaterana ilay izy, ary natao ho an'ny jiosy ilay fanomezana","answer":"A. no fiafarana azo inoana indrindra."},{"question":"\\"Аман болчу Кыргызстан!\\"- деген ыр кимге таандык?","answer":"Зарылбек Ажыматов го таандык.АМАН БОЛЧУ, КЫРГЫЗСТАН!Кагылайын Кыргызстан, кагылайын,Кайраттанып карууңду жаңылагын.Каным, жаным дартыңа шыпаа болсо,Канатыңды сун мага, дарылайын.Өлбө өлкөм, балапан жаш чагыңда,Өлөлү биз калганча арт жагыңда.Уялаштар, аздектеп карегиңдей,Урпактарга мекенди сактагыла.Жара тартар бөрү көп жан-жагыңда,Жүк бар билем опол тоо ай далыңда.Элди ая, керемет Кыргызстаным,Эссиз чыкты бектериң, хандарың даЖүрөгүңдү жебедей көзөп өттүк,Жүдөө кылдык, өйдө-ылдый көмөлөттүк.Мыскыл кылып душманга бул доордо,Мырза болчуң, биз сени чөгөлөттүк..Ынтымаксыз күчтөрдөн арыдыңбы,Ыйлап турам, өчүрбө жарыгыңды.Ала-Тоом, биз сени жыргатпадык,Аңкаябыз билбестен кадырыңды.Айланайын, Кыргызстан, айланайын,Аска - тооңду кучактап аймалайын.Өчө көрбө, картадан өчө көрбө,Катарын түк бузбасын тамгаларың.Бүтүн болуп дайыма турууң керек,А мен сага ырымды сунуум керек.Бизди кечир, Ата журт, аман болсоң,Бир доордо сен күткөн муун келет. "},{"question":"ما هي عاصمة السويد؟","answer":"عاصمة السويد هي ستوكهولم وهي أكبر مدينة في البلاد."},{"question":"Kayan Aiki yin Sussukar ?","answer":"Turmi da Taɓarya: Su ne muhimman kayan aikin sussuka, ana zuba dukkan abin da ake son casawa a cikin turmi sai kuma a riƙa bugunsa da taɓarya har sai an cire asalin ƙwayar daga jikin abin da ba a so.Babbar tabarma: Akan zuba abin da ake casawa a kai. Sannan kuma wasu lokutan akan yi sussukar a kan tabarmar ta hanyar bugu.Masaki: Ana zuba sussukakken abu a ciki.Ƙwarya: Kamar masaki take, sai dai girmanta bai kai na masaki ba. Da ita ake yin shiƙa (shiƙa ita ce cire ƙaiƙayi ko kwanso daga cikin asalin ƙwayar abin da aka sussuka ta hanyar ɗaga abin sama ana juyewa a cikin ƙwaryar da ke ƙasa, idan iska ta ratsa tsakani sai ta kore ƙaiƙayin ya fice daga cikin ƙwayar).Faifai: Ana tankaɗe sauran abin da bai sheƙu ba domin a cire abubuwan da ba a so kamar tsakuwa wacce ita bata sheƙuwa.Sanda: Dogon ita ce ne mai kauri da kuma ƙarfi. Da shi ake bugu idan ba a turmi za a yi casar ba."},{"question":"كيفية التسجيل للحصول على حساب تويتر باستخدام جوجل","answer":"1. اذهب إلى موقع تويتر على الإنترنت2. انقر على المتابعة بإستخدام جوجل3. سيظهر لك مربع اختيار حساب4. اختر المتابعة باستخدام حساب جوجل 5.إذا لم يظهر لك الحساب الذي ترغب في استخدامه انقر فوق إضافة حساب"},{"question":"O ṣoju mi koro (Apa Kin-in-ni)","answer":"Olori ilẹ wa, Ọgagun agba Muhammadu Buhari, lọ si orilẹ-ede Mali, lọsẹ to kọja. Ohun pataki kan naa lo tori ẹ lọ, o lọọ ba wọn pari ija lọhun-un ni. Ko pada yaayan lẹnu pe wọn ko rija naa pari, koda, abuku ni wọn sọ pe o kan Buhari nibẹ, nitori ko si ẹni to ka ọrọ rẹ si kinni kan laarin awọn olori ijọba to ku. Ọrọ yii ko le ṣe ko ma ri bẹẹ, ẹni ti yoo ba niyi nita, ile ni yoo ti niyi lọ. Ṣugbọn Aarẹ tiwa nigbagbọ pe ita loun yoo ti maa niyi wa sile nitori bẹẹ, awọn ohun to ba jẹ ti araata ni yoo mura lati ba wọn da si, ti yoo si fi ina buruku to n jo loriṣiiriṣii ni ile tirẹ silẹ. Nigba ti Buhari n lọ si Mali yii, o lo ibomu-bẹnu lati bo imu ati ẹnu rẹ, Naijiria nibi lo si ti gbe kinni naa lọ. Lara ohun ti awọn ti wọn n gbogun ti arun Korona yii kari aye sọ naa ni pe lati ma jẹ ki arun yii gbilẹ, afi ki gbogbo ẹni to ba fẹẹ jade sita, tabi to ba fẹẹ gbalejo, tabi ti yoo ba wa laarin eeyan meji mẹta, lo ibomu-bẹnu. Ṣugbọn lati ọjọ ti Buhari ti n jade ni Naijiria, tabi to n ba awọn eeyan sọrọ, ko lo kinnni naa ri. Boya lo si mọ pe ohun to n ṣe yii ni ọpọ awọn alaṣẹ ilu n ṣe, ti ọgọọrọ eeyan nilẹ Hausa n ṣe, oun ni wọn n fara we, nigba ti oun to jẹ olori ilu ko ṣe bẹẹ, kin ni araalu yoo maa ṣe bẹẹ si. Iye oku to nikan sun ni ilẹ Hausa, agaga ni Kano ati Katsina, wọn ko ṣee ka niye tan bayii o. Lojoojumọ, iku ni. Kin ni Buhari ri ṣe si iru nnkan bayii. Tabi eleyii ko to ohun to n dẹru ba olori ijọba ni. Awọn olori ologun to yẹ ko ri si iru nnkan bayii, gbogbo wọn lo ti rẹ, gbogbo aye lo si n pariwo pe ki Buhari paarọ wọn, ṣugbọn Buhari ko ṣe bii ẹni pe oun gbọ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn eeyan naa ko wulo fun Naijiria mọ. Ninu awọn minisita ati awọn ti wọn n ba a ṣejọba, ija buruku to n lọ laarin wọn ko ṣee gbọ, wọn aa ma ṣe tanadi ara wọn debii pe iṣẹ ijọba to yẹ ko lọ deede ko ni i lọ deede, ipalara oriṣiiriṣii lo si n lọ. Buhari to ni oun yoo gbogun ti iwa ibajẹ, iwa ibajẹ to wa ninu ijọba tirẹ funra rẹ ju eyi ti a ti n ba bọ latẹyin lọ. Awọn ohun to yẹ ki Buhari moju to gbogbo ree nile, awọn ohun to yẹ ki awọn oludamọran ẹ ba a sọ niyi! Tabi kin ni iṣẹ awọn to n gba Buhari nimọran! Bo ba si jẹ oun ni ko gbọ amọran wọn, ki wọn fi iṣẹ rẹ silẹ, ki aye le mọ ibi ti wọn yoo doju ọrọ wọn kọ. Ẹ gba a nimọran tootọ, ẹ jẹ ko mọ pe ẹni ti ko ba niyi ninu ile ẹ, ko ni i niyi nita o!Iwa ibajẹ inu ijọba yii le debii pe awọn ẹgbe oṣelu PDP pe lọsẹ to kọja pe ki Buhari kọwe fi ipo rẹ silẹ, nitori apa rẹ ko ka igbogun ti iwa ibajẹ yii mọ rara, ati ki awọn ti wọn n kowo jẹ ma wo Naijiria yii mọ gbogbo wa lori. Loootọ ẹgbẹ PDP naa ki i ṣe ẹni ti eeyan n ka ọrọ wọn si, nitori awọn naa ko kuku san to ba di ibi owo-kikojẹ, ṣugbọn awọn ohun to ṣẹlẹ lasiko yii ko le jẹ ki eeyan ko ọrọ wọn danu patapata. Ẹ jẹ ka fi ọrọ Magu ati Malami silẹ sẹgbẹẹ kan, ẹ jẹ ka wo ohun to n ṣẹlẹ nileeṣẹ ijọba ti wọn da silẹ fun idagbasoke agbegbe Naija-Delta, iyẹn NNDC (Niger Delta Development Commission). Awọn owo ti wọn ni wọn ko jẹ to foju han, ati awọn ọrọ aṣiwere ti wọn kọ siwee nipa bi wọn ṣe nawo naa jẹ ohun ti ko le mu orukọ orilẹ-ede yii ni iyi kan lẹyin odi rara. Lasiko ti Korona mu gbogbo eeyan yii, ti ijọba ṣofin pe ki ẹnikẹni ma jade, ileeṣẹ yii si kọ ọ sinu iwe wọn pe awọn fi milọnu ọtalelẹgbẹta o din mẹrin naira (N656m) ṣe idanilẹkọọ fawọn oṣiṣẹ awọn. Lasiko Korona! Awọn oṣiṣẹ wọn ko lọ sibi iṣẹ o, awọn kan kan jokoo sibi kan, wọn si ko owo naa jẹ, wọn si gbe e sinu iwe bẹẹ, pẹlu igbagbọ pe ko sẹni ti yoo yẹ awọn lọwọ wo. Awọn owo ti wọn ṣẹ si minisita wọn, Godswill Akpabio, lọrun ki i ṣe kekere, o si daju pe ọkunrin naa ti inu PDP waa kowo jẹ ninu ijọba APC yii ni. Ẹni ti wọn fi ṣe olori ileeṣẹ yii, nigba ti ọrọ da bayii, ti awọn aṣofin ni ko waa rojọ ohun to mọ, o kuku wa sibẹ o. Ṣugbọn ibeere ẹyọ kan ni wọn bi i, n lo ba daku pata. Ko si ji saye ti wọn fi gbe e jade, igba to jade lo ji saye pada. Akpabio ti wọn pe ko waa rojọ naa dewaju awọn aṣofin, o si sọ ọ loju wọn nibẹ pe gbogbo owo ti wọn n sọrọ ẹ pe o sọnu yii, pupọ wa lọwọ awọn aṣofin gan-an funra wọn, nitori awọn ọmọ ile-igbimọ naa gba iṣẹ lọwọ NNDC ti wọn ko si ṣe e, wọn si ti gbowo ẹ. N lawọn aṣofin ba binu, wọn ni ko maa lọ. Meloo leeyan waa fẹẹ ka ninu iwa ibajẹ to n lọ nileeṣẹ kan ṣoṣo. Gbogbo wa la n pariwo pe ijọba ko ran awọn ara Naija Delta, nibi ti wọn ti n wa epo bẹntiroolu ni Naijiria lọwọ, ṣugbọn awọn aṣiri to jade yii n fi han pe awọn oloṣelu Naija Delta gan-an lọta awọn eeyan wọn. Ṣugbọn Buhari lo yan awọn araabi yii sipo, ṣe bi yoo ṣe waa maa wo wọn niran ti wọn yoo ba aye jẹ, ti wọn yoo tun ba ọrun jẹ ree, ti wọn yoo si sọ Naijiria di ilu oniyẹyẹ laarin awọn orilẹ-ede aye gbogbo. Ko si ohun to n jẹ ki awọn eeyan yii mura si ole jija ju pe ijọba wa ki i ṣe nnkan kan fun wọn, paapaa ti wọn ba ti jẹ ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu wọn tabi ti wọn ba sun mọ Aarẹ funra rẹ. Ohun to n ba gbogbo ẹ jẹ ree o. Ẹ bẹ Buahri ko ma ṣe bii ẹni pe oun ko gbọ ọrọ awọn akowojẹ wọnyi, ko jẹ ki wọn ju wọn sẹwọn, ki Naijiria le sinmi.Ismail Issa Funtua, ọkan ninu awọn ti wọn sun mọ Buhari ju lọ ku lọsẹ to kọja yii. Bo ti ku laaarọ ni wọn ti palẹ oku ẹ mọ, koda, wọn ko rẹ ibi ti wọn sin in si, wọn kan ko yeepẹ le e lori lasan ni. Bẹẹ ni baba naa lọ. Ṣugbọn ninu awọn ti wọn lu ọmọ Naijiria ni jibiti to pọ ju lọ laye yii, ọkan ni Issa Funtua, awọn ekute ile to n jẹun nile ijọba gbogbo to ba ti jẹ ni Naijiria yii ni. Ṣugbọn laye ijọba Buhari yii ni Funtua di ikooko, ẹran nla lo ku to n gbe; o di kalokalo miwo miwo, o si n ko owo ọmọ Naijiria mi. Ọkunrin naa ko ni iṣẹ gidi kan, loootọ oniroyin ni, ṣugbọn lati ọdun 1980 to ti da iwe iroyin Democrat silẹ, ti iwe naa si ti ku ni bii ọdun marun-un lẹyin ẹ, ọkunrin yii ko ṣiṣẹ mi-in mọ, ka maa jẹ nidii ijọba to ba jẹ nikan lo n ṣe. Ohun to waa mu ti asiko Buhari yii le ni pe oun nikan ni ọrẹ ati ana Buhari ninu awọn mẹta ti wọn sun mọ ọn ju lọ. Awọn ti wọn n ba Buhari ṣejọba rẹ ree, oun, Maman Daura ati Abba Kyari. Nitori eyi lo ṣe n fi orukọ Buhari gba oriṣiiriṣii iṣẹ ijọba. Oun lo sun ọkunrin kan, Emefiele, kẹrẹkẹrẹ titi ti Buhari fi fi iyẹn ṣe olori banki apapọ ilẹ wa. Lati igba naa ni Funtua ti n gba owo dọla ni Central Bank, ti yoo ni oun fẹẹ fi raja kan lati oke-okun, ṣugbọn to jẹ awọn Mọla to n ṣẹwo ni yoo ta a fun, ti yoo si tibẹ ri ere rẹpẹtẹ ti awọn ti wọn nileeṣẹ nla ko le jẹ. Funtua gba iṣẹ ọgbọn biliọnu lọwọ Central Bank, o loun yoo ba wọn fi kọ aaye igbọkọ si (Car Park), si ileeṣẹ wọn l’Abuja. Bi eeyan ba tilẹ fẹẹ kọ aaye mọto fun gbogbo aye, owo rẹ wa gbọdọ to bẹẹ! Funtua ati ọkọ ọmọ rẹ fi jibiti ra banki Keynote. Bi wọn ṣe ṣe e ni pe ọkọ ọmọ rẹ lo wa nileeṣẹ ijọba to maa n gba awọn ileeṣẹ to ba jẹ gbese, tabi ti wọn fẹẹ kogba wọle (AMCON). Ọkọ ọmọ rẹ yii lo gba banki Keynote lorukọ ileeṣẹ yii, ti wọn ni ki awọn eeyan waa ra a. Funtua lawọn yoo ra a, bẹẹ ni Funtua ko lowo lọwọ. Ni ọkọ ọmọ rẹ ba gbowo lati ileeṣẹ AMCON, o gbe e si banki kan, banki naa ni awọn ya Funta lowo, ni wọn ba fi ra banki naa, wọn waa ni ki banki yii maa san gbese naa pada diẹ diẹ. Bi ileeṣẹ naa ṣe di tiwọn niyẹn. Nitori pe o sun mọ Buhari yii, ko sohun to nawọ si ti ko to o lọwọ. Ni awọn gomina, awọn minisita, awọn oloṣelu Naijiria gbogbo ba n wọ lọ sile ẹ bii pe oun gan-an ni olori ijọba. Ṣugbọn o ku lọṣẹ to kọja, o fi aye silẹ lai dagbere. Gbogb ohun to fi ọna buruku ko jọ yii, ko duro lati jẹ ere ọkankan nibẹ, nitori Ọlọrun fi han an pe oun ju gbogbo ẹda aye lọ. Ko si ọna mi-in ti awọn oloṣelu Naijiria fi le kọgbọn ju iru eyi lọ. Oloṣelu to ba fẹẹ ṣoriire, ko fi ti Funtua kọgbọn, ko ma wa ile aye mọya, ko mọ  pe ile aye ki i ṣe awaa lọ.Nijọ kan, awọn ọmọ orilẹ-ede Naijiria yoo gbọn daadaa lati mọ pe awọn eeyan ti wọn n rin kaakiri ti wọn n pe ara wọn ni oloṣelu yii, oniṣowo to n wa owo kiri nidii okoowo wọn ni gbogbo wọn. Bẹẹ ni ko si okoowo meji ti wọn n ṣe ju oṣelu lọ, owo araalu ni wọn fẹẹ gba, ki wọn maa jẹ ohun to jẹ ti gbogbo ilu nikan lo wa lọkan wọn. Ifẹ araalu, tabi ti idagbasoke ilu kan bayii ko si lọkan wọn, ibi ti awọn yoo ti ri jijẹ-mimu tiwọn nikan ni wọn n wa, ki wọn si ri owo ti wọn yoo fi ṣeranu gidi kiri. Ohun to ṣe rọrun fun wọn lati kuro ninu ẹgbẹ oṣelu kan bọ sinu omi-in ree, ti wọn yoo maa paarọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu bii ẹni to n paarọ aṣọ. Tabi ẹ ko ri olori ile-igbimọ aṣofin wa tẹlẹ, Yakubu Dogara. Ọmọ ẹgbẹ oṣelu PDP ni, inu ẹgbẹ naa lo si wa to fi di ara ile-igbimọ aṣofin ni 2007. Lẹyin to ti lo saa meji nile-igbimọ yii, o kuro ninu ẹgbẹ naa ni 2014, o dọmọ APC. Ni 2018, Dogara kuro ni APC, o tun pada sinu PDP. Lọsẹ to kọja yii, Dogara tun fi PDP silẹ, o si pada sinu APC. Ẹ jẹ ka bi ara wa, iru anfaani wo ni iru eeyan jakujaku bayii yoo ṣe fun ilu. Wọn yoo kan maa kowo ilu jẹ naa ni. Wọn ko ranti ọjọ iku tabi ọjọ ọla, owo ati ipo nikan ni wọn n le kiri. Ole ni wọn o, awọn alaparutu eeyan, awọn oniranu gbogbo!Ọkunrin Adams Oshiomhole yii ni yoo jẹ ki wọn maa bu awọn eeyan kukuru. Bi wọn ba n sọ pe eeyan kukuru biliisi, iru awọn Adams yii lo jẹ ki wọn maa wi bẹẹ. Biliisi gan-an lọkunrin naa, ki i ṣe ẹni to ṣee duro ti rara. Oshiomhole lo ba aye Ize-Iyamu jẹ ni 2016, to sọ pe ole ni, o kowo jẹ, ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun si ni, to n sọ pe ko si meji iru Godwin Obaseki, to ni oun fi Ọlọrun bura lori saare baba oun, Godwin lo dara ju ni ẹni to le ṣe gomina Edo. Oshiomhole naa lo n fo soke bayii pe Godwin yii ko daa, Ize-Iyamu ti oun pe ni ole lọjọsi lo daa ju lọ. Nigba  ti yoo ba ọrọ jẹ, o ni nitori Ọbaseki ko ri gomina ṣe lo ṣe kuro ninu APC, pe eeyan gidi kan ki i fi ẹgbẹ oṣelu to wa silẹ, ohun ti oun fi jẹ ọga niyẹn, nitori oun ko jẹ fi ẹgbẹ oṣelu oun silẹ. Ọkunrin yii ti gbagbe pe inu ẹgbẹ Labour loun wa tẹlẹ ki oun too sa lọ sinu ẹgbẹ AC, ki wọn too jọ waa di ọmọ ẹgbẹ APC. Nigba ti eeyan ba ti le parọ ju, iwa ọmọluabi yoo jinna si i. Bẹ ẹ ba ri Oshiomhole, ẹ jinna si i o, eeyan kukuru biliisi ni."},{"question":"Dame un buen título para el texto : Dos visitantes caminan sobre los pilares del monumento al Holocausto en Berlín.Un hombre hace malabarismo con seis bolas rosadas. Una posa en un movimiento de yoga, otra se para en una pierna, dos hombres saltan de un pilar a otro.Pero al escritor israelí-alemán Shahak Shapira no le pareció el monumento al Holocausto en Berlín. Shapira copió 12 selfies tomadas en el monumento y subidas a redes sociales y las publicó en un sitio web el jueves.Pero con un truco: quitó el fondo del monumento y lo reemplazó con escenas de los campos de concentración, dejando a los jóvenes tomadores de selfies involuntariamente rodeados de cuerpos y cadáveres.El sitio web se llama \\"Yolocaust\\", una combinación entre la popular etiqueta en inglés \\"Yolo\\" (you only live once, o sólo se vive una vez) y \\"Holocausto\\". Fue un éxito en línea y tomado por varios medios de comunicación que elogiaron la idea. Los protagonistas de las fotografías fueron tratados de \\"tontos\\", \\"irrespetuosos\\", e \\"idiotas tomadores de selfies\\".Shapira pensó la la idea durante aproximadamente un año antes de comenzar el trabajo el miércoles, dijo.\\"Es un fenómeno que había comenzado a notar en Berlín y luego empecé a ver esas imágenes en todas partes. Sentía que la gente necesitaba saber lo que estaban haciendo realmente, o cómo otros podrían interpretar lo que estaban haciendo\\".Así que revisó miles de selfies en Facebook, Instagram, Tinder y Grindr y eligió una docena de los más extremos.Las imágenes estaban todas en las cuentas públicas de redes sociales y no pidió permiso a ninguno de los titulares. En la parte inferior de su página web hay una dirección de correo electrónico -\\"undouche.me@yolocaust.de\\"- para solicitar que se elimine una imagen. \\"Supongo que ese es mi compromiso\\", comentó Shapira.Lo que vuelve el proyecto provocativo es \\"la gente y la forma en que se representan a sí mismos\\", en lugar de las escenas de muerte impactantes que ha superpuesto, dijo.\\"Si hubiese usado seres autónomos normales, con gente parada allí sin hacer.\\"","answer":"Yolocausto: ¿esta bien tomarse fotos en monumentos que recuerdan a las víctimas del Holocausto?. "},{"question":"\\"රු රසේ අදිනා ලෙසේ අත් ලෙල දිදි විදුලිය පබා,රන් රසේ එක්වෙන ලෙසෙ වෙණ නාද නුපා තබ තබා \\"මේ විරිතයි, පද්‍ය වල සිංහල අරුතයි. කියන්න පුලුවන්ද ?","answer":"නුපුන් සඳ විරිතරූප රාශියක් අඳිනා ආකාරයට විදුලි රේඛාවන් සේ කාන්තිය ඇති අත් ලෙලදවමින්, රන් සහ රසදිය එක්වන්නාක් මෙන් වීනා නාදයට අනුවම පාදය තබමින් අනංගයාගේ මල්හී බිඳිනා සේ නෙත් කොනින් සබය දෙස බලමින්, ඒ උතුම් දෙවඟනුන් නැටු විලාසය මම කෙසේ පවසන්නද?"},{"question":"一座大楼发生火灾,老陈逃到了楼顶后,无路可走,便逃到了隔壁的楼顶上,两楼只隔10公分,老陈却摔死了,为什么","answer":"答案：两座楼一个30层,一个3层"},{"question":"Ifẹ̀wàrá ","answer":"Ifẹ̀wàrá jẹ́ ìlú kékeré kan ní Ìpínlẹ̀ Ọ̀ṣun ni Nàìjíríà Gẹ́gẹ́ bí a sọ ṣaájú, ìwádìí lórí iṣẹ́ yìí dé Ìjọba Ìbílẹ̀ Àtàkúmọ̀sà tí ó ní ibùjókòó rẹ̀ ní Òṣú. Ní ìjọba ìbìlẹ̀ yìí, gbogbo àwọn ìlú àti abúlèko tí ó wà ní ibẹ̀ ló jẹ́ ti Ìjẹ̀ṣà. Ẹ̀yà ẹ̀ka-èdè Ìjẹ̀ṣà ni wọ́n sì ń sọ àfi Ifẹ̀wàrà tí ó jẹ́ ẹ̀yà ẹ̀kà-èdè Ifẹ̀ ni wọ́n ń sọ. Gẹ́gẹ́ bí ìtàn tí gbọ́, Ifẹ̀ ni àwọn ará Ifẹ̀wàrà ti ṣí lọ sí ìlú náà láti agboolé Arùbíìdì ní òkè Mọ̀rìṣà ní Ilé-Ifẹ̀1 . Ìwádìí fi hàn pé ọ̀rọ̀ oyè ló dá ìjà sílẹ̀ ní ààrin tẹ̀gbọ́ntàbúrò. Ẹ̀gbọ́n fẹ́ jẹ oyè, àbúrò náà sì ń fẹ́ jẹ oyè náà. Ọ̀rọ̀ yìí dá yánpọn-yánrin sílẹ̀ ní ààrin wọn. Lórí ìjà oyè yìí ni wọ́n w\`atí ẹ̀gbọ́n fi lọ sí oko. Ṣùgbọ́n kí ẹ̀gbọ́n tó ti oko dé, ipè láti jẹ oyè dún. Àbúrò tí ó wà ní ilé ní àsìkò náà ló jẹ́1. Ìfọ̀rọ̀wánilẹ́nuwò pẹ̀lú arábìnrin Julianah aya ni 17/6/92.2. Ìfọ̀rọ̀wánilẹ́nuwò pẹ̀lú Olóyè Fákówàjọ ni 17/6/92. Ipé náà. Ipè ti sé ẹ̀gbọ́n mọ́ oko. Èyí bí ẹ̀gbọ́n nínú nígbà tí ó gbọ́ pé àbúrò òun ti jẹ òyé, ó sì kọ̀ láti padà wá sí ilé nítorí pé kò lè fi orí balẹ̀ fún àbúrò rẹ̀ tí ó ti jẹ oyè. Ọ̀rọ̀ yìí di ohun tí wọn ń gbé ogun ja ara wọn sí fún ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ ọdún. Nígbà tí ẹ̀gbọ́n yìí wá ń gbé ogun ja àbúrò rẹ̀ ní Ifẹ̀ lemọ́lemọ́, ni àwọn Ifẹ̀ bá fi ẹ̀pà ṣe oògùn sí ẹnu odi ìlú ní Ìlódè. Wọ́n sì fi màrìwò ṣe àmì sì ọ̀gangan ibi tí wọ́n ṣe oògùn náà sí. Láti ìgbà yìí ni ogun ẹ̀gbọ́n kò ti lè wọ Ifẹ̀ mọ. Àwọn Ìjẹ̀ṣà ní ó ni kí ẹ̀gbọ́n tí ó ń bínú yìí lọ tẹ̀dó sí Ìwàrà. Nígbà tí wọ́n dé Ìwàrà, wọ́n fi mọ̀rìwò ọ̀pẹ gún ilẹ̀, kí ilẹ̀ tó mọ́ mọ̀rìwò kọ̀ọ̀kan ti di igi ọ̀pẹ kọ̀ọ̀kan.Ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ tẹ̀lẹ̀, wọ́n sì pinnu pé àwọn kò níí lè bá àwọn àlejò náà gbé nítorí pé olóògùn ni wọn. Èyí ló mú kí àwọn ara Ìwàrà lé àwọn àlejò náà sí iwájú. Ibi tí àwọn àlejò náà tẹ̀dó sí lẹ́yìn tí wọ́n kúrò ní Ìwàrà ni a mọ̀ sí Ifẹ̀wàrà lónìí. Lóòótọ́ orí ilẹ̀ Ìjẹ̀ṣà ni Ifẹ̀wàrà wà ṣùgbọ́n kò sí àjọṣepọ̀ kan dàbí alárà láàrin Ifẹ̀wàrà, Iléṣà àti Ìwàrà títí di òní pàápàá nípa ẹ̀ka-èdè tí wọn ń sọ.Àkíyèsí fi hàn pé gbogbo orúkọ àdúgbò tí ó wà ní Ifẹ̀ náà ni ó wà ní Ifẹ̀wàrà. A rí agboolé bí Arùbíìdì, Mọ̀ọ̀rẹ̀, Òkèrèwè, Lókòrẹ́ àti Èyindi ní Ifẹ̀wàrà.Bákan náà ẹ̀yà ẹ̀ka-èdè Ifẹ̀ nì wọ́n ń sọ ní Ifẹ̀wàrà. Àsìkò tí wọ́n bá sì ń ṣe ọdún ìbílẹ̀ ní Ifẹ̀ náà ni àwọn ará Ifẹ̀wàrà máa ń ṣe tiwọn.Ìwádìí nípa ìtàn ìṣẹ̀dálẹ̀ àwọn ìlú tí iṣẹ́ yìí dé fi hàn gbangba pé mọ̀lẹ́bí ni Ifẹ̀, Ifẹ̀ẹ́tẹ̀dó pẹ̀lú Òkè-Igbo, àti Ifẹ̀wàrà. Wọ́n jọra nínú ìṣesí wọn. Ẹ̀ka-èdè wọn dọ́gba, orúkọ àdúgbò wọn tún bára mu, bákan náà ni ẹ̀sìn wọn tún dọ́gba. Àkókó tí wọ́n ń ṣe ọdún ìbílẹ̀ kò yàtọ̀ sí ara wọn. Bí ẹrú bá sì jọra, ó dájú pé ilé kan náà ni wọ́n ti jáde."},{"question":"ඇස් දන් දෙන්න පුළුවන් කොහොමද?","answer":"ශ්‍රී ලාංකිකයන් ලක්ෂ 21කට අධික පිරිසක් මරණින් පසු ඇස් දන්දීම සඳහා සිය සංගමයේ ලියාපදිංචි වී සිටින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා අක්ෂිදාන සංගමය පවසයි.ඇස් දන් දීමට අවශ්‍ය නම් එය කළ හැකි ක්‍රම දෙකක් පවතින බව ශ්‍රී ලංකා අක්ෂි දාන සංගමයේ ජනත් සමන් මාතරආරච්චි බීබීසි සිංහල සේවය වෙත කියා සිටියේ පරිත්‍යාගශීලින්ගේ දැන ගැනීම පිණිස ය.“ඇස් දන් දෙන්න ක්‍රම දෙකක් තියෙනවා. එකක් තමයි තමන් ජීවත්ව ඉද්දි පොරොන්දු පත්‍රයක් පුරවලා ඒකට දායක වෙන්න පුළුවන්. අනිත් එක තමයි තමන්ගේ ඥාතීන්ට පුළුවන් කෙනෙක් මැරුණට පස්සේ ඒ වැඩේ කරන්න. අක්ෂි දාන සංගමය කතා කරලා අපිට ඇස් දන් දෙන්න පුළුවන්.”මරණයෙන් පැය 4 ක් ඉක්ම යාමට පෙර ඇස් ලබා ගත යුතු බව ද ඔහු අවධාරණය කළ අතර මිය ගොස් පැය 4න් පසුව සෛල මිය යාම ආරම්භ වීම හේතුවෙන් ඇස් ලබා ගත නොහැකි බව සඳහන් කළේය.ඔබේගේ දෙනෙත් වෙනත් අයෙකුට දන් දීමට කැමත්තක් දක්වන්නේ නම් දුරකතන අංක 011 2692051 / 011 2696109 ඔස්සේ ශ්‍රී ලංකා අක්ෂි දාන සංගමය හා සම්බන්ධ වී ලියාපදිංචි විය හැකිය."},{"question":"inona no zom-pirenena zakain'ny mpikambana ao amin'ny \\"Daft Punk\\"?","answer":"ny mpikambana ao amin'ny \\"Daft Punk\\" dia mizaka ny zom-pirenena frantsay"},{"question":"SIDEE U HAQIIJIN KARTAA HADAFKAAGA AMA GANACSIGAAGA?","answer":"Guul  ganacsi inta badan waxaa lagu gaaraa go’aan adag, geesinimo iyo in aad wax ka barato dadka waayo aragnimada buuxda u leh arirmaha ganacsiga,  islamarkaana hirgaliyay ganacsiyada horumarka gaaray ama guuleystay . Haddaba, Haddii aad doonayso in aad ganacsi horumar leh samayso waa in aad tixgalisaa talooyinka dadka waayoaragnimada leh ee soo arkay loolanka ganacsiga iyo horumarkiisa. Halkaan waxaan idinkugu soo gudbin doonana qaar ka mid ah talooyinka ugu muhiimsan ee laga dhaxlay qaar ka mid ah ganacsatada ugu taajirsan dunida,Waxaana ka mid ah :Naftaada loolan gali – Richard Branson oo ah ninka aasaasay shirkada Virgin ee caanka ah ayaa ku talinaya in qofka doonaya in uu ganacsi abuuro uu diyaar u noqdo in uu loolan joogto ah galiyo naftiisa. Waxa uu aaminsanyahay in noloshu ay tahay waxbarasho joogto ah oo aad maalinkasta wax-cusub barato.Qabo shaqo aad jeceshahay –  Steve Jobs oo ahaa ninkii horumarka weyn gaarsiiyay shirkadda Apple ayaa ku talin jiray in dadka dhalinyarada ah ay sameeyaan ganacsiyo aysan lacag darteed keliya u abuurin balse ay sameeyaan ganacsi la xiriira waxyaabaha ay jecelyihiin si ay ugu raaxaystaan.U barrer Qatarta – Jeﬀ Bezos oo ah agaasimaha Amazon waxa uu leeyahay in aadan waligaa ogaanayn qiimaha ﬁkradaada ilaa aad tijaabiso. Waxa uu sheegay in aad ka shalaaynayso in aadan tijaabin , halkii aad ka shalaayi lahayd fashilka. Waayo fashilkaas cashar ayaad ka qaadanaysaa balse ﬁkrad aadan tijaabin waxba kama faa’idaysid. Aragti lahoow– Agaasimaha Tumblr oo lagu magacaabo David Karp ayaa aaminsan in ganacsadaha halabuurka leh uu yahay mid aragti-dheer leh oo ay u caddahay waxyaabaha uu doonayo in uu sameeyo iyo sida uu ku gaarayo hadafkiisa.Naftaada aamin – Henry Ford oo ahaa ninkii aasaasay shirkada baabuurta ee Ford ayaa laga soo wariyay in uu yiri ” Haddii aad aaminsantahay in aad wax samayn karto iyo haddii aad aamisantahay in aadan samayn Karin, Labadaba waa ku saxsantahay” Haddii aad aaminsantahay in aad guuleysanayo, waad helaysaa wadooyinkii aad ku guuleysan lahayd balse haddii  aadan aaminsanayn waxaad helaysaa marmarsiiyo aad ku guuldaraysato."},{"question":"Dhaqtaradii ugu horeysay ee Islam-ka?","answer":"Rufeydah Bintu Sacad."},{"question":"ਬਗ਼ਦਾਦ ਦਾ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ : ਅਲਿਫ਼ ਲੈਲਾ","answer":"ਬੜੇ ਚਿਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਅਰਬ ਦੇਸ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਅਮੀਰ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਸੀ । ਉਹਦਾ ਚੰਗਾ ਵੱਡਾ ਪਰਵਾਰ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਨੌਕਰ ਚਾਕਰ ਵੀ ਬਹੁਤੇ ਸਨ । ਉਹ ਜੀਵਨ ਦੇ ਦਿਨ ਬੜੀ ਖੁਸ਼ੀ ਵਿਚ ਬਿਤਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ।ਉਹਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਸੂ ਵੀ ਸਨ । ਉਹਨੂੰ ਰਬ ਵਲੋਂ ਪਸੂਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਪੰਛੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਬੋਲੀ ਸਮਝਣ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਮਿਲੀ ਹੋਈ ਸੀ । ਪਰ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਉਹ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਸਕਦਾ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਇਸ ਭੇਤ ਦੇ ਖੋਲ੍ਹਣ ਦੀ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਮੌਤ ਸੀ।ਪਸੂਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਉਹਦੇ ਕੋਲ ਇਕ ਢੱਗਾ ਅਤੇ ਇਕ ਖੋਤਾ ਵੀ ਸਨ । ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਖੁਰਲੀ ਕੋਲ ਕੋਲ ਹੀ ਸੀ । ਕਈ ਵਾਰ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕੱਠਿਆਂ ਪੱਠੇ ਖਾਣ ਦਾ ਮੌਕਾ ਮਿਲਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਇਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੇ ਦੁਖ ਸੁਖ ਫੋਲ ਲੈਂਦੇ।ਇਕ ਦਿਨ ਤਰਕਾਲਾਂ ਵੇਲੇ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਆਪਣੇ ਨੌਕਰਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਬਾਲ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਬੈਠਾ ਹੱਸ ਖੇਡ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਉਹਨੇ ਢੱਗੇ ਅਤੇ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਸ ਵਿਚ ਘੁਸਰ ਮੁਸਰ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਸੁਣਿਆ ।ਢੱਗਾ ਕਹਿ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ, \\"ਤੂੰ ਤਾਂ ਮੋਤੀ ਮਣਸ ਕੇ ਇਹ ਜਨਮ ਲਿਆ ਜਾਪਦਾ ਦੇ ! ਬੁੱਲੇ ਲੁਟਦਾ ਏਂ, ਮਿੱਤਰਾ ! ਤੇਰੀਆਂ ਖ਼ਾਤਰਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਰੀਸਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ। ਟਹਿਲੀਏ ਤੇਰੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਪਏ ਫਿਰਦੇ ਨੇ । ਐਨ ਵੇਲੇ ਸਿਰ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਤਾਜ਼ੇ ਪੱਠੇ ਪਾਉਂਦੇ ਨੇ । ਪੀਣ ਨੂੰ ਚਸ਼ਮੇ ਦਾ ਠੰਡਾ ਠਾਰ ਪਾਣੀ ਲਿਆ ਦਿੰਦੇ ਨੇ ਤੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਥਾਂ ਸ਼ੀਸ਼ੇ ਵਾਂਙ ਸਾਫ਼ ਰਖਦੇ ਨੇ ! ਪਰ, ਯਾਰ, ਰਤੀ ਮੇਰੇ ਵੱਲ ਵੇਖ । ਅੱਧੀ ਅੱਧੀ ਰਾਤ ਤਕ ਪੰਜਾਲੀ ਵਿਚ ਜਕੜੀ ਮੇਰੀ ਧੌਣ ਵੀ ਆਕੜ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਏ । ਹਲ ਵਾਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਮੇਰੀਆਂ ਖੁੱਚਾਂ ਰਹਿ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ਨੇ । ਕਈ ਕਈ ਦਿਨ ਮੇਰੇ ਪਿੰਡੇ ਤੋਂ ਸੋਟੀ ਦੀਆਂ ਲਾਸ਼ਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾਂਦੀਆਂ ।ਦਿਨ ਚੜ੍ਹਨ ਤੋਂ ਰਾਤ ਪੈਣ ਤਕ ਅੰਨ੍ਹੇ ਵਾਹ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਰਗੜਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਏ। ਕੋਈ ਵੀ ਕੰਮ ਹੋਵੇ ਸਾਰਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਮੂੰਹ ਤੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਈ ਨਾਂ ਚੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਏ, ਜਿੱਦਾਂ ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ ਪਸੂ ਮਰ ਗਏ ਹੁੰਦੇ ਨੇ ! ਤੇ ਫੇਰ, ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਟੁੱਟੇ ਭੱਜੇ ਨੂੰ ਰਾਤ ਵੇਲੇ ਖੁਰਲੀ ਲਾਗ ਲਿਅ ਬੰਨ੍ਹਦੇ ਨੇ ਤਾਂ ਮੇਰੇ ਵਿਚ ਖੜ੍ਹਨ ਜੋਗੀ ਵੀ ਹਿੰਮਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ । ਪੱਠਿਆਂ ਵਲ ਮੂੰਹ ਕਰਦਾ ਆਂ ਤਾਂ ਨਿਰੀ ਖੋਹ ਈ ਖੋਹ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਏ ! ਤੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਥਾਂ ਵਲ ਵੇਖ ਲੈ। ਸਾਰੀ ਸਾਰੀ ਰਾਤ ਗੋਹੇ ਤੇ ਚਿੱਕੜ ਨਾਲ ਈ ਲਿਬੜਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਆਂ ਤੇ ਦਿਨੇ ਧੁਪ ਵਿਚ ਗੋਹੇ ਦੇ ਸੁੱਕਣ ਨਾਲ ਮੇਰਾ ਪਿੰਡਾ ਹੋਰ ਆਕੜ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਏ ਤੇ ਡੰਡਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਮਾਰ ਨਾਲ ਸੁੱਕੀਆਂ ਪਾਥੀਆਂ ਵਾਂਝ ਝੜ ਝੜ ਡਿਗਦਾ ਏ ।ਪਰ ਤੂੰ ਏਂ ! ਕਦੀ ਕੱਖ ਭੰਨ ਕੇ ਵੀ ਦੂਹਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤਾ ! ਹੋਇਆ, ਜੋ ਕਦੀ ਮਾਲਕ ਨੇ ਸ਼ਹਿਰ ਵਿਚ ਜਾਣਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਤਾਂ ਤੇਰੀ ਵਾਰੀ ਆ ਗਈ । ਤੇ ਉਹ ਵੀ ਤੇਰੀ ਸੈਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ । ਰੇਸ਼ਮੀ ਤੇਰੇ ਤੇ ਕਾਠੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਏ, ਲਾਲ ਫੁੰਮਣ ਤੇਰੇ ਕੰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚਕਾਰ ਕਲਗੀ ਵਾਙ ਸੱਜ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਏ: ਮਣਕਿਆਂ ਤੇ ਘੁੰਗਰੂਆਂ ਦੇ ਹਾਰ ਤੇਰੇ ਗਲ ਵਿਚ, ਲਿਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਪਏ ਮਾਰਦੇ ਨੇ। ਤੇ ਫੇਰ, ਸੋਹਣਿਆਂ, ਜਿਹੜਾ ਤੂੰ ਵਿੰਗਾ ਹੋ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਤੁਰਦਾ ਏਂ! ਤੇਰੀ ਟਹੁਰ ਵੇਖਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਏ ! ਜੋ ਤੂੰ ਮੌਜਾਂ ਮਾਣਦਾ ਏਂ ਤੇ ਮੈਂ ਦਿਨ ਰਾਤ ਸੜਿਆ ਬਲਿਆ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਆਂ । ਤੂੰ ਘਰਾੜੇ ਮਾਰਦਾ ਏਂ ਤੇ ਨੀਂਦ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਾਗੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਫੜਕਦੀ । ਮੈਂ ਭੁੱਖਾ ਭਾਣਾ ਉਬਾਸੀਆਂ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਆਂ ਤੇ ਤੂੰ ਗੁਲਛੱਰੇ ਉਡਾਉਂਦਾ ਏਂ। ਤੇਰੀਆਂ ਖ਼ਾਤਰਾਂ ਸਾਹ ਨਹੀਂ ਲੈਂਦੀਆਂ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਹੱਡ ਸੁੱਕੇ ਜਾਂਦੇ ਨੇ !\\"ਜਦੋਂ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੇ ਢੱਗੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਇਹ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਸੁਣੀਆਂ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਬੜੀ ਉੱਚੀ ਸਾਰੀ ਹੱਸਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਆਖਣ ਲੱਗਾ, \\"ਪਾਜੀਆ, ਤੇਰੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਬਦੋਬਦੀ ਹਾਸਾ ਨਿਕਲਦਾ ਜਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਏ ! ਤੂੰ ਨਿਰਾ ਅਕਲ ਦਾ ਅੰਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਏਂ ! ਮੂਰਖਾ, ਤੇ ਦੂਜਿਆਂ ਲਈ ਜੁ ਜਾਨ ਮਾਰਦਾ ਏਂ, ਇਹ ਕਿੱਥੋਂ ਦੀ ਅਕਲ ਏ ! ਸਵੇਰੇ ਘਰੋਂ ਨਿਕਲਿਆ ਤੇ ਨਖਿੱਧਾਂ ਵਾਂਝ ਸਾਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਹੱਡ ਗੋਡੇ ਰਗੜੇ ਤੇ ਕਿਧਰੇ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਰਾਤ ਪੈਣ ਤੇ ਮੁੜ ਆਪਣੀ ਖੁਰਲੀ ਦਾ ਮੂੰਹ ਵੇਖਿਆ !ਨਕਾਰਿਆ, ਸੁਣ ਧਿਆਨ ਨਾਲ ! ਕਦੀ ਕਦੀ ਥੋੜੀ ਬਹੁਤ ਚਲਾਕੀ ਵੀ ਵਰਤ ਲਈਦੀ ਏ । ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਾਗੇ ਆ ਬੰਨ੍ਹਦੇ ਨੇ, ਤੂੰ ਚੁਪ ਚਾਪ ਆ ਕੇ ਖੜ੍ਹ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਏਂ । ਉਹ ਸਮਝਦੇ ਨੇ ਕਿ ਤੂੰ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ ਏਂ । ਜਦੋਂ ਪੱਠੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਸੁਟਦੇ ਨੇ ਤਾਂ ਤੂੰ ਹਾਬੜਿਆਂ ਵਾਂਝ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਤੇ ਪੈਂਦਾ ਏਂ ਤੇ ਉਹ ਸਮਝਦੇ ਨੇ ਕਿ ਤੂੰ ਬੜਾ ਪ੍ਰਸੰਨ ਏਂ! ਪਰ ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੀ ਗੱਲ ਮੰਨੇਂ ਤਾਂ ਜਿੱਦਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਦਾ ਆਂ, ਉੱਦਾਂ ਈ ਕਰ ।ਜਦੋਂ ਤੂੰ ਹਲ ਵਾਹੁਣ ਲਈ ਜਾਏਂ, ਤੂੰ ਖੇਤ ਵਿਚ ਜਾ ਕੇ ਲਿਟਣ ਲਗ ਜਾਇਆ ਕਰ । ਤੇ ਫੇਰ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਉਹ ਭਾਵੇਂ ਕੁੱਟ ਕੁੱਟ ਕੇ ਝੰਬ ਦੇਣ, ਤੂੰ ਬਿਲਕੁਲ ਉਠਣਾ ਨੀ । ਜੇ ਉੱਠ ਵੀ ਖੜ੍ਹੇਂ ਤਾਂ ਫੇਰ ਲੇਟ ਜਾਈਂ।''ਅੰਤ ਨੂੰ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਪੱਠੇ ਪਾਉਣ, ਤੂੰ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੂੰਹ ਤਕ ਨ ਲਾਈਂ । ਪੱਠਿਆਂ ਵਲ ਵੇਖ ਕੇ ਫੂਕਾਂ ਮਾਰੀ ਜਾਈਂ । ਉਹ ਸਮਝਣਗੇ ਕਿ ਤੂੰ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਏਂ। ਦੋ, ਚਾਰ ਦਿਨ ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਰੀਂ, ਫੇਰ ਵੇਖੀ ਕਿਦਾਂ ਤੇਰੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਪਿਛੇ ਫਿਰਦੇ ਨੇ !''ਜਦੋਂ ਢੱਗੇ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਸੁਣਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਹਨੇ ਖੋਤੇ ਦਾ ਦਿਲੋਂ ਧੰਨਵਾਦ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਖੁਸ਼ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਕਹਿਣ ਲੱਗਾ, “ਵਾਹ, ਬਈ ਵਾਹ, ਕੀ ਕਹਿਣੇ ਤੇਰੀ ਨੇਕ ਸਲਾਹ ਦੇ ! ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਏਨਾ ਚਿਰ ਮੂਰਖ ਈ ਰਿਹਾ ਆਂ ! ਪਰ ਹੁਣ ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੀਆਂ ਅੱਖਾਂ ਖੋਲ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਤੇ ਮੂਰਖਤਾ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਹਨੇਰੇ ਵਿਚੋਂ ਕੱਢ ਲਿਆ ਏ ।\\"ਬਦਕਿਸਮਤੀ ਨਾਲ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਲਾਗੇ ਦੇ ਕਮਰੇ ਵਿਚ ਬੈਠਾ ਸੀ । ਉਹਨੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਸਭ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਸੁਣ ਲਈਆਂ । ਅਗਲੇ ਦਿਨ ਸਵੇਰੇ ਹਾਲੀ ਵੇਲੇ ਸਿਰ ਆਇਆ ਅਤੇ ਢੱਗੇ ਨੂੰ ਖੇਤ ਵਲ ਲੈ ਗਿਆ। ਉਹਨੇ ਹਰ ਰੋਜ਼ ਵਾਂਝ ਉਹਦੀ ਧੌਣ ਤੇ ਪੰਜਾਲੀ ਪਾਈ, ਪਰ ਢੱਗਾ ਆਪਣੀ ਥਾਂ ਤੇ ਅੜ ਕੇ ਖੜ੍ਹ ਗਿਆ। ਉਹਨੂੰ ਹਾਲੀ ਨੇ ਬਥੇਰੀ ਹੱਲਾਸ਼ੇਰੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ, ਪਰ ਕਿੱਥੇ ! ਢੱਗਾ ਹਿਲਣ ਤਕ ਦਾ ਨਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਲੈਂਦਾ । ਹਾਲੀ ਬੜਾ ਤੱਤਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਤੇ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਸੋਟੇ ਨਾਲ ਖ਼ੂਬ ਝੁੰਬਿਆ । ਇਸੇ ਮਾਰ ਕੁਟਾਈ ਵਿਚ ਪੰਜਾਲੀ ਥੱਲੇ ਜਾ ਪਈ ਅਤੇ ਢੰਗਾ ਉੱਥੋਂ ਨੱਸ ਉਠਿਆ । ਪਰ ਹਾਲੀ ਵੀ ਉਹਦਾ ਪਿੱਛਾ ਛੱਡਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਬਲਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ । ਉਹਨੇ ਢੱਗੇ ਨੂੰ ਜਾ ਘੇਰਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਐਸਾ ਫੈਂਟਾ ਚਾੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਕਿ ਢੱਗਾ ਉੱਥੇ ਹੀ ਵਿੱਛ ਗਿਆ । ਸਾਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਢੱਗਾ ਇਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਥੇ ਪਿਆ ਰਿਹਾ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨੇ ਜ਼ਰਾ ਕੰਮ ਨ ਕੀਤਾ । ਸ਼ਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਘਰ ਲਿਆ ਕੇ ਪੱਠੇ ਪਾਏ ਗਏ, ਉਹਨੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਵਲ ਮੂੰਹ ਤਕ ਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਰੀ ਰਾਤ ਹਉਕੇ ਲੈਂਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ।ਸਵੇਰ ਸਵੇਰ ਜਦ ਹਾਲੀ ਉਥੇ ਆਇਆ, ਉਹਨੇ ਵੇਖਿਆ ਕਿ ਢੱਗੇ ਦੀ ਖੁਰਲੀ ਉੱਸੇ ਤਰਾਂ ਪੱਠਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਭਰੀ ਪਈ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਆਪ ਚਿੱਕੜ ਅਤੇ ਗੋਹੇ ਨਾਲ ਲਿਬੜਿਆ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ। ਉਹਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ਉਹ ਹੋ ! ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਵਿਚਾਰਾ ਬਿਮਾਰ ਏ । ਮੈਂ ਐਵੇਂ ਈ ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਇਹਨੂੰ ਗ਼ਰੀਬ ਮਾਰ ਕੀਤੀ। ਵਿਚਾਰੇ ਦੇ ਪੱਠੇ ਵੀ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਉਸੇ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਪਏ ਨੇ ।ਸੋ ਉਹ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਕੋਲ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਸਾਰੀ ਗਲ ਜਾ ਸੁਣਾਈ । ਪਰ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਜਾਣਦਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਗੱਲ ਕੀ ਹੈ । ਉਹਨੇ ਹਾਲੀ ਨੂੰ ਕਿਹਾ, “ਜਾਹ, ਅੱਜ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਜਾ ਤੇ - ਇਹਦੇ ਕੋਲੋਂ ਢੱਗੇ ਦਾ ਕੰਮ ਲੈ ।\\"ਸੋ ਹਾਲੀ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਲੈ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਹਲ ਅੱਗੇ ਜੋਈ ਰੱਖਿਆ । ਖੋਤਾ ਇਤਨੀ ਮਿਹਨਤ ਦਾ ਆਦੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ । ਛੇਤੀ ਹੀ ਥੱਕ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਸੀ। ਹਾਲੀ ਉੱਸੇ ਵੇਲੇ ਉਹਦੀ ਵੱਖੀ ਵਿਚ ਇਕ ਜੜ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਸੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਅਗਾਂਹ ਹਿਕ ਦਿੰਦਾ ਸੀ ।ਜਦੋਂ ਸ਼ਾਮ ਪਈ ਤਾਂ ਖੇਤੇ ਦੇ ਗਲੋਂ ਹਲ ਲਾਹਿਆ ਗਿਆ । ਉਹਦੀਆਂ ਲੱਤਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਜ਼ਰਾ ਵੀ ਸਾਹ ਸੱਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ । ਵਿਚਾਰਾ ਬੁਰੇ ਹਾਲੀਂ ਹੌਲੀ ਹੌਲੀ ਲੰਗੜਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੋਇਆ ਘਰ ਪਹੁੰਚਿਆ। ਉਹਦੀਆਂ ਵੱਖੀਆਂ ਲਾਸ਼ਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਨੀਲੀਆਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਪਈਆਂ ਸਨ !ਓਧਰ ਢੱਗਾ ਸਾਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਬੁੱਲੇ ਲੁੱਟਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ । ਕਦੇ ਪੱਠਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਮੂੰਹ ਮਾਰ ਲਵੇ । ਕਦੇ ਜ਼ਰਾ ਪੂਛ ਨਾਲ ਮੱਖੀਆਂ ਉਡਾ ਲਵੇ । ਕਦੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਿੱਲੇ ਦੇ ਗਿਰਦ ਦੋ ਕੁ ਭੁਆਟਣੀਆਂ ਹੀ ਲੈ ਲਵੇ । ਰਾਤ ਪੈਣ ਤਕ ਉਹਦਾ ਚਿਹਰਾ ਖਿੜ ਗਿਆ । ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹਨੇ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੂੰ ਵਾਪਸ ਆਉਂਦਿਆਂ ਵੇਖਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਕਹਿਣ ਲੱਗਾ, “ਹੇ ਅਕਲ ਦੇ ਸਾਗਰ, ਤੇਰੀ ਈ ਨੇਕ ਸਲਾਹ ਦੀ ਬਦੌਲਤ ਮੇਰਾ ਜੀਵਨ ਸੌਰਿਆ ਏ । ਅਜ ਪਹਿਲਾ ਦਿਨ ਏ ਕਿ ਮੈਂ ਸੁਖ ਦਾ ਸਾਹ ਲਿਆ ਏ । ਮੈਂ ਕਿਸਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਤੇਰਾ ਜਸ ਗਾਵਾਂ !''ਪਰ ਖੋਤਾ ਰੋਣੀ ਬੂਥੀ ਬਣਾਈ ਚੁਪ ਚਾਪ ਖੜਾ ਰਿਹਾ । ਉਹਦੀ ਐਸੀ ਦੁਰਦਸ਼ਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਉਹਦੇ ਮੂੰਹੋਂ ਗੱਲ ਤਕ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਨਿਕਲਦੀ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਸਾਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਉਹਦੀਆਂ ਹੱਡੀਆਂ ਸਿਕਦਿਆਂ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਸਨ । ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਚ ਸੋਚਣ ਲੱਗਾ, 'ਇਹ ਸਾਰੀ ਮੁਸੀਬਤ ਮੇਰੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਈ ਬੇਵਕੂਫ਼ੀ ਦਾ ਨਤੀਜਾ ਏ । ਦੂਜਿਆਂ ਦੀ ਬਲਾ, ਖ਼ਾਹ ਮਖ਼ਾਹ ਗਲ ਸਹੇੜ ਲਈ ਏ । ਖ਼ੈਰ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਘਬਰਾਉਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ । ਰੱਬ ਦੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ੀ ਹੋਈ ਅਕਲ ਨੂੰ ਵਰਤ ਕੇ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਕਲਾ ਮਰੋੜਨੀ ਚਾਹੀਦੀ ਏ ਜਿਸ ਨਾਲ ਢੱਗਾ ਮੁੜ ਆਪਣੇ ਗੇੜ ਵਿਚ ਪੈ ਜਾਏ। ਨਹੀਂ ਤਾਂ ਮੇਰੀ ਬੜੀ ਭੁਗਤ ਸੌਰੇਗੀ ਤੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਜੀਊਣਾ ਮੁਹਾਲ ਹੋ ਜਾਏਗਾ।’ਕੁਝ ਚਿਰ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੇ ਪੱਠੇ ਖਾਣੇ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿਤੇ । ਢੱਗਾ ਕੋਲ ਖੜਾ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਸਲਾਹੁੰਦਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ ਥੱਕਦਾ।ਉਸੇ ਰਾਤ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਅਤੇ ਬੱਚਿਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਚੰਦਰਮੇ ਦੀ ਰੋਸ਼ਨੀ ਵਿਚ ਘਰ ਦੀ ਛੱਤ ਤੇ ਬੈਠਾ ਗੱਪਾਂ ਮਾਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ' ਖੋਤੇ ਨੇ ਢੱਗੇ ਨੂੰ ਆਖਿਆ “ਸੁਣਾ, ਬਈ ! ਫੇਰ ਕੱਲ੍ਹ ਲਈ ਤੇਰਾ ਕੀ ਇਰਾਦਾ ਏ ?\\"ਢੱਗੇ ਨੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, “ਇਰਾਦਾ ਕੀ ਹੋਣਾ ਏ। ਤੂੰ ਜਿਹੜੀ ਮੱਤ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਏ ਉਹਦੀ ਰੀਸ ਨਹੀਂ । ਮੇਰੀ ਜਾਚੇ ਇਹ ਨੁਸਖਾ ਤਾਂ ਸਾਰੀ ਉਮਰ ਵਰਤਣਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਏ । ਸਾਰਾ ਦਿਨ ਮੌਜ ਕਰਦਾ ਰਿਹਾ ਆਂ । ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਕੀ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਏ !”ਪਰ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੇ ਸਿਰ ਫੇਰਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਆਖਿਆ, 'ਨਾ, ਨਾ ! ਕਿਤੇ ਇਸਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਨਾ ਕਰ ਬੈਠੀ !\\"“ਕਿਉਂ ?\\" ਢੱਗੇ ਨੇ ਹੈਰਾਨ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ ।ਖੋਤੇ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, “ਇਕ ਗੱਲ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਪੱਲੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਬੰਨ੍ਹ ਛੱਡੀਦੀ । ਕਈ ਵਾਰ ਉਹ ਪੁੱਠੀ ਵੀ ਪੈ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਏ । ਮੇਰੇ ਕੋਲ ਨਵੀਆਂ ਨਵੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਘਾਟਾ ਨਹੀਂ । ਜਿੰਨੀਆਂ ਸਲਾਹਾਂ ਕਹੇਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਦੇ ਦਵਾਂ। ਮੈਂ ਅਜ ਹੀ ਮਾਲਕ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਕਹਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਸੁਣਿਆ ਏਂ, 'ਜੇ ਬੈਲ ਇਸੇ ਤਰਾਂ ਕਲ ਵੀ ਕੰਮ ਨਾਂ ਕਰੇ, ਤਾਂ ਇਹਨੂੰ ਕਸਾਈ ਦੇ ਹਵਾਲੇ ਕਰ ਦਿਓ। ਇਹ ਗ਼ਰੀਬਾਂ ਦੇ ਖਾਣ ਦੇ ਕੰਮ ਈ ਆਊ ਤੇ ਅਸੀਂ ਇਹਦੀ ਖੱਲ ਵੇਚ ਕੇ ਚਾਰ ਪੈਸੇ ਈ ਵਟ ਲਵਾਂਗੇ ।' ਇਹ ਤੂੰ ਹੁਣ ਸੋਚ ਲੈ ! ਕਿਤੇ ਹਾਸੇ ਦਾ ਮੜਾਸਾ ਈ ਨਾ ਬਣ ਜਾਏ। ਮੈਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਖ਼ਬਰਦਾਰ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਏ ! ਤੂੰ ਅੱਗੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਪੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਵਿਚਾਰ।'' ਜਦੋਂ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਨੇ ਇਹ ਸੁਣਿਆ, ਉਹ ਖਿੜ ਖਿੜਾ ਕੇ ਹਸ ਪਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਇਤਨਾ ਹਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਥੇ ਲੋਟ ਪੋਟ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ।ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਪੁੱਛਣ ਲੱਗੀ, “ਕੋਈ ਐਸੀ ਵੈਸੀ ਗੱਲ ਤਾਂ ਹੋਈ ਨਹੀਂ। ਇਹ ਹਾਸਾ ਕਾਹਦਾ ਏ ?''ਉਹਨੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, “ਢੱਗੇ ਤੇ ਖੋਤੇ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਹਾਸਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਰੁਕਦਾ।\\"ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨੇ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ, “ਮੈਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਤਾਂ ਕੁਝ ਪਤਾ ਲਗੇ । ਉਹ ਕੀ ਕਹਿ ਰਹੇ ਨੇ ।”ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਨੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, “ਇਹ ਮੈਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਸ ਸਕਦਾ ! ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ, “ਤੁਹਾਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਦੱਸਣਾ ਪਏਗਾ।''ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਨੇ ਫੇਰ ਉੱਤਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, “ਨਹੀਂ, ਮੈਂ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਕਿਹਾ ਜੁ ਏ ਮੈਂ ਦਸ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦਾ। ਤੈਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਇਹ ਦੱਸਣ ਦੀ ਸਜ਼ਾ ਮੌਤ ਏ ।”ਪਰ ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ, \\"ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਨਿਰਾ ਝੂਠ ਏ । ਮੈਨੂੰ ਭੋਲੀ ਭਾਲੀ ਸਮਝ ਕੇ ਠਗਦੇ ਓ ! ਹਸ ਮੇਰੇ ਤੇ ਰਹੇ ਓ ਤੇ ਨਾਂ ਪਸ਼ੂਆਂ ਦਾ ਲਾ ਰਹੇ ਓ । ਮੈਥੋਂ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਕੁਝ ਲੁਕਾ ਰਹੇ ਓ । ਪਰ ਜੇ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਸੋਗੇ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਇਥੋਂ ਚਲੀ ਜਾਣਾ ਏ ਮੁੜ ਕਦੇ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਆਉਣਾ !\\"ਇਹ ਕਹਿ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਬੈਠ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ ਉੱਚੀ ਉੱਚੀ ਰੋਣ ਲਗ ਪਈ । ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, “ਤੂੰ ਸ਼ੁਦੈਣ ਤਾਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੋ ਗਈ? ਰੱਬ ਤੋਂ ਡਰ ਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਦੇ ਇਸ ਗਲ ਨੂੰ । ਐਵੇਂ ਨਿੱਕੀ ਜਿਹੀ ਗੱਲ ਤੇ ਕਲੇਸ਼ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰੀਦਾ ।”ਪਰ ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਜਿੱਦੀ ਪੈ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ ਕਹਿਣ ਲੱਗੀ, 'ਨਹੀਂ, ਨਹੀਂ, ਮੈਨੂੰ ਸਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਹੱਸੇ ਕਿਉਂ ਓ !'ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਨੇ ਉੱਤਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ, “ਭਲੀਏ ਲੋਕੇ, ਤੈਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਏ ਕਿ ਜਦੋਂ ਰੱਬ ਨੇ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਜਾਨਵਰਾਂ ਤੇ ਪੰਛੀਆਂ ਦੀ ਬੋਲੀ ਸਮਝਣ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਸੀ ਤਾਂ ਨਾਲ ਈ ਉਹਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਸੀ ਕਿ ਜੇ ਮੈਂ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਨੂੰ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਬਚਣਾ ! ਖਾਮਖ਼ਾਹ ਦਾ ਅੜਬਪੁਣਾ ਛੱਡ ਦੇ ।\\"“ਪਰਵਾਹ ਨਹੀਂ ! ਮੈਨੂੰ ਜ਼ਰੂਰ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਢੱਗੇ ਤੇ ਖੋਤੇ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਨੂੰ ਕੀ ਕਿਹਾ ਏ । ਏਥੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਬਹਿ ਰਹਿਣਾ ਏ । ਅੰਤ ਵੇਲਾ ਤਾਂ ਅਖ਼ੀਰ ਸਭ ਦਾ ਆਉਣਾ ਈ ਏਂ।”ਇਸ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਉਹਦੇ ਖਹਿੜੇ ਪੈ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਬੜਾ ਅਵਾਜ਼ਾਰ ਹੋਇਆ । ਪਰ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨਾਲ ਬੜਾ ਪਿਆਰ ਕਰਦਾ ਸੀ । ਇਸ ਲਈ ਇਕ ਦਿਨ ਉਹ ਤੰਗ ਆ ਕੇ ਆਖਣ ਲੱਗਾ, ''ਅੱਛਾ, ਤਾਂ ਬੁਲਾ ਲਿਆ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਾਂ ਪਿਓ ਤੇ ਹੋਰ ਸਾਕ ਸਬੰਧੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਤਾਂ ਜੋ ਮੈਂ ਮਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਪਹਿਲਾਂ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਸੀਅਤ ਕਰ ਜਾਵਾਂ ।”ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਕੋਲ ਇਕ ਕੁੱਤਾ, ਇਕ ਕੁੱਕੜ ਅਤੇ ਪੰਜਾਹ ਕੁ ਕੁਕੜੀਆਂ ਵੀ ਸਨ । ਜਦੋਂ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਅੰਤ ਵੇਲੇ ਦੀ ਤਿਆਰੀ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਸੀ, ਤਾਂ ਉਹਨੇ ਕੁੱਤੇ ਅਤੇ ਕੁੱਕੜ ਨੂੰ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਸੁਣਿਆ । ਕੁੱਤੇ ਨੇ ਕੁੱਕੜ ਨੂੰ ਆਖਿਆ, “ਕੀ ਤੈਨੂੰ ਪਤਾ ਏ ਕਿ ਸਾਡਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਮਰਨ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਏ । ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਇਸ ਗੱਲ ਤੇ ਅੜੀ ਹੋਈ ਏ ਕਿ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਸਾਡੀਆਂ ਸੁਣੀਆਂ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਦਸੇ । ਉਹਦੇ ਸਮਝਾਣ ਬੁਝਾਣ ਤੇ ਵੀ ਉਹ ਬਾਜ ਨਹੀਂ ਆ ਰਹੀ ।ਕੁੱਕੜ ਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ, “ਸਾਡਾ ਮਾਲਕ ਆਖਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਏ ਕਿ ਉਹਨੂੰ ਗੈਬ ਦੀਆਂ ਗੱਲਾਂ ਦਾ ਪਤਾ ਏ, ਪਰ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ ਜੇ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਚਾਰ ਸਕਦਾ !”ਕੁੱਤੇ ਨੇ ਪੁੱਛਿਆ, “ਫੇਰ ਤੇਰੇ ਖ਼ਿਆਲ ਵਿਚ ਸਾਡੇ ਮਾਲਕ ਨੂੰ ਹੁਣ ਕੀ ਕਰਨਾ ਚਾਹੀਦਾ ਏ ?”“ਕਿਉਂ, ਇਹ ਤਾਂ ਗੱਲ ਈ ਕੁਝ ਨਹੀਂ ! ਆਪਣੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨੂੰ ਇਹ ਕਹਿ ਦਵੇ ਕਿ ਸੁਣਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਸਦਾ ਲਈ ਸ਼਼ੁਦਾਈ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਏ ਤੇ ਉਹਦੀ ਮੌਤ ਬੁਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਹੁੰਦੀ ਏ । ਬਸ ਇਸੇ ਡਰ ਨਾਲ ਈ ਉਹ ਆਪਣੀ ਜਿੱਦ ਛੱਡ ਦਵੇਗੀ ।”ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਕੁੱਕੜ ਦੀ ਗੱਲ ਸੁਣ ਕੇ ਬਹੁਤ ਖੁਸ਼ ਹੋਇਆ । ਉਹ ਉਸੇ ਵੇਲੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਕਮਰੇ ਵਿਚ ਗਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨੂੰ ਬੁਲਾ ਕੇ ਕਹਿਣ ਲੱਗਾ, 'ਹਾਂ ਸੱਚ, ਇਹ ਦਸਣਾ ਤਾਂ ਮੈਂ ਭੁਲ ਈ ਗਿਆ ਸਾਂ ਕਿ ਭੇਤ ਵਾਲੀ ਗੱਲ ਨੂੰ ਸੁਣਨ ਵਾਲਾ ਵੀ ਨਾਲ ਈ ਸ਼ੁਦਾਈ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਏ ਤੇ ਬੁਰੀ ਤਰ੍ਹਾਂ ਮਰਦਾ ਏ ! ਸੋ ਤੂੰ ਵੀ ਮਰਨ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਹੋ ਜਾ।''ਇਹ ਸੁਣਦਿਆਂ ਹੀ ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਦੇ ਹੋਸ਼ ਉੱਡ ਗਏ ਅਤੇ ਉਹ ਘਬਰਾ ਕੇ ਬੋਲੀ, “ਨਾ, ਨਾ, ਇਹੋ ਜਹੀ ਗਲ ਸੁਣਨੋਂ ਕੀ ਥੁੜ੍ਹਿਆ ਏ ! ਮੈਂ ਸ਼ੁਦੈਣ ਥੋੜ੍ਹੀ ਆਂ । ਮੈਂ ਤਾਂ ਐਵੇਂ ਹੱਸ ਰਹੀ ਸਾਂ !\\" ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਨੇ ਆਖਿਆ-''ਚੰਗਾ ! ਫੇਰ ਨਾ ਕਦੀ ਪੁੱਠੇ ਸਿੱਧੇ ਸਵਾਲ ਕਰੀਂ।”ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਪਿੱਛੋਂ ਸੌਦਾਗਰ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਖ਼ੁਸ਼ੀ ਰਹਿਣ ਲਗ ਪਿਆ ਅਤੇ ਉਹਦੀ ਵਹੁਟੀ ਨੇ ਫੇਰ ਕਦੀ ਅੜੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ।"},{"question":"Raha resaka sakafo, inona avy no afaka hanaovana ny voatabia?","answer":"Ny voatabia dia afaka hanaovana:- lasary na rogay- sosy miaraka amin'ny tongolo na sosy amin'izao - ranom-boankazo - fangaro-kanina ( mofo hamburger ... )"},{"question":"கேள்வி:தஞ்சையில் பொறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ள அரசாணையால் அறியப்படும் செய்தி யாது?","answer":"பதில்:தஞ்சாவூரில் வாழ்ந்த ஆகம சாஸ்திர பண்டிதராகிய சர்வசிவ பண்டிதரிடத்தில் பல நாட்டைச்  சார்ந்த மாணாக்கர்கள் கல்விக் கற்க வந்திருந்தார்கள் என்ற செய்தி, முதல் இராஜராஜ சோழன் காலத்தில் தஞ்சையில் பொறிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"د افغانستان توکمیز ویش د تاریخ په اوږدو کې خپل ټولنیز-سیاسي منظره څنګه بدله کړې ده؟","answer":"د افغانستان توکمیز ویش، چې د لویو ډلو لکه پښتون، تاجک، هزاره او ازبکو څخه جوړ دی، د هیواد د پیچلې ټولنیز-سیاسي منظرې په جوړولو کې مهم رول لوبولی دی. په تاریخي توګه، د واک مبارزې او شخړې اکثرا په قومي تاوتریخوالو کې ریښې لري، چې مختلف ګروپونه د نفوذ او استازیتوب لپاره سیالي کوي. د پښتنو واکمني، چې تر ټولو لویه توکمیزه ډله ده، یوه تکراري موضوع ده، چې د حکومتوالۍ په تحرکاتو اغیزه کوي او د بې ثباتۍ په دوره کې مرسته کوي. د مختلفو قومونو ترمنځ د منابعو، سیاسي واک، او کلتوري پیژندنې سیالۍ شخړو ته لاره هواره کړې، چې د یو همغږي ملي هویت د پراختیا مخه نیسي. د یو ټول شموله سیاسي سیسټم د رامینځته کولو هڅې چې د ټولو توکمونو ګټې پکې ځای په ځای شوي روانې دي، په افغان دولت کې د تنوع د انډول کولو پیچلې ننګونې منعکس کوي."},{"question":"Taiza no niandohan'ny kafe?","answer":"Avy any Etiopia ny kafe, izay nahitana ny hazo kafe voalohany. Niparitaka nanerana izao tontolo izao ny zava-pisotro avy eo tamin’ny alalan’ny varotra."},{"question":"દૂધ પૌવા બનાવવાની સ્પેશ્યલ રેસીપી જણાવો.","answer":"1. દૂધને ઉકાળી લો, તેમા ખાંડ નાખો અને ખાંડ ઓગળે ત્યાં સુધી હલાવો. 2. દૂધને ઠંડુ થવા દો. 3. હવે પૌઆને ધોઈ લો. ધોયેલા પૌઆને ઠંડા દૂધમાં નાખો. 4. હવે દૂધ-પૌઆને 4-5 કલાક માટે ફ્રીજમાં મુકો. 5. હવે તેમાં ઈલાયચી પાવડર નાખી હલાવી લો. 6. દૂધ પૌઆ તૈયાર છે. આ દૂધ પૌઆને ચાંદની રાતમાં બેસીને તેનો આનંદ ઉઠાવો."},{"question":"Ọlọpaa n wa mọlẹbi ọmọbinrin ti wọn ba oku ẹ lotẹẹli kan ni Kwara","answer":"Ọmọbinrin kan ti wọn ko ti i mọ ibi to ti wa, ni wọn ba oku rẹ nileetura kan, Premium Diamond, to wa ni agbegbe Adewọle, nijọba ibilẹ Iwọ Oorun Ilọrin (West)  nipinlẹ Kwara.Agbẹnusọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Ọkasanmi Ajayi, lo fidi iṣẹlẹ naa mulẹ ninu atẹjade kan to fi lede lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọṣẹ yii. O lobinrin ti wọn pa sileetura ọhun ni wọn o ti ri ẹnikẹni ko waa beere rẹ, ati pe awọn Dokita ti ṣe ayẹwo oku naa ti gbogbo ara rẹ ṣi pe pẹrẹpẹrẹ.Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Kwara ti waa kede pe gbogbo obi ati alagbatọ ti wọn o ba ri ọmọbinrin wọn bẹrẹ lati ọjọ kejidinlọgbọn, oṣu karun-un, ọdun yii, ki wọn wa si ẹka to n ri si ọrọ oku, lolu ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Kwara, lati wo oku ọmọbinrin ọhun, ki wọn le gba oku wọn.Nigba ti Ọkasanmi n ṣalaye lori iṣẹlẹ naa, o ni ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹfa yii, ni arakunrin kan torukọ rẹ n jẹ Ọlamilekan Hanafi to jẹ alaamojuto ileetura Premium Diamond, to wa ni Adewọle, niluu Ilọrin, pe ileesẹ ọlọpaa, to si salaye pe ọkunrin kan torukọ rẹ n jẹ Adegboyega James, (No 12, Okelewo Street, Ẹdẹ) nipinlẹ Ọsun, waa gba yara, lẹyin to gba a tan lo jade lọ, nigba to de pada loun pẹlu ọmọbinrin kan jọ pada de lalẹ ọjọ naa, ṣugbọn nigba to di owurọ ọjọ keji ti awọn ko gbọ nnkan kan ninu yara naa lawọn lo kọkọrọ miiran lati ṣilẹkun, ṣugbọn iyalẹnu lo jẹ pe oku obinrin yii nikan lawọn ri ninu yara, awọn o si mọ igba ti ọmọkunrin ọhun sa lọ. Lẹyin iwadii ni awọn too mọ pe ayederu ni adirẹsi to fi silẹ.Ọkasanmi ni Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa, Mohammed Lawal Bagega, ti paṣẹ pe ki wọn mu awọn to n sakoso ileetura ọhun fun ẹkunrẹrẹ iwadii."},{"question":"Awọn ọmo Oodua ni Kwara ati Kogi fẹẹ darapọ mọ awọn eeyan wọn nilẹ Yoruba","answer":"Awọn ọmọ Yoruba ti wọn wa ni ipinlẹ Kwara ati Kogi ti kọwe si ile igbimọ aṣofin agba lati beere fun ẹtọ didarapọ mọ awọn eeyan wọn nilẹ Yoruba yooku. Wọn ni ki wọn ṣe atunṣe si aala ilẹ ni agbegbe mejeeji, ki awọn le bọ si aarin awọn ọ̄o baba awọn.Ẹgbẹ awọn ọmọ Yoruba to wa ijọba ibilẹ meje ni Kwara, ti marun-un wa ni Kogi, ni wọn panupọ sọrọ yii lọjọ Ẹti, Fraidee, to kọja pe awọn ti kọwe ranṣẹ sí ile igbimọ aṣofin agba, ti awọn si sọ pe yoo wu awọn ti ijọba ba le ṣe atunṣe si eto aala ilẹ, eyi ti yoo fun awọn lanfaani lati wa lara awọn ilẹ Yoruba yooku ni Naijiria.Orukọ ẹgbẹ wọn naa ni Kwara South Consultative Forum.Ninu ọrọ Aarẹ ẹgbẹ naa, Alagba Joseph Aderibigbe, ẹni to jẹ akọwe agba akọkọ fun ijọba ipinlẹ Kwara lọdun 1967, o ni iwe awọn ti wa nile igbimọ aṣofin agba, ohun tawọn si fẹ ni bi gbogbo aye yoo ṣe maa ri awọn Yoruba tó wà ní Kwara àti Kogi bi Yoruba tootọ, tawọn eeyan awọn ti wọn wa ni iha Iwọ-oorun Naijiria yoo si mọ pe ọkan naa làwọn n ṣe.Bẹẹ gẹgẹ ni won tun bẹbẹ pe inu awọn yoo dun ti awọn naa ba ni eto iṣakoso to dara bii tawon ilẹ̀ Yorùbá yooku lawọn agbegbe ti ori da wọn si. Ati pe yoo jẹ ohun idunnu ti awọn Yoruba to wa ni ìjọba ibilẹ marun-un ni Kogi ba le wa labẹ akoso awọn Yoruba Kwara, eyi ti yoo fí wọn han gẹgẹ ọkan lara awọn ẹya Yoruba ti wọn n gbe nilẹ Yoruba."},{"question":"Mowduuc kusaaabsan Qodbada jimcaha maiqori kartaaa ?","answer":"Haa waan kuqori karaa isheeg Mowduuca ."},{"question":"Nork idatzi zuen \\"Moby Dick\\" liburua?","answer":"\\"Moby Dick\\" liburua Herman Melvillek idatzi zuen."},{"question":"Wat is een Trachysarus ovalipennis?","answer":"Een Trachysarus ovalipennis is een keversoort uit de familie van de loopkevers. De wetenschappelijke naam van de soort is voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1955 door Straneo en Jeannel. "},{"question":"Generate a headline for the following text: nTawagar kwallon kafa ta mata ta Afirka ta Kudu ta yi nasara a kan ta Najeriya da ci 2-1 a wasan farko a rukuni na uku a gasar cin kofin Afirka a Morocco. Banyana-Banyana ta ci kwallayen ta hannun Jermaine Seoposenwe da kuma Hildah Tholakele Magaia. Najeriya ta zare kwallo daya daf da za a tashi daga karawar ta hannun Rasheedat Ajibade. Super Falcons mai kofi uku a jere 11 jumulla a gasar kofin Afirka, za ta yi wasa na biyu a rukuni na uku da Bostwana ranar 7 ga watan Yuni. A kuma ranar Banyana-Banyana za ta kece raini da Burundi. A cikin watan Satumba tawagar Afirka ta Kudu ta doke Super Falcons da ci 4-2 a gasar Aisha Buhari Cup ta kuma lashe kofin a Najeriya. Ranar Talata Rukunin farko zai yi wasa na biyu, inda mai masaukin baki Morocco za ta fafata da Uganda, yayin da Senegal za ta yi gumurzu da Burkina Faso. Morocco tana da maki uku, bayan cin Burkina Faso 1-0 ranar Asabar, ita kuwa Senegal ta doke Uganda 2-0 ranar Lahadi.","answer":"Sure, here's a headline for the given text -kungiyar kwallon kafa ta Banyana-Banyana ta doke kungiyar Super Falcons a gasar kofin Afirka ta mata"},{"question":"Dhab ka hadal","answer":"#Dhab_ka_hadalKan Doonaya in uu Madaxwe noqdo oo dhawr kun ama dhawr Malyan ku bixinaya In uu Dowlad Islaam dhiso miyuu doonayaa?Qofka Soomaaliga ah ee Nairobi ka dhistay guri 6 ama 7 dabaq ah oo ay ugu taallo 50 Qol oo midkiiba loogu jiro kiro dhan 500 oo doollar oo haddii Soomaaliya xasilooni ka dhacdo gurigiisa laga guurayo nabad ma rabaa?!Qofka Furihii isgaarsiinta ku shaqeysta ee hawadii Soomaaliya heysta ee hadalka aad ku hadleysid mobile kaaga lacag u yahay ee ka baqaya in dawladdu kala wareegto nabad ma rabaa?Qofka badeeca canshuur la aan ama mid dhacday soo geliya dalka ee ku lacageystay dawlad la aanta, filayana in haddii dawlad Islaam dhalato oo sharciga Islaamka  shaqeynayo nabad ma rabaa?Shirkadaha diyaaradaha ee xujeyda ka qaada 4000 ilaa 5000 oo doollar ee dadkaas xujeyda xoolahooda sida jajuubka ah ku cuna ee sidaas ku hela lacagta xad dhaafkaa haddii xasilooni timaadana ay macquul tahay in lagu soo xajiyo 1000 ama ka yar, kuwaasi iyaguna nabad ma rabaan?Hoggaamiye goboleedka horjoogaha u ah dhawr gobol ee loogu wanqalay madaxweyne ayaad tahay ee u qaraab taga dawlaha carabta ee soo helo boorso doollar ah ee Dubai ama Nairibi gurya ka dhista ilmihiisuna dibadda wax ugu bartaan nabad ma rabaa?Inta gacan ku dhiigla ah inta takana qabto oo sharciga ka baqeysa inta guri dawlo ama mid dadweyne ku jirta inta beer islaameed heysata, inta xaaraan ku noolka ah nabad ma rabaan?Intaasi marka loo fiiriyo bulshada inteeda  kale ma dhama 20% ayagana waxa ay u Sacab tumayaan kuwa kor lagu soo xusay in yar oo uu Alle u naxariistay mooyaanee#Dadyahow Baraarugoo #Diinta Dhab u qaatoo#Dimuqraadiyada diidoo#Duulkaan doobinaayee(dhawaaqida) #Diiday Sharciga Islaamkiyo#Qiyamkii Wanaagsanaa#Intaad Alle ka baqataan#Doqon-nimada deysaan#Dib isu waaniyoo#Diida oo ku Kufriya#Daacada Allaah iyo#Rasuulkiisa raaca#Rafaad waad ka baxeysaan#Raxmad waad heleysane"},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan langkah-langkah mengatasi masalah pencemaran alam sekitar. ","answer":"Fenomena pemanasan global semakin hari semakin menjadi realiti. Kenaikan suhu bumi yang kian terasa di setiap pelusuk dunia telah menjadi tajuk berita dan amaran yang diberikan oleh para saintis kini dialami sendiri oleh manusia. Salah satu punca berlakunya perubahan iklim yang ekstrim dan tidak menentu ini adalah disebabkan pencemaran terhadap alam sekitar. Tamadun manusia telah mengecapi suatu kejayaan apabila sektor perindustrian diperkenalkan. Namun disebalik kejayaan tersebut, pemeliharaan alam sekitar telah terabai dan meninggalkan kesan kepada kita generasi hari ini. Berbekalkan kemajuan sains dan teknologi ketika ini, kita masih berpeluang untuk memperbaiki kesilapan generasi terdahulu agar khazanah alam yang kita miliki dapat dinikmati selamanya. Oleh yang demikian, penting untuk kita mengetahui apakah langkah-langkah untuk mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar demi kemaslahatan manusia sejagat.Langkah pertama untuk mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar adalah dengan melaksanakan dasar kerajaan dan polisi pentadbiran yang mesra alam. Pihak kerajaan berperanan besar dalam membentuk undang-undang yang wajid dipatuhi oleh rakyat yang menetap di negara tersebut. Maka, penggubal polisi dan undang-undang negara bertanggungjawab untuk melaksanakan dasar yang mementingkan pemeliharaan alam sekitar. Sebagai contoh, dasar negara bebas karbon pada tahun 2050 perlu dilaksanakan dengan tepat dan menyeluruh. Perlepasan gas karbon ke udara perlu dikurangkan secara berperingkat bermula hari ini. Pihak kerajaan juga perlu menukarkan cara kita menjana kuasa elektrik pada hari ini iaitu dengan pembakaran arang batu dan menggantikannya dengan penjanaan kuasa yang boleh diperbaharui. Pelbagai alternatif dan teknologi yang telah dicipta supaya mesra alam tetapi memerlukan modifikasi dan kos untuk menggunakannya secara domestik. Ibarat peribahasa, dayung sudah di tangan, perahu di air. Tegasnya, Dengan melaksanakan dasar dan polisi yang mesra alam, pemeliharaan alam sekitar pasti dapat dicapai. Langkah seterusnya untuk mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar adalah dengan memperkasa pendidikan mengenai penjagaan alam sekitar. Pepatah melayu ada berkata, melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Begitu juga apabila kita ingin mendidik generasi muda supaya menghargai alam sekitar dan tidak melakukan pencemaran. Pendidikan mengenai kepentingan alam sekitar terhadap kehidupan manusia dan tahap kebergantungan kita kepada satu-satunya alam yang boleh kita diami ini adalah signifikan. Misalnya jika sungai-sungai dicemari dengan sisa toksik, mereka mungkin sukar untuk mendapat sumber air bersih untuk kegunaan harian. Pendidikan mengenai contoh-contoh tindakan yang mencemarkan alam sekitar juga penting untuk mereka mengetahui modus operandi pesalah laku terhadap alam sekitar. Apabila pendedahan seperti ini diberikan kepada mereka yang berusia setahun jagung, pastinya mereka akan melakukan perkara yang betul untuk memastikan kelangsungan generasi mereka kekal. Jelasnya, pencemaran terhadap alam sekitar dapat diatasi melalui pendidikan yang efektif dan berkesan.Di samping itu, kaedah untuk membendung pencemaran alam sekitar adalah dengan menyediakan pengurusan sisa yang terbaik. Secara konvensional, kita membuang sampah tanpa mengasingkan kategorinya dan akhirnya loggokan sampah tersebut akan dibiarkan lupus di tanah pelupusan sampah. Jika kaedah konvensional ini berterusan, jumlah tanah pelupusan sampah akan bertambah dan menyebabkan pencemaran berlaku. Justeru, sebagai individu kita perlu mengamalkan budaya kitar semula secara proaktif. Dengan melakukan kitar semula, kita dapat mengurangkan jumlah sisa sampah dan pencemaran dapat dikurangkan. Dari aspek masyarakat pula, kita hendaklah mengamalkan sikap bersederhana dalam kehidupan khususnya pemakanan. Malaysia mencatatkan lebih 17,000 tan sisa makanan pada setiap hari. Jika kita berhemah dalam kehidupan seperti memastikan makanan kita dimakan sehingga habis dan sisanya digunakan untuk membaja pastinya jumlah sisa sampah dapat dikurangkan. Intihannya, budaya pengurusan sisa sampah yang baik dapat membantu mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar.Akhir sekali, pencemaran alam sekitar dapat diatasi dengan menghukum pesalah laku terhadap dengan hukuman yang berat. Pihak berkuasa seperti Jabatan Alam Sekitar sewajarnya menguatkuasakan undang-undang dan menghukum pihak yang berkenaan. Jika kita lihat pada hari ini, hanya segelintir kilang industri yang dibina mengikut piawai yang ditetapkan oleh kerajaan. Dan juga terdapat berita mengenai kilang yang membuang sisa toksik terus ke sungai atau parit sebelum merawat sisa tersebut. Sikap pemain industri yang seperti enau dalam belukar, melepaskan pucuk masing-masing akan menyebabkan pencemaran untuk terus berlaku. Oleh sebab itu, apabila pesalah ditangkap dan dikenakan hukuman yang berat seperti menarik lesen perniagaan atau kilang mereka. Jika hukuman hanya sekadar bayaran denda, mereka pasti akan mengulangi kesalahan yang sama kerana hukuman tersebut tidak memberikan kesan kepada mereka. Izharnya, pencemaran alam sekitar boleh diatasi sekiranya pesalah yang membuat pencemaran dihukum dengan berat sebagai iktibar kepada masyarakat umum.Kesimpulannya, terdapat banyak langkah-langkah yang boleh dilakukan untuk mengatasi masalah pencemaran kepada alam sekitar. Tidak dinafikan masalah pencemaran alam sekitar merupakan satu isu yang tidak asing lagi di negara kita. Anggota masyarakat perlu memainkan peranan masing-masing untuk memastikan inisiatif-inisiatif mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar dilaksanakn dengan efisien. Hari ini kita sendiri dapat mengalami kesan pencemaran seperti jerebu, banjir kita dan sebagainya. Cuba fikirkan apa yang bakal dihadapi oleh anak cucu kita nanti jika pencemaran terhadap alam sekitar ini tidak dibendung? Ibarat peribahasa melayu berkata, ingat antara belum kena, hemat antara belum habis. Semoga usaha yang kita lakukan hari ini memberikan hasil kepada generasi akan datang untuk manfaat mereka."},{"question":"Sommige auto’s en vooral landbouwmachines zijn wel heel erg breed. Op smalle landweggetjes hebben ze de hele breedte van de weg nodig en soms zelfs de berm. Als ik daar wandel met mijn hond moet ik vaak uitwijken. Om nog maar niet te spreken van het moment dat ik daar met de auto rijd. Ik heb toch recht op de helft van de weg?","answer":"Het recht op de helft van de weg bestaat niet. Dat is echt niet wettelijk vastgelegd. Er zijn nu eenmaal smalle Nederlandse wegen waar zelfs twee auto’s van gewoon formaat elkaar niet kunnen passeren. In dat geval gaat het erom elkaar de ruimte te geven door even bij een breder stuk te wachten tot de ander gepasseerd is, of van de berm gebruik te maken, als dat kan.Er geldt wel een maximumbreedte voor voertuigen. De wet schrijft voor dat vrachtauto’s en de daaraan gekoppelde aanhangwagens en opleggers maximaal 2,55 meter breed mogen zijn. Voor koelwagens met de nodige, extra dikke wanden geldt zelfs 2,60 meter. Landbouwvoertuigen en andere zogenaamde rijdende werktuigen mogen inclusief de banden 3,00 meter breed zijn. Ook aanhangwagens hebben te maken met een breedtebeperking. Die mogen sinds 1 januari van dit jaar over de bak gemeten hooguit 2,55 meter breed zijn. Voorheen gold een maximumbreedte van 3,00 meter. Overigens kunnen voertuigen met een speciale ontheffing altijd toch nog breder zijn dan wat de wet voorschrijft."},{"question":"Ọkọ mi kì í ṣe pidán-pidán, àmọ́ Nàìjíríà ṣì máa dára - Oluremi Tinubu","answer":"Aya aarẹ orilẹ ede Najiria Sẹnẹtọ Olurẹmi Tinubu sọ pe ọkọ oun Aarẹ Bọla Tinubu ki ṣe pidan-pidan, ṣugbon o n ṣe iṣẹ rẹ bo ṣe tọ ati bo ṣe yẹ lati jẹ ki orilẹede Naijiria pada bọ sipo.Nigba ti o n sọrọ ni ile ijosin kan nibi ti wọn ti n ṣe ayẹyẹ ayajọ ọdun ominira ni ilu Abuja lanaa ọjọ Aiku, Olurẹmi sọ pe ọkọ oun ko ni dẹbi ohun to bajẹ ni Naijiria ru awọn to ti ṣe ijọba sẹyin.Amọṣa, Oluremi ni ijọba Tinubu yoo tun gbogbo ohun to ti bajẹ ṣe, ati pe yoo mu irọrun ba awọn ọmọ orilẹ ede Najiria.O fikun ọrọ rẹ pe oun ni igbagbọ ninu ọkọ oun pe o maa ṣiṣẹ lati ri pe alaafia yoo fi jọba ni Naijiria.Sẹnẹtọ Oluremi tun sọ ninu ọrọ rẹ pe ọjọ ola si n bọ wa dara lorilẹ ede Naijiria.Igba ọpọ ti de ni Naijiria, nitori naa, awọn ọmọ Naijiria gbọdọ ri ju ohun ti o n ṣẹlẹ lọwọ bayii lọ ti wọn be fẹ jẹ alabapin ninu igbega orilẹede wọn.O si tun rọ awon ọmọ orilẹ ede Najiria lati ṣe ajọyọ ominira ni iṣọkan eyi to n gbe orilẹ ede leke.''Ko si idojukọ ti a ko le bori ti a ba le tẹ le ọrọ ti Ọlọrun sọ ninu iwe mimọ pe ẹ wa si ọdọ mi ẹyin ti n ṣiṣẹ ti a di ẹru wuwo le lori emi o si fi isinmi fun ọkan yin.Ni iru asiko bayii, gbogbo ohun ti a le ṣe ni lati di igbagbọ wa mu sinsin ninu Ọlọrun.Aya aarẹ tun fi da awọn ọmọ orilẹ ede Najiria loju pe Tinubu ti ke si awon orilẹ ede lagbaye lati wa da ile iṣẹ silẹ fun irọrun gbogbo eeyan,'' Oluremi lo sọ bẹẹ."},{"question":"గోధుమకొవ్వు, తెలుపుకొవ్వుల మధ్య తేడాలను తెలపండి.","answer":"గోధుమ కొవ్వు గర్భస్థ పిండాలలోను, శిశువులలోను ఎక్కువగా ఉంటుంది. దీని ఎడిపోసైట్ కణాలలో అనేక చిన్న కొవ్వు బిందువులు ఉంటాయి. ఇది శిశువులలో ఉష్ణాన్ని ఉత్పత్తిచేసి దేహ ఉష్ణోగ్రతను కాపాడుతుంది.తెలుపు కొవ్వు పౌఢ జీవులలో అధికముగా ఉండి ఎడిపోసైట్ కణములో ఒక పెద్ద కొవ్వు బిందువు ఉంటుంది."},{"question":"请给以下的文言文它的译文：匡衡字稚圭，勤学而无烛，邻居有烛而不逮。衡乃穿壁引其光，以书映光而读之。邑人大姓文不识，家富多书，衡乃与其佣作而不求偿。主人怪问衡，衡曰：“愿得主人书遍读之。”主人感叹，资给以书，遂成大学。","answer":"匡衡字稚圭，勤奋好学，但家中没有蜡烛照明。邻居家有蜡烛，光线却照不到他家，匡衡就凿穿墙壁引来邻居家的烛光，把书映照着光来读。同乡有个大户不识字，但家中有很多书。于是匡衡就到他家去做他的佣人却不求得到报酬。主人对匡衡的举动感到奇怪，问他，他说：“我希望能够读遍主人家的书。”文不识感到惊叹，就把书借给他。最终(匡衡)成为了大学问家。"},{"question":"Dime cuál es el tema principal o categoría de esta pregunta: ¿Cuántas expansiones hay de World of Warcraft?","answer":"La categoría de esta pregunta es videojuegos."},{"question":"சிறு சிறு உதவிகளை பிறருக்குச் செய்வது பற்றி உனது கருத்து என்ன? வகுப்பில் கலந்துரையாடுக.","answer":"கமலன் : ராமு! சிறு சிறு உதவிகளைப் பிறருக்குச் செய்வது பற்றி நீ என்ன நினைக்கிறாய்?மாறன் : கட்டாயம் நாம் அவற்றை நாம் செய்ய வேண்டும். நீ என்ன நினைக்கிறாய்?கமலன் : செய்ய வேண்டும் என்று தான் நினைக்கிறேன்.மாறன் : சரி, அப்படி நீ செய்யும் போது உன் மனநிலை எப்படியிருக்கும்?கமலன் : அப்படி உதவி செய்யும் போது மகிழ்ச்சியாகவும், திருப்தியாகவும் இருக்கும். ஏதோ பெரிய சாதனை புரிந்தது போல மனதில் தோன்றும். உனக்கு எப்படியிருக்கும்?மாறன் : ராமு எனக்கும் அதே மனநிலைதான் இருக்கும். நமக்குள் பல ஒற்றுமை இருக்கிறதே!கமலன் : நமக்கு மட்டுமல்ல, நம்மைப்போல உதவி செய்கின்ற அனைவருக்குள்ளும் இதே ஒற்றுமையிருக்கும். இப்படி உதவி செய்கிறவர்களால்தான் இன்றளவும் உலகம் இயங்கிக் கொண்டிருக்கிறது.மாறன் : ஆமாம், ராஜா! சரியாகச் சொன்னாய். மனிதர்கள் மனிதருக்கு உதவி செய்வதுதான் மானுடத்தின் மாண்பு. ஆனால் இதைப் புரிந்து எல்லோரும் நடந்தால் எவ்வளவு சிறப்பாக இருக்கும்.கமலன் : ஆமாம்பா சரியாக சொல்கிறாய். நாம் செய்கிற சிறிய உதவிகூட பலருக்குப் பேருதவியாக அமைந்து விடுகிறது.மாறன் : நாம் இருவரும் இணைந்து செயல்பட நான் விரும்புகிறேன். நீ என்ன நினைக்கிறாய்?கமலன் : நல்லது செய்ய இணைவது தப்பேயில்லை நண்பா- இணைவோம் – செயல்படுவோம் – நன்றி நண்பா!"},{"question":"휴대폰 다크모드가 근시를 유발할까?","answer":"아직 근시의 정확한 원인은 밝혀지지 않았으며, 복잡한 요인들이 결합하여 발병할 수 있는 것으로 알려져 있습니다. 다크모드를 사용하는 것이 직접적으로 근시를 유발하는 것은 아니지만, 디지털 기기 사용 패턴과 눈 건강 사이에 연관성이 있을 수 있습니다.디지털 기기를 오랫동안 사용하거나 잘못된 자세로 사용할 경우 눈에 부담이 가며, 눈이 피로하게 느껴질 수 있습니다. 이것이 근시 발생과 관련되어 있을 수 있습니다. 또한, 장거리 시야의 부족과 가까운 거리에서의 과도한 화면 시청은 근시 위험을 증가시킬 수 있습니다.근시 예방을 위해서는 디지털 기기 사용 시 정기적인 휴식을 취하고, 디지털 스크린에서 눈을 쉬게 하는 화면 각도나 밝기 설정, 안면 운동, 적절한 조명을 사용하는 것이 도움이 될 수 있습니다. 또한, 근시와 같은 눈 건강 문제가 발견되면 안과 의사와 상담하는 것이 좋습니다."},{"question":"ما مدى انتشار استخدام الطب التقليدي؟","answer":"كان الطب التقليدي والتكميلي موردًا أساسيًا للصحة في الأسر والمجتمعات المحلية على مدار عدة قرون. وأبلغت مائة وسبعون دولة عن استخدام الطب التقليدي، وكان الوخز بالإبر هو الشكل الأكثر شيوعًا للممارسة في 113 بلدًا. وبدأت العديد من البلدان المتقدمة أيضًا في الاعتراف بالطب التقليدي ودمجه في نُظُم الرعاية الصحية الخاصة بها.ووفقًا لبيانات عام 2012، يستخدم ما يقرب من نصف السكان في العديد من البلدان الصناعية الآن بعض أشكال الطب التقليدي والتكميلي بانتظام (الولايات المتحدة، 42%؛ أستراليا، 48%؛ فرنسا، 49%؛ كندا، 70%)؛ ويوجد استخدام كبير لبعض أشكال الطب التقليدي والتكميلي في العديد من البلدان الأخرى، مثل شيلي (71%) وكولومبيا (40%) وبنسبة تصل إلى 80% في بعض البلدان الأفريقية."},{"question":"\\"T\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ කී වෙනි අකුර ද?","answer":"\\"T\\" අක්ෂරය නූතන ඉංග්‍රීසි හෝඩියේ 20 වන අකුරේ ස්ථානය හිමි වන අතර භාෂා සහ ක්ෂේත්‍ර හරහා පොහොසත් ඉතිහාසයක් සහ භාවිතයක් ඇත.මූලාරම්භය: \\"T\\" අක්ෂරයේ මූලාරම්භය ෆීනීෂියානු අකුර \\"Taw\\" තුලින් ඇති අතර, එය \\"Tau\\" යන ග්‍රීක අකුරටද හේතු විය. එය /t/ ලෙස පිටපත් කර ඇති කටහඬක් නැති ඇල්වෙයෝලර් ප්ලෝසිව් ශබ්දයක් නිරූපණය කිරීමට අඛණ්ඩව භාවිතා කර ඇත.උච්චාරණය: ඉංග්‍රීසියෙන්, \\"T\\" සාමාන්‍යයෙන් උච්චාරණය කරනු ලබන්නේ කටහඬ රහිත ඇල්වලෙයෝලර් ප්ලෝසිව් ලෙසය, එය ඉහළ ඉදිරිපස දත් පිටුපසින් ඇති ඇල්වලෙයෝලර් කඳු මුදුනේ වාතය ප්‍රවාහයට බාධා කිරීමෙන් නිපදවන ශබ්දයකි.භාවිතය: \\"T\\" යනු ඉංග්‍රීසි භාෂාවේ පොදු අකුරක් වන අතර \\"ගස\\", \\"වගුව\\", \\"කාලය\\" සහ \\"තාක්‍ෂණය\\" වැනි බොහෝ වචන වලින් දිස්වේ.වෙනත් භාෂාවලින්: \\"T\\" අක්ෂරය විවිධ උච්චාරණ සහිත බොහෝ භාෂා සහ හෝඩියේ භාවිතා වේ. නිදසුනක් වශයෙන්, ස්පාඤ්ඤ භාෂාවෙන්, උච්චාරණය ඉංග්‍රීසි හා සමාන වේ, නමුත් එය දිවෙන් දත් ස්පර්ශ කිරීමෙන් නිපදවන අතර එහි ප්‍රතිඵලයක් ලෙස මෘදු ශබ්දයක් ඇති වේ.කේත සහ සංකේත තුළ: ගුවන්විදුලිය සහ දුරකථනය හරහා පැහැදිලි සහ නිරවද්‍ය සන්නිවේදනය සඳහා භාවිතා කරන නේටෝ ශබ්ද හෝඩියේ, \\"T\\" අක්ෂරය \\"Tango\\" යන වචනයෙන් නියෝජනය වේ.ගණිතයේ සහ විද්‍යාවේ: භෞතික විද්‍යාවේ උෂ්ණත්වය හෝ ගණිතයේ පරිවර්තනයක් වැනි විචල්‍යයක් හෝ නියතයක් නිරූපණය කිරීමට \\"T\\" අක්ෂරය බොහෝ විට භාවිතා වේ.සාහිත්‍යය සහ මාධ්‍ය තුළ: ජනප්‍රිය සංස්කෘතියේ චරිතයක් වන \\"ටී-ෂර්ට්\\" හෝ \\"මිස්ටර් ටී\\" වැනි කෙටි යෙදුමක් හෝ සංකේතයක් ලෙස \\"ටී\\" භාවිතා කළ හැක.මුද්‍රණ ශිල්පය සහ අත් අකුරු: අත් අකුරු වල \\"T\\" අකුර ලියා ඇත්තේ දළ වශයෙන් මැදින් වෙනත් රේඛාවකින් හරස් කරන ලද සරල රේඛාවක් ලෙස වන අතර කුඩා අකුරු \\"t\\" ට සමාන ස්වරූපයක් ඇති නමුත් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් කුඩා වන අතර සමහර විට පාදයේ වක්‍රයක් ඇතුළත් වේ.මෙම අංශ සලකා බැලීමෙන්, විවිධ වසම් හරහා \\"T\\" අක්ෂරයේ විවිධ යෙදුම් සහ වැදගත්කම අපට අගය කළ හැකිය."},{"question":"Dukkanin su sun samu shahada a yakin Uhud, amma ban da","answer":" (a) Hamza bin Abdil Mudallib (b) Mus'ab bin Umair (c) Sa'ad bin Abi Waqqas"},{"question":"Manomeza lahatsoratra miresaka momba ny fitaovam-pitantanana noforonina ho an’ny mpiompy trondro.","answer":"Ny Feon’ny Mpiompy Trondro n° 53Marsa 3, 2022LOHAHEVITRA : Atsaraina ny famokarana trondro tantanam-pianakavianaHafa ny fiompiana trondro ! Matetika mifandray amin’ny  fiompiana omby ohatra izy, vokatry ny fampiasana zezika. Tena miankina amin’ny tahirim-bola ihany koa ny fampiharana ny teknika : tsy azo ampiharina indraindray ny teknika nohatsaraina vokatry ny tsy fisian’ny vola. Afakamanatsara ny kalitaon’ny tohana entin’ny mpanentana (ACP) sy ny fitantanan’ny mpiompy trondro ny famokarany ny TFT.Namorona sy nanandrana ny fomba fiasa TFT tao amin’nyfaritra Itasy izahay ny taona 2019 hatramin’ny 2020.Nofantarinay tamin’izany aloha ireo olana eo amin’ny fitantanana ny famokarana trondro. Izany no nahafahanay nanamboatra fitaovana tsotra, mety amin’ny mpiompy trondro sy ny ACP, hanampiana azy ireo amin’ny fandalinana.Ankehitriny, ireo no fitaovana fototra ifampiresahan’ny ACP sy ny mpiompy trondro. Ampiasaina ireo amin’ny fanjohiana eny ifotony sy amin’ny fotoana manan-danja amin’ny taom-pamokarana. Mora ho an’ny mpiompy trondro ny mamantatrany fanatsarana entina amin’ny famokarana trondro vokatry ny fisian’ireo fitaovana ireo sy ny fiarahan-dian’ny ACP. Tsara kokoa anefa ny manontany mivantana ny hevitr’izy ireo !Ho anareo mpiompy trondro na lehilahy na vehivavy izay mamaky ity lahatsoratra ity ary mampiasa ny fitaovan’ny TFT ihany koa dia aza misalasala mizara ny fahitànareo izany aoamin’ny laharana manaraka !FMT : Inona no fanambinareo tamin’ny nametrahana ireo fitaovam-pitantanana ireo ?Chloé : Ny tarehimarika, ny kajy, ny firaiketana an-tsoratra, … mety ho vaovao sy sarotra ho an’ny mpiompy trondro ireo rehetra ireo ! Nisy ny ezaka fampiofananasy « fanapariahana » ireo voambolan’ny fitantanana tsy maintsy natao. Voarain’ny mpiompy trondro tsara anefa ireo fitaovana taorian’ny fiarahan-dia mifanaraka amin’izany syny famerimberenana ny fiofanana natao. Nisy ihany koa ny fanamby ho an’ny ACP, fomba fiasa vaovao mantsy izy io : nasainay nampivelatra ny fomba fijeriny izy ireo fa tsyhifantoka amin’ny fiompiana trondro sy ny lafiny teknika fotsiny ihany. Taorian’ny fampiofanana vitsivitsy sy ny fampiharana ifotony dia nandeha tsara ny asa rehetra.FMT : Tena nila ireo fitaovam-pitantanana ireo ve ny mpiompy trondro ary inona no fiovana azon’izy ireo tamin’izany ?Chloé : Malalaka ny mpiompy trondro na hampiasa na tsia ireo fitaovana ireo. Anjaranay kosa anefa ny manome azy ireo fahalalana sy fahaiza-manao mikasika ny fitantanana ny fiompiana trondro. Ny fanomezana azy ireo teknika tsy miaraka amin’ny fanalahidin’ny fitantanana dia tahaka ny manome boky tsy misy solomaso amakiana azy ! Araka ny efa nohazavaiko, niezaka namaly ny filàn’ny mpiompy trondro mikasika ny olan’ny fitantanana izahay. Ireo fitaovana izay mamaly tsara ny fangatahan’izy ireo dia ampiasainy amin’ny ankapobeny. Manampy azy amin’ny fifampidinihana sy ny fanatsarana ny lamina amin’ny taom-pamokarana zana-trondro sy fanatavizana, ny ara-bola, ny famarotana sy ny fitantanana ny valam-pamokarana. Ankoatra izay, rehefa atao ny tombana ara-tekinika sy ara-toekarena (fa tsy ara-tekinika fotsiny) dia afaka manova ny safidiny eo amin’ny lafiny teknika sy ny fitantanana araka ny tanjona kendreny ny mpiompy trondro. Ny fitahirizany ireo fitaovana ireo ho an’ny taom-piompiana mifandimby dia ahafahan’izy ireo manaraka akaiky ny fivoaran’ny famokarana ataony.Fitaovam-pitantanana maro no noforonina niaraka tamin’ireo mpanentana sy ireo mpiompy trondro miara-miasa amin’ny APDRA mba hamahana ny olan’ny fitantanana sedrain’ireto farany.Ireto avy ny fitaovam-pitantanana nampiasaina :Peta-drindrina fandraiketana an-tsoratra ny teknika sy ny ekonomika : fitaovana mora ampiasaina kokoa mitaha amin’ny kahie firaiketana an-tsoratra ; natao hitahirizana ny zava-mitranga rehetra eo amin’ny famokarana mandritra ny taom-pamokarana iray izy ity, na eo amin’ny lafiny teknika (daty fampanatodizana, fandrotsahana trondro, fanajariana, famahanana, sns.) na ny lafiny toekarena (fidirana sy fivoaham-bola).Fisy fikajiana ireo tondro ara-teknika sy ara-ekonomika : natao hikajiana ireo mari-drefy manan-danja tamin’ny taom-pamokarana teo aloha ity fitaovana ity ; mifototra amin’ny tarehimarika hita tao amin’ny peta-drindrina firaikena ara-teknika sy ara-toekarena ny kajy rehetra. Tanjona ny hamintina ny fotoam-pamokarana sy hanatsoaka lesona hampivoarana ny taom-pamokaranamanaraka.Fitantanana ny asa famokarana zana-trondro na ny « 4 Fzana-trondro » : izy no ahafahan’ny mpamokatra zana-trondro mandamina mialoha ny famokarany hifanaraka amin’ny zava-misy (tsy fisian’ny rano, tinadin’ny tsena, sns.) sy mamaly tsara ny filàn’ny mpanatavy zana-trondro. Tetiandro famatsiam-bola ny asa famokarana trondro : manampy ny mpiompy trondro tojo fahasahiranana ara-bola ary tsy afaka mamita tsara ny asany izy ity. Tanjona ny hahazoan’izy ireo mitantana tsara ny famokarany araka ny vola misy eo am-pelatanana, amin’ny alàlan’io fitaovana io. Ankehitriny, mbola mamorona fitaovana hamaliana ireo fanontaniana vaovao sy olana hovahana ny mpanentana. Foronina miaraka amin’ny mpiompy trondro ary natao ho azy ireo izany fitaovana izany, lasa fampiasany ary ampifanarahany amin’ny filàny sy ny zava-misy iainany avy eo. Efa anaovana andrana ankehitriny ny fitaovana sasany mialoha ny hanapariahana azy.Fitaovam-pitantanana noforonina ho an’ny mpiompy trondro."},{"question":"Berikan judul yang tepat untuk artikel berita berikut.Artikel: Foto mengejutkan yang mengingatkan tentang pentingnya masalah sampah di laut. Kenapa tak ada tindakan untuk mengatasi masalah sampah? Seberapa gawatkah masalah sampah di laut Indonesia? Tulisan ini akan menjelaskannya.Beberapa waktu terakhir ini warganet kembali diingatkan pada masalah sampah plastik melalui video wisatawan Inggris yang menyelam di antara lautan sampah di Nusa Penida, Bali. Aneka sampah plastik mengapung di sekitar penyelam. Ditambah lagi, tumpukan sampah yang terhampar di sepanjang pantai di Bali beberapa bulan terakhir membuat persoalan plastik yang selama ini terpinggirkan, kembali menyita perhatian publik. Pria Inggris ini menyelam dengan banyak sampah plastik.Kementerian Pariwisata membantah video tersebut melalui akun Twitter resminya. \\"Siapa bilang laut Nusa Penida banyak sampah? Dikepung sampah plastik seperti yang diviralkan diver Inggris Rich Horner? Lautnya ternyata clear. Biota lautnya juga hidup sangat sehat,\\" kata akun @Kemenpar_RI pada 10 Maret 2018. Kementerian tersebut berusaha memberikan bukti dengan video laut yang bersih dan diberi tagar #IniLhoAslinyaNusaPenida #WonderfulNusaPenida. Pada 10 Maret 2018 ada sekitar 3.800 tagar #IniLhoAslinyaNusaPenida diikuti 2.882 tagar terkait, #WonderfulNusaPenida. Kedua tagar tersebut hanya muncul hingga 11 Maret dan pada 12 Maret, sudah hampir tidak ada lagi twit baru dengan tagar tersebut.Reaksi Kementerian ini disayangkan warganet, karena tidak memberikan solusi terhadap masalah sampah. Sebenarnya, benarkah soal sampah di laut ini adalah sebuah masalah yang besar? Seperti apa kondisi sampah di laut?Untuk melihat seberapa gawatnya kondisi sampah di laut, berikut ini fakta yang bisa disimak. Apa dampak sampah di laut hanya untuk manusia?Sampah plastik membunuh para penghuni laut, dari ikan, penyu, bahkan burung yang tinggal di sekitar pantai. Makhluk laut terbelit aneka sampah plastik. Dalam film dokumenter BBC, Blue Planet 2, penonton bisa melihat bagaimana seekor kura-kura penyu sisik terjerat kantong plastik.Jawaban:","answer":"Sampah di Laut Indonesia: Fakta atau Hoax?"},{"question":"ಈ ವಾಕ್ಯದ ಒಂದು ಹೆಚ್ಚು ಸಂಕೀರ್ಣ ಆವೃತ್ತಿಯನ್ನು ರಚಿಸಿ ಅವರು ಸೊಕ್ಕಿನ ಹೀಲ್ ಪಾತ್ರವನ್ನು ಪರಿಪೂರ್ಣಗೊಳಿಸಿದರು.","answer":"\\"ಅವರು ಅಹಂಕಾರಿ ಎದುರಾಳಿಯ ಚಿತ್ರಣವನ್ನು ಸೂಕ್ಷ್ಮವಾಗಿ ಗೌರವಿಸಿದರು, ಅಸಾಧಾರಣ ಕೈಚಳಕ ಮತ್ತು ದೃಢೀಕರಣದೊಂದಿಗೆ ಸೊಕ್ಕಿನ 'ಹೀಲ್' ಪಾತ್ರವನ್ನು ಸಾಕಾರಗೊಳಿಸಿದರು.\\""},{"question":"Complete o seguinte extrato: O terceiro álbum de estúdio da banda, \\"Midnight Memories,\\" foi lançado em 25 de novembro de 2013. Este foi o álbum mais vendido em todo o mundo em 2013, com 4 milhões de cópias vendidas. \\"Best Song Ever\\", o primeiro single do álbum, se tornou a música de maior sucesso do One Direction nos Estados Unidos. Após o lançamento do álbum, o grupo embarcou na turnê","answer":"turnê \\"Where We Are\\". A banda teve uma média de 49,848 fãs por show, com ingressos esgotados no minuto em que as vendas começaram. A turnê arrecadou mais de USD 290 milhões e foi a turnê com maior bilheteria de 2014."},{"question":"De qual categoria é essa pergunta: Tóquio fica na China?.","answer":"Geografia"},{"question":"Chii chinoitika panguva yechikamu chinonzi \\"Giggle Box\\"? Mutambo weTV wakaiswa nyeredzi uye wakagadzirwa naJustin Fletcher, uyo anotamba vatambi mune ese ezvikeche zvekomedhi uye akanyorawo mashoma mashoma mumutsara wayo wekutanga. Mamwe emifananidzo akatorwa mu studio, nepo mamwe mapikicha akatorwa kunze; semuenzaniso, imwe inotorwa paPortmeirion, inoshandiswa kudhorobha rengano reWiggyville uko mifananidzo yaKaputeni Adorable inoiswa kubva Series 1 kusvika 2. Chiratidziro chinopindirana nesarudzo yevana vanonzi maGigglekids, vanotaura majee kuna Justin pachake, mumutauro wavo. chikamu chako chinonzi 'Giggle Box'.","answer":"Vana vanonzi maGigglekids vanotaura majee kuna Justin."},{"question":"கேள்வி : இத்தாலியின் தலை நகர் எது ?","answer":"பதில் : ரோம்."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo hita any an-tanindrazana?","answer":"Ireto avy no hita any an-tanindrazana:- ny trano nonenan'ny razana.- ny fasana nilevenan'ny razana.- ny tanimboly nambolen'ny razana."},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：人类学如何研究不同文化的身份与权力？","answer":"答案：人类学通过研究不同文化的身份认同、权力结构、社会阶层等方面来了解其身份与权力的文化构建和社会关系。"},{"question":"In de Verenigde Staten heeft president Joe Biden het controversiële olieproject in Alaska goedgekeurd. Het bedrijf ConocoPhilips zou tot 180.000 olievaten per dag kunnen produceren. Wat is de naaam van dit omstreden olieproject?","answer":"Willow "},{"question":"Тогуз ","answer":"9 цифрасынын жазма түрүндө жазылганы"},{"question":"Hãy cung cấp cách làm Phở bò sốt vang Hà Nội.","answer":"Cách làm Phở bò sốt vang Hà Nội:a. Sơ chế, chuẩn bị:Chọn bò nấu sốt vang ngon nhất là phần dẻ sườn có cả gân khi ăn có vị mềm béo, sần sật mà không bị khô. Bò mua về bóp chút rượu trắng và gừng đập dập rồi rửa sạch, thái miếng to hình bao diêm. Các gia vị đặc trưng gồm có quế, hồi, thảo quả và không thể thiếu lá nguyệt quế. Rượu vang đỏ vừa giúp mềm thịt, vừa tăng hương thơm đặc trưng. Gừng, tỏi giã hoặc băm nhỏ. Để tạo màu nâu đỏ hấp dẫn cho món ăn nên sử dụng dầu màu điều hoặc bột ớt paprika. Cà chua rửa sạch, khía hình chữ thập trên quả, cho vào nước sôi chần 1 - 2 phút cho vỏ bong vớt ra ngâm vào nước lạnh, bóc tách bỏ vỏ, băm nhuyễn. b. Tẩm ướp:Cho thịt bò vào âu lớn rồi ướp với 1/2 gừng tỏi giã, thêm 3 thìa canh dầu màu điều, 2 thìa canh nước mắm, 1 thìa cà phê muối (bột canh), 1 thìa cà phê hạt nêm, 1 thìa cà phê hạt tiêu, 1/2 chén rượu vang đỏ cùng quế, hồi, thảo quả đã rang thơm. Trộn đều tất cả và ướp tối thiểu trong 1 giờ. Nếu có thời gian, bọc màng bọc thực phẩm để qua đêm trong ngăn mát tủ lạnh. c. Nấu sốt vang:Phi thơm 1/2 tỏi với bơ, trút thịt bò đã ướp vào xào săn. Nêm nếm lại gia vị cho vừa miệng. Tiếp tục phi thơm bơ và tỏi, cho cà chua vào, nêm chút muối.Nếu có điều kiện, nên nấu nước dùng để món ăn có vị ngọt tự nhiên. Xương bò ngâm với nước muối loãng, thêm chút rượu trắng rồi đem nướng, chần rửa sạch lại. Ninh xương ở lửa nhỏ, thêm hành tây, hành khô, gừng nướng cùng chút muối và đường phèn cho dịu vị. Thỉnh thoảng hớt bỏ bọt. Nên ninh xương trước để khi nấu sẽ tiện hơn. Nước dùng đạt là có màu vàng cánh gián óng ánh mỡ bò mà trong, có mùi thơm đặc trưng. Một số hàng quán khi bán thường múc sốt vang nấu riêng cho vào, cuối cùng múc nước dùng phở. Trút thịt bò xào săn, cà chua xào mềm vào nồi, thêm nước, nước dùng bò (căn đủ lượng người ăn), 1/2 chén rượu vang đỏ còn lại vào. Nêm nếm lại gia vị cho vừa miệng. Khi nước sôi, hạ nhỏ lửa và ninh tối thiểu trong 1 giờ hoặc cho tới khi thịt mềm, nước dùng sốt sánh lại. Vớt bỏ quế, hồi, thảo quả và như vậy là sốt vang đã hoàn thành. Bánh phở tươi chần qua nước sôi rồi chia đều ra các bát, rắc rau thơm (hành, mùi tàu, mùi ta), gắp mỗi bát 5 - 6 miếng sốt vang rồi chan nước sốt vang, thêm nước dùng (nếu thích) và thưởng thức. d. Yêu cầu thành phẩm:Bát phở sốt vang hội tụ cả sắc, hương và vị với thịt bò đỏ nâu, mềm ngọt, có chút sần sật từ gân mà không bị khô bở. Nước dùng nâu đỏ, hơi sánh, dậy mùi thơm của quế, hồi, thảo quả. Chút hành lá, rau mùi xanh tươi mát tăng thêm phần bắt mắt. Món này ăn trong tiết trời mát mẻ rất hợp."},{"question":"إذا كانت 'ومن الجميل الكلام معك' صحيحة فإني 'انا اتحدث اليك كل يوم .' صحيحة؟ صح أم خطأ؟","answer":"غالباً صحيحة."},{"question":"Meeqo sano ayuu  jiray  nabiga csw markuu dhimanaayay?","answer":"Nabiga csw wuxuu jiray 63 sano"},{"question":"Gịnị bụ azịza gwam gwam gwam(agwụgwa) a?Gwa m ọdara ọbụ ereghi ure","answer":"Ọ bụ Nkume"},{"question":"Ọlọpaa ti mu Otubọ, ọkunrin ẹgbẹ ẹ lo ki mọlẹ laarin oru to fẹẹ maa ṣe ‘kinni’ fun l’Oṣodi","answer":"Ọkunrin kan, Jane Otubọ, ẹni ọdun mejidinlọgbọn, ti wa lakata awọn ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ ni Panti, lagbegbe Yaba, o ti n ṣalaye ohun to ri lọbẹ to fi waro ọwọ, wọn lọkunrin ẹgbẹ ẹ lo fẹẹ fipa ba lo pọ tọwọ awọn agbofinro fi tẹ ẹ.Gẹgẹ bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe sọ, wọn ni ori ikanni atẹ ayelujara kan lafurasi ọdaran ti wọn lo n gbe Ojule kẹta, Opopona Ẹniọla, ni Mafoluku, l’Oṣodi, ti pade Ọgbẹni Francis Azeez, agbegbe Gwagwalada, niluu Abuja, olu-ilu ilẹ wa, lawọn mejeeji jọ n ṣọrẹ, wọn jọ n ṣaati (chat).Ibi ti wọn ti n sọrọ loorekoore yii ni wọn ni Otubọ ti ṣeleri fun Francis pe oun aa da a lokoowo, oun aa si ran an lọwọ, o ni ko waa ba oun l’Ekoo kawọn jọ foju rinju, kawọn le jọ sọ bi bisinẹẹsi naa aa ṣe bẹrẹ.Francis ṣalaye fawọn ọlọpaa pe ohun ti ko jẹ koun fura si ọkunrin ti wọn lọmọ bibi ipinlẹ Enugu ni yii ni pe funra ẹ lo fowo ti oun maa fi wọkọ ofurufu wa s’Ekoo ṣọwọ sinu akaunti oun, lai mọ oun ri, loun naa ba gbera, o mori le Eko lọsẹ to kọja, ọdọ ọrẹ rẹ yii lo de si.Olumuyiwa Adejọbi, Alukoro ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa Eko, sọ pe ninu alaye ti Francis ṣe ni teṣan ọlọpaa Makinde, l’Oṣodi, nigba to waa fẹjọ sun, o ni ọrọ bisinẹẹsi lawọn kọkọ n sọ, afi bo ṣe di oru Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ti olugbalejo oun bẹrẹ si i fọwọ pa oun lara, to n fọwọ pa oun labẹ nigba toun sun lọ, titaji toun taji, o ni ihooho goloto lọkunrin naa wa, o si ti bu ṣokoto oun so, o loun fẹ kawọn jọ laṣepọ, loun ba yari mọ ọn lọwọ.Francis ṣalaye siwaju si i pe ijakadi gidi lawọn ba ara awọn ja, tori ọkunrin naa ni afi dandan ni koun ṣe ‘kinni’ foun lai ki i ṣe obinrin, ariwo kitakita tawọn n ṣe lo ji awọn araale silẹ, eyi lo mu ki ọkunrin kan ti wọn n pe ni aafaa tẹ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa laago  loru naa, n ni wọn ba waa fi pampẹ ọba gbe afurasi ọdaran ọhun.Wọn ni lanlọọdu ile naa tun ṣalaye fawọn ọlọpaa pe ọkunrin yii ko ṣẹṣẹ maa huwa palapala ọhun, lanlọọdu ni ọpọ igba loun ti pari aawọ latari bawọn eeyan ṣe n n fẹjọ tẹnanti yii sun pe o n fi ilọkulọ lọ awọn.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe okoowo awọn nnkan jijẹ ni afurasi ọdaran naa loun n ṣe, awọn aladuugbo naa ni irin ẹsẹ rẹ ko mọ, wọn lọganjọ oru lo maa n wọle lọpọ igba, ẹnu si ti n kun un laduugbo pe afaimọ ni ko ma jẹ oniṣẹẹbi ẹda kan ni, wọn ni boya tori ẹ lọkunrin naa ṣe n pe ara ẹ ni Jane.Ṣa, ọrọ rẹ ti detiigbọ kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Eko, o si ti ni ki wọn fa a le ọlọpaa ọtẹlẹmuyẹ lọwọ fun iwadii gidi, lẹyin eyi lo maa lọọ ṣalaye ara ẹ ni kootu laipẹ"},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、最大500語の段落を書いてください： 「女性が働きやすい国」日本は29の国の中で28番","answer":"3月8日は国連が決めた「国際女性デー」でした。イギリスの経済の雑誌は、世界の29の国の男性と女性の給料や働く人の数などを調べて、女性が働きやすい国を発表しています。29の国の中で、1番はアイスランドで、日本は28番でした。日本は会社の管理職と衆議院の議員の女性の割合がいちばん低くなっていました。29番は韓国でした。雑誌は「日本と韓国では今でも、女性が家族と仕事のどちらかを選ばなければなりません」と言っています。政府の松野官房長官は「男性も女性も、働きながら子どもを育てることができるようにして、みんなが活躍できる社会にしたいです」と話しました。"},{"question":"પેરિસમાં ફરવા માટેના સુંદર સ્થળો: ","answer":"પેરિસ એ પ્રેમ અને રોમાંસનું શહેર છે, જેમાં ઇતિહાસ, સંસ્કૃતિ અને અદભૂત સ્થાપત્યથી ભરપૂર છે. નીચે પેરિસમાં ફરવા માટેના કેટલાક સુંદર સ્થળો આપ્યા છે:આઇકોનિક સ્થળો:એફિલ ટાવર:  પેરિસનું પ્રતીક, આ લોખંડની ટાવર શહેરના અદભૂત નજારાઓ પ્રદાન કરે છે.લુવ્રે મ્યુઝિયમ:  વિશ્વના સૌથી પ્રખ્યાત મ્યુઝિયમોમાંનું એક, લુવ્રે મોના લિસા, વિનસ ડી મિલો અને ઘણી અન્ય કલાકૃતિઓનું ઘર છે.નોટ્રે ડેમ:  12મી સદીનું ગોથિક કૅથેડ્રલ, જે તેની અદભૂત સ્થાપત્ય અને સુંદર ગુલાબી કાચની બારીઓ માટે જાણીતું છે.આર્ક ડી ટ્રાયમ્ફ:  નેપોલિયન દ્વારા તેના વિજયોની ઉજવણી માટે બનાવવામાં આવેલ, આ વિજય સ્થાપત્ય શહેરના કેન્દ્રમાં સ્થિત છે.સુંદર પાર્કો અને બગીચાઓ:જાર્ડિન ડુ લક્સેમબર્ગ:  25 હેક્ટરમાં ફેલાયેલો આ સુંદર બગીચો પેરિસિયનો અને પ્રવાસીઓ માટે એક લોકપ્રિય સ્થળ છે.ચેમ્પ્સ-એલિસીસ: આ વિશાળ બુલેવર્ડ તેની ફૂટપાથ, બગીચાઓ અને લક્ઝરી દુકાનો માટે જાણીતું છે.બોઇસ ડી વિન્સેન્સ:  પેરિસના પૂર્વમાં આવેલું આ વિશાળ જંગલ બાઇક ચલાવવા, દોડવું, બોટિંગ કરવા અને પ્રકૃતિનો આનંદ માણવા માટે એક શાનદાર સ્થળ છે.અન્ય રસપ્રદ સ્થળો:મોન્ટમાર્ટ્રે:  એક સુંદર ઘાટી જેમાં સેક્રેડ-કોયર બેસિલિકા અને ઘણા આર્ટ ગેલેરીઓ અને કલાકારોના સ્ટુડિયો આવેલા છે. મ્યુઝી ડી'ઓરસે:  19મી સદીની કલાનું એક મહત્વનું સંગ્રહ, જેમાં મોનેટ, રેનોઇર અને ડેગાસ જેવા કલાકારોના કાર્યો છે.પેન્થિઓન:  એક ઐતિહાસિક સ્મારક જેમાં વિક્ટર હ્યુગો, એમિલ ઝોલા અને મારી ક્યુરી જેવા પ્રખ્યાત લોકોના અવશેષો છે.પેલેસ ગાર્નિયર:  એક ભવ્ય ઓપેરા હ"},{"question":"Which Dutch darts player became victorious at the Lakeside Country Club in Frimley Green on January 15, 2012, in the BDO World Championship?","answer":"On January 15, 2012, Christian Kist won the BDO World Championship at the Lakeside Country Club in Frimley Green."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai alah limau oleh benalu\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud orang baik kalah kepada orang jahat."},{"question":"சரியான விடையை தேர்ந்தெடுத்து எழுதுக .கேள்வி: 1942 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஹஜிராபாக் மத்திய சிறையிலிருந்த போது ‘வால்காவிலிருந்து கங்கை வரை’ என்ற நூலை இந்தி மொழியில் எழுதியவர் ………………..அ) ராகுல் சாங்கிருத்யாயன்ஆ) சசிதேவ்இ) கணமுத்தையாஈ) வெ. ஸ்ரீராம்","answer":" பதில்: 1942 ஆம் ஆண்டு ஹஜிராபாக் மத்திய சிறையிலிருந்த போது ‘வால்காவிலிருந்து கங்கை வரை’ என்ற நூலை இந்தி மொழியில் எழுதியவர் அ) ராகுல் சாங்கிருத்யாயன்.இராகுல் சாங்கிருத்தியாயன் (ஏப்ரல் 9, 1893 - ஏப்ரல் 14, 1963) இந்தி பயண இலக்கியத்தின் தந்தை என அறியப்படுபவர்; தன் வாழ்நாளில் 45 வருட காலத்தை உள்நாட்டு மற்றும் வெளிநாட்டுப் பயணத்தில் செலவழித்தவர்; பன்மொழிப்புலவர்; பல்துறை வித்தகர்; புத்தத் துறவியாகி பின்னர் மார்க்சியவாதியானவர். அதுமட்டுமன்றி ஆங்கிலேயர் ஆட்சிக்கெதிரான கருத்துகளை எழுதியதற்காக மூன்றாண்டு கால சிறைவாசம் அனுபவித்தவர்."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : deporte. ","answer":"¿Qué golfista terminó subcampeón en el U. S. Abierto la mayoría de las veces sin ganar nunca? Phil Mickelson. "},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Tooñkat ya weccee baat ya Nu leen waxoon, ak yeneeni baat yu wuuteek yooya, Nu daldi wàcce ca way-tooñ ña mbugal mu bawoo asamaan ngir la ñu nekkoon di saay-saay [su génn diine].","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Tooñkat ya weccee baat ya Nu léen wàxoon, ak yeneen i baat yu wùutee'k yooya, Nu daldi wàcce ca waytooñ ña mbugal mu bawoo àsamaan ngìr la ñu nekkoon di saay-saay [su génn diine]."},{"question":"Jawab soalan yang rumit ini: Apakah anugerah yang menamakan Anna Kendrick dalam filem muzikal?","answer":"Anugerah Tony"}]`),M={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:S},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:I,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},C={class:"search-container"},O={class:"card-container"},B=["disabled"],D={key:0},L={key:1};function K(e,a,s,g,t,u){const d=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",C,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",O,[(i(!0),o(p,null,c(u.filteredPoems,(r,m)=>(i(),f(d,{key:m,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",L,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",D,"See more"))],8,B)):j("",!0)])}const P=k(M,[["render",K],["__scopeId","data-v-34f586a7"]]),F=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/26.md","filePath":"chatai/26.md"}'),H={name:"chatai/26.md"},E=Object.assign(H,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(P)]))}});export{F as __pageData,E as default};
